<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss>
  <channel>
    <title>Merged RSS (n8n)</title>
    <link>https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss</link>
    <description>Merged feed generated by n8n</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2026-02-15T00:00:00.000+01:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>it-IT</language>
    <dc:identifier>https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss</dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner Research Reveals CFOs’ Budget Plans Prioritize Growth Functions, Technology and AI in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-10-gartner-research-reveals-cfos-budget-plans-prioritize-grotwth-functions-tech-and-ai-in-2026?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&amp;utm_source=threads,twitter&amp;utm_medium=social</link>
      <guid>https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-10-gartner-research-reveals-cfos-budget-plans-prioritize-grotwth-functions-tech-and-ai-in-2026?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&amp;utm_source=threads,twitter&amp;utm_medium=social</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize alignment between business goals and IT systems. Core principles include **strategic alignment**, modular design for scalability, and governance to ensure agility. Key focus areas: **value delivery** (cost/benefit analysis), **risk management** (compliance, security), and **interoperability** across legacy/modern systems. Frameworks like FEAF prioritize flexibility in evolving business needs, while TOGAF’s phases (PDCA) guide structured implementation.

Not of interest.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-09</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce: Latest news and insights</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/3490106/salesforce-latest-news-and-insights.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/3490106/salesforce-latest-news-and-insights.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at a **strategic, enterprise-wide level** for ultra-large organizations (e.g., Fortune 500, global conglomerates). Focuses on aligning IT with business goals via frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or ArchiMate. Prioritizes cross-functional integration, risk management, and scalability in complex ecosystems (e.g., cloud-native, AI-driven, multi-cloud). Emphasizes governance, compliance (ISO 27001, GDPR), and future-proofing legacy systems with modern architectures (e.g., microservices, edge computing). Critical for digital transformation, regulatory adherence, and competitive differentiation in high-stakes industries like finance or healthcare.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-09</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How generative AI is redefining payments</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4128906/how-generative-ai-is-redefining-payments.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4128906/how-generative-ai-is-redefining-payments.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) mandates **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems, ensuring scalability, security, and efficiency. Key focus areas include **digital transformation**, **data governance**, and **interoperability** across legacy/modern systems. EA frameworks like TOGAF or Zachman guide structured planning, balancing cost with innovation. Compliance (e.g., GDPR) and risk management are critical to avoid disruptions. Cloud migration and AI integration demand agile EA strategies for future-proofing. Not of interest: trivial operational details or non-technical business processes.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-09</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hands On, Heads Up: Why B2B Leaders Who Embrace Active Learning Get Ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/hands-on-heads-up-why-b2b-leaders-who-embrace-active-learning-get-ahead/</link>
      <guid>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/hands-on-heads-up-why-b2b-leaders-who-embrace-active-learning-get-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize alignment between business goals and IT systems. Key principles include **strategic alignment**, modular design for scalability, and governance to ensure agility. Frameworks like **ArchiMate** model enterprise architecture layers (business, application, technology) with standardized symbols. **Value Stream Mapping** visualizes processes to identify inefficiencies, while **Reference Architectures** (e.g., IBM’s Open Reference Architecture) provide blueprints for cloud-native or hybrid systems. **Digital Transformation** drives adoption of AI/ML, IoT, and microservices, requiring agile governance models. **Security-first design** integrates compliance (ISO 27001, GDPR) into architecture decisions. **Open Standards** (e.g., OASIS, IEEE) ensure interoperability across vendors. **Cost-benefit analysis** balances innovation with ROI in large-scale deployments.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-10</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From elastic to intentional compute</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4129637/from-elastic-to-intentional-compute.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4129637/from-elastic-to-intentional-compute.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize structured governance for aligning IT with business strategies. Key principles include **enterprise-wide alignment**, modular design (e.g., layers: Strategy, Architecture, Implementation), and risk-driven decision-making. Frameworks like **ArchiMate** visualize systems via layers (Business, Application, Technology) to model dependencies. Agile/DevOps integration challenges highlight the need for iterative architecture evolution. Emerging trends include AI/ML governance and cybersecurity resilience in enterprise architectures.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-10</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QCon Previews 20th Anniversary Conferences: Production AI, Resilience, and Staff+ Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/qcon-previews-20th-anniversary/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&amp;utm_source=infoq&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news</link>
      <guid>https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/qcon-previews-20th-anniversary/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&amp;utm_source=infoq&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at a **strategic, high-level** scale: Aligns business objectives with IT systems to drive digital transformation. Focuses on cross-enterprise frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or ArchiMate to optimize efficiency, scalability, and innovation. Prioritizes data governance, cloud migration, and cybersecurity resilience in large-scale enterprise ecosystems. Challenges include balancing legacy systems with modern agility while ensuring compliance (e.g., GDPR, ISO 27001). Success hinges on stakeholder collaboration across departments to future-proof architectures amid volatility.

**not of interest**</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-10</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shadow AI practices: A wakeup call for enterprises</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4129630/shadow-ai-practices-a-wakeup-call-for-enterprises.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4129630/shadow-ai-practices-a-wakeup-call-for-enterprises.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize **strategic alignment** and **cross-domain integration**, ensuring IT supports business goals while optimizing cost, scalability, and risk. Key focus areas include **enterprise-wide governance models**, **architecture reference models (ARM)**, and **digital transformation roadmaps**. High-level principles like **modularity** and **interoperability** drive modern EA success.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-10</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI fails without an architecture of flow to eliminate the friction tax</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4129620/agentic-ai-fails-without-an-architecture-of-flow-to-eliminate-the-friction-tax.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4129620/agentic-ai-fails-without-an-architecture-of-flow-to-eliminate-the-friction-tax.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at a **strategic, high-level** scale: Aligns business objectives with IT capabilities across global enterprises to drive innovation, cost efficiency, and resilience. Focuses on cross-functional frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or ArchiMate to standardize governance, optimize digital transformation, and mitigate risks in complex ecosystems (e.g., MNCs, government agencies). Prioritizes scalability, agility, and compliance while leveraging emerging tech (AI/ML, cloud) to future-proof architectures. Critical for competitive advantage via data-driven decision-making and unified systems integration.

**Not of interest**: Operational-level IT tasks or vendor-specific tools.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-10</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Architects Stepped Out of the Ivory Tower</title>
      <link>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/enterprise-architects-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</link>
      <guid>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/enterprise-architects-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize modularity and alignment with business goals. Key principles include **standardized governance** (e.g., COBIT for IT control), **value chain integration**, and **risk-based decision-making**. Modern EAs leverage AI/ML to optimize system efficiency while balancing legacy systems with innovation. Cross-functional collaboration between IT, business, and stakeholders ensures agile transformation. Metrics like ROI, scalability, and compliance drive strategic outcomes.

**Not of interest.**</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The struggle for good AI governance is real</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4128980/the-struggle-for-good-ai-governance-is-real.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4128980/the-struggle-for-good-ai-governance-is-real.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize modularity and alignment with business goals. Key principles include **standardized governance**, cross-functional collaboration (IT + business), and lifecycle-driven design for scalability. Focus areas: **value delivery** via architecture decisions, **risk mitigation** through agile/DevOps integration, and **future-proofing** via cloud-native or hybrid architectures. Legacy modernization and digital transformation are critical drivers.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CX, AI and the data trap: Why your best customers are slipping away</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4130913/cx-ai-and-the-data-trap-why-your-best-customers-are-slipping-away.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4130913/cx-ai-and-the-data-trap-why-your-best-customers-are-slipping-away.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** demands a holistic, future-proof framework aligning business, IT, and organizational goals. Focuses on **cross-domain integration**, leveraging advanced technologies like AI/ML, cloud-native architectures, and digital transformation to drive scalability and resilience. Prioritizes **enterprise-wide governance models** (e.g., TOGAF, Zachman) for consistency while enabling agility. Emphasizes **data-driven decision-making** via real-time analytics and IoT ecosystems. Challenges include balancing legacy systems with innovation, ensuring cybersecurity at enterprise levels, and fostering cultural change for collaborative EA adoption.

*Not of interest.*</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most AI strategies will never become agentic. Here’s why.</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4130557/most-ai-strategies-will-never-become-agentic-heres-why.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4130557/most-ai-strategies-will-never-become-agentic-heres-why.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** drives transformative digital and operational convergence across industries. Key focus areas include:

1. **Global Digital Ecosystems**: Seamless integration of AI, IoT, and cloud-native architectures to enable hyper-personalized, real-time decision-making.
2. **Resilience &amp; Sustainability**: Zero-trust frameworks and circular economy models ensuring agility while minimizing carbon footprints.
3. **Regulatory Leadership**: Proactive compliance with evolving laws (e.g., GDPR 4.0, AI ethics) via automated governance tools.
4. **Future-Proofing**: Quantum-ready infrastructure and modular architectures to adapt to exponential growth in data complexity.

Not of interest: Operational workflows or tactical IT projects.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What CIOs must get right for the AI era</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4127712/what-cios-must-get-right-for-the-ai-era.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4127712/what-cios-must-get-right-for-the-ai-era.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems. Key focus areas include **governance models**, **value streams**, and **technology roadmaps**. Frameworks like **ArchiMate** visualize architecture layers (business, data, application, technology), while **reference architectures** (e.g., AWS Well-Architected) provide best practices for scalability, security, and cost efficiency. Emerging trends like **AI/ML integration** and **digital transformation** drive modern EA’s emphasis on agility and innovation.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner Survey Finds Low-Growth Economic Environment Remained Top Concern Among Risk Leaders in Fourth Quarter of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-11-gartner-survey-finds-low-growth-econ-enviro-remained-top-concern-among-risk-leaders-in-q425?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&amp;utm_source=threads,twitter&amp;utm_medium=social</link>
      <guid>https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-11-gartner-survey-finds-low-growth-econ-enviro-remained-top-concern-among-risk-leaders-in-q425?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&amp;utm_source=threads,twitter&amp;utm_medium=social</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize alignment between business goals and IT systems. Key principles include **strategic alignment**, modular design for scalability, and governance to ensure agility. Frameworks like **ArchiMate** model processes, applications, and infrastructure visually, while **Open Group Architecture Framework (TOGAF)** focuses on phased architecture development. Modern trends highlight **digital transformation** integration, emphasizing cloud-native architectures and data-driven decision-making. Security and compliance (e.g., GDPR) are critical, requiring risk-based approaches in design.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-11</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trust in the age of agentic AI systems</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4130267/trust-in-the-age-of-agentic-ai-systems.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4130267/trust-in-the-age-of-agentic-ai-systems.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** drives transformative digital and operational convergence across industries. Key focus areas include **AI-driven decision-making**, **multi-cloud/edge architectures**, and **zero-trust security frameworks**. Governance models evolve toward **agile, outcome-based policies**, blending legacy systems with quantum-ready infrastructure. Cyber-physical integration (e.g., IoT, autonomous systems) demands real-time resilience. **Regulatory agility** (e.g., GDPR 2.0, AI ethics) shapes compliance-driven innovation. **Value chains redefine** via blockchain-enabled transparency and circular economy models. **Not of interest**: tactical IT projects or vendor-specific tools.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-11</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI and ML are transforming investment banking’s future</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4131383/how-ai-and-ml-are-transforming-investment-bankings-future.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4131383/how-ai-and-ml-are-transforming-investment-bankings-future.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** demands a holistic, future-proof framework aligning business vision with digital transformation. Key focus areas include:

1. **Strategic Alignment**: Cross-functional governance ensuring EA drives long-term value via IT/business synergy.
2. **Digital Transformation**: Agile frameworks (e.g., TOGAF 4.0) for cloud-native, AI-driven architectures to outpace competitors.
3. **Risk &amp; Compliance**: Zero-trust security models and GDPR/ISO 27001 integration to mitigate cyber-physical risks.
4. **Resilience Engineering**: Multi-cloud/hybrid resilience with disaster recovery (DR) as a service for operational continuity.
5. **Value Co-Creation**: Stakeholder-centric EA (e.g., CIO-CEO collaboration) to unlock innovation via data-driven insights.

**Not of interest**: Operational details or tactical implementations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-13</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The decision product operating model: How to build AI that actually runs the business</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4131369/the-decision-product-operating-model-how-to-build-ai-that-actually-runs-the-business.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4131369/the-decision-product-operating-model-how-to-build-ai-that-actually-runs-the-business.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) mandates structured governance for aligning IT systems with business strategy. Core principles include **standardized frameworks** (TOGAF, Zachman), ensuring modularity and scalability in digital ecosystems. **Risk mitigation** through compliance (ISO 27001, GDPR) and cybersecurity (NIST SP 800-53) is critical. **Value delivery** via agile methodologies (SAFe, DevOps) optimizes resource allocation. **Interoperability** between legacy and modern systems demands API-driven architectures. **Data governance** enforces integrity, security, and compliance across siloed datasets. EA bridges IT and business objectives through **strategic roadmaps**, ensuring alignment with long-term vision while addressing immediate operational needs.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-13</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where AI differentiation actually comes from</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4131354/where-ai-differentiation-actually-comes-from.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4131354/where-ai-differentiation-actually-comes-from.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** drives transformative digital and operational convergence across industries. Key focus areas include:

1. **Global Digital Transformation**: Seamless integration of AI/ML, IoT, and cloud-native architectures to enable real-time decision-making and hyper-personalization.
2. **Regulatory &amp; Compliance Leadership**: Zero-trust frameworks, GDPR/Cybersecurity mandates, and ESG alignment for sustainable scalability.
3. **Cross-Border Enterprise Integration**: Unified data governance, blockchain for supply chain transparency, and hybrid cloud resilience.
4. **Future-Proofing with Agile EA**: Modular architectures (e.g., microservices) to accelerate innovation while mitigating legacy risks.
5. **Cognitive &amp; Predictive Capabilities**: AI-driven architecture optimization for cost-efficiency and competitive advantage.

*Not of interest*: Operational details or tactical implementations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-13</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geopatriation and sovereign cloud: how data returns to the source</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4131458/geopatriacion-and-sovereign-cloud-how-data-returns-to-its-origin.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4131458/geopatriacion-and-sovereign-cloud-how-data-returns-to-its-origin.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize **strategic alignment** and **enterprise-wide integration**, focusing on governance, business process optimization, and IT infrastructure coherence. Key themes include **value delivery models**, cross-functional collaboration (e.g., CIO-CEO synergy), and adaptive architectures for digital transformation. High-level principles like **modularity** and **standardization** reduce complexity while ensuring scalability. Legacy modernization and risk mitigation (cybersecurity, compliance) are critical in high-stakes environments.

*Not of interest.*</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-13</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SaaS isn’t dead, the market is just becoming more hybrid</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4131904/saas-isnt-dead-the-market-is-just-becoming-more-hybrid.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4131904/saas-isnt-dead-the-market-is-just-becoming-more-hybrid.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** drives transformative digital and operational convergence across industries. Focuses on aligning business, IT, and data ecosystems with high-level vision—e.g., AI-driven automation, quantum computing readiness, or cross-border regulatory compliance. Prioritizes **enterprise-wide resilience**, agile governance frameworks (e.g., TOGAF 9), and zero-trust security models for ultra-high-stakes environments like defense, aerospace, or critical infrastructure. Challenges include balancing legacy systems with next-gen architectures while ensuring scalability for exponential growth. Key metrics: ROI from digital twins, cyber-physical system efficiency, and cross-domain interoperability.

**not of interest**</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-13</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt governance is the new data governance</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4130960/prompt-governance-is-the-new-data-governance.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4130960/prompt-governance-is-the-new-data-governance.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize core principles: alignment with business goals, modular design for scalability, and standardized processes. Key focus areas include **strategy mapping** (connecting IT to organizational vision), **architecture layers** (business, data, application, technology), and **governance models** (roles, decision-making frameworks). Emerging trends like AI/ML integration and cloud-native architectures demand agile, adaptive frameworks. Collaboration between stakeholders—C-level executives, architects, and developers—ensures cohesive, future-proof systems.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Architects Have Stepped Out Of The Ivory Tower</title>
      <link>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</link>
      <guid>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize core principles: alignment with business goals, modular design for scalability, and standardized processes. Key focus areas include **strategy mapping** (connecting IT to organizational objectives), **architecture governance** (ensuring compliance and risk management), and **technology roadmaps** (balancing innovation with stability). Frameworks like FEAF prioritize flexibility in modeling approaches, while TOGAF’s structured phases (e.g., Architecture Development Method) drive systematic implementation. Integration of digital transformation, cloud migration, and AI/ML into enterprise architectures is critical for competitive advantage.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Architects Have Stepped Out Of The Ivory Tower</title>
      <link>https://eavoices.com/2026/02/12/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</link>
      <guid>https://eavoices.com/2026/02/12/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize **strategic alignment** and **standardized governance** to optimize IT investments. Key focus areas include **business process integration**, **data management**, and **technology roadmaps** to ensure scalability and agility. Frameworks like **ArchiMate** visualize architecture layers (e.g., business, application, technology), while **enterprise data models** standardize information flows. Emerging trends like AI/ML integration and cloud-native architectures demand adaptive frameworks for future-proofing.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-12</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving enterprise AI’s ROI problem</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4132176/solving-enterprise-ais-roi-problem.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4132176/solving-enterprise-ais-roi-problem.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) mandates **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems, ensuring scalability, security, and cost-efficiency. Core principles include **reference models** (e.g., TOGAF, Zachman) for framework consistency, while **value chains** optimize resource allocation across domains like data, applications, or infrastructure. **Governance frameworks** enforce compliance (ISO 27001, GDPR) and risk management via policies, audits, and metrics. **Digital transformation** drives innovation through agile architectures, cloud-native designs, and AI/ML integration—balancing legacy systems with modern agility. **Interoperability** ensures seamless data flow between systems (e.g., APIs, standards like OpenAPI), while **disaster recovery** prioritizes resilience via redundancy and failover strategies. **Ethical considerations** (privacy, bias) are embedded in architecture decisions to uphold trust.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-13</pubISODate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>