<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss>
  <channel>
    <title>Merged RSS (n8n)</title>
    <link>https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss</link>
    <description>Merged feed generated by n8n</description>
    <lastBuildDate>2026-02-22T00:00:00.000+01:00</lastBuildDate>
    <language>it-IT</language>
    <dc:identifier>https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss</dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title>Giving AI ‘hands’ in your SaaS stack</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4132320/giving-ai-hands-in-your-saas-stack.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4132320/giving-ai-hands-in-your-saas-stack.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) mandates **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems, ensuring scalability, security, and efficiency. Core principles include **standardized frameworks** (TOGAF, Zachman), modular design for flexibility, and risk mitigation via governance models. EA drives **digital transformation** by optimizing legacy systems while integrating emerging tech (AI/ML, cloud). Compliance (ISO 27001, GDPR) and vendor neutrality are critical to avoid lock-in. Collaboration between stakeholders—business, IT, and external partners—ensures cohesive, future-proof architectures.

*Not of interest.*</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-16</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t rip and replace PeopleSoft — pair it with emerging tech instead</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4132315/dont-rip-and-replace-peoplesoft-pair-it-with-emerging-tech-instead.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4132315/dont-rip-and-replace-peoplesoft-pair-it-with-emerging-tech-instead.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** demands a holistic, future-proof framework aligning business vision with tech innovation. Key focus areas include:

1. **Global Governance**: Cross-border compliance (e.g., GDPR, CCPA), unified standards, and risk mitigation for high-stakes enterprises.
2. **Digital Transformation**: AI/ML integration, quantum computing readiness, and hyper-automation to outpace competitors.
3. **Resilience &amp; Agility**: Zero-trust security, cloud-native architectures, and modular systems for rapid adaptation in volatile markets.
4. **Data Sovereignty**: Centralized yet decentralized data governance with real-time analytics for high-value decision-making.
5. **Ethical AI**: Bias mitigation, explainable AI, and regulatory alignment (e.g., EU AI Act) to build trust in critical applications.

**Not of interest**: Operational-level workflows or tactical IT projects.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-16</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taming agent sprawl: 3 pillars of AI orchestration</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4132287/taming-agent-sprawl-3-pillars-of-ai-orchestration.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4132287/taming-agent-sprawl-3-pillars-of-ai-orchestration.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems. Key focus areas include **governance models**, **value streams**, and **technology roadmaps**. Frameworks like **ArchiMate** visualize architecture layers (business, data, application, technology), while **enterprise-wide integration** ensures seamless data flow across systems. **Agile/DevOps adoption** is critical for flexibility in dynamic environments. **Risk management** and compliance (e.g., GDPR) are mandatory for security and regulatory adherence.

Not of interest: Detailed case studies or vendor-specific tools.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-16</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Agentic Commerce Emerges, Services Providers Are Rewriting Commerce Playbooks End To End</title>
      <link>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/as-agentic-commerce-emerges-services-providers-are-rewriting-commerce-playbooks-end-to-end/</link>
      <guid>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/as-agentic-commerce-emerges-services-providers-are-rewriting-commerce-playbooks-end-to-end/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize modularity and alignment with business goals. Key principles include **standardized governance**, cross-functional collaboration (IT, business), and lifecycle management of systems/services. Focus areas: **strategy-to-execution** via architecture blueprints, risk mitigation through agile/DevOps integration, and scalability for digital transformation. Legacy modernization and cloud-native migration are critical trends. Data sovereignty and cybersecurity are mandatory compliance drivers.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-17</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ‘Genesis’ gamble: Creating order from chaos in the age of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4132853/the-genesis-gamble-creating-order-from-chaos-in-the-age-of-ai.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4132853/the-genesis-gamble-creating-order-from-chaos-in-the-age-of-ai.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at a **strategic, high-level** scale: Aligns business objectives with IT capabilities across global enterprises to drive innovation, cost efficiency, and risk mitigation. Focuses on frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF for governance, leveraging digital transformation, cloud migration, and AI/ML integration to optimize scalability and agility. Prioritizes cross-functional collaboration (IT, business, stakeholders) while addressing compliance (e.g., GDPR, ISO 27001) and emerging threats like cybersecurity and ESG mandates. Outcomes include standardized architectures for legacy modernization, vendor-neutral platforms, and data-driven decision-making via analytics.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-17</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI’s energy wake-up call</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4132833/ais-energy-wake-up-call.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4132833/ais-energy-wake-up-call.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** demands a holistic, future-proof framework aligning business vision with transformative digital/operational capabilities. Key focus areas include:

1. **Strategic Alignment**: Cross-domain integration of IT, data, and innovation to drive competitive advantage via agile governance.
2. **Digital Transformation**: AI-driven automation, cloud-native architectures, and IoT ecosystems for scalability and resilience.
3. **Regulatory Compliance**: Zero-trust security models and GDPR/CCPA-ready frameworks ensuring ethical AI and privacy-first design.
4. **Resilience &amp; Agility**: Multi-cloud hybrid architectures with disaster recovery (DR) and chaos engineering to mitigate risks.
5. **Value-Driven EA**: Cost-efficiency via lean methodologies (DevOps, SAFe) while maximizing ROI on legacy modernization.

**Not of interest**: Operational details or tactical implementations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-17</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI isn’t the risk — not being able to explain it is</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4132817/ai-isnt-the-risk-not-being-able-to-explain-it-is.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4132817/ai-isnt-the-risk-not-being-able-to-explain-it-is.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at **strategic scale** drives transformative digital and operational convergence across industries. Key focus areas include **AI-driven decision-making**, **hyper-personalization**, and **real-time global optimization**. Mandatory integration of **quantum computing** and **blockchain** for ultra-secure, decentralized ecosystems reshapes compliance (e.g., GDPR 3.0) and cyber-physical systems. **Zero-trust architecture** evolves into **trust-as-a-service**, while **autonomous governance** automates policy enforcement via AI-driven ethics frameworks. Supply chain resilience leverages **predictive analytics** and **digital twins** for adaptive, resilient networks. **Interoperability standards** (e.g., ISO 27001+AI) ensure cross-domain compatibility. **Regulatory agility** prioritizes dynamic compliance via automated audits. **Sustainable EA** merges circular economy principles with carbon-neutral infrastructure. **Cyber-physical convergence** enables smart cities, autonomous logistics, and energy grids. **Ethical AI governance** mandates bias mitigation and explainability in high-stakes systems (e.g., healthcare, defense). **Post-human collaboration** integrates biotech with digital twins for augmented human performance.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-17</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When cloud-only isn’t realistic: why hybrid desktop strategies are back</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4134635/when-cloud-only-isnt-realistic-why-hybrid-desktop-strategies-are-back.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4134635/when-cloud-only-isnt-realistic-why-hybrid-desktop-strategies-are-back.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize core principles: alignment with business goals, modular design for scalability, and standardized governance. Key focus areas include **strategy mapping** (connecting IT to business objectives), **architecture layers** (data, applications, infrastructure), and **risk/value management**. Frameworks like FEAF prioritize agility and customer-centricity, while TOGAF’s phased approach ensures structured implementation. Integration of open standards (e.g., OASIS) and cloud-native principles is critical for modern EA success.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-20</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why CIOs need analytics capability to scale AI</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4134765/why-cios-need-analytics-capability-to-scale-ai.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4134765/why-cios-need-analytics-capability-to-scale-ai.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) at a **strategic, high-level** scale: Aligns enterprise goals with IT systems, processes, and data to drive digital transformation. Focuses on cross-functional integration—governance, risk, and innovation frameworks ensuring scalability, agility, and compliance across global operations. Prioritizes value delivery via architecture patterns (e.g., microservices, cloud-native) while balancing legacy modernization with future-proofing. Critical for C-level decision-making in complex ecosystems like defense, finance, or healthcare.

**Not of interest**: Operational day-to-day tasks or tactical implementations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-20</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce Acquires Momentum: What it means</title>
      <link>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/whats-salesforces-acquisition-of-momentum-means/</link>
      <guid>https://www.forrester.com/blogs/whats-salesforces-acquisition-of-momentum-means/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize core principles: alignment between business and IT goals, modular design for scalability, and standardized governance. Key focus areas include **strategy mapping** (connecting long-term vision with execution), **architecture layers** (business, data, application, technology), and **risk management** via lifecycle models. Frameworks like FEAF prioritize agility, while TOGAF’s phased approach ensures structured implementation. Collaboration between stakeholders is critical to balance innovation with stability.

not of interest</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-20</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Architects Have Stepped Out Of The Ivory Tower</title>
      <link>https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</link>
      <guid>https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/</guid>
      <description>**Enterprise Architecture: Strategic Alignment &amp; Digital Transformation**
Modern EAs drive **end-to-end value delivery**, blending IT, business, and data strategies to optimize digital transformation. Key focus areas include **agile frameworks (TOGAF, Zachman)**, governance models (ITIL, COBIT), and cloud-native architectures. Stakeholder collaboration ensures alignment with organizational goals—balancing legacy systems with innovation while mitigating risks in complex ecosystems.

*Not of interest.*</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-20</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Architects Have Stepped Out Of The Ivory Tower</title>
      <link>https://eavoices.com/2026/02/20/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower-2/</link>
      <guid>https://eavoices.com/2026/02/20/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower-2/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) mandates **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems, ensuring scalability, security, and cost-efficiency. Key focus areas include **digital transformation**, **data governance**, and **interoperability** across legacy/modern systems. EA frameworks like TOGAF or Zachman guide structured planning, balancing agility with compliance (e.g., GDPR). Critical success factors: **stakeholder collaboration**, modular architectures, and risk mitigation via vendor-neutral standards. Emerging trends like AI/ML integration and cloud-native shifts demand adaptive EA strategies to future-proof IT ecosystems.

**Not of interest:** Technical implementation details or non-strategic operational workflows.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-20</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How agentic AI will reshape engineering workflows in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.cio.com/article/4134741/how-agentic-ai-will-reshape-engineering-workflows-in-2026.html</link>
      <guid>https://www.cio.com/article/4134741/how-agentic-ai-will-reshape-engineering-workflows-in-2026.html</guid>
      <description>**Structural Differences in Agentic AI**
Agentic AI introduces autonomous, goal-driven agents with real-time decision-making, unlike traditional AI’s reactive or rule-based systems. These agents leverage multi-agent collaboration, dynamic workflows, and context-aware reasoning to optimize outcomes across domains (e.g., supply chain, healthcare). Their modularity enables scalability, while reinforcement learning and adversarial training enhance adaptability—critical for high-stakes enterprise environments.

**Enterprise AI Platforms/Architectures**
Modern platforms integrate AI into core infrastructure via microservices, cloud-native architectures, and hybrid models. Key components include data pipelines (Kafka/Spark), model orchestration (Kubeflow), and governance layers (AI ethics frameworks). Architectures prioritize explainability (SHAP/LIME) and cybersecurity (model protection), ensuring compliance with regulations like GDPR.

**Enterprise Transformation**
AI-driven transformation accelerates digital disruption by automating processes, enhancing predictive analytics, and fostering innovation. Enterprises must balance agility with control—leveraging AI for cost reduction while mitigating risks via change management and upskilling initiatives. Success hinges on aligning AI strategies with business KPIs (e.g., revenue growth, operational efficiency).

**Frameworks &amp; Methods**
Agile frameworks like SAFe or Lean AI guide iterative AI deployment, while methods like NLP (BERT) and generative models (LLMs) enable context-aware interactions. Enterprise-specific tools include MLOps pipelines (Airflow), compliance audits (AI Fairness 360), and ROI calculators for AI investments. Emerging trends: explainable AI (XAI), federated learning, and quantum-enhanced decision-making.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-20</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Onboarding from 48 Hours to 4: inside Amazon Key’s Event-Driven Platform</title>
      <link>https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&amp;utm_source=infoq&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news</link>
      <guid>https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&amp;utm_source=infoq&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news</guid>
      <description>Enterprise architecture frameworks like TOGAF, Zachman, or FEAF emphasize **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems. Key focus areas include **governance models**, **value chains**, and **technology roadmaps**. Frameworks like **ArchiMate** visualize enterprise structure via layers (business, application, technology). Emerging trends highlight **digital transformation** integration, **AI/ML-driven decision-making**, and **cybersecurity resilience**. Not of interest.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-19</pubISODate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Excellent Technology Architecture Fails to Deliver Business Results</title>
      <link>https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/</link>
      <guid>https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Architecture (EA) mandates **strategic alignment** between business goals and IT systems, ensuring scalability, security, and efficiency. Key focus areas include **digital transformation**, **data governance**, and **interoperability** across legacy/modern systems. EA frameworks like TOGAF or Zachman guide structured architecture, balancing cost with innovation while mitigating risks through agile methodologies. Compliance (e.g., GDPR) and vendor neutrality drive sustainable, future-proof architectures.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <pubISODate>2026-02-19</pubISODate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>