<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:07:48 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Quesma Releases OTelBench to Evaluate OpenTelemetry Infrastructure and AI Performance]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/quesma-otel-bench-performance-ai/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/quesma-otel-bench-performance-ai/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/quesma-otel-bench-performance-ai/en/headerimage/header-1771767302848.jpeg"/><p>Quesma has launched OTelBench, an open-source suite to benchmark OpenTelemetry pipelines and AI-driven instrumentation. It evaluates collector performance under stress while testing how accurately LLMs handle complex SRE tasks like context propagation. Initial data shows AI agents often achieve success rates below 30%, highlighting the gap between code generation and production observability.</p> <i>By Mark Silvester</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[엔비디아, 인도서 ‘GPU 대신 데이터’···AI 주권 전략 재설계]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136340/%ec%97%94%eb%b9%84%eb%94%94%ec%95%84-%ec%9d%b8%eb%8f%84%ec%84%9c-gpu-%eb%8c%80%ec%8b%a0-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ec%a3%bc%ea%b6%8c-%ea%b8%b0%eb%b0%98-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136340/%ec%97%94%eb%b9%84%eb%94%94%ec%95%84-%ec%9d%b8%eb%8f%84%ec%84%9c-gpu-%eb%8c%80%ec%8b%a0-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ec%a3%bc%ea%b6%8c-%ea%b8%b0%eb%b0%98-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>엔비디아는 수년간 AI 주권(소버린 AI)를 강조해 왔지만, 인도의 문화적·경제적 다양성으로 인해 기존과는 다른 방식으로 접근하고 있다.</p> <p>미국과 달리, 인도에서는 대량의 GPU 공급만으로는 사업 확장을 견인하기 어렵다고 평가됐다. 엔비디아는 우선 소프트웨어 역량에 집중하고, 이후 컴퓨팅 인프라를 단계적으로 확대하는 전략을 구상하고 있다. 인구 구성과 문화, 언어의 폭넓은 차이를 반영한 현지화 AI 계획을 기반으로, 데이터 우선 접근 방식을 택하겠다는 전략이다.</p> <p>엔비디아는 오픈소스 기술 역량을 앞세 방대한 인도 개발자 커뮤니티와의 접점을 넓히는 한편, 현지 에너지 환경과 데이터센터 인프라 수준에 맞춘 소형 언어 모델을 포함하는 로컬 AI 전략도 마련하고 있다.</p> <p>엔비디아 남아시아 총괄 비샬 두파르는 “인도에서 생성되는 데이터가 하나의 ‘인도형 스택’으로 통합되면, 시민이 활용할 수 있는 인구 규모의 플랫폼이 구축된다. 이를 통해 교육, 헬스케어, 모빌리티 등 인도가 직면한 다양한 대형 과제를 해결할 수 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>인도 정부는 자국의 AI 활용 방식이 미국 등과는 다르다는 점을 분명히 해왔다. 예를 들어 농업 종사자는 대규모 언어 모델(LLM)에 직접 접근할 필요가 없으며, 저전력 칩에서 구동되는 목적형 소형 모델만으로도 충분히 문제를 해결할 수 있다고 설명했다.</p> <p>인도를 대상으로 한 엔비디아의 IT 주권 전략에는 네모트론(Nemotron)과 같은 오픈 모델과 각종 개발 도구를 인도 개발자에게 확대 제공하는 방안이 포함돼 있다. 두파르는 “오픈 모델은 AI 주권을 한층 가속화할 수 있다. 개발자가 자신의 언어와 전통, 문화를 기술 전반에 반영할 수 있도록 돕는다”라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>엔비디아는 지난해 인도에서 널리 사용되는 프로그래밍 언어 파이썬(Python)으로 쿠다(CUDA) 프로그램을 작성할 수 있도록 지원했다. 개발자가 쿠다 코드를 작성하면 AI 연산을 처리하기 위해 엔비디아 GPU가 필요해지기 때문에, 이는 간접적으로 GPU 판매 확대와도 연결되는 구조다.</p> <p>엔비디아의 블랙웰(Blackwell) 아키텍처 기반 GPU는 현재 인도 데이터센터에 설치되고 있다. 다만 인도의 인프라는 미국만큼 성숙한 단계는 아니다. 그럼에도 전력과 자원 제약을 고려할 때, 인도는 GPU 중심 구조를 넘어서는 차세대 AI 인프라를 설계할 여지가 있다. 인도는 저전력 칩과 엣지 프로세싱 중심의 환경을 미리 준비하고 있다.</p> <p>인도 IT 장관 아슈위니 바이슈나우는 지난달 세계경제포럼에서 소형 언어 모델을 구동할 수 있는 저전력 칩으로 곧바로 전환할 것을 제안했다.</p> <p>바이슈나우는 소형 모델이 훨씬 낮은 비용으로 인도 사용자 문제의 95%를 해결할 수 있다는 점을 근거로 들었다. 또한 과도하게 고평가된 AI 기업 한 곳이 무너질 경우 경제 전반에 충격을 줄 수 있는 ‘AI 버블’에 휘말리지 않겠다는 점도 분명히 했다.</p> <p>엔비디아에 따르면, 오픈소스 모델인 네모트론은 일부 현지화 모델 개발에 활용됐다. 여기에는 공공 서비스, 농업, 보안, 문화 보존 분야 애플리케이션을 구동하는 170억 개 파라미터 규모의 ‘바라트젠(BharatGen)’도 포함된다.</p> <p>엔비디아는 인도의 중앙 디지털 결제 시스템인 통합결제인터페이스(UPI)에도 AI 기술을 지원하고 있다. UPI는 속도와 효율성 측면에서 높은 평가를 받아왔다. UPI를 운영하는 인도국가결제공사(NPCI)는 “엔비디아 네모트론 3 나노(Nemotron 3 Nano) 모델과 자체 데이터셋을 활용해 인도형 금융 모델 ‘FiMi’ 학습을 검토하고 있다”라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>엔비디아 AI 기술은 80억 개 파라미터 규모의 다국어 커뮤니케이션 플랫폼 모델 ‘채리엇(Chariot)’과도 연관돼 있다. 또한 인도 특화 애플리케이션을 위한 멀티모달 AI 플랫폼 ‘사르밤.ai(Sarvam.ai)’와도 기술적으로 연결돼 있다.</p> <p>이와 함께 엔비디아는 차세대 개발자 양성과 신생 스타트업 육성을 위해 인도와 협력을 확대하고 있다. 대표적으로 인도 정부 산하 아누산단 국가연구재단(ANRF)과 협력해 주요 대학을 중심으로 첨단 AI 연구를 강화하는 프로젝트를 추진 중이다.</p> <p>엔비디아는 ANRF 지원 기관에 엔비디아 AI 엔터프라이즈 소프트웨어를 무상으로 제공하고, 엔비디아 AI 테크놀로지 센터를 통해 전문 기술 멘토링도 지원할 계획이다. 엔비디아 대변인은 “이번 협력에는 AI 부트캠프와 워크숍, 해커톤도 포함된다”라며 “인도의 AI 연구 생태계를 강화하는 데 목적이 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>기업 요타(Yotta)는 인도의 AI 주권 인프라 구축 계획을 기반으로, 샥티(Shakti) 클라우드에 엔비디아 블랙웰 울트라 GPU 2만 개를 도입할 예정이다. 라르센앤투브로(Larsen &amp; Toubro)와 E2E 네트웍스(E2E Networks)도 엔비디아 GPU 기반 신규 데이터센터를 설립하겠다고 발표했다.</p> <p>엔비디아는 유럽에서도 AI 주권 전략을 지속적으로 언급해왔다. 이를 위해 GPU 데이터센터 설립과 함께 통신, 소프트웨어, 산업 분야 기업과의 파트너십을 확대할 전망이다. 가트너는 <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4129552/gartner-european-spending-on-sovereign-cloud-iaas-to-nearly-double-in-2026.html" target="_blank">최근 보고서</a>에서 유럽의 IaaS 주권 투자 규모가 2025년 69억 달러에서 2026년 126억 달러로 증가할 수 있다고 내다봤다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[생성형 AI 확산 속 개발자 역량 재정의…무엇을 배우고 버려야 하나]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136337/%ec%83%9d%ec%84%b1%ed%98%95-ai-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0-%ec%86%8d-%ea%b0%9c%eb%b0%9c%ec%9e%90-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89-%ec%9e%ac%ec%a0%95%ec%9d%98%eb%ac%b4%ec%97%87%ec%9d%84-%eb%b0%b0%ec%9a%b0%ea%b3%a0.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136337/%ec%83%9d%ec%84%b1%ed%98%95-ai-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0-%ec%86%8d-%ea%b0%9c%eb%b0%9c%ec%9e%90-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89-%ec%9e%ac%ec%a0%95%ec%9d%98%eb%ac%b4%ec%97%87%ec%9d%84-%eb%b0%b0%ec%9a%b0%ea%b3%a0.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>오늘날 소프트웨어 개발 직무에 종사하면서 AI 기술을 피해 가는 것은 사실상 불가능에 가깝다. 이는 부정적인 변화라기보다, 개인과 팀 모두에게 AI 기반 개발이 다양한 잠재적 이점을 제공한다는 의미에 가깝다.</p> <p>분명한 사실은 아직 변화에 대응하지 못한 소프트웨어 개발자라면 이제는 새로운 시대의 요구에 맞춰 역량을 조정해야 한다는 점이다. 그리고 그 속도 역시 중요하다.</p> <p>전 세계 4만 9,000명 이상의 전문 개발자를 대상으로 진행된 ‘<a href="https://survey.stackoverflow.co/2025/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">스택오버플로 2025 개발자 설문조사</a>’에 따르면, 응답자의 84%가 개발 워크플로에서 AI 도구를 사용하고 있거나 사용할 계획이라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>이는 전년도 76%에서 증가한 수치다. 2025년 말 기준으로는 설문 응답자의 약 절반이 이미 AI 도구를 매일 사용하고 있다고 답했다.</p> <p>보안 플랫폼 제공 기업 앱스트랙트 시큐리티(Abstract Security)의 공동 설립자 겸 COO 크리스 카마초는 “이제 전 세계 개발자들은 AI가 일상적인 워크플로의 일부가 된 환경에 맞춰 역량을 조정하라는 압박을 받고 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>카마초는 “업계 전반에서 변화는 분명하다”라며 “여러 대기업의 내부 인력 분석 결과, 대다수 개발자가 이미 어떤 형태로든 AI 지원 도구를 사용하고 있는 것으로 나타났다. 또한 절반이 넘는 기업이 AI 및 데이터 관련 역량을 최우선 채용 요건으로 제시하고 있다”라고 전했다. 이어 “초기 클라우드 확산기와 비슷한 분위기지만, 도입 속도는 훨씬 빠르게 전개되고 있다”라고 분석했다.</p> <p>개발 도구를 제공하는 기업 디덕티브 AI(Deductive AI)의 공동 설립자 겸 CTO 사미어 아가르왈은 “개발자는 이미 직접 코드를 작성하는 방식에서, 에이전트가 생성한 코드를 감독하고 제약을 설정하며 그 논리를 검증하는 방식으로 전환되는 변화를 체감하고 있다”라고 말했다. 이어 “이에 따라 중요하게 여겨지는 역량 역시 달라지고 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>이미 많은 개발자가 AI 기반 개발 환경에 맞춰 역량을 조정하고 있다. 이에 본지는 개발자와 기술 리더에게 변화에 어떻게 대응하고 있는지 물었다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%b2%b4%ea%b3%84%ec%a0%81%ec%9d%b8-%ea%b5%90%ec%9c%a1%ec%9d%98-%ec%a4%91%ec%9a%94%ec%84%b1">체계적인 교육의 중요성</h2> <p>조직 내부에서 제공하든 외부 교육 과정을 활용하든, 공식적이고 지속적인 교육은 AI 코딩 에이전트 활용의 최신 흐름을 따라잡는 가장 효과적인 방법 중 하나로 꼽힌다.</p> <p>개발 도구 제공 기업 디덕티브 AI의 공동 설립자 겸 CTO 사미어 아가르왈은 “엔지니어링 팀 내부에서는 체계적으로 설계된 사내 교육을 통해 가장 큰 학습 효과를 얻을 수 있다”라고 밝혔다. 이어 “이미 많은 기업이 프롬프트 설계, 에이전트 행동 방식, 신뢰성 리스크, AI가 생성한 코드의 실패 유형 등을 주제로 한 교육 세션을 운영하기 시작했다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>아가르왈은 “이제 가장 가치 있는 교육은 AI 코딩 에이전트를 사용하는 방법 자체를 다루는 과정이 아니다”라며 “대신 AI 에이전트를 디버깅하는 방법과, 에이전트의 행동이 얼마나 적절하고 품질이 높은지 평가하는 방법을 다루는 과정이 더 중요해지고 있다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>마케팅 서비스 기업 마켓리(Marketri)의 AI 혁신 담당 수석 디렉터 브래디 루이스는 모든 개발자가 체계적인 학습 접근법을 통해 도움을 받을 수 있다고 설명했다. 루이스는 “머신러닝, 데이터 엔지니어링, 통계학 분야의 전통적인 교과 과정이나 특정 자격증 프로그램을 통한 구조화된 학습 경로는 개발자가 AI 모델과 연동되는 애플리케이션을 구축할 수 있는 기초를 제공한다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>루이스는 체계적인 학습이 개발자를 데이터 사이언티스트로 만들기 위한 것은 아니라고 선을 그었다. 대신 이러한 교육은 AI 시스템의 한계를 이해하도록 돕고, 이를 바탕으로 보다 예측 가능하고 견고한 애플리케이션 설계를 가능하게 한다고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%b4%88%ea%b8%b0-%eb%8f%84%ec%9e%85%ec%9e%90%eb%a5%bc-%ec%9c%84%ed%95%9c-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85-%ec%a7%80%ec%9b%90-%ed%99%95%eb%8c%80">초기 도입자를 위한 기업 지원 확대</h2> <p>기업이 개발 전반에 AI 활용을 확대하려는 움직임에 따라, 개발자가 받는 AI 교육의 상당 부분은 고용주로부터 제공되고 있다.</p> <p>마켓리의 브래디 루이스는 “기업 내부 AI 교육 프로그램에 대한 수요가 증가하면서, 자체 교육 과정을 먼저 수용하는 직원에게 추가적인 지원을 제공해 차별화를 꾀하는 고용주가 늘고 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>이러한 교육은 단순한 학습을 넘어 새로운 기회로 이어질 가능성도 있다.</p> <p>루이스는 “많은 조직이 여전히 AI 활용에 대한 내부 기준과 원칙을 정립하는 과정에 있다”라며 “이 기준을 마련하는 초기 단계부터 참여하는 개발자는 그렇지 않은 개발자보다 더 큰 영향력을 발휘할 수 있다”라고 분석했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%a9%98%ed%86%a0%ec%8b%ad-%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c%ea%b7%b8%eb%9e%a8%ec%9d%98-%ec%97%ad%ed%95%a0">멘토십 프로그램의 역할</h2> <p>팀 단위 멘토십 프로그램 역시 AI 도구와 프로세스에 대한 지식을 확산하는 데 효과적인 수단으로 주목받고 있다.</p> <p>앱스트랙트 시큐리티의 크리스 카마초는 “최근 여러 팀에서 조용히 나타나는 변화 중 하나는, AI 도구가 빠르게 답을 제시해주면서 저연차 직원이 질문을 덜 하게 되는 현상”이라고 설명했다. 이어 “단기적으로는 업무 속도가 빨라질 수 있지만, 장기적인 성장 측면에서는 오히려 부정적 영향을 줄 수 있다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>카마초는 “성과가 좋은 팀일수록 저연차 직원과 시니어 개발자를 더 자주 짝지어 협업하게 하고, AI가 제안한 코드가 어떻게 검증됐는지를 중심으로 코드 리뷰를 진행한다”라고 소개했다.</p> <p>AI 기반 프로세스를 도입하는 기업이 늘어나면서 멘토십 기회도 함께 확대되고 있다.</p> <p>루이스는 “AI 기반 프로세스 구축을 주도하는 인물과 협업하는 개발자는 혼자 학습하는 경우보다 더 빠르게 실무 경험을 쌓을 수 있다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>카마초는 “지속적인 학습은 이제 선택이 아니라 기본 요건이 되고 있다”라며 “AI 기능은 데이터, 안전성, 보안에 대한 이해를 전제로 작동하기 때문에 개발자는 해당 영역에 대한 문해력을 더욱 강화해야 한다”라고 설명했다. 이어 “도구에만 의존하기보다 멘토십을 중심에 두는 팀이 더 빠르게 성장할 것”이라고 전망했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-%ec%a0%9c%ea%b3%b5%ec%97%85%ec%b2%b4%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%ec%a7%81%ec%a0%91-%eb%b0%b0%ec%9a%b0%eb%8b%a4">AI 제공업체에서 직접 배우다</h2> <p>AI 기반 개발 환경에 적응하기 위해, 기술을 직접 개발하고 제공하는 기업의 자료를 활용하는 방법도 있다.</p> <p>소프트웨어 개발 관련 서적을 제공하는 기업 왓츠디스의 설립자 겸 CEO이자 소프트웨어 개발자인 크리스 미닉은 “AI에 맞춰 역량과 이력서를 조정하기 위해 최신 AI 기술을 제공하는 기업의 공식 문서와 교육 자료를 직접 학습했다”라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>미닉은 “예를 들어 오픈AI는 오픈AI 아카데미를 운영하고 있으며, AI 분야에서 활동하는 대부분의 기업도 유사한 교육 리소스를 제공하고 있다”라며 “기술 변화 속도를 고려했을 때 대학 강의는 이를 따라가기 어렵다고 판단해 복학은 고려하지 않았다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>또한 “아마존웹서비스의 AWS AI 프랙티셔너 자격증을 취득했다”라며 “이 자격증은 AWS의 AI 관련 도구 활용 능력과 생성형 AI 작동 원리에 대한 기본 이해를 갖추고 있음을 입증하는 기초 인증”이라고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-%ec%9a%b0%ec%84%a0-%ec%82%ac%ea%b3%a0%eb%b0%a9%ec%8b%9d%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ed%95%98%eb%9d%bc">AI 우선 사고방식으로 전환하라</h2> <p>많은 개발자에게 AI 기반 개발로 전환하는 첫 단계는 가장 어려운 과정일 수 있다. 기술 습득 이전에 사고방식의 변화가 필요하기 때문이다.</p> <p>개발 플랫폼 제공 기업 멘딕스의 CEO 레이 콕은 “소프트웨어 개발자는 자신의 업무 방식이 근본적으로 바뀔 것이라는 점을 먼저 받아들여야 한다”라고 밝혔다. 이어 “AI 우선 사고방식은 매일 단련해야 하는 근육과 같다”라고 표현했다.</p> <p>콕은 또 개발자가 더 높은 수준의 추상화 계층에서 소프트웨어를 이해하는 훈련을 해야 한다고 설명했다. 콕은 “기존의 프로그래밍 중심 사고에서 벗어나 모델 기반 소프트웨어 개발을 소프트웨어 구성과 애플리케이션 개발을 위한 보완적 도구로 채택해야 한다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>루이스는 “개별 AI 도구를 배우는 데서 벗어나 AI 시스템의 근본적인 작동 방식과 행동 원리를 이해하기 시작할 때 개발자의 적응 속도가 가장 빠르다”라고 분석했다. 이어 “성과를 내는 개발자는 문법을 암기하는 데 집중하기보다 오케스트레이션, 데이터 품질, 워크플로 구조가 AI 보조 개발의 신뢰성에 어떤 영향을 미치는지를 학습하는 데 더 많은 시간을 투자한다”라고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%8b%9c%ed%96%89%ec%b0%a9%ec%98%a4%eb%a5%bc-%ed%86%b5%ed%95%9c-%ed%95%99%ec%8a%b5">시행착오를 통한 학습</h2> <p>AI 기반 개발에 익숙해지는 또 다른 방법은 직접 프로젝트를 수행하며 무엇이 효과적이고 무엇이 그렇지 않은지를 검증하는 것이다.</p> <p>웹사이트 및 애플리케이션 개발 서비스 기업 론치 터틀의 설립자 겸 수석 개발자 잭슨 화이트는 “개발자가 역량을 확장하는 방식은 과거 뛰어난 개발자가 성장해온 방식과 다르지 않다”라며 “관련 문서와 사용자 사례를 읽고, 직접 프로젝트를 만들어보는 과정이 핵심”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>화이트는 “론치 터틀에서 AI 기반으로 처음 구축한 웹사이트는 완성도가 낮았고, 상당 부분을 기존 코딩 방식으로 수정해야 했다”라고 회상했다. 이어 “그러나 시행착오를 거치며 모델과 프롬프트 설계 역량이 점차 정교해졌고, 그 결과 AI가 훨씬 더 많은 작업을 담당할 수 있게 됐다”라며 “다른 개발자도 비슷한 경험을 하게 될 것”이라고 내다봤다.</p> <p>딥페이크 및 AI 기반 사기 방어 솔루션을 제공하는 기업 폴리가드의 공동 설립자 겸 CEO 조슈아 맥켄티는 자기 주도적이고 경험 중심의 학습을 강조했다. 맥켄티는 “직접 부딪혀보라”라며 “몇 주마다 새로운 AI 도구를 시도하고, 한 AI 챗봇에게 다른 AI 도구 사용법을 물어보는 방식도 도움이 된다”라고 조언했다.</p> <p>이어 “진정한 숙련도는 도구를 어떻게 사용하는지뿐 아니라 언제 사용하지 않아야 하는지를 아는 데서 드러난다”라며 “도구를 한계까지 밀어붙이고, 그 한계에 도달했을 때 어떤 결과가 나타나는지 경험해야 한다”라고 전했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9d%b4%eb%a0%a5%ec%84%9c-%ec%97%85%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%8a%b8%eb%8f%84-%ed%95%84%ec%88%98">이력서 업데이트도 필수</h2> <p>AI 기반 개발 경험은 이제 이력서에서 중요한 요소로 자리 잡고 있다.</p> <p>루이스는 “기업이 내부 AI 역량을 강화하고 AI 수요가 지속적으로 증가하면서 이력서의 내용도 함께 변화하고 있다”라며 “에이전트 패턴, 워크플로 설계, 프롬프트 평가, 품질 관리 등 실제 현장 경험을 구체적으로 강조하는 개발자는 단순히 AI 도구 목록만 나열하는 개발자보다 훨씬 앞서 나가고 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>또한 채용 담당자는 AI가 어디에서, 어떻게, 왜 가치를 창출하는지, 반대로 어떤 위험을 초래하는지, 그리고 이를 실제 환경에서 어떻게 신뢰 가능하게 구현할 수 있는지를 명확히 설명할 수 있는 개발자를 찾고 있다고 루이스는 분석했다.</p> <p>크리스 미닉은 “새로운 AI 역량을 갖추게 될 때마다 이력서를 즉시 업데이트하는 것이 중요하다”라고 밝혔다. 이어 “채용 공고에 AI 역량이 명시돼 있지 않더라도, 생성형 AI를 소프트웨어에 활용하고 통합하는 이해도는 빠르게 소프트웨어 개발 직무의 기본 요건으로 자리 잡고 있다”라고 설명했다. <br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[News of IT Services’ Death Is Greatly Exaggerated]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/news-of-it-services-death-is-greatly-exaggerated/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/news-of-it-services-death-is-greatly-exaggerated/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[We are seeing a spate of disruptive headlines and predictions around the demise of IT services. With the progress made by AI, specifically in software development, it is easy to assume that traditional IT services are on their way out. This narrative is fundamentally flawed. Yes, AI-driven automation deflates the unit cost of technology work. [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[오픈텍스트, 거버넌스 및 데이터 중심의 AI 운영 전략 제시]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136268/%ec%98%a4%ed%94%88%ed%85%8d%ec%8a%a4%ed%8a%b8-%ea%b1%b0%eb%b2%84%eb%84%8c%ec%8a%a4-%eb%b0%8f-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%ec%a4%91%ec%8b%ac%ec%9d%98-ai-%ec%9a%b4%ec%98%81-%ec%a0%84%eb%9e%b5-%ec%a0%9c.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136268/%ec%98%a4%ed%94%88%ed%85%8d%ec%8a%a4%ed%8a%b8-%ea%b1%b0%eb%b2%84%eb%84%8c%ec%8a%a4-%eb%b0%8f-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%ec%a4%91%ec%8b%ac%ec%9d%98-ai-%ec%9a%b4%ec%98%81-%ec%a0%84%eb%9e%b5-%ec%a0%9c.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>오픈텍스트는 AI 도입이 IT 서비스 관리(ITSM) 영역 전반으로 빠르게 확산되고 있다며, 반복적인 서비스 요청 처리부터 장애 분류, 변경 관리, 지식 검색까지 AI가 IT 운영의 효율성과 속도를 동시에 끌어올린다고 밝혔다. 그러나 자동화 수준이 고도화될수록 기업은 단순한 기술 적용을 넘어 ‘신뢰할 수 있는 AI 운영 체계’를 구축해야 하는 과제에 직면하고 있다.</p> <p>오픈텍스트는 AI 기반 ITSM 환경에서 신뢰를 확보하기 위한 핵심 요소로 거버넌스 체계와 데이터 품질 관리를 제시했다. AI가 생성한 워크플로우와 자동화 실행 결과가 조직 내에서 신뢰받기 위해서는 기술 자체의 정교함보다 이를 통제하고 검증할 수 있는 구조가 선행돼야 한다는 설명이다.</p> <p>특히 오픈텍스트는 AI가 코드 수준의 자동화 실행과 의사결정 보조까지 수행하는 환경에서는 ‘설명 가능성’과 ‘추적 가능성’이 중요해진다고 설명했다. 어떤 데이터가 활용됐는지, 어떤 기준으로 판단이 내려졌는지, 그리고 문제가 발생했을 경우 어디까지 되돌릴 수 있는지가 명확해야 한다는 것이다. 이는 단순한 운영 효율의 문제가 아니라 기업 리스크 관리와 직결된다.</p> <p>오픈텍스트는 “AI의 정확성과 안정성은 데이터 품질에 의해 결정된다. 최신 상태로 유지되는 구성관리DB(CMDB), 서비스 간 의존 관계를 반영한 토폴로지 데이터, 검증된 지식 콘텐츠가 기반이 돼야 AI의 판단 역시 신뢰를 얻을 수 있다. 데이터가 부정확하거나 단절돼 있다면, AI는 오히려 오류를 증폭시키는 도구가 될 수 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>오픈텍스트는 AI를 ITSM에 적용할 때 3가지 전략적 접근이 필요하다고 강조했다. 먼저 AI 자동화 전 과정에 대한 엔드투엔드 거버넌스를 구축해야 하며, 개발, 승인, 배포, 롤백까지 전 단계가 관리되고 책임 구조가 명확해야 한다고 밝혔다. 둘째는 운영 데이터의 정확성과 최신성을 지속적으로 유지해야 한다는 것이다. 셋째로는 조직 내 축적된 지식 자산을 신뢰 가능한 형태로 구조화해 AI가 활용할 수 있도록 해야 한다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>오픈텍스트는 AI 기반 ITSM의 경쟁력이 얼마나 많은 자동화를 구현했는지가 아니라, 얼마나 안정적이고 신뢰 가능한 방식으로 운영하느냐에 달려있다고 전했다. 기술 도입 속도가 빨라질수록 통제와 관리의 중요성은 더욱 커진다는 설명이다.</p> <p>오픈텍스트는 “AI 시대의 IT 운영은 더 이상 속도만의 경쟁이 아니라, 신뢰를 기반으로 한 구조적 혁신의 단계로 진입하고 있다”라며, AI 혁신과 거버넌스 체계를 동시에 강화하는 전략을 통해 기업이 효율성과 안정성을 모두 확보할 수 있도록 지원한다는 방침이다. <br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Java News Roundup: JDK26-RC2, Payara Platform, Hibernate, Quarkus, Apache Camel, Jakarta EE 12]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb16-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb16-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb16-2026/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771882551481.jpg"/><p>This week's Java roundup for February 16th, 2026, features news highlighting: the second release candidate of JDK 26; an update on Jakarta EE 12; the February 2026 edition of Payara Platform; a point release of Apache Camel; and maintenance releases of Hibernate Search and Quarkus.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Gartner HR Survey Reveals Australian Job Market Confidence Has Hit a Three-Year Low]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-24-gartner-hr-survey-reveals-australian-job-market-confidence-has-hit-a-three-year-low?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-24-gartner-hr-survey-reveals-australian-job-market-confidence-has-hit-a-three-year-low?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Confidence among Australian employees in the availability of jobs has declined to its lowest level in more than three years, according to Gartner.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[US Tariff Tumult Reinforces The Need For Always-On Scenario Planning For Executives]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/us-tariff-tumult-reinforces-the-need-for-always-on-scenario-planning-for-executives/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/us-tariff-tumult-reinforces-the-need-for-always-on-scenario-planning-for-executives/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Last Friday, the US Supreme Court decided that the International Emergency Economic Powers Act does not allow a US president the authority to unilaterally impose tariffs. Over the last year, the US government has been leveraging tariff policy to negotiate new trade agreements (for example, recently signing agreements with Indonesia and India.) Despite the fact that the [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Tides Have Turned: The Forrester Wave™ For EUEM Solutions Is Now DEXM Solutions]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-tides-have-turned-forresters-euem-solutions-wave-is-now-dexm-solutions/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-tides-have-turned-forresters-euem-solutions-wave-is-now-dexm-solutions/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Markets evolve. And when the terminology used to describe a market no longer reflects how buyers, practitioners, and vendors describe the solutions within it, it’s time to reassess. For almost 20 years, Forrester has led research in what we originally defined as end user experience management (EUEM), evaluating the market as early as 2007 in [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI利用を昇進条件に据えるのはアリ？アクセンチュアの事例から考える]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135045/ai%e5%88%a9%e7%94%a8%e3%82%92%e6%98%87%e9%80%b2%e6%9d%a1%e4%bb%b6%e3%81%ab%e6%8d%ae%e3%81%88%e3%82%8b%e3%81%ae%e3%81%af%e3%81%82%e3%82%8a%ef%bc%9f%e3%82%a2%e3%82%af%e3%82%bb%e3%83%b3%e3%83%81%e3%83%a5.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135045/ai%e5%88%a9%e7%94%a8%e3%82%92%e6%98%87%e9%80%b2%e6%9d%a1%e4%bb%b6%e3%81%ab%e6%8d%ae%e3%81%88%e3%82%8b%e3%81%ae%e3%81%af%e3%81%82%e3%82%8a%ef%bc%9f%e3%82%a2%e3%82%af%e3%82%bb%e3%83%b3%e3%83%81%e3%83%a5.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai%e5%88%a9%e7%94%a8%e5%ae%9f%e7%b8%be%e3%82%92%e6%98%87%e9%80%b2%e6%9d%a1%e4%bb%b6%e3%81%ae%e4%b8%80%e3%81%a4%e3%81%ab">AI利用実績を昇進条件の一つに</h2> <p>コンサルティング世界最大手のアクセンチュアが、幹部社員を対象に人工知能（AI）ツールの利用状況を監視し、その実績を昇進条件の一つに据え始めたというイギリス紙フィナンシャル・タイムズの報道は、世界の産業界に小さからぬ衝撃を与えた。報道によれば、同社は独自開発した企業向けAIプラットフォームへのログイン数などのデータを週単位で収集し、対象となる社員がどの程度テクノロジーを日々の業務に組み込んでいるかを定量的に測定しているという。</p> <p>この動きは、単に一企業の人事制度の変更という枠に収まるものではない。生成AIをはじめとする高度なテクノロジーが急速に普及する中、企業がいかにして自社の労働力を新しい時代に適応させるかという、極めて現代的かつ普遍的な課題に対する一つの過激な解答例であると言える。これまで企業における新しいITツールの導入は、研修の実施や利用の推奨といった「ソフト」なアプローチが主流であった。しかし、利用実績を直接的に個人のキャリアパス、すなわち昇進や給与という「ハード」な評価に結びつける今回の手法は、企業統治とテクノロジー推進のあり方を根本から変容させる可能性を秘めている。</p> <p>本稿では、企業が従業員に対してAIの利用を強制し、それを人事評価の基準とすることの是非について、経営陣が期待するメリットと、現場の労働環境や組織文化にもたらされる深刻なデメリットの双方から、極力中立的かつ批判的な視点で深掘りしていく。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e7%b5%84%e7%b9%94%e5%85%a8%e4%bd%93%e3%81%ae%e3%83%87%e3%82%b8%e3%82%bf%e3%83%ab%e3%83%88%e3%83%a9%e3%83%b3%e3%82%b9%e3%83%95%e3%82%a9%e3%83%bc%e3%83%a1%e3%83%bc%e3%82%b7%e3%83%a7%e3%83%b3%e3%82%92">組織全体のデジタルトランスフォーメーションを加速させる強力な牽引力</h2> <p>企業がAI利用を昇進の条件とする背景には、極めて合理的かつ切実な経営上の課題が存在する。最大のメリットは、組織全体のデジタルトランスフォーメーション（DX）を不可逆的かつ強制的に前進させることができるという点である。人間の本質として、長年慣れ親しんだ業務プロセスや思考の枠組みを変更することには強い心理的抵抗と現状維持バイアスが働く。特に、社内で既に一定の地位を築き、旧来の手法で成功体験を積み重ねてきた幹部層においては、未知のテクノロジーを習得するための学習コストを忌避する傾向が強い。利用状況を昇進条件に直結させることは、こうした人間特有の「変化への抵抗」を打ち破るための最も強力なカンフル剤となる。</p> <p>また、莫大なIT投資に対するリターン（ROI）を確実に回収するという財務的な観点からも、この施策は経営陣にとって魅力的に映る。企業向けの大規模なAIプラットフォームの構築やライセンス契約には、数百億円から数千億円規模の投資が必要となる場合がある。どれほど優れたシステムを導入しても、現場の社員がそれを使わなければ投資は完全に無駄に終わる。ログイン数や利用時間を監視し、それを評価に組み込むことで、企業は「使われないシステム」という最悪の事態を物理的に回避し、投下資本の回収を確実なものにしようと試みているのである。</p> <p>さらに、組織文化の変革という観点でも一定の効果が見込める。上位の役職者が日常的にAIを使いこなしている姿勢をデータとして示し、実際にそれが評価されるという事実が社内に周知されれば、部下たちも自然とその潮流に追随せざるを得なくなる。トップダウンによる強力な動機付けは、社内に「AIファースト」という新しい共通言語と文化を根付かせるための、荒療治ではあるものの確実な手段となり得る。経営陣からすれば、激化するグローバル競争において、のんびりと従業員の自主的なITリテラシー向上を待っている猶予はなく、強制力を伴ってでも組織全体の能力の底上げを図る必要があるという切迫した事情があるのだ。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e7%9b%ae%e7%9a%84%e3%81%a8%e6%89%8b%e6%ae%b5%e3%81%ae%e5%80%92%e9%8c%af%ef%bc%9a%e6%95%b0%e5%80%a4%e5%8c%96%e3%81%ae%e7%bd%a0%e3%81%a8%e3%80%8c%e8%a6%8b%e3%81%9b%e3%81%8b%e3%81%91%e3%81%ae%e5%8a%b4">目的と手段の倒錯：数値化の罠と「見せかけの労働」の蔓延</h2> <p>一方で、AIの利用状況を昇進条件にすることには、企業の根幹を揺るがしかねない深刻なデメリットと副作用が存在する。その最たるものが、「目的と手段の倒錯」である。本来、AIは業務の効率化や新たな価値創出、顧客への提供価値を最大化するための「手段」に過ぎない。しかし、その利用自体（例えばログイン数）を評価基準に設定した瞬間、AIを使うこと自体が「目的」へとすり替わってしまう。</p> <p>これは経済学で「グッドハルトの法則」として知られる現象である。ある指標が目標とされたとき、その指標はもはや良い指標ではなくなる、という法則だ。従業員は昇進という強力なインセンティブを前にして、システムをハックしようと試みるようになる。業務で本当にAIが必要かどうかにかかわらず、とりあえず毎朝システムにログインし、無意味なプロンプトを入力して利用回数を稼ぎ、ログアウトするといった「見せかけのAI利用」が横行するリスクは極めて高い。このような形骸化した行動は、企業にとって何の付加価値も生み出さないばかりか、無駄な業務時間を増大させ、真の生産性を著しく低下させる要因となる。</p> <p>さらに、業務の性質とツールの相性を完全に無視している点も重大な欠陥である。コンサルティングや高度な専門職の業務には、複雑な人間関係の調整、高度な感情的知性を用いた交渉、または直感的なクリエイティビティが求められる場面が多々ある。これらは現在のAIが最も苦手とする領域である。特定の業務プロセスにおいては、AIを介在させるよりも、人間の頭脳だけで処理した方がはるかに迅速かつ高品質な結果を出せるケースも少なくない。それにもかかわらず、「AIを使わなければ評価が下がる」という強迫観念を植え付けることは、最適な課題解決のアプローチを歪め、結果として顧客へのサービス品質を劣化させる危険性を孕んでいる。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e7%9b%a3%e8%a6%96%e7%a4%be%e4%bc%9a%e5%8c%96%e3%81%ab%e3%82%88%e3%82%8b%e5%bf%83%e7%90%86%e7%9a%84%e5%ae%89%e5%85%a8%e6%80%a7%e3%81%ae%e5%96%aa%e5%a4%b1%e3%81%a8%e5%b0%82%e9%96%80%e8%81%b7%e3%81%ae">監視社会化による心理的安全性の喪失と専門職の尊厳</h2> <p>さらに批判的な視座から考察すべきは、この施策がもたらす労働環境のディストピア化である。企業が従業員のシステムへのログイン状況やツールの利用頻度を常時監視するという行為は、職場におけるパノプティコン（一望監視施設）を構築することと同義である。従業員は常に経営陣から「AIを使っているか」という監視の目に晒されることになり、これは組織内の心理的安全性を著しく毀損する。</p> <p>心理的安全性は、現代の知識集約型ビジネスにおいてイノベーションを生み出すための不可欠な土壌であると広く認知されている。しかし、監視と強制によるマネジメントは、従業員から自律性と内発的動機付けを奪い取る。特に、アクセンチュアのような高度な専門家集団において、個人の裁量や独自の思考プロセスを尊重せず、特定のツールの利用という画一的な行動様式を強要することは、プロフェッショナルとしての尊厳を傷つける行為と受け取られかねない。結果として、本当に優秀で独立心の強い人材は、監視と制約の多い職場を嫌気して他社へ流出し、従順でシステムのハックに長けた「イエスマン」ばかりが社内に残るという、最悪の人材逆淘汰を引き起こす可能性がある。</p> <p>また、評価の公平性という観点でも大きな疑問が残る。本来、人事評価の対象となるべきは「ビジネスにどれだけのインパクトを与えたか」というアウトプットや成果であるはずだ。AIを全く使わずに卓越した成果を上げる社員と、AIを頻繁に使いながら凡庸な成果しか出せない社員がいた場合、後者が「ログイン数が多かったから」という理由で高く評価される制度は、能力主義の原則を根本から否定するものである。インプット（努力やツールの利用）だけを評価し、アウトプットの質を軽視する評価体系は、長期的には組織の競争力を確実に削いでいく。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e3%83%86%e3%82%af%e3%83%8e%e3%83%ad%e3%82%b8%e3%83%bc%e3%81%b8%e3%81%ae%e9%81%a9%e5%bf%9c%e3%82%92%e7%9c%9f%e3%81%ae%e7%ab%b6%e4%ba%89%e5%8a%9b%e3%81%b8%e3%81%a8%e6%98%87%e8%8f%af%e3%81%95%e3%81%9b">テクノロジーへの適応を真の競争力へと昇華させるために</h2> <p>アクセンチュアがAI利用を昇進条件に組み込んだという決断は、AI革命という歴史的転換点において、企業が生き残りをかけてテクノロジーの定着を焦る強烈な危機感の表れとして理解することはできる。変化を拒む組織の重い腰を上げさせるためのショック療法として、一定の初期的な効果を発揮することは想像に難くない。</p> <p>しかしながら、極力中立的かつ批判的に分析すれば、ログイン数などの表面的な利用状況を評価の指標とすることは、経営の怠慢と言わざるを得ない。「従業員がAIを使ってどれだけ素晴らしい価値を創出したか」という複雑で本質的な成果を測定する能力が経営陣に不足しているため、測定が容易な「ログイン数」という安易な代替指標に逃げ込んでいるという見方もできる。</p> <p>企業がテクノロジーを真の競争力へと昇華させるためには、強制や監視というテイラー主義的な工場モデルの手法から脱却する必要がある。AIはあくまで人間の知的作業を拡張するためのツールであり、それをどう使いこなし、どのような価値を生み出すかは、個人のクリエイティビティと自律性に委ねられるべきである。真に求められる人事評価とは、AIの「利用回数」を数えることではなく、AIを活用することによって生み出された「革新的なアイデア」や「劇的なプロセスの改善」、「卓越した顧客満足」そのものを正当に評価し、報いる制度を構築することに他ならない。目的と手段の倒錯を防ぎ、人間の尊厳とテクノロジーの可能性を調和させる新たな評価軸の探求こそが、すべての企業に突きつけられた次なる時代の重い課題である。</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Claude Code Security Causes A SaaS-pocalypse In Cybersecurity]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/claude-code-security-causes-a-saas-pocalypse-in-cybersecurity/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/claude-code-security-causes-a-saas-pocalypse-in-cybersecurity/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[We have seen this pattern before, even if the specifics look different. Think back to the day AWS introduced GuardDuty, when Microsoft folded Defender for Endpoint into its enterprise licensing commitments and launched Microsoft Sentinel, or when Google acquired Mandiant and eventually Wiz. Sure, the launch of fully autonomous AI agents that can ingest entire [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Reduce downtime, improve efficiency, and kick-start automation with the power of AI]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136054/reduce-downtime-improve-efficiency-and-kick-start-automation-with-the-power-of-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136054/reduce-downtime-improve-efficiency-and-kick-start-automation-with-the-power-of-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Building systems downtime rarely starts where it is first detected—a minor failure can begin far upstream from where it’s revealed. For example, an HVAC power anomaly can degrade cooling, which then cascades into compute throttling and SLA risk. </p> <p>The good news is that facilities operators can be immediately notified of even the most minor of system failures. The bad news is often they face an overwhelming flood of incident alarms but don’t have the necessary visibility to address the critical ones.</p> <p>Even partial power outages can lead to hundreds of power and mechanical alarms in a 60-second period, making it very difficult to identify and correct the root cause. </p> <p>“During normal operations, we see systems where facility managers have a long-term build-up of alarms that remain unacknowledged and are not acted upon,” says Sadiq Syed, senior vice president of digital buildings for Schneider Electric. “This leads to operator alarm fatigue where meaningful alarms that could lead to downtime are missed or ignored.”</p> <p>The challenge for CIOs, IT, and operational technology (OT) teams is that power and mechanical systems in the environment often operate in silos. Without centralized control it becomes practically impossible to analyze and act on disconnected data. One solution is to integrate multiple edge-control systems into a single dashboard using middleware software. But implementation can be complex, costly, and time-consuming. </p> <p><strong>The solution: AI-powered operations platforms</strong></p> <p>The problems of alarm overload are not new. In fact their significance is acknowledged by <a href="https://www.isa.org/products/ansi-isa-18-2-2016-management-of-alarm-systems-for" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">ANSI/ISA-18.2-2016</a>, a global industry standard that outlines a structured framework to help organizations develop, implement, operate, and maintain effective alarm systems. </p> <p>However, even when standards like ISA-18.2 are designed into alarm systems, it’s the consolidation of notifications across various OT domains, such as power and mechanical, that can greatly improve solution value for facility managers. </p> <p>This is where AI-powered analytics come in, unifying power, energy, and building systems into one data model so operators see real-time cause and effect. Thousands of alarms become prioritized incidents based on likely root cause, probable impact, and recommended actions.</p> <p>This is precisely how Schneider Electric makes it possible to turn a flood of alarms into consolidated, actionable data. This in turn enables faster resolution, longer equipment lifetime, fewer repeat events, and service levels that hold up under pressure.</p> <p><strong>EcoStruxure™ Foresight: Advanced insights for operational efficiency</strong></p> <p>Schneider Electric has been at the heart of technology innovation for over 180 years, leading the convergence of electrification, automation, and digital intelligence for cross-domain operational resilience. The company’s EcoStruxure™ Foresight is a groundbreaking AI-powered operations platform designed to unify operations across energy, power, and building management.</p> <p>With pre-integrated multidomain power and mechanical applications, the platform consolidates alarms into a single interface and dashboard. It eliminates the need for middleware or manual integrations, empowering facility managers to save time and money, speed deployment, improve life cycle efficiency, and enable autonomous operations.</p> <p>Embedded AI accelerates root cause analysis by up to 90% in the built environment, enabling predictive maintenance and simplifying decision-making. “We see these results with customers that have large siloed systems and face large numbers of alarms produced by physical failure of power or mechanical assets in their facilities,” says Syed. “By accelerating root cause analysis during these failure conditions, we can reduce asset downtime that affects critical business processes.”</p> <p>Foresight can contribute up to 50% more efficiency across the life cycle for customers leveraging both the power and mechanical applications, says Syed. And with consistent user experience across applications and tooling, onboarding new facility managers can be up to 60% faster versus other solutions. In today’s environment of increasing employee retirement and workforce shortages, nonstop operations depend on incoming staff to hit the ground running.</p> <p>EcoStruxure<strong>™ </strong>Foresight provides a single intuitive interface for supervision, control, and advanced insights for next-level operational efficiency.<strong></strong></p> <p><strong>The bottom line </strong></p> <p>Mechanical and power systems downtime in a built environment are both problematic and expensive. With disconnected equipment, alarm overload is all too common, leading to problems going unnoticed until it’s too late. </p> <p>The AI-powered EcoStruxure<strong>™</strong> Foresight platform eliminates silos, simplifies complexity, and embeds intelligence at the core of operations, delivering the unmatched visibility, control, and actionable insights CIOs and building operators need.</p> <p>EcoStruxure™ Foresight will be available to early-adopter customers in Q4 2026 and in BETA versions even earlier in 2026. <a href="https://www.se.com/ww/en/work/products/product-launch/ecostruxure-foresight/?utm_source=advocacy&amp;utm_medium=organic_social&amp;utm_campaign=2025_nov_ww_de_etech_pr&amp;campaign_objective=awareness&amp;mcl_name=etech&amp;" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Learn more here</a>.</p> <hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Three Realities About B2B Buying Networks]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/three-realities-about-b2b-buying-networks/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/three-realities-about-b2b-buying-networks/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[B2B buying is more chaotic than it’s ever been — and buyers feel it. According to Forrester’s Buyers’ Journey Survey, 2025, 73% of purchases involve three or more departments, with an average of 13 people inside the buyer’s organization and nine from outside involved in making a purchase decision. As a result, buyers tap colleagues, communities, [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI Pricing Is Product Strategy: Five Questions Every Product Manager Must Answer Early]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/ai-pricing-is-product-strategy-five-questions-every-product-manager-must-answer-early/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/ai-pricing-is-product-strategy-five-questions-every-product-manager-must-answer-early/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[AI pricing isn’t something you bolt on after the product is built. It is product strategy — shaping adoption, ROI, and long-term monetization. Yet most B2B teams still treat pricing as a late-stage deliverable instead of an early design decision. This blog outlines the five dimensions every PM and marketer must consider when pricing AI [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Uforwarder: Uber’s Scalable Kafka Consumer Proxy for Efficient Event-Driven Microservices]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/uber-uforwarder-kafka-push-proxy/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/uber-uforwarder-kafka-push-proxy/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/uber-uforwarder-kafka-push-proxy/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771098351627.jpg"/><p>Uber has open-sourced uForwarder, a push-based Kafka consumer proxy built to handle trillions of messages and multiple petabytes of data daily. The system introduces context-aware routing, head-of-line blocking mitigation, adaptive auto-rebalancing, and partition-level delay processing to improve scalability, workload isolation, and hardware efficiency in large-scale event-driven microservices.</p> <i>By Leela Kumili</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Gartner Survey Reveals CMO “AI Blind Spot” as 65% Expect Role Disruption, Yet Only 32% Say Significant Skill Changes Are Needed]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-23-gartner-survey-reveals-cmo-ai-blind-spot-as-65-percent-expect-role-disruption-yet-only-32-percent-say-significant-skill-changes-are-needed?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-23-gartner-survey-reveals-cmo-ai-blind-spot-as-65-percent-expect-role-disruption-yet-only-32-percent-say-significant-skill-changes-are-needed?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Sixty-five percent of CMOs say advances in AI will dramatically change the role of the CMO in the next two years, yet only 32% say significant changes are needed to the CMO profile and skill set, according to a survey by Gartner, Inc., a business and technology insights company.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How vertical SaaS is redefining enterprise efficiency]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135398/how-vertical-saas-is-redefining-enterprise-efficiency.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135398/how-vertical-saas-is-redefining-enterprise-efficiency.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Early in my work building software for regulated industries, I learned a lesson the hard way. Efficiency doesn’t come from adding features. It comes from understanding a single challenge more intimately and solving it by narrowing our focus. That approach made the solutions more meaningful. The adoption improved. Support tickets dropped. Customers trusted us more. </p> <p>In every industry I worked in, from healthcare operations to waste-management logistics, I saw teams struggling to make horizontal software fit workflows it was never designed for. That’s when I realized the real transformation in enterprise efficiency would come not from broader platforms, but from vertical SaaS: <em>products purpose-built for a single domain</em>, where compliance, automation and insight are woven into the fabric of daily operations.</p> <p>This realization has shaped my perspective on building and scaling technology ever since. Over time, it became clear to me that the next wave of enterprise innovation won’t come from louder, broader platforms. It will come from companies that choose one industry, learn its edge cases and build systems customers can’t easily replace because those systems quietly become part of how the business runs.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-horizontal-to-vertical-why-depth-wins">From horizontal to vertical: Why depth wins</h2> <p>For the past decade, horizontal SaaS has been the defining force in enterprise technology. Platforms like CRMs, ERP suites and collaboration tools promised universality, offering a single platform to manage every business function across all industries. The strategy made sense: a large total addressable market, reusable architecture and marketing scale.</p> <p>However, over time, the cracks began to show. Horizontal SaaS required endless customization to handle industry-specific workflows, from clinical documentation to transport manifests. I saw customers paying more for consultants than for the product itself. The software wasn’t the choke point. It was the lack of specialization.</p> <p>Vertical SaaS flips that model. It is narrow by design but deep in impact. A<a href="https://www.strategyand.pwc.com/n1/en/media/pdf/b2b-vertical-software-new.pdf" rel="nofollow"> report by Strategy&amp;</a> found that B2B vertical software companies are now growing faster than their horizontal peers, thanks to higher retention rates, lower churn rates and better unit economics. When software mirrors how a business already works, people stop treating it like a tool they tolerate and start relying on it like infrastructure. It becomes part of the operating system because it removes friction from daily work.</p> <p>I have witnessed this firsthand in industries where compliance is mandatory. A generic ERP couldn’t track regulated waste disposal or manage medical manifests without layers of manual oversight. But a vertical platform built for that purpose, one that embeds audit logs, route optimization and generator management, removes inefficiency at its core.</p> <p>This is where depth starts to compound. Each workflow you automate makes the next one easier. Each regulation you encode reduces manual oversight elsewhere. Over time, the product stops being optional, not because of lock-in, but because replacing it would require rebuilding too much institutional knowledge.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-and-scaling-a-vertical-platform">Building and scaling a vertical platform</h2> <p>When I led product teams building domain-specific SaaS, we learned quickly that vertical success isn’t about copying horizontal frameworks. It’s about rethinking products, people and processes within the industry itself.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-map-the-workflow-end-to-end">1. Map the workflow end-to-end</h3> <p>Start where the work happens. Spend time in the field, in the warehouse and in the compliance department. I’ve found that observing just a handful of customers often reveals 80 percent of the workflow logic that’s common across an entire industry. Build your product to support those real-world steps, not abstract process charts.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-bake-in-compliance-from-day-one">2. Bake in compliance from day one</h3> <p>In regulated industries, compliance isn’t a feature; it’s the baseline for trust. I learned early that trying to retrofit audit trails or data retention policies after go-live only creates technical debt. Instead, design for compliance as a first-class product layer: immutable logs, permission hierarchies and exportable compliance reports built into the system.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-design-modular-but-opinionated-systems">3. Design modular but opinionated systems</h3> <p>Vertical SaaS works best when it strikes a balance. Modular enough to scale, but opinionated enough to guide users toward proven workflows. In our case, introducing a structured manifest flow increased adoption because customers preferred the system’s clarity over their own spreadsheets.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-instrument-domain-metrics">4. Instrument domain metrics</h3> <p>Measure what matters to the vertical, not what’s convenient to your analytics stack. Instead of tracking “logins per day,” track compliance incident reduction or turnaround time for regulatory submissions. Those are the metrics that justify budgets and renewals.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-partner-inside-the-ecosystem">5. Partner inside the ecosystem</h3> <p>Vertical products don’t thrive in isolation. Integration with industry hardware, marketplaces and regulatory systems drives adoption. In one case, we partnered with a hardware vendor to automatically sync manifest data from their devices, cutting onboarding time in half and unlocking co-marketing opportunities.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-plan-for-adjacency">6. Plan for adjacency</h3> <p>Your initial niche might be narrow, but the architecture should allow lateral growth. Once you solve one core workflow, expansion often comes naturally: from waste transport to shredding, from route optimization to compliance analytics. The infrastructure remains the same; the modules expand.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-leadership-shift-what-ceos-must-prioritize">The leadership shift: What CEOs must prioritize</h2> <p>The vertical SaaS play isn’t just a product shift — it’s a leadership mindset shift. When your business commits to serving one domain deeply, your decisions as a CEO evolve accordingly.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Hire for domain empathy. </strong>Early in my career, I made the mistake of hiring brilliant technologists who didn’t understand the customer’s day-to-day reality. Product innovation suffered because we were solving for elegance, not relevance. In vertical markets, domain empathy isn’t optional. It’s the engine of innovation.</li> <li><strong>Invest in data and knowledge assets. </strong>Data is your defensibility. The more domain-specific behavioral data your platform captures, the stronger your insights and automation become. It’s what separates a “good product” from an irreplaceable one.</li> <li><strong>Align pricing with outcomes. </strong>Horizontal SaaS prices by seats; vertical SaaS prices by results. In one engagement, we transitioned from per-user pricing to compliance-success pricing, charging based on verified process completions and risk reduction. Revenue increased because customers could tie the cost directly to measurable value.</li> <li><strong>Build a repeatable implementation. </strong>Customization kills margins. Instead, codify your deployment process. We created an “industry implementation playbook” that captured common workflows and pre-approved configurations. Every new rollout became faster and more predictable, without sacrificing flexibility.</li> <li><strong>Manage concentration risk. </strong>Vertical focus naturally narrows your total addressable market. To mitigate, plan adjacencies early. Expand into regions, sub-sectors or related regulatory frameworks that share infrastructure. Growth shouldn’t depend on the economic cycle of a single sector.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-the-timing-is-perfect-for-vertical-saas">Why the timing is perfect for vertical SaaS</h2> <p>Three macro forces are accelerating this shift.</p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Regulatory complexity is surging.</strong> Across healthcare, logistics and finance, compliance costs are rising and generic software can’t keep up. Companies want systems that natively enforce regulatory standards, not add-ons that patch them later.</li> <li><strong>Workforce shortages are amplifying automation needs.</strong> As industries face labor constraints, automation that directly mirrors field operations is a necessity. Vertical SaaS delivers process automation where it matters most — inside industry-specific workflows.</li> <li><strong>Investors are rewarding defensibility.</strong> Analysts and private equity firms have noted that vertical SaaS companies show stronger retention and more sustainable growth than horizontal peers (<a href="https://hackernoon.com/what-is-a-vertical-saas" rel="nofollow">Hackernoon</a>). Specialization isn’t a limitation; it’s a moat.</li>
</ol> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-new-definition-of-enterprise-efficiency">The new definition of enterprise efficiency</h2> <p>True enterprise efficiency isn’t about doing more; it’s about doing what matters with fewer compromises. Horizontal SaaS promised universality but created complexity. Vertical SaaS, by contrast, reduces friction by embedding intelligence where the work happens.</p> <p>As leaders, our challenge isn’t just to build software that scales, it’s to build software that <em>fits</em>. I have come to believe that real efficiency comes from empathy, understanding an industry’s constraints well enough that the software fades into the background and the work simply gets easier.</p> <p>The next great enterprise platforms won’t be those that try to be everything to everyone. They’ll be the quiet operators — laser-focused, regulation-aware, operationally embedded systems that power industries from within.</p> <p>As a builder and leader, I’ve come to believe that specialization is the new scale. The future belongs to the companies that choose to go deep instead of wide, that build not just software, but trust, one vertical at a time.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The GTM Illusion Is Cracking — These Three Leaders Aren’t Waiting For The Collapse]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-gtm-illusion-is-cracking-these-three-leaders-arent-waiting-for-the-collapse/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-gtm-illusion-is-cracking-these-three-leaders-arent-waiting-for-the-collapse/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Most leaders know that their go-to-market model isn’t built for what’s coming, yet only a few are doing something about it. Here, we highlight three B2B Summit guest speakers who will describe how they’re taking their organizations into the future.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The self-aware enterprise: Why AI only transforms companies that know themselves]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135371/the-self-aware-enterprise-why-ai-only-transforms-companies-that-know-themselves.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135371/the-self-aware-enterprise-why-ai-only-transforms-companies-that-know-themselves.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>AI is now a standard topic in boardrooms, signaling a clear shift from experimental capability to declared strategic priority. When we examine earnings call transcripts across sectors, we see AI mentions spiking sharply beginning in 2022, coinciding with the maturation of large language models and the broad availability of generative tools.</p> <p>To understand whether that narrative translates into measurable business outcomes, we analyzed the <a href="https://fortune.com/topic/aiq/" rel="nofollow">Fortune AIQ Top 50</a>, a representative set of companies with material exposure to the AI ecosystem. We separated them into two groups to distinguish between organizations where AI is central to the portfolio, i.e., companies that enable AI through infrastructure, hardware, software, revenue model and those where AI functions primarily as a strategic input rather than the product itself, i.e., companies that consume AI to deliver value to customers, employees and shareholders. We then compared the intensity of AI mentions in earnings transcripts with Return on Invested Capital, a core indicator of long-term value creation.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1024" alt="Return on AI-invested capital" class="wp-image-4135373" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all 2013w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=300%2C83&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=768%2C213&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=1024%2C284&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=1536%2C427&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=1240%2C344&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=150%2C42&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=854%2C237&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=640%2C178&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/return-on-ai-invested-capital.jpg?resize=444%2C123&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="284" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p class="imageCredit">Surendar Narasimhan</p></div> <p>The analysis reveals two complementary patterns. Companies for which AI is core to the business show a strong and accelerating relationship between AI emphasis and ROIC, reflecting the direct monetization of AI capabilities. Companies that primarily consume AI exhibit more stable ROIC trends that largely track historical and macroeconomic cycles, suggesting AI is not delivering material value. When AI is embedded at the core, value creation appears relatively quickly. When AI is adopted as an enabler, the realization curve is longer and more uneven. In this article, we examine the root causes of that lag and outline what it truly means for an organization to be AI-ready.</p> <p>For companies where AI is not a core offering, accelerating ROIC has less to do with access to tools or the sheer scale of investment and far more to do with organizational structure. AI compounds value in enterprises that are internally coherent, well-aligned and self-aware in how decisions are made and executed. In fragmented organizations, however, AI often amplifies existing inefficiencies and inconsistencies, accelerating dysfunction rather than delivering sustained financial impact.</p> <p>This is the defining leadership challenge of the AI era: building the self-aware enterprise, moving away from considering AI as a technology and more as a field, a field that encompasses far more than the technology itself.</p> <p>Previous technology waves primarily optimized execution. AI changes the role of technology from execution to interpretation. Traditional systems understand content. AI understands context. That shift exposes a hard truth we see repeatedly: context cannot be inferred reliably from disconnected workflows, fragmented systems and siloed data.</p> <p>When we walk through the evolution and growth of organizations, what we see resembles less an integrated system and more a collection of powerful parts assembled without a unified nervous system. We refer to this condition as the Frankenstein enterprise.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-frankenstein-enterprise">The Frankenstein enterprise</h2> <p>Most large organizations were not designed as integrated systems. They were assembled through acquisitions, regional expansions, product overlays, functional silos and decades of tactical IT decisions. The result is an enterprise composed of strong and capable parts that can move and operate but lack shared awareness.</p> <p>In Mary Shelley’s story, the monster is not weak. It is powerful and resilient. Its tragedy is not capability but consciousness. Sensation, memory, interpretation and action are not integrated into a single learning loop. Pain is recognized only after damage spreads. Responses occur without understanding how one part affects another.</p> <p>This is precisely the failure mode AI exposes in the modern enterprise.</p> <p>For CIOs, this reframes accountability. AI readiness is not an IT maturity issue or a tooling gap. It is a systems problem. Until sensing, interpretation, memory and action are aligned into a single learning organism, AI will accelerate motion without creating understanding. The result is an enterprise that can transact, reconcile and report but cannot learn coherently. Signals arrive late. Decisions conflict. AI trained on fragmented inputs magnifies latency and contradiction rather than producing intelligence.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-6-myths-that-keep-the-monster-alive">The 6 myths that keep the monster alive</h2> <p>When we speak with executive teams, the same myths surface repeatedly. They are what keep fragmented enterprises functioning without becoming self-aware.</p> <ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Scale equals invincibility.</strong> Past survival is mistaken for future safety, and AI trained on lagging indicators reinforces delayed awareness rather than early warning.</li> <li><strong>The monster should remain intact.</strong> Legacy approval paths and operating models are preserved because they once worked, even when they no longer align with how value is created.</li> <li><strong>Stronger parts fix weak coordination.</strong> New platforms, tools and consultants (with the best of capabilities) are added without redesigning how decisions connect across the enterprise.</li> <li><strong>External polish reflects internal health.</strong> Dashboards, reports and transformation narratives mask structural fractures and growing employee friction.</li> <li><strong>Point integration creates unity.</strong> Systems are connected at the interface level while semantics, workflows and ownership remain misaligned.</li> <li><strong>More models mean more intelligence.</strong> Specialized AI proliferates without a shared decision architecture, multiplying contradictions instead of clarifying choices.</li>
</ol> <p>The charts show where executive attention is going. The Frankenstein analogy explains why results often lag. These myths create the illusion of coherence while structural damage accumulates beneath the surface. AI does not fix this condition. It exposes it.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-makes-an-enterprise-self-aware">What makes an enterprise self-aware</h2> <p>A self-aware enterprise resembles a living organism rather than an assembled machine. It shares a common understanding of how work flows, how customers experience value and how decisions propagate across the system. In organizations like this, people across functions describe value creation in remarkably similar terms.</p> <p>This state emerges through six reinforcing imperatives.</p> <ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Workflow congruence inside and out</strong>. Internally, processes flow end to end across functions rather than stopping at organizational boundaries. Externally, workflows align with how customers operate rather than how the company assumes they do. When organizations map day-in-the-life experiences for employees and customers, they uncover friction invisible to dashboards, including duplicate data entry, circular approvals, confusing handoffs and rework cycles. These exercises consistently reveal where AI can remove friction or augment decisions long before KPIs surface the issue.</li> <li><strong>Governance of data and process. </strong>Garbage in is garbage out. For any model to function effectively, organizations need a single, trusted foundation of high-quality data that is well connected across the enterprise. Governing data quality and lineage is, therefore, a critical step in becoming AI-ready. When organizations recognize that a parsimonious set of clean, connected data delivers far more value than vast volumes of incomplete and disconnected information, the journey to AI readiness truly begins.</li> <li><strong>Engineering excellence beyond code.</strong> AI readiness depends as much on process and experience engineering as on technology. Process engineering maps how work flows and where it breaks. Experience engineering ensures people adopt systems without workarounds. Technology engineering shifts architecture from application-centric silos to unified data-centric platforms. Without these disciplines, AI strategies become elegant narratives that cannot be implemented in the real anatomy of the organization.</li> <li><strong>Mastery of time</strong>. AI initiatives fail when leaders either chase isolated quick wins or over-rotate toward distant end states. Effective roadmaps balance immediate value with foundational capability building, one use case at a time. The most successful first-year programs focus on visibility, governance and a unified data backbone, allowing AI to learn safely and compound over time.</li> <li><strong>Structure for change</strong>. Self-awareness cannot be delegated to IT. It requires governance that evaluates initiatives through financial value, architectural coherence and human experience simultaneously. Unified demand management, shared metrics and enterprise-level value dashboards replace siloed decision-making with collective intelligence.</li> <li><strong>Sustaining the change</strong>. Once coherence is established, sustaining it becomes essential. Like a living system, the enterprise requires nourishment to maintain long-term value generation.</li>
</ol> <p>A structured demand framework unifies incoming requests, reveals common needs across the organization and enables scalable solutions. Standardization of digital solutions reduces complexity, lowers cost and concentrates expertise where it has the most leverage. Unified value generation and monitoring ties digital and AI initiatives directly to profit and loss outcomes, shifting focus from feature delivery to margin impact.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-fragmentation-to-compounding-advantage">From fragmentation to compounding advantage</h2> <p>When sensing, interpretation, memory and action are aligned, AI becomes transformative. Across sectors and industries, the growth pattern becomes consistent. AI delivers step-change value only when the enterprise itself becomes coherent. Revenue accelerates. Margins expand. Innovation compounds.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cios-mandate">The CIO’s mandate</h2> <p>For CIOs, the message is clear. AI strategy is enterprise strategy. Tools, vendors and models are secondary to the anatomical work of understanding how the organization senses, interprets, remembers and acts. The question is no longer whether your company uses AI. It is whether your organization understands itself well enough for AI to understand it too. The future belongs to enterprises that move beyond stitched-together systems and develop true organizational self-awareness.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="whats-not-in-this-article">What’s not in this article</h2> <p>The human aspect of this shift. Context has been the domain of humans; it has driven culture, hierarchy and identity. AI will impact context and, hence, impact certain core aspects of identity. The empathy needed to adapt successfully is above all aspects discussed. But that’s for another article/paper/book in itself! </p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Salesforce to acquire Momentum to boost Agentforce 360, Slack for sales teams]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135865/salesforce-to-acquire-momentum-to-boost-agentforce-360-slack-for-sales-teams.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135865/salesforce-to-acquire-momentum-to-boost-agentforce-360-slack-for-sales-teams.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Salesforce has signed a definitive agreement to acquire San Francisco-based startup Momentum to boost the capabilities of Agentforce 360 and Slack for enterprise sales teams.</p> <p>The acquisition will allow Salesforce to extend <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4102862/salesforces-agentforce-360-gets-an-enterprise-data-backbone-with-informaticas-metadata-and-lineage-engine.html" target="_blank">Agentforce 360</a> and Slackbot’s ability to ingest and analyze unstructured data from third-party voice and video channels, such as Zoom and Google Meet, and apply those insights directly to agentic workflows so that sales teams can be armed with actionable revenue insights, the company said in a statement.</p> <p>The integration of Momentum, analysts say, fills a longstanding gap in traditional customer relationship management (<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272365/what-is-crm-software-for-managing-customer-data.html">CRM</a>) systems or processes, which rely on sales executives to manually fill critical signals such as buying intent, objections, pricing discussions, and next steps post calls with customers.</p> <p>“By embedding Momentum’s capabilities, Salesforce reduces reliance on manual updates and external systems,” said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gaurav-dewan-pmp-8644a19/?originalSubdomain=in" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Gaurav Dewan</a>, research director at Avasant.</p> <p>Momentum’s integration should also help enterprises get cleaner pipeline data, better forecasting, and AI agents grounded in real customer context, not just manual notes, echoed <a href="https://pareekh.com/about/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pareekh Jain</a>, principal analyst at Pareekh Consulting.</p> <p>“In practical terms, this means automated execution of complex workflows, accelerating revenue execution and reducing friction across go-to-market processes,” Jain added.</p> <p>Beyond tightening sales workflows, analysts said the payoff from Momentum’s integration will be uneven across industries, with the biggest gains accruing to sectors where high-value deals hinge on long, conversation-heavy buying cycles.</p> <p>Vertical software, B2B SaaS, professional services, financial services, and enterprise technology vendors are likely to see the earliest returns, as sales teams in these segments depend heavily on nuanced signals from discovery calls, demos, and negotiations, Dewan said.</p> <p>Regulated industries such as healthcare and insurance could also benefit from better capture of intent and objections, Jain noted, as long as compliance and data governance guardrails are maintained.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-vs-standalone-vendors">Salesforce vs standalone vendors</h2> <p>Analysts say that the deal hints at Salesforce’s strategy to redraw the competitive lines in revenue intelligence and orchestration.</p> <p>“Traditionally, CRM platforms focused on storing customer and pipeline data, while <a href="https://www.forrester.com/blogs/a-new-supergroup-for-revenue-technology-emerges-revenue-orchestration-platforms/" rel="nofollow">revenue orchestration</a>, intelligence tools sat on top to interpret signals, guide sellers, and trigger actions. Momentum’s integration into Agentforce 360 shows that this separation is breaking down,” Dewan said.</p> <p>“Salesforce is explicitly embedding conversational insights and orchestration logic directly into its CRM and workflow layer so that insights can immediately trigger actions, not just populate dashboards,” Dewan added.</p> <p>There are also other examples of consolidation in the same segment — the <a href="https://www.salesloft.com/company/newsroom/clari-and-salesloft-announce-merger-agreement" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Clari–Salesloft merger in 2025</a> and <a href="https://www.sap.com/investors/en/resources/acquisitions.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">SAP’s acquisition of CallidusCloud</a> in 2018, both of which, according to Dewan, were aimed at boosting revenue orchestration capabilities.</p> <p>In fact, Momentum’s acquisition is not Salesforce’s first deal to attempt to boost how revenue is generated, interpreted, and executed inside its Agentforce 360 offering.</p> <p>“The agreement to acquire <a href="https://www.salesforce.com/news/stories/salesforce-signs-definitive-agreement-to-acquire-qualified/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Qualified in December</a> added automated, conversational buyer engagement at the top of the funnel, enabling AI‑driven inbound qualification and pipeline creation within Salesforce and Slack,” Dewan said.</p> <p>“The Momentum acquisition extends this strategy into the mid‑funnel by converting customer conversations from calls and meetings into structured intelligence that can directly drive workflows inside Agentforce 360,” Dewan added.</p> <p>All this consolidation, analysts say, also reflects a deeper shift in how buying conversations are changing for CIOs: from “which conversation intelligence tool is best?” to “which platform do we want to anchor our revenue execution on for the next 5–7 years?”</p> <p>“Enterprises must now decide whether they want a suite‑led model, where engagement, insight, and execution live inside one platform, or a best‑of‑breed model, where these functions are sourced from multiple vendors and stitched together,” Dewan said.</p> <p>Either way, buyers face a trade-off between stitching together a complex, multi-vendor stack or leaning more heavily on a single platform, with the risk of deeper lock-in, Dewan added. The acquisition is expected to close by April.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When Systems Recognize Capability But Governance Delays Authorization: A Structural Gap in Modern Institutions]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/uncategorized/when-systems-recognize-capability-but-governance-delays-authorization-a-structural-gap-in-modern-institutions/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/uncategorized/when-systems-recognize-capability-but-governance-delays-authorization-a-structural-gap-in-modern-institutions/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Mansi S. Rai Executive Summary Modern institutions increasingly rely on digital systems capable of detecting performance, eligibility, and risk in real time. Yet governance frameworks often remain constrained by legacy authorization models that were <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/uncategorized/when-systems-recognize-capability-but-governance-delays-authorization-a-structural-gap-in-modern-institutions/" title="When Systems Recognize Capability But Governance Delays Authorization: A Structural Gap in Modern Institutions">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When Systems Recognize Capability But Governance Delays Authorization: A Structural Gap in Modern Institutions]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/23/when-systems-recognize-capability-but-governance-delays-authorization-a-structural-gap-in-modern-institutions/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/23/when-systems-recognize-capability-but-governance-delays-authorization-a-structural-gap-in-modern-institutions/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Mansi S. Rai Executive Summary Modern institutions increasingly rely on digital systems capable of detecting performance, eligibility, and risk in real time. Yet governance frameworks often remain constrained by legacy authorization models that were...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Salesforce: Latest news and insights]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/3490106/salesforce-latest-news-and-insights.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/3490106/salesforce-latest-news-and-insights.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Salesforce (<a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/CRM/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">NYSE:CRM</a>) is a vendor of cloud-based software and applications for sales, customer service, marketing automation, ecommerce, analytics, and application development. Based in San Francisco, Calif., its services include <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2139149/salesforce-updates-sales-and-service-cloud-with-new-capabilities.html">Sales Cloud, Service Cloud</a>, Marketing Cloud, Commerce Cloud, and Salesforce Platform. Its subsidiaries include Tableau Software, Slack Technologies, and MuleSoft, among others.</p> <p>The company is undergoing a pivot to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3496519/agentic-ai-decisive-operational-ai-arrives-in-business.html">agentic AI</a>, increasingly focused on blending <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/2338115/what-is-generative-ai-artificial-intelligence-that-creates.html">generative AI</a> with a range of other capabilities to offer customers the ability to develop autonomous decision-making agents for their service and sales workflows. Salesforce has a market cap of $293 billion, making it the world’s <a href="https://companiesmarketcap.com/salesforce/marketcap/" rel="nofollow">36th most valuable company</a> by market cap.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-news-and-analysis">Salesforce news and analysis</h2> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-to-acquire-momentum-to-boost-agentforce-360-slack-for-sales-teams">Salesforce to acquire Momentum to boost Agentforce 360, Slack for sales teams</h3> <p><em>February 23, 2026</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4135865/salesforce-to-acquire-momentum-to-boost-agentforce-360-slack-for-sales-teams.html">Salesforce signed a definitive agreement to acquire Momentum</a>, a San Francisco-based startup that aims to boost the capabilities of Agentforce 360 and Slack for enterprise sales teams.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-lays-off-staffers-as-executive-leadership-churn-continues">Salesforce lays off staffers as executive leadership churn continues</h3> <p><em>February 10, 2026</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4130028/salesforce-lays-off-staffers-as-executive-leadership-churn-continues.html">Salesforce has laid off a fresh round of employees</a> as the cloud CRM software giant continues to grapple with ongoing churn in its executive leadership ranks, underscoring a period of internal restructuring as the company seeks to sharpen its focus on scaling AI-driven offerings, such as Agentforce, across enterprises.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-may-be-prepping-to-phase-out-heroku">Salesforce may be prepping to phase out Heroku</h3> <p><em>February 9, 2026</em>: <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4129430/salesforce-may-be-prepping-to-phase-out-heroku.html">Salesforce has signaled a major strategic shift</a> for its long-standing cloud platform Heroku by ending sales of new Heroku Enterprise contracts and moving the service into a maintenance-focused “sustaining engineering” phase.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-to-shake-up-salesforce-workforce-with-possible-shift-to-sales-over-it">AI to shake up Salesforce workforce with possible shift to sales over IT</h3> <p><em>February 5. 2026</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3817774/ai-shakes-up-the-salesforce-workforce.html">Salesforce wants to cut 1,000 jobs </a>to hire new staff elsewhere as part of an effort to bring its new AI products to customers, according to financial news service Bloomberg, citing internal sources.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-agentforce-recalibration-raises-costs-and-complexity-for-cios">Salesforce’s Agentforce recalibration raises costs and complexity for CIOs</h3> <p><em>January 7, 2026</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4113617/salesforces-agentforce-recalibration-raises-costs-and-complexity-for-cios.html">Salesforce is recalibrating its enterprise AI strategy </a>— and CIOs could be footing the bill. Analysts warn the move will force CIOs to absorb new costs, revisit delivery timelines, and defend AI decisions that were once marketed as autonomous.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-is-tightening-control-of-its-data-ecosystem-and-cios-may-have-to-pay-the-price">Salesforce is tightening control of its data ecosystem and CIOs may have to pay the price</h3> <p><em>December 17, 2025:</em> Software partners are now feeling the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4108001/salesforce-is-tightening-control-of-its-data-ecosystem-and-cios-may-have-to-pay-the-price.html">impact of changes Salesforce announced in February</a> to how it charges for API access and are weighing whether to absorb the higher the costs, pass them on to customers and risk backlash, or pursue alternative ways to access the data and risk straining its relationship with Salesforce.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-agentforce-360-gets-an-enterprise-data-backbone-with-informaticas-metadata-and-lineage-engine">Salesforce’s Agentforce 360 gets an enterprise data backbone with Informatica’s metadata and lineage engine</h3> <p><em>December 9, 2025</em>: While studies suggest that a high number of AI projects fail, many experts argue that it’s not the model’s fault, it’s the data behind it. Salesforce aims to tackle this problem with the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4102862/salesforces-agentforce-360-gets-an-enterprise-data-backbone-with-informaticas-metadata-and-lineage-engine.html">integration of its newest acquisition, Informatica</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-unveils-observability-tools-to-manage-and-optimize-ai-agents">Salesforce unveils observability tools to manage and optimize AI agents</h3> <p><em>November 20, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4093688/salesforce-unveils-observability-tools-to-manage-and-optimize-ai-agents.html">Salesforce unveiled new Agentforce 360 observability tools</a> to give teams visibility into why AI agents behave the way they do, and which reasoning paths they follow to reach decisions.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-unveils-simulation-environment-for-training-ai-agents">Salesforce unveils simulation environment for training AI agents</h3> <p><em>November 14, 2025</em>: Salesforce AI Research today unveiled a new simulation environment for training voice and text agents for the enterprise. Dubbed eVerse, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4089684/salesforce-unveils-simulation-environment-for-training-ai-agents.html">the environment leverages synthetic data generation</a>, stress testing, and reinforcement learning to optimize agents.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-to-acquire-doti-to-boost-ai-based-enterprise-search-via-slack">Salesforce to acquire Doti to boost AI-based enterprise search via Slack</h3> <p><em>November 14, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4090123/salesforce-to-acquire-doti-to-boost-ai-based-enterprise-search-via-slack-2.html">Salesforce wii acquire Israeli startup, Doti</a>, aiming to enhance AI-based enterprise search capabilities offered via Slack. The demand for efficient data retrieval and interpretation has been growing within enterprises, driven by the need to streamline workflows and increase productivity.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-glaring-dreamforce-omission-vital-security-lessons-from-salesloft-drift">Salesforce’s glaring Dreamforce omission: Vital security lessons from Salesloft Drift</h3> <p><em>October 22, 2025</em>: Salesforce’s Dreamforce conference offered a range of sessions on best practices for securing their Salesforce environments and AI agents, but what it didn’t address were weaknesses exposed by the <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4076024/dreamforce-finds-salesforce-weathering-a-security-storm.html">recent spate of Salesforce-related breaches</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-updates-its-agentic-ai-pitch-with-agentforce-360">Salesforce updates its agentic AI pitch with Agentforce 360</h3> <p><em>October 13, 2025:</em> Salesforce has announced a new release of Agentforce that, it said, “gives teams the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4071597/salesforce-updates-its-agentic-ai-pitch-with-agentforce-360.html">fastest path from AI prototypes to production-scale agents</a>” — although with many of the new release’s features still to come, or yet to enter pilot phases or beta testing, some parts of that path will be much slower than others.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="lessons-from-the-salesforce-breach">Lessons from the Salesforce breach</h3> <p><em>October 10, 2025</em>: The chilling reality of a <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4070540/lessons-from-the-salesforce-breach.html">Salesforce.com data breach is a jarring wake-up call</a>, not just for its customers, but for the entire cloud computing industry. </p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-brings-agentic-ai-to-it-service-management">Salesforce brings agentic AI to IT service management</h3> <p>October 9, 2025: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4069900/salesforce-brings-agentic-ai-to-it-service-management.html">Salesforce is bringing agentic AI to IT service management (ITSM)</a>. The CRM giant is taking aim at competitors like ServiceNow with Agentforce IT Service, a new IT support suite that leverages autonomous agents to resolve incidents and service requests.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-trusted-ai-foundation-seeks-to-power-the-agentic-enterprise">Salesforce Trusted AI Foundation seeks to power the agentic enterprise</h3> <p><em>October 2, 2025:</em> As <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4066640/salesforce-trusted-ai-foundation-provides-scaffolding-for-the-agentic-enterprise.html">Salesforce pushes further into agentic AI</a>, its aim is to evolve Salesforce Platform from an application for building AI to a foundational operating system for enterprise AI ecosystems. The CRM giant took a step toward that vision today, announcing innovations across the Salesforce Platform, Data Cloud, MuleSoft, and Tableau.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-ai-research-unveils-new-tools-for-ai-agents">Salesforce AI Research unveils new tools for AI agents</h3> <p><em>August 27, 2025</em>: Salesforce AI Research announced three advancements designed to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4046713/salesforce-ai-research-unveils-new-tools-for-ai-agents.html">help customers transition to agentic AI</a>: a simulated enterprise environment framework for testing and training agents, a benchmarking tool to measure the effectiveness of agents, and a data cloud capability for autonomously consolidating and unifying duplicated data.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="attackers-steal-data-from-salesforce-instances-via-compromised-ai-live-chat-tool">Attackers steal data from Salesforce instances via compromised AI live chat tool</h3> <p><em>August 26, 2025: </em>A threat actor managed to <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4046407/attackers-steal-data-from-salesforce-instances-via-compromised-ai-live-chat-tool.html">obtain Salesforce OAuth tokens</a> from a third-party integration called Salesloft Drift and used the tokens to download large volumes of data from impacted Salesforce instances. One of the attacker’s goals was to find and extract additional credentials stored in Salesforce records that could expand their access.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-acquires-regrello-to-boost-automation-in-agentforce">Salesforce acquires Regrello to boost automation in Agentforce</h3> <p><em>August 19, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4042377/salesforce-acquires-regrello-to-boost-automation-in-agentforce.html">Salesforce is buying Regrello to enhance Agentforce</a>, its suite of tools for building autonomous AI agents for sales, service, and marketing. San Francisco-based startup Regrello specializes in turning data into agentic workflows, primarily for automating supply-chain business processes.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-adds-new-billing-options-to-agentforce">Salesforce adds new billing options to Agentforce</h3> <p><em>August 19, 2025</em>: In a move that aims to improve accessibility for agentic AI, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4042126/salesforce-adds-new-billing-options-to-agentforce.htm">Salesforce announced new payment options for Agentforce</a>, its autonomous AI agent suite.The new options, built on the flexible pricing the company introduced in May, allow customers to use Flex Credits to pay for the actions agents take.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-to-acquire-waii-to-enhance-sql-analytics-in-agentforce">Salesforce to acquire Waii to enhance SQL analytics in Agentforce</h3> <p><em>August 11, 2025</em>: Salesforce has signed a definitive agreement to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4037742/salesforce-to-acquire-waii-to-enhance-sql-analytics-in-agentforce.html">acquire San Francisco-based startup Waii</a> for an undisclosed sum to enhance SQL analytics within <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3518646/salesforce-unveils-agentforce-to-help-create-autonomous-ai-bots.html" target="_blank">Agentforce</a>, its suite of tools aimed at helping enterprises build autonomous AI agents for sales, service, marketing, and commerce use cases.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="could-agentforce-3s-mcp-integration-push-salesforce-ahead-in-the-crm-ai-race">Could Agentforce 3’s MCP integration push Salesforce ahead in the CRM AI race?</h3> <p><em>June 25, 2025: </em>“[Salesforce’s] implementation of MCP is one of the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4012370/could-agentforce-3s-mcp-integration-push-salesforce-ahead-in-the-crm-ai-race.html">most ambitious interoperability moves</a> we have seen from a CRM vendor or any vendor. It positions Agentforce as a central nervous system for multi-agent orchestration, not just within Salesforce but across the enterprise,” said <a href="https://futurumgroup.com/dion-hinchcliffe/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Dion Hinchcliffe</a>, lead of the CIO practice at The Futurum Group. But it introduces new considerations around security.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-agentforce-3-promises-new-ways-to-monitor-and-manage-ai-agents">Salesforce Agentforce 3 promises new ways to monitor and manage AI agents</h3> <p><em>June 24, 2025: </em>This is the fourth version of Salesforce Agentforce since its debut in September last year, with the newest, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4011936/salesforce-agentforce-3-promises-new-ways-to-monitor-and-manage-ai-agents.html">Agentforce 3</a>, succeeding the previous ‘2dx’ release. A new feature of the latest version is Agentforce Studio, which is also available as a separate application within Salesforce.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-supercharges-agentforce-with-embedded-ai-multimodal-support-and-industry-specific-agents">Salesforce supercharges Agentforce with embedded AI, multimodal support, and industry-specific agents</h3> <p><em>Jun 18, 2025:</em> Salesforce is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4008975/salesforce-supercharges-agentforce-with-embedded-ai-multimodal-support-and-industry-specific-agents.html">updating Agentforce</a> with new AI features and expanding it across every facet of its ecosystem with the hope that enterprises will see the no-code platform as ready for tackling real-world digital execution, shaking its image of being a module for pilot projects.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cios-brace-for-rising-costs-as-salesforce-adds-6-to-core-clouds-bundles-ai-into-premium-plans">CIOs brace for rising costs as Salesforce adds 6% to core clouds, bundles AI into premium plans</h3> <p><em>Jun 18, 2025:</em> Salesforce is rolling out <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4008898/salesforce-implements-a-6-price-increase-while-mandating-ai-bundle-adoption.html">sweeping changes to its pricing</a> and product packaging, including a 6% increase for Enterprise and Unlimited Editions of Sales Cloud, Service Cloud, Field Service, and select Industries Clouds, effective August 1.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-study-warns-against-rushing-llms-into-crm-workflows-without-guardrails">Salesforce study warns against rushing LLMs into CRM workflows without guardrails</h3> <p><em>June 17, 2025: </em>A new benchmark study from Salesforce AI Research has revealed <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4008228/salesforce-study-warns-against-rushing-llms-into-crm-workflows-without-guardrails.html">significant gaps</a> in how large language models handle real-world customer relationship management tasks.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-industry-cloud-riddled-with-configuration-risks">Salesforce Industry Cloud riddled with configuration risks</h3> <p><em>June 16, 2025: </em>AppOmni researchers found 20 <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4006341/salesforce-industry-cloud-riddled-with-configuration-risks.html">insecure configurations and behaviors</a> in Salesforce Industry Cloud’s low-code app building components that could lead to data exposure.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-changes-slack-api-terms-to-block-bulk-data-access-for-llms">Salesforce changes Slack API terms to block bulk data access for LLMs</h3> <p><em>June 11, 2025: </em>Salesforce’s Slack platform has <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4005509/salesforce-changes-slack-api-terms-to-block-bulk-data-access-for-llms.html">changed its API terms of service</a> to stop organizations from using Large Language Models to ingest the platform’s data as part of its efforts to implement better enterprise data discovery and search.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-to-buy-informatica-in-8-billion-deal">Salesforce to buy Informatica in $8 billion deal</h3> <p>May 27. 2025: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3995868/salesforce-to-buy-informatica-in-8-billion-deal.html">Salesforce has agreed to buy Informatica </a>in an $8 billion deal as a way to quickly access far more data for its AI efforts. Analysts generally agreed that the deal was a win-win for both companies’ customers, but for very different reasons. </p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-wants-your-ai-agents-to-achieve-enterprise-general-intelligence">Salesforce wants your AI agents to achieve ‘enterprise general intelligence’</h3> <p><em>May 1, 2025:</em> Salesforce AI Research unveiled a slate of new benchmarks, guardrails, and models to help customers develop agentic AI optimized for business applications.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-ceo-marc-benioff-ai-agents-will-be-like-iron-mans-jarvis">Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff: AI agents will be like Iron Man’s Jarvis</h3> <p><em>April 17, 2025:</em> AI agents are more than a productivity boost; they’re fundamentally <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3960660/salesforce-ceo-marc-benioff-ai-agents-will-be-like-iron-mans-jarvis.html">reshaping customer interactions</a> and business operations. And while there’s still work to do on trust and accuracy, the world is beginning a new tech era — one that might finally deliver on the promises seen in movies like <em>Minority Report</em> and <em>Iron Man</em>, according to Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff.</p> <figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Marc Benioff: Why 2025 Will Be the Year of AI Agents | Ep. 224" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0KYfebo0_Kc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="agentblazer-salesforce-announces-agentic-ai-certification-learning-path">Agentblazer: Salesforce announces agentic AI certification, learning path</h3> <p><em>March 6, 2025:</em> Hot on the heels of the <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3838999/salesforces-agentforce-2dx-update-aims-to-simplify-ai-agent-development-deployment.html">release of Agentforce 2dx</a> for developing, testing, and deploying AI agents, Salesforce introduced <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3839403/agentblazer-salesforce-announces-agentic-ai-certification-learning-path.html">Agentblazer Status</a> to its Trailhead online learning platform.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-takes-on-hyperscalers-with-agentforce-2dx-updates">Salesforce takes on hyperscalers with Agentforce 2dx updates</h3> <p><em>March 6, 2025:</em> Salesforce’s <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3840122/salesforce-takes-on-hyperscalers-with-agentforce-2dx-updates.html">updates to its agentic AI offering</a> — Agentforce — could give the CRM software provider an edge over its enterprise application rivals and hyperscalers including AWS, Google, IBM, Service Now and Microsoft.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-agentforce-2dx-update-aims-to-simplify-ai-agent-development-deployment">Salesforce’s Agentforce 2dx update aims to simplify AI agent development, deployment</h3> <p><em>March 5, 2025:</em> Salesforce released the third version of its agentic AI offering — <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3838999/salesforces-agentforce-2dx-update-aims-to-simplify-ai-agent-development-deployment.html">Agentforce 2dx</a> — to simplify the development, testing, and deployment of AI agents that can automate business processes across departments, such as sales, service, marketing, finance, HR, and operations.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-agentexchange-targets-ai-agent-adoption-monetization">Salesforce’s AgentExchange targets AI agent adoption, monetization</h3> <p><em>March 4, 2025: </em>Salesforce is launching a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3837608/salesforces-agentexchange-targets-ai-agent-adoption-monetization.html">new marketplace named AgentExchange</a> for its agents and agent-related actions, topics, and templates to increase adoption of AI agents and allow its partners to monetize them.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-and-google-expand-partnership-to-bring-agentforce-gemini-together">Salesforce and Google expand partnership to bring Agentforce, Gemini together</h3> <p><em>February 25, 2025:</em> The <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3832936/salesforce-and-google-expand-partnership-to-bring-agentforce-gemini-together.html">expansion of the strategic partnership</a> will enable customers to build Agentforce AI agents using Google Gemini and to deploy Salesforce on Google Cloud.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-to-shake-up-salesforce-workforce-with-possible-shift-to-sales-over-it">AI to shake up Salesforce workforce with possible shift to sales over IT</h3> <p><em>February 5, 2025:</em> With the help of AI, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3817774/ai-shakes-up-the-salesforce-workforce.html">Salesforce can probably do without some staff</a>. At the same time, the company needs salespeople trained in new AI products, CEO Marc Benioff has stated.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-agentforce-2-0-update-aims-to-make-ai-agents-smarter">Salesforce’s Agentforce 2.0 update aims to make AI agents smarter</h3> <p><em>December 18, 2024:</em> The <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3628094/salesforce-adds-skills-to-its-ai-agents-and-agentic-platform-to-serve-more-enterprise-use-cases.html">second release of Salesforce’s agentic AI platform</a> offers an updated reasoning engine, new agent skills, and the ability to build agents using natural language.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="meta-creates-business-ai-group-led-by-ex-salesforce-ai-ceo-clara-shih">Meta creates ‘Business AI’ group led by ex-Salesforce AI CEO Clara Shih</h3> <p><em>November 20, 2024</em>: The ex-CEO of Salesforce AI, Clara Shih, has turned up at Meta just a few days after quitting Salesforce. In her new role <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3609450/meta-creates-business-ai-group-led-by-ex-salesforce-ai-ceo-clara-shih.html">at Meta she will set up a new Business AI group</a> to package Meta’s Llama AI models for enterprises.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ceo-of-salesforce-ai-clara-shih-has-left">CEO of Salesforce AI Clara Shih has left</h3> <p><em>November 15, 2024</em>: The <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3607317/ceo-of-salesforce-ai-clara-shih-has-left.html">CEO of Salesforce AI, Clara Shih, has left</a> after just 20 months in the job. Adam Evans, previously senior vice president of product for Salesforce AI Platform, has moved up to the newly created role of executive vice president and general manager of Salesforce AI.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="marc-benioff-rails-against-microsofts-copilot">Marc Benioff rails against Microsoft’s copilot</h3> <p><em>October 24, 2024</em>: Salesforce’s boss doesn’t have a good word to say about Microsoft’s AI assistants, saying the technology is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3586887/marc-benioff-rails-against-microsofts-copilot.html">basically no better than Clippy 25 years ago</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-financial-services-cloud-targets-ops-automation-for-insurance-brokerages">Salesforce’s Financial Services Cloud targets ops automation for insurance brokerages</h3> <p><em>October 16, 2024</em>: Financial Services Cloud for Insurance Brokerages will bring new features to help with <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3565530/salesforces-financial-services-cloud-targets-ops-automation-for-insurance-firms.html">commissions management and employee benefit servicing</a>, among other things, when it is released in February 2025. </p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="explained-how-salesforce-agentforces-atlas-reasoning-engine-works-to-power-ai-agents">Explained: How Salesforce Agentforce’s Atlas reasoning engine works to power AI agents</h3> <p><em>September 30, 2024:</em> AI agents created via Agentforce differ from previous Salesforce-based agents in their use of Atlas, a reasoning engine designed to <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3542521/explained-how-salesforce-agentforces-atlas-reasoning-engine-works-to-power-ai-agents.html">help these bots think like human beings</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-key-takeaways-from-dreamforce-2024">5 key takeaways from Dreamforce 2024</h3> <p><em>September 20, 2024:</em> As Salesforce’s 2024 Dreamforce conference rolls up the carpet for another year, here’s a look at <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3535722/5-key-takeaways-from-dreamforce-2024.html">a few high points as Salesforce pitched a new era for its customers</a>, centered around Agentforce, which brings agentic AI to enterprise sales and service operations.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="alation-and-salesforce-partner-on-data-governance-for-data-cloud">Alation and Salesforce partner on data governance for Data Cloud</h3> <p><em>September 19, 2024:</em> Data intelligence platform vendor Alation has <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3532160/alation-and-salesforce-partner-on-data-governance-for-data-cloud.html">partnered with Salesforce to deliver trusted, governed data</a> across the enterprise. It will do this, it said, with bidirectional integration between its platform and Salesforce’s to seamlessly delivers data governance and end-to-end lineage within Salesforce Data Cloud. This enables companies to directly access key metadata (tags, governance policies, and data quality indicators) from over 100 data sources in Data Cloud, it said.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="new-data-cloud-features-to-boost-salesforces-ai-agents">New Data Cloud features to boost Salesforce’s AI agents</h3> <p><em>September 17, 2024:</em> Salesforce <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3525909/new-data-cloud-features-to-boost-salesforces-ai-agents.html">added new features to its Data Cloud</a> to help enterprises analyze data from across their divisions and also boost the company’s new autonomous AI agents released under the name Agentforce, the company announced at the ongoing annual Dreamforce conference.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="dreamforce-2024-latest-news-and-insights">Dreamforce 2024: Latest news and insights</h3> <p><em>September 17, 2024</em>: Dreamforce 2024 boasts more than 1,200 keynotes, sessions and workshops. While this year’s <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3516181/dreamforce-2024-latest-news-and-insights.html" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.cio.com/article/3516181/dreamforce-2024-latest-news-and-insights.html">Dreamforce will encompass a wide spectrum of topics</a>, expect Salesforce to showcase Agentforce next week at Dreamforce.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-unveils-agentforce-to-help-create-autonomous-ai-bots">Salesforce unveils Agentforce to help create autonomous AI bots</h3> <p><em>September 12, 2024:</em> The <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3518646/salesforce-unveils-agentforce-to-help-create-autonomous-ai-bots.html">CRM giant’s new low-code suite</a> enables enterprises to build AI agents that can reason for themselves when completing sales, service, marketing, and commerce tasks.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-to-acquire-data-protection-specialist-own-company-for-1-9-billion">Salesforce to acquire data protection specialist Own Company for $1.9 billion</h3> <p><em>September 6, 2024:</em> The CRM company said <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3509023/salesforce-to-acquire-data-protection-specialist-own-company-for-1-9-billion.html">Own’s data protection and data management solutions</a> will help it enhance availability, security, and compliance of customer data across its platform.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-previews-new-xgen-sales-model-releases-xlam-family-of-llms">Salesforce previews new XGen-Sales model, releases xLAM family of LLMs</h3> <p><em>September 6, 2024:</em> The XGen-Sales model, which is based on the company’s open source APIGen and its family of large action models (LAM), will <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3507169/salesforce-previews-new-xgen-sales-model-releases-xlam-family-of-llms.html">aid developers and enterprises</a> in automating actions taken by AI agents, analysts say.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-mulls-consumption-pricing-for-ai-agents">Salesforce mulls consumption pricing for AI agents</h3> <p><em>August 30, 2024:</em> Investors expect AI agent productivity gains to reduce demand for Salesforce license seats. CEO Marc Benioff says a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3499283/salesforce-mulls-consumption-pricing-for-ai-agents.html">per-conversation pricing model is a likely solution</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="coforge-and-salesforce-launch-new-offering-to-accelerate-net-zero-goals">Coforge and Salesforce launch new offering to accelerate net zero goals</h3> <p><em>August 27, 2024:</em> Coforge ENZO is designed to <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3496693/coforge-and-salesforce-launch-new-offering-to-accelerate-net-zero-goals.html">streamline emissions data management</a> by identifying, consolidating, and transforming raw data from various emission sources across business operations.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-unveils-autonomous-agents-for-sales-teams">Salesforce unveils autonomous agents for sales teams</h3> <p><em>August 22, 2024:</em> Salesforce <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3490043/salesforce-unveils-autonomous-agents-for-sales-teams.html">today announced two autonomous agents</a> geared to help sales teams scale their operations and hone their negotiation skills. Slated for general availability in October, Einstein Sales Development Rep (SDR) Agent and Einstein Sales Coach Agent will be available through Sales Cloud, with <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3499250/salesforce-might-start-charging-for-each-ai-chat.html">pricing yet to be announced</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-to-acquire-pos-startup-predictspring-to-augment-commerce-cloud">Salesforce to acquire PoS startup PredictSpring to augment Commerce Cloud</h3> <p><em>August 2, 2024:</em> Salesforce has signed a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3480701/salesforce-to-acquire-pos-startup-predictspring-to-augment-commerce-cloud.html">definitive agreement to acquire</a> cloud-based point-of-sale (PoS) software vendor PredictSpring. The acquisition will augment Salesforce’s existing Customer 360 capabilities.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="einstein-studio-1-what-it-is-and-what-to-expect">Einstein Studio 1: What it is and what to expect</h3> <p><em>July 31, 2024:</em> Salesforce has released a set of low-code tools for creating, customizing, and embed AI models in your company’s Salesforce workflows. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3478756/einstein-studio-1-what-it-is-and-what-to-expect.html">Here’s a first look</a> at what can be achieved using it.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-are-salesforce-and-workday-building-an-ai-employee-service-agent-together">Why are Salesforce and Workday building an AI employee service agent together?</h3> <p><em>July 26, 2024:</em> Salesforce and Workday are partnering to build a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3478064/why-are-salesforce-and-workday-building-an-ai-employee-service-agent-together.html">new AI-based employee service agent</a> based on a common data foundation. The agent will be accessible via their respective software interfaces.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-debuts-gen-ai-benchmark-for-crm">Salesforce debuts gen AI benchmark for CRM</h3> <p><em>June 18, 2024:</em> The software company’s <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2151993/salesforce-debuts-gen-ai-benchmark-for-crm.html">new gen AI benchmark for CRM</a> aims to help businesses make more informed decisions when choosing large language models (LLMs) for use with business applications.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-updates-sales-and-service-cloud-with-new-capabilities">Salesforce updates Sales and Service Cloud with new capabilities</h3> <p><em>June 6, 2024:</em> The CRM software vendor has <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2139149/salesforce-updates-sales-and-service-cloud-with-new-capabilities.html">added new capabilities</a> to its Sales Cloud and Service Cloud with updates to its Einstein AI and Data Cloud offerings, including additional generative AI support.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="idc-research-salesforce-1qfy25-building-a-data-foundation-to-connect-with-customers">IDC Research: Salesforce 1QFY25: Building a Data Foundation to Connect with Customers</h3> <p><em>June 5, 2024:</em> Salesforce reported solid growth including $9.13 billion in revenue or 11% year-over-year growth. The company has a <a href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=lcUS52328624">good start to its 2025 fiscal year</a>, but the market continues to shift in significant ways, and Salesforce is not immune to those changes.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="idc-research-salesforce-connections-2024-making-every-customer-journey-more-personalized-and-profitable-through-the-einstein-1-platform">IDC Research: Salesforce Connections 2024: Making Every Customer Journey More Personalized and Profitable Through the Einstein 1 Platform</h3> <p><em>June 5, 2024: </em>The Salesforce Connections 2024 event <a href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=lcUS52337424">showcased the company’s efforts</a> to revolutionize customer journeys through its innovative artificial (AI)-driven platform, Einstein 1. Salesforce’s strategic evolution at Connections 2024 marks a significant step forward in charting the future of personalized and efficient AI-driven customer journeys.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-launches-einstein-copilot-for-general-availability">Salesforce launches Einstein Copilot for general availability</h3> <p><em>April 25, 2024:</em> Salesforce has <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2095127/salesforce-einstein-copilot-now-available.html">announced the general availability</a> of its conversational AI assistant along with a library of pre-programmed ‘Actions’ to help sellers benefit from conversational AI in Sales Cloud.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-debuts-zero-copy-partner-network-to-streamline-data-integration">Salesforce debuts Zero Copy Partner Network to streamline data integration</h3> <p><em>April 25, 2024: </em>Salesforce has <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2095136/salesforce-debuts-zero-copy-partner-network-to-ease-data-integration.html">unveiled a new global ecosystem</a> of technology and solution providers geared to helping its customers leverage third-party data via secure, bidirectional zero-copy integrations with Salesforce Data Cloud.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-informatica-acquisition-talks-falls-through-report">Salesforce-Informatica acquisition talks falls through: Report</h3> <p><em>April 22, 2024: </em>Salesforce’s negotiations to acquire enterprise data management software provider Informatica <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2093946/salesforce-informatica-acquisition-talks-falls-through-report.html">have fallen through</a> as both couldn’t agree on the terms of the deal. The disagreement about the terms of the deal is more likely to be around the price of each share of Informatica.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="decoding-salesforces-plausible-11-billion-bid-to-acquire-informatica">Decoding Salesforce’s plausible $11 billion bid to acquire Informatica</h3> <p><em>April 17, 2024: </em>Salesforce is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2092247/decoding-salesforces-plausible-11-billion-bid-to-acquire-informatica.html">seeking to acquire</a> enterprise data management vendor Informatica, in a move that could mean consolidation for the integration platform-as-a-service (iPaaS) market and a new revenue stream for Salesforce.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-adds-contact-center-updates-to-service-cloud">Salesforce adds Contact Center updates to Service Cloud</h3> <p><em>March 26, 2024:</em> Salesforce has announced <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2074693/salesforce-adds-contact-center-updates-to-service-cloud.html">new Contact Center updates</a> to its Service Cloud, including features such as conversation mining and generative AI-driven survey summarization.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-bids-to-become-ais-copilot-building-platform-of-choice">Salesforce bids to become AI’s copilot building platform of choice</h3> <p><em>March 7, 2024: </em>Salesforce has entered the race to offer the preeminent platform for building generative AI copilots with Einstein 1 Studio, a new set of low-code/no-code AI tools for accelerating the development of gen AI applications. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1312132/salesforce-bids-to-become-copilot-building-platform-of-choice.html">Analysts say</a> the platform has all the tools to become the platform for building out and deploying gen AI assistants.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforce-rebrands-its-low-code-platform-to-einstein-1-studio">Salesforce rebrands its low-code platform to Einstein 1 Studio</h3> <p><em>March 6, 2024: </em>Salesforce has <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1311863/salesforce-rebrands-its-low-code-platform-to-einstein-1-studio.html">rebranded its low-code platform</a> to Einstein 1 Studio and bundled it with the company’s Data Cloud offering. The platform has added a new feature, Prompt Builder, which allows developers to create reusable LLM prompts without the need for writing code.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="salesforces-einstein-1-platform-to-get-new-prompt-engineering-features">Salesforce’s Einstein 1 platform to get new prompt-engineering features</h3> <p><em>February 9, 2024:</em> Salesforce is working <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1306845/salesforces-einstein-1-platform-to-get-new-prompt-engineering-features.html">on adding two new prompt engineering features</a> to its Einstein 1 platform to speed up the development of generative AI applications in the enterprise. The features include a testing center and the provision of prompt engineering suggestions.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><br></h3>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI isn’t failing, people are failing with AI]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135361/ai-isnt-failing-people-are-failing-with-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135361/ai-isnt-failing-people-are-failing-with-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>In 2018, Google released the AI model <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1810.04805" rel="nofollow">BERT</a>, forever changing how machines understood context in a language. BERT, short for Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers, solved a long-standing problem in natural language understanding. Before BERT, researchers needed multiple bespoke models (and datasets) to understand the different contextual meanings of human languages. BERT demonstrated that one model could process contextual meaning across multiple languages (via mBERT).</p> <p>While BERT became a fundamental building block in natural language processing (NLP), its impact on how we interact with computers came from its application. That change did not come from shoehorning the technology into existing solutions. It stemmed from an applied understanding of how BERT functioned, would evolve and could solve domain-specific challenges. I know because my team at Google used BERT to create responsive search ads. Our work transformed online text advertising.</p> <p>Our success in applying BERT wasn’t simply because we had TPUs or more resources than our competitors. (Those things helped, undoubtedly.) Our advantage was my team’s domain expertise and close collaboration with the Google Research team, who created the model. Collectively, we could envision how to apply BERT to fundamentally reshape advertising because we understood:<br><br></p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>How the model operates</strong>, including its strengths, weaknesses and dependencies.</li> <li><strong>The specific industry problems and operational challenges</strong> we were solving for.</li> <li><strong>The way we’d tune the model and create a system around it,</strong> at scale.</li>
</ol> <p>This framework remains pertinent today, as business leaders seek to understand how to build and deliver scaled impact with large language models (LLMs).</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">Weighing the pros and cons of models</h2> <p>As critics and pundits debate the efficacy of generative AI, numerous studies underscore a similar finding: people are unsure of how to use LLMs. To address these uncertainties, leaders need to ensure that their organization’s decision-makers understand, at a high level, how these models function and can be applied.</p> <p>That technical understanding mattered when we applied BERT. It matters even more now. Because while BERT required domain expertise to deploy effectively, today’s LLMs make it dangerously easy to deploy them poorly and unknowingly. It’s likely the reason so many AI projects never proceed past pilots, <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/quantumblack/our-insights/the-state-of-ai#/download/%2F~%2Fmedia%2Fmckinsey%2Fbusiness%20functions%2Fquantumblack%2Four%20insights%2Fthe%20state%20of%20ai%2Fnovember%202025%2Fthe-state-of-ai-in-2025-agents-innovation-and-transformation.pdf%3FshouldIndex%3Dfalse">as McKinsey reported.</a></p> <p>BERT’s success underscored the power of pre-training and fine-tuning a model on a large dataset to enhance token-level semantic context within NLP. But where BERT zigged, OpenAI’s Generative Pre-trained Transformer (GPT) zagged. Unlike BERT’s encoder-only architecture, GPTs use a decoder-only architecture to generate outputs, trained to predict the next token in a sequence. BERT was trained on billions of tokens, while today’s GPTs are trained on trillions. The more tokens these LLMs were trained upon, the more capabilities they gained.</p> <p>Early applications of these LLMs have centered on their ability to generate creative, fluent and coherent writing, coding and imagery. This “creativity” reflects the probabilistic patterns that these models have learnt from their massive training datasets. But this same predictive output can be disadvantageous when these models need to be deployed in factual, deterministic environments.</p> <p>Deep learning researchers have long argued that setting any rules, following the historical method of symbolic reasoning, would inhibit the model’s abilities. Structured to predict an output, even when the model is uncertain, LLMs have demonstrated a tendency to hallucinate. Hallucinations are not a bug, but a feature. They’re inherent to how these models operate and should limit your applications without guardrails. After all, mistakes in consequential industries like healthcare, finance and legal can be catastrophic.</p> <p>This historical comparison, while surface-level, still illustrates how the model’s underlying functions impact its outputs and applications. Understanding these architectures solves half the problem. The other half is building a strategy to collect and scale data within your specific domain.<strong></strong></p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI’s scaling problem is a domain problem</h2> <p>Healthcare, finance and legal are all industries with ample data and capital to spend. While each sector presents distinct challenges, they all have found success with AI.</p> <p>Hospitals epitomize the opportunities and obstacles within the healthcare industry. The average<a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/12/03/health-care-data-storage-environmental-cost-climate-change/#:~:text=Ask%20anyone%20in%20this%20field,of%20data%20becomes%20incomprehensibly%20large."> hospital generates 50 petabytes</a> of data annually, enough tokens to train a sophisticated model. But 97 percent of this data isn’t used: it consists of unstructured clinical notes and radiology reports, redacted documents following HIPAA compliance, and data siloed or managed under regulatory scrutiny. When you can access it cleanly, as illustrated by <a href="https://pubs.rsna.org/doi/abs/10.1148/radiol.243688" rel="nofollow">AI detections of tumors in radiology images</a>, a measurable impact is possible. When you can’t, your pilot stalls.</p> <p>Finance presents different tradeoffs. Transaction data is generally well-structured and high-volume, enabling novel applications in fraud detection and customer service automation. But limiting these applications is<a href="https://arxiv.org/html/2508.05201v2" rel="nofollow"> </a><a href="https://arxiv.org/html/2508.05201v2" rel="nofollow">LLMs’ high error rates</a> on multi-step numerical reasoning, creating fundamental misalignment for calculation-intensive applications.</p> <p>The pervasiveness of<a href="https://www.thomsonreuters.com/en-us/posts/technology/genai-hallucinations/" rel="nofollow"> </a><a href="https://www.thomsonreuters.com/en-us/posts/technology/genai-hallucinations/" rel="nofollow">hallucinations spotted in trial briefs</a> and documents has sown distrust in AI within the legal industry.<a href="https://www.msba.org/site/site/content/News-and-Publications/News/General-News/ABAs_2024_Legal_Technology_Survey_Report_Trends_in_Online_Research.aspx" rel="nofollow"> </a><a href="https://www.msba.org/site/site/content/News-and-Publications/News/General-News/ABAs_2024_Legal_Technology_Survey_Report_Trends_in_Online_Research.aspx" rel="nofollow">The ABA’s 2024 Legal Technology Survey</a> found 75% of attorneys cite accuracy concerns as a primary barrier to their AI adoption. But outside the courtroom, there are many applications of AI to radically reshape legal work, including managing contracts, conducting compliance and risk assessments, protecting intellectual property, etc. These instances lend themselves to LLMs’ strengths: ability to handle unstructured data, pattern recognition, information extraction and data structure analysis.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">Your development framework to scale data</h2> <p>The distinction between courtroom risk and contract is exactly the advantage that we identified at Ironclad. Every business function generates contracts that include information on renewal dates, payment terms, obligations and counterparty details. Training models on this data is a strategy that leverages LLMs’ strengths with minimal risk.</p> <p>Compared to legal briefs and documents, where incorrect AI summaries have massive implications, the risk of applying AI to contracts is lower. Our approach at Ironclad is modeled after the automotive industry’s safety framework for deploying autonomous vehicles, the SAE J3016. This standard distinguishes between systems in which humans retain responsibility (Levels 1-2, driver assistance) and those in which machines become accountable (Levels 3-5, automated driving).</p> <p>Applied to enterprise AI, this risk-based framework clarifies deployment roadmaps and boundaries. We chose to develop our Intake Agent, which extracts contract data from third-party papers, and our Conversational Search Agents, which enable natural language querying of documents, because we saw them as “Level 1-2” applications with low adoption barriers and associated risks. Verifying a contract autonomously, while plausible with today’s LLMs, might seem innocuous, but unsupervised verification could be very risky. There’s a plausible scenario in which an agent could overlook litigation between the two engaged parties and autonomously renew a contract because it can’t access the tort proceedings data.</p> <p>Using a risk-based framework can help determine where and how to build your AI applications by answering the question: what’s the likelihood we’ll get this right, and what happens if we’re wrong? This calculation, not competitive pressure, should then determine your deployment sequencing.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a>Build a foundation, create transformation</h2> <p>During my twenty-plus years of working with AI, I’ve found that the most significant determinant of a technology’s impact on a business is the organization’s fluency with it.</p> <p>As planning ensues, organizations trying to determine how and where to apply generative AI to their business need first to have an introspective look and ask themselves:</p> <ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Do you understand the technology’s actual mechanisms? </strong>Not marketing promises, but fundamental architecture. LLMs perform statistical pattern matching, not logical reasoning. They require extensive general training followed by domain-specific fine-tuning. Without this understanding, you’ll deploy for impossible tasks.</li> <li><strong>How does the industry you’re serving share, collect and store data? </strong>W<strong>hat data will you use to tune and fine-tune your models, if at all? </strong>LLMs are foundational because they require sophisticated pre-training, followed by fine-tuning to generate meaningful, domain-specific outputs.</li> <li><strong>Do you have a framework, such as a risk-based model, to prioritize, deploy and assess which products to develop?</strong> Start with low-risk, human-supervised applications. Conduct evaluations and build feedback loops. Expand systematically as reliability proves out.</li>
</ol> <p>Over my career, I’ve watched people overestimate what AI can do this quarter while underestimating what it will do this decade. Technology evolves. Industries are reshaped. But transformations are created by businesses that do the foundational work.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.<br><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When speed stops working]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135347/when-speed-stops-working.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135347/when-speed-stops-working.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For more than a decade, speed defined modern technology leadership.</p> <p>I was in the room when it happened. Board decks rewarded velocity. Executive meetings celebrated acceleration. CIOs were measured by how quickly platforms migrated, products shipped and transformations launched. Speed became synonymous with relevance, and hesitation was framed as risk.</p> <p>But something subtle began to change toward the end of 2025.</p> <p>The questions coming from boards no longer centered on how fast we could move. Instead, they sounded more reflective, more surgical and frankly, more consequential: What happens when these scales? What breaks under stress? What risks are we introducing faster than the organization can absorb?</p> <p>By 2026, a quiet strategic reversal is underway.</p> <p>Across enterprises, technology leaders are no longer optimizing for maximum speed. They are optimizing for stability under continuous change. And that shift is redefining what strong CIO leadership looks like.</p> <p>This is not a retreat from innovation. It is a maturation of judgment.</p> <p>For years, enterprise technology was rewarded for how fast it moved. In 2026, it will be judged by how well it holds.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-speed-stopped-being-enough">Why speed stopped being enough</h2> <p>Speed once solved a real problem.</p> <p>Legacy architectures were brittle. Markets were compressing. Digital natives rewrote customer expectations while established enterprises struggled to respond. Accelerating delivery was not optional, it was existential.</p> <p>But speed was never meant to be a permanent operating strategy.</p> <p>What many organizations are now confronting is the accumulated cost of sustained urgency. In my own experience, the warning signs show up quietly: architectures that scale usage faster than governance, teams optimized for delivery but not durability, platforms launched before ownership is clear, and risks introduced faster than accountability can mature.</p> <p>None of these failures looks dramatic in isolation. Together, they create instability.</p> <p>Boards are increasingly aware of this pattern. They see that faster execution does not automatically translate into resilience. In fact, relentless acceleration often masks fragility until the moment pressure arrives.</p> <p>That is when speed stops looking like progress and starts looking like exposure.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="stability-is-becoming-the-new-competitive-advantage">Stability is becoming the new competitive advantage</h2> <p>Stability is often misunderstood as conservatism. In practice, it is the opposite.</p> <p>Stability is what allows organizations to change direction without breaking trust, budgets or balance sheets. It is what enables enterprises to absorb regulatory shifts, leadership transitions, market volatility and technological disruption without resetting the organization every eighteen months.</p> <p>In 2026, the highest-performing enterprises share a common trait: they are not the fastest movers, but they are the most adaptable without chaos.</p> <p>I see this in organizations where technology decisions survive executive turnover, where platforms tolerate partial failure without cascading outages, and where costs remain predictable even as capabilities expand. Stability does not slow innovation. It compounds it.</p> <p>This broader emphasis on durability and adaptability as strategic capabilities is increasingly reflected in board-level discussions of operational resilience and enterprise continuity, including perspectives outlined by Deloitte on <a href="https://www.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/topics/leadership/building-organizational-resilience.html" rel="nofollow">how resilience has become a governance priority rather than a compliance exercise</a>.</p> <p>Investors increasingly recognize this. Predictability now carries a premium, especially in regulated and capital-intensive industries. Analysts are less impressed by velocity alone and more interested in whether technology investments produce a durable advantage rather than episodic wins. Research from McKinsey reinforces this shift, noting that <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/operations/our-insights" rel="nofollow">sustained value creation increasingly comes from disciplined execution rather than isolated transformation bursts</a>.</p> <p>Stability has quietly become strategic insurance.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cio-role-is-re-centering-around-judgment">The CIO role is re-centering around judgment</h2> <p>During the peak of digital acceleration, the CIO was often positioned as a catalyst, someone expected to remove friction and compress timelines. In many cases, that framing was necessary.</p> <p>In 2026, the role is evolving again.</p> <p>The modern CIO is becoming the enterprise’s custodian of stability, not as stasis, but as a design principle. This means deciding when not to modernize yet, sequencing initiatives so organizations can absorb change and designing systems that tolerate ambiguity rather than collapse under it.</p> <p>Much of this work is invisible. It rarely appears on roadmaps or transformation dashboards. But boards notice it immediately when it is missing.</p> <p>In my conversations with directors, the questions have shifted from feature delivery to structural integrity. They want to understand how decisions are sequenced, how risk is contained and how technology choices reinforce organizational coherence rather than erode it.</p> <p>This is where CIO leadership becomes less about tools and more about judgment.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-are-boards-and-investors-leaning-into-stability">Why are boards and investors leaning into stability?</h2> <p>From a governance perspective, the board’s concern is no longer simply whether technology can deliver, but whether the enterprise can withstand the consequences if it does not.</p> <p>Technology failures today are rarely isolated technical events. They trigger regulatory scrutiny, reputational damage, financial volatility and leadership credibility issues. Directors understand that the risk surface has expanded and that stability is the only sustainable counterweight.</p> <p>This concern aligns with how systemic operational and technology fragility is now being discussed by global financial authorities such as the Bank for International Settlements, which has highlighted <a href="https://www.bis.org/topics/operational_resilience.htm" rel="nofollow">how weaknesses in operational resilience can amplify enterprise-wide risk</a>.</p> <p>Investors see the same signals. In growth-stage and public companies alike, they increasingly assess whether technology platforms can scale without exponential cost, whether operating models are resilient to disruption and whether leadership teams demonstrate control rather than constant reaction. Commentary from BlackRock and other institutional investors has emphasized <a href="https://www.blackrock.com/corporate/insights" rel="nofollow">operational resilience and governance maturity as material factors in long-term valuation</a>.</p> <p>Speed still matters. But speed without stability now raises questions rather than confidence.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-hidden-cost-of-perpetual-acceleration">The hidden cost of perpetual acceleration</h2> <p>One of the most overlooked consequences of speed-first cultures is decision debt.</p> <p>When everything is urgent, tradeoffs go undocumented, exceptions become precedents and temporary workarounds harden into permanent dependencies. Over time, organizations lose the ability to explain why systems exist as they do.</p> <p>I have seen this firsthand. When boards eventually ask, Why is this structured this way? Who owns this risk? What assumptions were made? The answers are often fragmented or incomplete. That is not a technology problem. It is a leadership problem.</p> <p>This dynamic mirrors a broader body of research on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_quality" rel="nofollow">decision quality</a> and execution discipline, which shows that effective decision processes matter more than raw speed in complex environments.</p> <p>Stability restores narrative clarity. It forces explicit decisions, documented intent and accountable ownership. It creates the conditions under which technology decisions can be explained, defended and evolved rather than constantly patched.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-effective-cios-are-doing-differently-in-2026">What effective CIOs are doing differently in 2026</h2> <p>The most effective CIOs are not announcing this shift publicly. They are embedding it quietly into how decisions are made.</p> <p>Across industries, common patterns are emerging. Fewer “big bang” initiatives and more staged commitments. Architectural ownership established before platform expansion. Investment pacing aligned to organizational readiness rather than vendor timelines. Explicit tolerance thresholds for complexity, cost and risk.</p> <p>These leaders are not slower. They are more deliberate.</p> <p>They understand that credibility compounds faster than velocity. And in a climate where executive trust is fragile, credibility is the CIO’s most valuable currency.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="founders-face-the-same-reckoning">Founders face the same reckoning</h2> <p>This shift is not limited to large enterprises.</p> <p>Founders often associate stability with late-stage maturity. In 2026, that assumption is increasingly dangerous. Investors now scrutinize whether platforms can survive leadership transitions, whether systems scale without disproportionate cost, and whether governance exists beyond the founding team.</p> <p>Speed still opens doors. Stability keeps them open.</p> <p>Startups that cannot articulate a credible stability narrative find it harder to attract patient capital, especially in environments where regulatory, security and operational scrutiny is intensifying. Founders who embrace stability early do not lose agility, they gain legitimacy.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-strategic-reversal-no-one-announced">The strategic reversal no one announced</h2> <p>No memo declared this shift. No keynote celebrated it.</p> <p>But it is unmistakable.</p> <p>Enterprise technology leadership is moving from speed as identity to stability as advantage, from reaction to orchestration, from momentum to endurance. The CIO who thrives in 2026 will not be the loudest advocate for acceleration. They will be the quiet architect who ensures the enterprise can move again without losing its footing.</p> <p>In a world that no longer waits, stability may be the most radical form of leadership left.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Anthropic Study: AI Coding Assistance Reduces Developer Skill Mastery by 17%]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-coding-skill-formation/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-coding-skill-formation/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-coding-skill-formation/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771340718616.jpg"/><p>Anthropic research shows developers using AI assistance scored 17% lower on comprehension tests when learning new coding libraries, though productivity gains were not statistically significant. Those who used AI for conceptual inquiry scored 65% or higher, while those delegating code generation to AI scored below 40%.</p> <i>By Steef-Jan Wiggers</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[6 strategies for accelerating IT modernization]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135451/6-strategies-for-accelerating-it-modernization.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135451/6-strategies-for-accelerating-it-modernization.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Modernization remains a priority for CIOs, with IT executives saying that legacy systems and outdated infrastructure <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3828614/outdated-business-apps-can-cloud-your-ai-vision.html">stymie AI adoption</a>, innovation, and ultimately business growth.</p> <p>Indeed, CIOs cite modernization as a key component of their transformation work, which dominates the agenda of most IT leaders — some 77%, according to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3976500/state-of-the-cio-survey-2025.html">CIO.com’s 2025 State of the CIO report</a>.</p> <p>But the priority today is not just modernization, but modernization at top speed.</p> <p>“Technology is moving fast, but society and business conditions are moving faster, so now you have to modernize just to keep up,” says veteran IT leader <a href="https://org.works/about/" rel="nofollow">Janet Sherlock</a>, founder and CEO of Org.Works, an advisory firm on organization structure and strategy. “Modernization has to happen at a faster clip all the time, so your whole organization can move faster.”</p> <p>Most CIOs say they’re up for the challenge: Roughly three-quarters believe they’ll complete a wide range of legacy modernization initiatives within two years, according to <a href="https://www.cognizant.com/us/en/insights/insights-blog/legacy-modernization-mandate-ai-timeline" rel="nofollow">research from Cognizant</a>, an IT services and consulting firm.</p> <p>Researchers, however, aren’t as optimistic, noting that organizations face a host of challenges — <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3805174/67-of-digital-transformations-delayed-due-to-skill-shortages.html">from skills shortages</a> to budget constraints — as they move to more rapidly modernize.</p> <p>Despite such challenges, IT advisors and long-serving IT leaders say there are efforts CIOs can undertake to accelerate IT modernization. Here are six strategies they say can help speed the process.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-use-ai-as-a-bridge-to-the-future">1. Use AI as a bridge to the future</h2> <p>Many — if not most — organizations want to speed up their modernization efforts to quickly capitalize on AI, but they should also be using <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4085184/using-ai-to-modernize-mainframes-turning-legacy-tech-into-a-strategic-advantage.html">AI to accelerate that modernization work</a>, says <a href="https://www.westmonroe.com/our-team/erik-brown" rel="nofollow">Erik Brown</a>, a senior partner at consulting firm West Monroe and leader of its Technology and Experience Practice.</p> <p>As Brown notes, teams typically have had to manually review documentation and code and work to decompose legacy monoliths before implementing more modern infrastructure and systems. Now, however, they can use AI “to help move the current state into the future.”</p> <p>“AI can analyze millions of lines of code. It can understand stored procedures and ETL scripts and create modern versions to move data into a modern platform. It’s turning months of laborious manual work into days. That’s a massive lift,” he says. “And it builds institutional knowledge to build speed. That’s a massive accelerator.”</p> <p>West Monroe says there’s a financial incentive to moving faster, as its research shows that most <a href="https://go.westmonroe.com/SpeedWinsResearch" data-type="link" data-id="https://go.westmonroe.com/SpeedWinsResearch" rel="nofollow">leaders believe their organizations lose 1% to 5% of annual revenue</a> due to slow decisions and actions. West Monroe calls it the “slowness tax.”</p> <p>Furthermore, Brown believes AI will play an increasingly more significant role in IT modernization in the years to come. He predicts that AI agents will someday be capable of constantly reviewing the IT environment, including resources within applications, for pieces that are out of date; once agents identify the outdated pieces, they will determine how best to update them and then execute the updates — with limited to no human intervention, only human oversight.</p> <p>“AI gives us an amazing mechanism to handle continuous modernization,” Brown says, acknowledging agentic AI is not yet capable of doing that yet but is “confident it will be.”</p> <p>In today’s incarnation, while agentic AI shows promise, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4022454/applying-agentic-ai-to-legacy-systems-prepare-for-these-4-challenges.html">applying it to legacy systems still presents challenges</a>.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-adopt-managed-services-and-serverless-architectures">2. Adopt managed services and serverless architectures</h2> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulsullivan/" rel="nofollow">Paul Sullivan</a>, vice president of cloud governance at Capital One, says the company views “modernization as the continuous refinement of our operational DNA, enabling a permanent state of evolution.”</p> <p>The goal, he explains, “is a frictionless environment where we can rapidly deliver new capabilities, including AI-driven ones, without being slowed down by the weight of how we used to build software and deliver value.”</p> <p>Case in point is its recent enterprise-wide shift to a serverless approach for application development, which made managed, cloud-native compute as the default for new applications. Sullivan says the change “allowed us to treat infrastructure as a set of services rather than something developers directly operate. We moved away from manual management and toward a model where the platform handles the undifferentiated heavy lifting.”</p> <p>The shift enabled faster innovation, a stronger security posture, and better cost efficiency, he says.</p> <p>Given such benefits, Sullivan lists the adoption of managed services and serverless architectures as a key strategy for accelerating modernization.</p> <p>“CIOs should stop viewing infrastructure as a set of assets to manage and start viewing it as a product delivered through services,” he says. “When you pair this with automated governance and observability, you create a safe space for innovation. It allows teams to move fast without the risk of compromising security or resilience.”</p> <p>“Teams spend less time on maintenance and more time on the creative part of engineering,” Sullivan adds. “We want them to be able to focus on writing exceptional code and building innovative applications. This reduction in toil translates directly into faster delivery. It creates a culture where experimentation is cheap and quick. When the platform handles the plumbing, the engineers can focus on the product.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-establish-a-culture-of-modernization">3. Establish a culture of modernization</h2> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lauren-wilkinson-02b288/" rel="nofollow">Lauren Wilkinson</a>, divisional CIO of Financial Advisor Services at Vanguard, says her company has modernized its systems “to the cloud using microservices architecture that enables speed and resilience.”</p> <p>She adds, “The results have been promising, including upgrading our website experience and launching a new mobile app, and moving to daily continuous delivery of enhancements, meaning our teams can respond faster to client feedback.”</p> <p>Wilkinson says the ability to tackle such modernization initiatives with speed requires alignment with the organization’s goals.</p> <p>“The most important strategy is to establish a north star at the top of the organization,” she explains. “Modernization cannot simply be deemed a tech initiative; it must be a business initiative. An enterprise-wide north star will determine your course and potentially alleviate competing priorities between technology and business functions, a common roadblock.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-introduce-ai-to-re-engineer-processes">4. Introduce AI to re-engineer processes</h2> <p>Wilkinson says a more recent modernization effort was the introduction of vibe coding for its development teams.</p> <p>“By integrating advanced tools, we eliminated traditional handoffs between engineering, product, and design teams, accelerating our webpage design process by 40% and reducing prototyping time from two weeks to just 20 minutes,” she adds. “It has not just transformed our engineering process; it’s reshaped how we deliver value to our clients.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-get-clarity-on-roles-responsibilities-and-decision-making-authority">5. Get clarity on roles, responsibilities, and decision-making authority</h2> <p>Companies that don’t have clarity on who makes what decisions on technology and processes can’t move as fast on modernization efforts. That’s because teams must spend valuable time determining who owns what platforms, systems, and capabilities that their modernization initiatives will impact, says Sherlock.</p> <p>“Ambiguity,” she adds, “is a tax on performance.”</p> <p>She says her research found that speed is negatively impacted by about 25% in organizations with CIOs and chief AI officers who are peers because of such ambiguity.</p> <p>“If decision-making responsibilities are not clear, and multiple teams or multiple people believe they’re responsible for [something], decisions are held up. IT has to circle around and spend time trying to figure out who is really responsible,” she explains. “And then you get into a turf situation, then you get friction, which holds up communication and that holds up speed, and that slows the entire ship.”</p> <p>Sherlock says she has encountered ambiguity in her past executive roles, which include chief digital and technical officer at Ralph Lauren from 2022 to 2024 and its CIO from 2017 to 2022.</p> <p>“If I ever felt like someone on another team stepped over something on my team, I set up a meeting and said, ‘We should do this, and you should do that. It’s not about turf. It’s about clarity, so that we can move faster together.’”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-get-modular-with-your-it-architecture">6. Get modular with your IT architecture</h2> <p>IT needs to move like racecar pit crews, who can rapidly change worn-out components, says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniellephaneuf/" rel="nofollow">Danielle Phaneuf</a>, a partner with PwC Technology Strategy and leader of the firms’ CIO Program.</p> <p>To do that, CIOs need to go with modular IT architecture so “everything can be changed out,” she says.</p> <p>Modular IT architecture features independent, interoperable components that can be developed, deployed, and scaled separately. Because each module has clear interfaces and responsibilities, IT teams can update or replace capabilities without disrupting the entire stack — just as pit crews do when they replace parts but not the racecar itself.</p> <p>“You want modularity. You don’t want that monolithic model to creep back in. But you also don’t want modularity from the standpoint of fragmentation. The whole key is to create the fewest dependencies, so you can literally unplug something when you want to plug the new thing in,” Phaneuf explains.</p> <p>This approach is particularly useful when it comes to AI models, Phaneuf says. Ongoing innovations are happening so fast that today’s leading AI model could become tomorrow’s laggard, so organizations need the ability to quickly switch out one model for another when needed.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[4 tips to help the new innovator’s struggle with AI and traditional code]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4133150/4-tips-to-help-the-new-innovators-struggle-with-ai-and-traditional-code.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4133150/4-tips-to-help-the-new-innovators-struggle-with-ai-and-traditional-code.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>What most people thought was going to be another year of agentic AI is quickly turning into a more practical focus on simultaneously dealing with probabilistic (AI/ML-driven) and deterministic (traditional rule-based) code. Not a portfolio of both, but a growing number of hybrid applications that need to carefully and skillfully integrate the best of both guessing and knowing.</p> <p>Many CIOs are no longer dealing with <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4080608/the-great-ai-reset-cios-pivot-from-pilots-to-business-value.html?utm=hybrid_search">pilots and prototypes</a> focused on specific off-the-shelf AI apps or custom agentic apps built solely within agent builder platforms. They’re now dealing with new application development requirements that need to combine both AI and traditional code.</p> <p>These applications aren’t apps with AI bolted on, but new ones designed from the ground up where CIOs are quickly finding the messy middle, and having to decide where to draw boundaries and organize their teams.</p> <p>Here are four recommendations for CIOs when deciding how best to integrate agentic, probabilistic, and traditional, deterministic code, particularly within software development projects that require careful integration of the two.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="establish-boundaries-and-guardrails">Establish boundaries and guardrails</h2> <p>The first step is to understand where each technology works best and to develop architectural guidelines and best practices for development and integration teams.</p> <p>Quais Taraki, CTO at AI and data company EDB, recommends using deterministic code for the authoritative rules of your business, and probabilistic agents for the messy ambiguity of human intent. “The key is a dual-representation architecture where agents suggest, but traditional logic guards the system of record,” he says. “By co-locating these in a single platform, you eliminate the integration tax that typically comes with bolting AI onto existing systems, while maintaining absolute sovereignty over your data and logic.”</p> <p>Then there’s Michael Fauscette, chief analyst at Arion Research LLC, who says the key decision framework for CIOs is to use deterministic code wherever outcomes must be predictable, auditable, and repeatable, and reserve agentic and probabilistic approaches for tasks that require reasoning, judgment, or handling ambiguity at scale. “In practice, that means letting agents handle the messy middle of workflows, like interpretation, summarization, and decision support,” he says, “while traditional code owns data validation, transaction processing, compliance logic, and structured output generation.”</p> <p>However, Sangeet Paul Choudary, a C-level advisor on AI strategy and author, believes it really depends on the tolerance for failure versus the upside of innovation. “Agents can help come up with novel solutions to problems coders wouldn’t have thought through, so where that’s valuable, I’d design with agents at the core, and code as checks and balances,” he says. “In scenarios with low tolerance for failure, though, I’d flip it.”</p> <p>If you’re working on the agentic side first, as part of a new software development project, it’s also important to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4119297/how-to-get-your-enterprise-architecture-ready-for-agentic-ai.html?utm=hybrid_search">optimize your agentic code</a> and outputs first. You generally want to get this as accurate and repeatable as possible before deciding when and where to bring in the guardrails of traditional code. As an example, poor prompting or less than optimal LLMs for a specific use case, can shift the boundaries and might even make you under-utilize the power of your agents in a search for the safety of traditional code. </p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="organize-for-new-hybrid-teams">Organize for new hybrid teams</h2> <p>These new hybrid applications require teams with mixed skillsets as well. Taraki recommends CIOs think of <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4127774/1-5-million-ai-agents-are-at-risk-of-going-rogue-2.html?utm=hybrid_search">agents as highly capable employees inside your organization</a>. “Like any employee with significant access and autonomy, they come with a large blast radius and can have a profound impact on your business, for better or worse,” he says. “Success requires collapsing the silos between AI and traditional dev teams to ensure that orchestration and observability are treated as critical infrastructure.”</p> <p>Fauscette recommends CIOs rethink team composition to include bridge roles — engineers who understand both traditional software architecture and agentic design patterns — because siloed AI and engineering teams create integration debt that compounds quickly.</p> <p>According to Choudary, it’s important to focus on less reactive QA, and more proactive checks in the development and tooling environment with agents working alongside coders.</p> <p>Overall, the handoffs and intersections between agentic and traditional code aren’t always as simple as an API call and structured output. It’s therefore important to think about not only the macro workflows between humans and AI, but also the numerous interfaces between probabilistic and deterministic code. Just like the handoffs between humans and machines, we also need well-positioned ones between AI and traditional code, and engineers who understand the tradeoffs. </p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="prepare-for-time-well-spent-on-governance-and-cost-modeling">Prepare for time well spent on governance and cost modeling</h2> <p>While the software development side may be accelerated with hybrid applications, the time and cost savings will likely need to be reallocated to careful upstream software design and architecture, as well as downstream testing, monitoring, and cost modelling.</p> <p>Fauscette says that on the governance and TCO side, hybrid systems introduce new complexity in testing, monitoring, and cost modeling since probabilistic components have variable execution paths and token-based cost structures that don’t fit neatly into traditional capacity planning or QA frameworks.</p> <p>In terms of cost modeling, while inference costs may necessitate new business rules to set usage boundaries for end users, Taraki says that, ultimately, the TCO of the agentic era isn’t just about inference costs but the operational rigor required to manage non-deterministic systems at scale.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="recognize-how-multi-agent-workflows-will-further-blur-the-lines">Recognize how multi-agent workflows will further blur the lines</h2> <p>As if the new design considerations and organizational requirements for building hybrid systems with agentic and traditional code weren’t complex enough, we’re also dealing with a moving target as agents evolve.</p> <p>Choudary adds that the center of gravity inside hybrids keeps shifting toward agents year by year. “We started with agents working on top of legacy code,” he says. “Now we’re increasingly seeing innovation-demanding systems designing around agentic capabilities, and using code for performance and risk management.”</p> <p>Fauscette also recommends choosing a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4123497/what-cios-in-finance-do-to-navigate-ai-agents.html?utm=hybrid_search">multi-agent workflow</a> when the task is end-to-end cognitive work like research, analysis, and planning, and a hybrid AI and traditional approach when you need precise control over outputs, regulatory compliance, or integration with existing systems of record. “Looking ahead, the line between these two patterns will blur as agentic frameworks mature and offer better native support for deterministic checkpoints, structured outputs, and human-in-the-loop controls, making hybrid by default the standard architecture pattern within the next year to 18 months,” he says.</p> <p>Taraki’s advice is to build for graceful degradation by ensuring every agentic step has a deterministic fallback, so your platform stays resilient and available even when models fail. “The future of the agentic will look less like agentic glue and more like a sovereign, governed platform with SLAs, auditability, and standardized patterns for retrieval, tool use, and safety,” he adds. “Our research shows that the 13% of global enterprises prioritizing sovereignty over their data and AI are already seeing five times the ROI, and running twice as many use cases in mainstream production as their peers.”</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Does using AI in QA testing increase risk for software companies?]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135334/does-using-ai-in-qa-testing-increase-risk-for-software-companies.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135334/does-using-ai-in-qa-testing-increase-risk-for-software-companies.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>If you want a signal of just how widespread AI has become in software development, consider this: Vibe coding was named Collins Dictionary’s <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cpd2y053nleo" rel="nofollow">Word of the Year</a> for 2025. The term describes developers quickly prototyping apps using AI tools with minimal planning or structure — a trend that captures the current mood of experimentation with artificial intelligence.</p> <p>While we’re still far from letting AI build entire mission-critical applications on its own, we are entering a new era in how software is tested. With the right mindset and safeguards, QA teams can use AI to reduce manual work, increase speed and cover more ground during release cycles.</p> <p>But using AI in testing is not without risk. The same tools that generate helpful test scripts can also produce misleading or faulty ones. And in QA, where trust and accuracy are non-negotiable, careless use of AI can lead to real damage — to products, to teams and to the people who use the software.</p> <p>This article explores both the potential and the pitfalls of using AI in QA, and how software companies can strike the right balance between speed and safety.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-shift-toward-ai-in-testing">The shift toward AI in testing</h2> <p>AI-assisted coding has already changed how developers work. Tools that generate code, sometimes entire applications, from natural language prompts have made it easier to build features faster. Developers spend less time searching through documentation or worrying about syntax — the productivity gains are hard to ignore.</p> <p>But AI-generated code is not always correct. It can contain subtle logic errors, security vulnerabilities, or poorly structured logic that’s hard to maintain. This means that strong testing practices are more important than ever. QA teams are the safety net for modern development — and now they too are starting to use AI in their workflows.</p> <p>For testers, AI can help write test cases, generate test scripts, summarize test runs and even write bug reports. Used thoughtfully, these tools reduce the tedious, repetitive work that often slows QA down. But these benefits come with caveats. The same models that write helpful test cases can also hallucinate — that is, invent fake scenarios — miss critical logic, or generate test scripts that look right but don’t actually test anything meaningful.</p> <p>That’s a serious concern. If a test appears valid and passes, but doesn’t actually verify the correct behavior of the software, it creates a false sense of confidence. This is how flawed products reach customers — with the worst-case outcome being not just bugs, but reputational or legal damage.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-makes-agentic-testing-risky">What makes agentic testing risky</h2> <p>A newer and more ambitious application of AI in QA is what’s called agentic testing. Here, AI agents don’t just generate test code — they attempt to simulate the actions of human testers. They interact with the app directly: clicking buttons, filling out forms, navigating screens and logging results. The idea is that these agents can autonomously explore the app, find issues, and even generate bug reports. It’s almost like having an extra QA engineer on the team.</p> <p>While this sounds promising, it’s also where some of the biggest risks are emerging. Agentic testing introduces unpredictability into a process that depends on clear pass-or-fail results. While good prompting and careful temperature settings can guide agents toward more deterministic behavior, they remain sensitive to subtle changes in context — a slightly delayed loading state, a minor UI shift or even dynamic content reordering. These variations can cause the agent to behave differently across runs, leading to test flakiness that stems not from actual bugs, but from the AI’s inconsistent interpretation of the interface. This fragility makes agentic testing difficult to rely on, especially at scale.</p> <p>With traditional test scripts, a human tester or developer can read through the code, understand the intent and verify whether the test is sound. Agentic testing doesn’t offer that same transparency. While agentic testing tools often provide video recordings, logs or DOM snapshots of their actions, relying on these outputs for validation creates a new kind of bottleneck. Reviewing even a few minutes of footage to understand what the agent did — and why — is dramatically slower than scanning through a deterministic test script. You lose the quick readability and repeatability of traditional test code, and instead inherit a review process that feels more like a forensic investigation. Over time, this erodes confidence in the system and adds significant overhead every time a test misfires or fails without a clear reason.</p> <p>This lack of visibility is a major red flag for any experienced QA professional. Testing isn’t just about the outcome — it’s about traceability, repeatability and accountability. Without those things, QA becomes a black box. And black boxes are dangerous, especially in tightly regulated industries like finance, healthcare or infrastructure.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="using-ai-in-qa-without-compromising-quality">Using AI in QA without compromising quality</h2> <p>There’s no question that AI tools can help QA teams move faster. Writing test cases, automating repetitive checks, and generating documentation are all areas where AI can reduce friction and free up time. But relying on these tools without human oversight is risky — especially when there’s no system in place to track what was generated, who approved it or whether it has been validated.</p> <p>Human review remains essential. Every AI-written test case, script or bug report must be checked by someone with the experience to spot errors and ask the right questions. Accountability must be clearly assigned — not just for the test execution, but for the outputs of any AI-assisted work. If a mistake is made, someone must be responsible for fixing it, and more importantly, understanding why it happened.</p> <p>And beyond people, the team also needs the right tools. Managing QA in spreadsheets, chat threads or sticky notes isn’t enough when AI starts to touch more parts of the process. There needs to be structure — a system that captures what was tested, how it was tested, who reviewed it and what the outcomes were. Without that infrastructure, AI will only add noise to an already complex process.</p> <p>This risk is especially high with AI-driven testing. If someone simply asked an agent to “go test the app” and later reports that “it works,” you’re left with no clear ownership — and no way to verify what was actually done. When something breaks, you need to know who ran the test, how it was created and whether it was ever reviewed. Without that level of traceability and responsibility, it’s impossible to enforce quality. And when bugs slip through, there’s no one to hold accountable — just a vague AI trail and a broken build.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-as-an-unreliable-booster">AI as an unreliable booster</h2> <p>Using AI in QA gives teams what could be called unreliable productivity. It speeds things up, but doesn’t guarantee quality. The time saved can be valuable — but only if it’s reinvested into deeper validation, more exploratory testing and stronger processes overall.</p> <p>AI is not a replacement for human testers. It’s a tool — and like any tool, it can be dangerous in the wrong hands. The right way to use it is with clear policies, transparent systems and a strong culture of accountability. That’s how teams can gain the benefits of AI without falling into the traps.</p> <p>For high-stakes products and environments where trust is everything, there’s no room for blind faith. You need to know, not just assume, that your software works. And that’s something no AI can do alone.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Inside Jack Henry’s bold-but-balanced AI revolution]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4133475/inside-jack-henrys-bold-but-balanced-ai-revolution.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4133475/inside-jack-henrys-bold-but-balanced-ai-revolution.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Figuring out how AI fits into enterprises can feel like a full-time job in itself. No surprise then that 72% of CEOs are the main decision makers on AI–double from a year ago, according to recent Boston Consulting Group <a href="https://www.bcg.com/press/15january2026-as-ai-investments-surge-ceos-take-lead" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">research</a>.</p> <p>At Jack Henry, the honor of leading AI strategy falls to Chief Data Officer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/keith-fulton-jh/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Keith Fulton</a>, who oversees AI deployment for a financial technology firm that boasts $2.4 billion in annual revenue. Since joining the 50-year-old company 15 months ago, Fulton has been rolling out AI solutions for 7,200-plus employees, as well as for the 7,400 banks and credit unions Jack Henry counts as customers.</p> <aside class="sidebar">
<h3 id="cio-100-leadership-live-atlanta">CIO 100 Leadership Live Atlanta</h3> <p>Join Keith and other IT leaders on March 5, 2026 at The Westin Buckhead Atlanta for a day of candid conversations on innovation, talent retention, and real-world digital transformation strategies.</p> <p><a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio-100-leadership-live-atlanta/?utm_source=db&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=CIOATL_foundry_article" target="new" rel="nofollow">Register now!</a></p> <p>Learn more: <a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio-100-leadership-live-atlanta/agenda/" target="new" rel="nofollow">Agenda</a> | <a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio-100-leadership-live-atlanta/speakers/" target="new" rel="nofollow">Speakers</a> | <a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio-100-leadership-live-atlanta/awards/" target="new" rel="nofollow">Awards</a></p> </aside><p>The company has approved over 100 AI tools for internal use, including everything from Microsoft Copilot 365, as well as AI capabilities in ServiceNow help desk software and AI programming tools, such as Claude Code and GitHub Copilot.</p> <p>“We’ve seen big productivity gains from that,” Fulton says, adding that employees can serve clients more effectively.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">AI, served responsibly bold and balanced</h2> <p>Applied with care and precision, AI affords fintech companies huge opportunities to foster competitive differentiation for their customers.</p> <p>In 2026 Fulton expects Jack Henry will turbocharge AI development and deployment “to get these magical capabilities into the hands of our bankers.” One promising AI feature includes real-time translation in Jack Henry’s customer service chatroom, which supports more than 70 languages. How it works: a customer might type a question in Spanish, which will be translated into English for an American banker to read and respond to.</p> <p>As he oversees such capabilities, Fulton is following Jack Henry’s philosophy of being “responsibly bold and balanced.” This includes offering toggle switches for AI features that customers can choose to use–or not. Some customers might use all of them, some or none. Giving the customer the control of choice is what matters most.</p> <p>“AI is the tech revolution of a lifetime, it seems clear, and we need to be ‘bold’ to take advantage of it ourselves and help our clients leverage it as well,” Fulton says. “But our financial clients are very risk averse—mistakes can be super costly and regulators don’t like finding them. So, it’s incumbent on us to also be ‘responsible.’ The ‘balancing’ act between these two mandates is where the exciting innovation is for our company.”</p> <p>Governance is a top priority for financial services firms operating in a highly regulated space–and AI, with its attendant hallucinations and other gaffes, presents its own special challenge.</p> <p>To that end, Jack Henry employs a cross-functional governance team that includes staff from Fulton’s team and IT, HR legal and other business units to help determine how to best support employees and customers with AI.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a>Balancing work, life servant leadership and culture change</h2> <p>While shepherding AI at Jack Henry is Fulton’s chief remit, he feels a strong obligation to help aspiring IT leaders looking to navigate the bureaucratic gauntlet to reach the upper corporate crust that is the vaunted C-suite.</p> <p>Fulton began his career as a programmer out of college and worked his way up with hard work and technical chops. The skills that Fulton leverages to manage large teams today are broader and deeper than the coding skills that helped him land the CDO role.</p> <p>Out went the 1s and 0s of coding. In came everything from financial forecasts and budget planning to organizational design, not to mention collaboration with peers from other divisions and presenting and selling ideas to upper management. All of these tasks are very different from coding, let alone IT architecture.</p> <p>Fulton will share key lessons from his book, “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Maxing-Out-most-yourself-your/dp/B0DLB56Y9Y#:~:text=MAXING%20OUT%20uses%20unconventional%20lessons,your%20own%20boss%2C%20how%20to" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Maxing Out: How to Get the Most out of Yourself and Your Team</a>,” at the <a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio-100-leadership-live-atlanta/?utm_source=db&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=CIOATL_foundry_article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">CIO 100 Leadership Live Atlanta</a> event in March.</p> <p>Topics will include the importance of creating work-life balance. “You can’t check out at 5:01 p.m. and be a good teammate for your people or be dependable for your boss,” Fulton says, adding that being dependable for family is also a top priority.</p> <p>Fulton will also discuss the importance of cultivating trust across team members, peers and vendors. This was especially challenging for a no-nonsense developer like Fulton.</p> <p>“As the teams kept growing, I couldn’t even know what they were all coding! I had to learn to trust them and delegate the work that I was best at, to make time for the management work I was learning.”</p> <p><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/303848/what-is-servant-leadership-a-philosophy-for-people-first-leadership.html">Servant leadership</a>, including how to be a better leader for and coax more out of their teams, is another talking topic. Fulton will also tackle <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/191000/5-myths-and-realities-of-it-culture-change.html">culture change</a>, a frightening theme for people averse to too much disruption.</p> <p>“These are some of the dilemmas I’ve wrestled with over the past 10 years of my career,” says Fulton, who also dispenses these nuggets of advice on <a href="https://maxingout.substack.com/?utm_source=global-search" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Substack</a> in articles titled “Just Give Me the Damn Ball” and “Deck Chairs on the Titanic.”</p>
</div></div></div>
</div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Ferran Urgelés (Boehringer Ingelheim): “Hacer las simulaciones de manera digital nos permite tomar muchísima más velocidad”]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135729/ferran-urgeles-boehringer-ingelheim-hacer-las-simulaciones-de-manera-digital-nos-permite-tomar-muchisima-mas-velocidad.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135729/ferran-urgeles-boehringer-ingelheim-hacer-las-simulaciones-de-manera-digital-nos-permite-tomar-muchisima-mas-velocidad.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>En los últimos años, <strong>la industria farmacéutica ha abrazado el uso de inteligencia artificial</strong>: su potencial en el <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4102962/la-industria-farmaceutica-abraza-la-inteligencia-artificial.html">desarrollo de nuevos fármacos</a> ha posibilitado que las grandes farmas la integren en la parte de investigación, además de habilitar nuevas empresas con esta herramienta —en sus distintas versiones— en el foco. Sin embargo, la aplicación de nuevas tecnologías en este sector va mucho más allá de la clave inteligente. Así lo explica <strong>Ferran Urgelés, director de TI de Boehringer España y del <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1316121/boehringer-invierte-13-millones-de-euros-en-digitalizar-su-hub-tecnologico-en-barcelona.html">centro global de TI que la farmacéutica tiene en Barcelona</a>, que ya emplea a más de 390 profesionales.</strong> El directivo, en la casa desde hace más de 18 años, desgrana la evolución tecnológica de una de las multinacionales del sector más relevantes del mundo, cuya actividad se enfoca en la investigación, el desarrollo y la comercialización de fármacos dirigidos tanto a la salud humana como a la animal, así como en la fabricación biofarmacéutica; un gigante que sigue haciendo gala de su carácter familiar, pero ya emplea a más de 50.000 profesionales y opera en más de 130 mercados a nivel mundial, entre los que se encuentra España.</p> <p>“Muchas de las cosas que llamamos inteligencia artificial ya existían, ya las hacíamos”, señala. “Al final trabajas con información, con datos, con los que haces procesos, y hay muchas cosas que ya puedes automatizar”. Es aquí donde pone el foco. “<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4033494/boehringer-ingelheim-un-viaje-digital-con-foco-en-el-dato.html">La revolución en los últimos años han sido los datos</a>, la gran cantidad de datos que tenemos y cómo los podemos procesar para obtener patrones, predicciones, etc. y leer esos datos y obtener todo el valor que podamos. Sí que es verdad que a lo que llamamos hoy en día inteligencia artificial nos está ayudando a que todo el mundo tenga acceso a temas de complejidad, que antes necesitabas un conocimiento y una experiencia”. “Es un progreso, porque nos permite ser más eficientes, más productivos”, apunta Urgelés, quien también advierte sobre la necesidad de revisar el trabajo de la IA para evitar sesgos o limitaciones.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="proyectos-de-ti-en-boehringer-ingelheim">Proyectos de TI en Boehringer Ingelheim</h2> <p>Urgelés reconoce que ahora mismo los esfuerzos de su departamento se están centrando en una rama. “Lo primordial es la <strong>investigación</strong>”, explica, “para poder continuar aportando soluciones a los pacientes, que tengan una mejor calidad de vida y mayor expectativa de vida”. Con este fin emplean en la farma tecnología que aprovecha ese recurso esencial, los datos, sobre el que se articulan varias claves. Por un lado, aplicando tecnología puntera de procesamiento se pueden encontrar patrones, afinando hacia una medicina “mucho más personalizada, más eficiente y efectiva”. “<strong>Estamos trabajando <em>in silico</em>, haciendo las simulaciones de manera digital</strong>, lo cual nos permite tomar muchísima más velocidad”. Si los tiempos desde que se encuentra un posible tratamiento hasta que este llega al mercado suelen ser de unos 10 años, el uso de herramientas inteligentes ayuda a acelerar el proceso de forma significativa, para que “se beneficien los pacientes de una manera mucho más temprana”.</p> <p>Otro de los ejes de aplicación tecnológica es en <strong>ensayos clínicos</strong>, con procesos de gestión complejos que se pueden ver agilizados gracias a la buena gestión de datos. Urgelés profundiza en uno de los proyectos concretos de la compañía: su sistema One Medicine Platform, que permite gestionar todo el proceso a través de una única plataforma. “Antes teníamos múltiples plataformas que se tenían que conectar entre sí, lo cual es una ineficiencia. Podía haber incluso solapamientos, repeticiones, etc”. Con su nuevo sistema se avanza en la agilización de procesos y la eficiencia en el manejo de datos, facilitando la colaboración con otros agentes de salud, como las administraciones públicas o las aseguradoras. “Es importante que trabajemos conjuntamente para entender cómo podemos ayudar mejor a los pacientes”, enfatiza. Este proceso ayuda a tener una visión y un conocimiento global. “Creo que los datos y la colaboración nos puedan permitir ser mucho más eficaces y que todos estos tratamientos que existen se pongan en marcha de una manera mucho más eficiente”.</p> <figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p><strong><em>“La revolución en los últimos años han sido los datos, la gran cantidad que tenemos y cómo los podemos procesar para obtener todo el valor”</em></strong></p></blockquote></figure> <p>Otra de sus iniciativas, en marcha desde hace cinco años, es su Dataland. “Apostamos por tener una plataforma única de toda la compañía, globalmente, de todos los departamentos, donde tener […] todos los datos de una manera catalogada, accesibles”. Esto no implica que se pueda usar toda la información: se han establecido unos términos de intercambio que marcan cuáles son críticos y precisan que se valide su uso de forma estricta. “Pero hay datos, como de ventas mensuales o anuales, que no son tan críticos y que están en el catálogo, y se puede pedir el acceso”. Un sistema de gobernanza de datos compartidos que supone un impulso para su trabajo: “<strong>Al conectar los datos entre sí se</strong> <strong>multiplica el valor de lo que estos pueden hacer</strong>”. Hace años, explica, estos procesos de conexión eran más dificultosos: cada departamento (finanzas, producción, investigación, ensayos clínicos…) tenían sus propios datos. Tenerlos organizados y disponibles a través de esta plataforma les ha dado, insiste, un nuevo valor.</p> <p>Lo explica con otro proyecto vinculado: Opex Prime, en el que, gracias a la revisión de los datos de las plantas de producción, se ha conseguido optimizar el desempeño, con incrementos en la efectividad de entre el 10 y el 12%.</p> <p>El uso de datos en farma también se extiende a otros campos, comunes a otras industrias, como la seguridad en la cadena de producción u otras labores de administración o facturación. “<strong>La seguridad de la producción es, en el mundo farmacéutico, clave</strong>. Todos los datos de la inteligencia artificial nos permiten también ser más ágiles en hacer estos chequeos y comprobaciones de calidad, que algunas requieren mucho de esfuerzo”, resume.</p> <p>Urgelés cita también el uso de sistemas de proveedores externos, como Servicenow, SAP o Viva, que van incorporando tecnología de IA para automatizar tareas entre el personal. Reconoce que es necesaria también el trabajo en gestión del cambio y de mentalidad de transformación entre la plantilla, de “cómo podemos trabajar de una manera más eficiente”, de integrar herramientas de IA para no verlas como “una amenaza, sino todo lo contrario”. “<strong>Todas estas tecnologías nos pueden ayudar a gestionar mejor nuestra carga de trabajo, a tener más tiempo para cosas más estratégicas, en las que tenemos que ser más creativos, que pensar, que colaborar</strong>”, resume.</p> <p>Desde el departamento de TI de Boehringer Ingelheim se gestionan también otras iniciativas, como su Hackathon, que en 2025 cumplió siete años, a través del cual dan la oportunidad a estudiantes o a profesionales de enfrentarse a retos concretos de su sector. Por ejemplo, en esta edición se planteó un desafío para ayudar a profesionales de centros de salud primarios a estar más presentes con sus pacientes, en un entorno de presión asistencial elevada. Entre las 150 personas que participaron —más de 30 equipos—, hubo propuestas muy interesantes, destaca. Entre los objetivos, estar en contacto con el talento tecnológico y científico y darles a conocer los retos reales. Han llegado a incorporar a su plantilla profesionales procedentes de este evento.</p> <figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p><em><strong>“Hay que estar siempre atento a qué hay en esa ‘caja negra’, controlarla y tener especialistas”, incide el portavoz, “para que no caigamos en posibles sesgos que no estamos controlando”</strong></em></p></blockquote></figure> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="los-desafios-en-gestion-tecnologica">Los desafíos en gestión tecnológica</h2> <p>El responsable de TI de Boehringer Ingelheim define dos grandes retos cuando se trata de liderar el departamento de TI en una farma. En primer lugar, llama a no “<strong>embriagarnos de tecnología</strong>”: “Cuando hablas en el ámbito de la tecnología, puede haber la tentación de poner la tecnología en el centro”, desarrolla, a emprender iniciativas solo porque hay una determinada herramienta de moda y se quiere utilizar. Hay que definir, primero, “qué necesitamos como farma, cuál es nuestra prioridad, cuál es nuestra estrategia, cómo ayudamos al paciente. Y a partir de ahí buscamos el cómo”, profundiza. “Pero no al revés”. “Esto es no es algo nuevo, es algo continuo, pero que siempre tenemos que tener en mente”.</p> <p>“<strong>Otro tema que en farma tenemos muy presente es la ética, evitar que se puedan dar sesgos</strong>”. Urgelés alude a cómo históricamente se han producido sesgos en ensayos clínicos y lo lleva al terreno de TI. “Hay que tener cuidado también con la tecnología. Pensamos que le pedimos lo que queremos hacer y nos lo da, pero hay que estar siempre atento a qué hay en esa ‘caja negra’, controlarla y tener especialistas”, incide, “para que no caigamos en posibles sesgos que no estamos controlando”.</p> <p>Esto no quita que haya otros retos, incide. Por ejemplo, al trabajar con datos sensibles, la ciberseguridad es una prioridad. “Tenemos datos que son muy sensibles, [con] la máxima clasificación en el nivel de protección de datos, y nos tomamos muy en serio cómo protegerlos”. La compañía cuenta en su sede de San Cugat con un centro global de ciberseguridad para enfrentar los problemas en este terreno, que se vincula con otras unidades para dotar así de una cobertura global 24 horas.</p> <p>Desde una visión más global, Urgelés considera que “en general, el mundo farma hace un esfuerzo grande en utilizar la tecnología para sus objetivos, que al final son el beneficio del paciente. Otra cosa es que todas esas transformaciones tienen su complejidad y requieren sus tiempos”, valora. Pero termina en clave optimista: “<strong>Hay mucha, mucha voluntad de colaboración entre las farmacéuticas</strong>”, destaca. “Veo muchas iniciativas donde hay colaboración, y yo creo que eso que eso es importante para realmente llegar a progresos destacables en beneficio del paciente”.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[칼럼 | 데이터센터 투자 열풍이 현실을 왜곡하고 있다]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135695/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0%ec%84%bc%ed%84%b0-%ed%88%ac%ec%9e%90-%ec%97%b4%ed%92%8d%ec%9d%b4-%ed%98%84%ec%8b%a4%ec%9d%84-%ec%99%9c%ea%b3%a1%ed%95%98%ea%b3%a0-%ec%9e%88%eb%8b%a4.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135695/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0%ec%84%bc%ed%84%b0-%ed%88%ac%ec%9e%90-%ec%97%b4%ed%92%8d%ec%9d%b4-%ed%98%84%ec%8b%a4%ec%9d%84-%ec%99%9c%ea%b3%a1%ed%95%98%ea%b3%a0-%ec%9e%88%eb%8b%a4.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>이야기는 대개 그렇듯, 지평선이 비현실적으로 넓어 보이는 작은 농촌 마을에서 조용히 시작된다. 마을 도시계획위원회는 탄 커피 냄새와 낡은 카펫 향이 뒤섞인 소박한 회의실에 모여, 곧 이 마을이 현대 경제의 수혜자가 될 것이라는 소식을 듣는다. 마을 경계 안에 데이터센터 10곳이 새로 들어선다는 계획이다. 한두 곳이 아니라 무려 10곳이다. 파워포인트 화면에는 건설 일자리, 일부 상시 고용, ‘지역사회 투자’, 그리고 지역을 탈바꿈시킬 새로운 세수 기반이라는 약속이 화려하게 제시된다.</p> <p>물론 일자리는 생긴다. 그러나 마을의 근간을 되살릴 수준의 일자리는 아니다. 데이터센터는 완공 이후 수천 명을 고용하지 않는다. 운영 자동화 수준에 따라 수십 명, 경우에 따라 그보다 적은 인력만 필요하다. 진짜 영향은 사람이 아니라 전력, 부지, 송전 용량, 그리고 물에 있다. 소규모 전력망에 대형 시설 10곳이 한꺼번에 들어서면, 수요 급증은 울타리 안에만 머물지 않는다. 그 여파는 외부로 확산된다. 전력회사는 변전소를 증설하고 송전선을 보강하며 차세대 설비를 도입해야 한다. 이 투자에 필요한 자금도 조달해야 한다. 시간이 지나면서 그 비용의 상당 부분을 누가 부담하게 될까. 결국 지역 전기요금 납부자가 인상된 요금을 떠안거나, 다른 인프라 사업이 조용히 뒤로 밀리는 방식으로 영향을 받게 된다.</p> <p>물 문제는 종종 그 다음 단계에서 불거진다. 운영사가 ‘물 효율이 높다’고 주장하더라도, 냉각은 결국 냉각이며 대규모 냉각에는 반드시 비용이 따른다. 일부 시설은 증발식 시스템을, 일부는 폐쇄형 순환 시스템을 사용한다. 또 어떤 곳은 보도자료에서 인상적으로 보이는 혁신 기술을 내세운다. 그 사이 마을 농부는 지하수 수위와 일기예보를 같은 무게로 바라본다. 이제는 가뭄과 싸우는 것에 더해, 갈증이 공학 도면으로 계산되는 산업과 물을 놓고 경쟁해야 하기 때문이다.</p> <p>현장에서 마주하는 데이터센터 붐의 실체는 이렇다. 화려한 약속을 내세우지만, 그 이면에는 매우 물리적인 제약이 단단히 자리하고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9e%90%eb%b3%b8-%ec%a7%80%ec%b6%9c%ec%9d%b4%eb%9d%bc%eb%8a%94-%ec%83%88%eb%a1%9c%ec%9a%b4-%ec%8b%a0%eb%85%90">자본 지출이라는 새로운 신념</h2> <p>자주 공개적으로 언급되지는 않지만, 분명한 사실이 있다. 첨단 기술 기업이 데이터센터에 막대한 자금을 쏟아붓는 이유는 시장이 그런 행동에 보상을 주기 때문이다. 자본적 지출은 일종의 기업 신호로 자리 잡았다. 실적 발표 자리에서 “공격적으로 투자하고 있다”는 발언은 곧 “우리가 이기고 있다”는 의미로 받아들여진다. 그 투자가 낙관적인 전망에 근거했거나, 심할 경우 희망적 사고와 크게 다르지 않은 예측에 기반하더라도 분위기는 크게 달라지지 않는다.</p> <p>이 흐름을 주도하는 것은 클라우드 서비스 제공업체다. 이들은 충분한 규모와 현금 흐름을 갖추고 있으며, 월가가 선호하는 서사도 확보했다. 수요는 폭발적으로 증가하고, 공급은 제한적이며, 기회를 선점할 만큼 빠르게 인프라를 구축할 수 있는 주체는 거대 기업뿐이라는 이야기다. 이런 서사가 자리를 잡으면, 지출 자체가 하나의 증거로 작용한다. 숫자가 클수록 기업은 더 진지해 보인다. 기업이 진지해 보일수록 투자자는 그 기업이 자신들이 모르는 무언가를 알고 있다고 추정한다. 이는 자신감처럼 보이지만 실제로는 관성처럼 작동하는 자기 강화적 순환 구조다.</p> <p>여기에 최근 몇 년간 이어진 수십억 달러 규모의 기술 기업 간 계약이 더해진다. 하드웨어 선구매 약정, 장기 GPU 공급 계약, ‘전략적 파트너십’, 용량 예약, 그리고 내부 진입을 노리는 수많은 벤더 생태계가 겹겹이 쌓였다. 이러한 계약은 단순한 운영상의 결정이 아니다. 시장을 향한 일종의 무대 연출에 가깝다. 경영진이 구체적으로 제시할 수 있는 사례를 제공하고, 미래가 이미 정해진 것처럼 들리게 만든다. A사가 B사와 대규모 금액의 계약을 체결했다면, 미래는 이미 도래했으며 지금 참여하지 않으면 뒤처질 것이라는 메시지를 던지는 셈이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%b9%85%ed%85%8c%ed%81%ac-%eb%b0%9c%ec%a0%84%ec%86%8c%eb%a5%bc-%ec%a7%93%eb%8b%a4">빅테크, 발전소를 짓다</h2> <p>이 문제는 단지 서버로 가득 찬 건물을 몇 채 더 짓는 데 그치지 않는다. AI 수요의 특성은 기존의 계산식을 바꿔놓는다. 대규모 학습과 추론에는 고밀도 연산 자원, 특수 목적 하드웨어, 그리고 점점 더 복잡해지는 네트워킹 기술이 필요하다. 그 결과 단위 면적당 전력 소비는 증가하고, 랙당 발열은 커지며, 전력망에 가해지는 부담도 커진다. 하이퍼스케일러와 주요 사업자는 산업 플레이어가 합리적으로 대응하듯 병목을 통제하려는 방향으로 움직이고 있다.</p> <p>병목이 전력이라면, 최소한 재무제표상 해법은 전력을 선점하는 것이다. 장기 전력 구매 계약을 체결하고, 전력회사와 협력하며, 송전망에 투자하고, 전용 발전 설비를 직접 구축하거나 지원하는 움직임이 나타나는 배경이다. 이를 발전소, 에너지 캠퍼스, 혹은 인접 발전 자산이라고 부를 수 있다. 명칭은 중요하지 않다. 핵심은 의도다. 하이퍼스케일러는 예측 가능하고 확장 가능한 전력을 확보하려 한다. 매출 성장 스토리가 예측 가능하고 확장 가능한 연산 능력에 달려 있기 때문이다.</p> <p>전략은 단순하다. 수요가 급증하면 가격과 가동률이 상승하고, 먼저 인프라를 구축한 기업이 수익을 거둔다. 용량을 확보하고 이를 채운 뒤, 희소 자원에 프리미엄을 부과하며 향후 10년간의 디지털 확장을 타고 간다는 구상이다. 과거 여러 인프라 붐에서 반복됐던 전략과 크게 다르지 않다. 다만 이번에는 인프라가 실리콘과 전자로 구성돼 있으며, ‘전환’이라는 언어로 포장돼 있다는 점이 다를 뿐이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%88%98%ec%9a%94%eb%a5%bc-%ec%98%88%ec%b8%a1%ed%95%9c%eb%8b%a4%eb%8a%94-%ea%b2%83">수요를 예측한다는 것</h2> <p>이제 컨퍼런스장에서 꺼내기 불편한 이야기를 해보자. 필자 개인적인 견해로는, 클라우드 사업자를 포함한 상당수 첨단 기술 기업이 감당하기 어려운 수준까지 나아가고 있다. 이들이 인프라를 구축할 능력이 없어서가 아니다. 자금을 조달할 역량이 부족해서도 아니다. 문제는 예측을 물리 법칙처럼 다루고 있다는 점이다.</p> <p>3년 혹은 5년 뒤 AI 수요가 어느 정도일지 정확히 아는 사람은 없다. 우리는 트렌드와 채택 곡선, 신제품 출시를 관찰하며 기대를 키운다. 그러나 수요는 단순한 관심이나 화제성과는 다르다. 수요에는 예산, 거버넌스, 시스템 통합이 포함된다. 수요가 발생하면 보안 검토, 조달 절차, 데이터 준비 상태 점검 등 수많은 작은 마찰이 뒤따른다. 이러한 요소는 결국 하나의 큰 제약으로 이어진다. 기업은 어떤 기술이든 도입 속도가 느리며, AI 역시 예외가 아니다.</p> <p>기업의 기술 채택은 벤더의 선언만으로 이뤄지지 않는다. 기술이 기존 운영 모델에 부합하고, 리스크가 충분히 이해되며, 데이터 접근성이 확보되고, 법무 검토를 통과하고, 사업 타당성이 검증되며, 결과에 책임질 주체가 명확해질 때 비로소 도입이 이뤄진다. 이 과정에는 시간이 필요하다. 모든 기업이 전력 질주하듯 AI를 도입할 것이라는 전제하에 인프라를 구축하는 것은, 대부분 조직이 조깅하듯 움직이고 더 많은 조직이 걷는 속도로 변화해왔다는 수십 년의 경험을 간과하는 셈이다.</p> <p>비용이라는 현실도 있다. 의미 있는 운영 성과를 내는 AI 시스템은 연산 자원, 데이터 이동, 스토리지, 도구, 그리고 이를 책임감 있게 운영할 인력까지 고려하면 기존 시스템 대비 5~10배의 비용이 들 수 있다. 이는 단순한 계산상의 오차 범위가 아니다. 전혀 다른 지출 범주에 가깝다. 대부분 기업의 예산은 무한하지 않다. 실험과 파일럿 프로젝트를 거쳐 선별적으로 배포하는 방식이 일반적일 가능성이 크다. 모든 기업이 갑자기 하이퍼스케일 수준의 대규모 AI 사용을 지속적으로 감당할 것이라는 가정은 현실과 거리가 있다.</p> <p>그렇다면 수요가 구축 주체의 기대에 미치지 못할 경우 어떤 일이 벌어질까. 과잉 설비가 발생하고, 가격 압박이 커지며, 자산 가치가 하향 조정될 수 있다. “공격적으로 투자하고 있다”는 메시지는 어느 순간 “효율을 최적화하고 있다”는 표현으로 조용히 바뀔 가능성이 있다. 그리고 그 농촌 마을에는 단기적 과열의 장기적 결과가 남는다. 한계까지 압박받는 전력망, 정치적 쟁점으로 번진 물 문제, 그리고 약속된 최대 가동률에 한참 못 미친 채 서 있는 대형 건물들이 지역 풍경을 바꿔놓는다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Rivet Launches the Sandbox Agent SDK to Solve Agent API Fragmentation]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/rivet-agent-sandbox-sdk/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/rivet-agent-sandbox-sdk/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/rivet-agent-sandbox-sdk/en/headerimage/rivet-agent-sandbox-sdk-1771748160207.jpeg"/><p>Rivet Sandbox Agent SDK provides a universal API for coding agents, allowing developers to work with different agent runtimes like Claude Code, Codex, OpenCode, and Amp without rewriting their integration for each one. It addresses the fragmentation across agent APIs, session handling, and streaming formats that has historically made agent integrations complex and difficult to maintain.</p> <i>By Sergio De Simone</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[젯브레인, VS 코드용 ‘자바→코틀린’ 변환기 공개···코틀린 전환 지원]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135692/%ec%a0%af%eb%b8%8c%eb%a0%88%ec%9d%b8-vs-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c%ec%9a%a9-%ec%9e%90%eb%b0%94%e2%86%92%ec%bd%94%ed%8b%80%eb%a6%b0-%eb%b3%80%ed%99%98%ea%b8%b0-%ea%b3%b5%ea%b0%9c%c2%b7%c2%b7.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135692/%ec%a0%af%eb%b8%8c%eb%a0%88%ec%9d%b8-vs-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c%ec%9a%a9-%ec%9e%90%eb%b0%94%e2%86%92%ec%bd%94%ed%8b%80%eb%a6%b0-%eb%b3%80%ed%99%98%ea%b8%b0-%ea%b3%b5%ea%b0%9c%c2%b7%c2%b7.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>자바 개발자의 코틀린 도입을 확대하기 위해, 젯브레인이 마이크로소프트(MS)의 비주얼 스튜디오 코드(Visual Studio Code)용 ‘자바→코틀린’ 변환기 확장 프로그램을 공개했다. 코틀린은 오랫동안 자바의 대안 언어로 자리매김해 왔으며, 안드로이드 모바일 애플리케이션 개발 등 자바 기반 생태계 전반에서 폭넓게 활용되고 있다.</p> <p>2월 19일 공개된 이 확장 프로그램은 비주얼 스튜디오 마켓플레이스에서 내려받을 수 있다. 개발자는 컨텍스트 메뉴를 통해 개별 자바 파일을 코틀린 코드로 변환할 수 있다. 이를 통해 레거시 코드베이스를 마이그레이션하거나 프로젝트 진행 중 언어를 전환할 때 발생하는 수작업 부담을 줄일 수 있다.</p> <p>젯브레인에 따르면, 해당 확장 프로그램은 자사 IDE에 적용된 것과 동일한 기반 엔진을 사용한다. 또한 대규모 언어 모델(LLM)을 활용해 코틀린 관용구에 맞는 변환 제안을 제공한다. 개발자는 VS 코드 환경에서 한 번의 클릭으로 자바 코드를 코틀린으로 전환하고, 커밋 전에 결과를 검토할 수 있다.</p> <p>젯브레인의 코틀린 제품 관리자 알리나 돌기흐는 코틀린의 관용적 표현과 문법 요구사항을 충실히 반영하는 신뢰성 높은 변환 결과를 기대할 수 있다고 설명했다. 알리나 돌기흐는 또 많은 개발자가 다양한 프로젝트와 작업에서 VS 코드를 사용하고 있다는 점을 고려해 확장 프로그램을 개발했다고 전했다. 인텔리J IDEA가 여전히 코틀린을 위한 대표 IDE이지만, VS 코드 사용자 역시 중요한 대상이라는 판단에서다.</p> <p>이번 ‘자바→코틀린’ 변환기 확장 프로그램은 다음과 같은 설정 항목을 제공한다.</p> <p>• j2k.provider: 자바→코틀린 변환에 사용할 LLM 백엔드를 지정하는 항목이다. 기본값은 깃허브 코파일럿(GitHub Copilot)이다.<br>• j2k.model: 선택한 제공자와 함께 사용할 모델 태그를 설정하는 항목이다. 기본값은 codellama:instruct이다.<br>• j2k.ollama.baseUrl: 제공자로 올라마(Ollama)를 선택했을 때 대상 인스턴스의 기본 URL을 지정하는 항목이다.<br>• j2k.openRouter.baseUrl: 제공자로 오픈라우터(OpenRouter)를 선택했을 때 대상 인스턴스의 기본 URL을 지정하는 항목이다.<br>• j2k.apiKey: 선택한 제공자와 함께 사용할 API 키를 설정하는 항목으로, VS 코드 시크릿 저장소에 보관된다.<br></p> <p>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com<br><br></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Starting Your Career in EA]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/23/starting-your-career-in-ea/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/23/starting-your-career-in-ea/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Embarking on a career in Enterprise Architecture can feel a bit like being handed a map of a city you’ve never visited, and being told that every street, alley, and café is critical. You're then asked to solve a mystery. To put it in simple terms: starting your career in EA can be a challenge!<br>
There’s a lot to take in: frameworks, models, technologies, stakeholders, business strategies, and a universe of acronyms that seem to multiply when you’re not looking. If you’re just starting out in EA—or thinking about it—you’re probably asking yourself, “Where do I even begin?” The good news is, you’re not alone, and the journey, while complex, is also incredibly rewarding.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://eawheel.com/blog/2026/02/starting-your-career-in-ea/">Starting Your Career in EA</a> appeared first on <a href="https://eawheel.com/">EAWheel</a>.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[“채용 기준이 달라진다” AI가 뒤흔드는 IT 일자리의 현주소]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135668/%ec%b1%84%ec%9a%a9-%ea%b8%b0%ec%a4%80%ec%9d%b4-%eb%8b%ac%eb%9d%bc%ec%a7%84%eb%8b%a4-ai%ea%b0%80-%eb%92%a4%ed%9d%94%eb%93%9c%eb%8a%94-it-%ec%9d%bc%ec%9e%90%eb%a6%ac%ec%9d%98-%ed%98%84.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135668/%ec%b1%84%ec%9a%a9-%ea%b8%b0%ec%a4%80%ec%9d%b4-%eb%8b%ac%eb%9d%bc%ec%a7%84%eb%8b%a4-ai%ea%b0%80-%eb%92%a4%ed%9d%94%eb%93%9c%eb%8a%94-it-%ec%9d%bc%ec%9e%90%eb%a6%ac%ec%9d%98-%ed%98%84.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>AI가 비즈니스 전반에 깊숙이 스며들면서 IT 인력 시장도 빠른 속도로 재편되고 있다. 지난 1년 동안 IT 업계는 AI로 인한 업무 환경의 변화를 겪었다. AI는 필요한 기술 역량의 수요를 바꾸고, 일부 IT 경력 개발 과정을 재정의했으며, 거의 모든 기업에서 일상 운영 방식까지 흔들어 놓았다. IT 리더와 구성원들이 워크플로우와 프로세스에 AI를 끼워 넣는 과정에서 업무 방식 자체가 달라지고 있다는 의미다.</p> <p>최근 다시 감원 소식이 헤드라인을 장식하는 가운데, 기업은 AI를 구현·도입·보호·최적화하는 데 필요한 ‘특정 역량’ 중심으로 채용 방향을 전환하고 있다. 동시에 내부 인력을 재교육해 이런 역량을 갖추도록 만드는 전략도 병행하는 분위기다.</p> <p>2026년으로 접어들며 채용 시장의 우선순위는 IT 보안, AI/ML 통합, 데이터 분석, 거버넌스와 컴플라이언스, 소프트웨어 엔지니어링·개발, AI 거버넌스와 윤리 등으로 바뀌었다. 하지만, 기업이 찾는 역량과 지원자 이력서에 담긴 역량 사이의 격차는 여전히 크다. 빠르게 변하는 인력 시장에 대응하기 위해 IT 채용과 교육 전략이 어떻게 바뀌고 있는지, 현재 IT 일자리의 흐름을 정리했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ea%b2%bd%eb%a0%a5%eb%b3%b4%eb%8b%a4-%ea%b8%b0%ec%88%a0-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89-%ec%9a%b0%ec%84%a0%ec%9d%98-%ec%b1%84%ec%9a%a9-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0">경력보다 기술 역량 우선의 채용 확산</h2> <p>지난 1년 사이 기업은 경력·학력·배경보다 ‘기술 역량’ 자체를 우선해 채용하는 쪽으로 이동했다. 전통적인 기준이 완전히 사라진 것은 아니지만, 조직에 “지금 필요한 역량” 또는 “조직에 부족한 역량”을 정확히 채울 수 있는 인재를 찾는 데 초점을 맞추고 있다. 이는 과거라면 이력서 단계에서 걸러졌을 후보군까지 인재 풀을 넓히는 방법이 되기도 한다.</p> <p>인력 채용업체 로버트 하프(Robert Half)의 자료에 따르면, 2025년 IT 리더의 65%는 2024년보다 공석에 맞는 숙련 인력을 찾기 더 어려웠다고 답했다. 2026년 상반기에는 61%가 정규직 인력을 늘릴 계획이며, 55%는 같은 기간 계약직·임시직 채용을 확대하겠다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>로버트 하프는 지난 1년 동안 “평균 이상의 연속 성장과 꾸준한 수요”를 보인 직무로 AI/ML 엔지니어, 사이버보안 엔지니어, 데이터 분석가, 데이터 과학자, 데브옵스 엔지니어, ERP 비즈니스 분석가, IT 프로젝트 매니저, 네트워크/클라우드 엔지니어, 소프트웨어 엔지니어, 시스템 관리자 등을 꼽았다.</p> <p>또 로버트 하프가 IT 리더를 대상으로 실시한 설문에서 가장 두드러진 역량 격차를 보인 직무는 다음과 같다.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI/ML(45%)</li> <li>IT 운영 및 인프라(36%)</li> <li>IT 거버넌스 및 컴플라이언스(25%)</li> <li>클라우드 아키텍처 및 운영(24%)</li> <li>데이터 엔지니어링 및 분석(22%)</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-%eb%a6%ac%ed%84%b0%eb%9f%ac%ec%8b%9c-%ea%b3%b5%ea%b3%a0-70-%ec%9d%b4%ec%83%81-%ec%a6%9d%ea%b0%80%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89%eb%8f%84-%ea%b8%89">‘AI 리터러시’ 공고 70% 이상 증가…에이전트 역량도 급부상</h2> <p>AI 관련 수요는 계속 증가하고 있다. 링크드인(LinkedIn)의 ‘AI 노동시장 업데이트’ 보고서에 따르면, AI 리터러시를 요구하는 채용 공고는 전년 대비 70% 이상 증가했다. 2025년 가장 빠르게 성장한 AI 역량으로는 AI 에이전트가 꼽혔다. 프롬프트 엔지니어링 같은 AI 역량 수요도 IT를 넘어 마케팅, 영업, 디자인 직무로 확장되고 있다.</p> <p>링크드인은 2025년에 성장 폭이 컸던 AI 역량으로 마이크로소프트 애저 AI 스튜디오, AI 생산성, 스프링 AI, 커스텀 GPT, 프롬프트 플로우, LLM옵스, AI 전략, 오픈AI API, 자동화 피처 엔지니어링 등을 제시했다.</p> <p>2023년과 비교하면 결이 달라졌다는 것을 알 수 있다. 당시에는 모델 학습, 하이퍼파라미터 최적화 등 ‘AI 도구를 만드는 데 필요한 역량’이 빠르게 성장했지만, 불과 몇 년 만에 기업들은 ‘AI 도구를 최대한 활용할 수 있는 인력’과 ‘도구 개발을 뒷받침할 인력’을 함께 채용·육성하는 방향으로 무게중심을 옮기고 있다.</p> <p>AI가 기술 작업을 더 많이 떠맡을수록 소프트 스킬의 중요성이 커진다는 분석도 나온다. 로버트 하프에 따르면, IT 리더는 AI 기반 솔루션을 감독·가이드하기 위해 다음과 같은 역량을 갖춘 인재를 찾고 있다.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>비판적 사고 및 문제 해결(72%)</li> <li>적응력 및 지속적 학습(69%)</li> <li>창의성 및 혁신(65%)</li> <li>커뮤니케이션(36%)</li> <li>감성 지능(22%)</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="it-%ec%97%b0%eb%b4%89-%ea%b0%95%ec%84%b8-%ec%86%8d%ec%97%90-%ec%a0%84%eb%ac%b8-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89%ec%97%90-%ed%94%84%eb%a6%ac%eb%af%b8%ec%97%84%ea%b9%8c%ec%a7%80">IT 연봉 강세 속에 전문 역량에 프리미엄까지</h2> <p>로버트 하프는 2026년 IT 직군 평균 연봉이 1.6% 상승할 것으로 전망했다. 직무별로는 AI/ML 엔지니어와 데이터 사이언티스트 연봉이 4.1% 오르고, 소프트웨어·애플리케이션 개발 직군은 2.3%, 컨설팅·엔터프라이즈 시스템 직군과 데이터 엔지니어링·분석·리포팅 직무는 1.7% 상승할 것으로 내다봤다.</p> <p>또 IT 리더의 87%는 “전문 역량을 보유한 후보자에게는 그렇지 않은 후보자보다 더 높은 연봉을 제시하는 것이 일반적”이라고 답했으며, 52%는 “해당 역할이 핵심 비즈니스 니즈를 지원한다면, 더 높은 초봉을 두고 협상할 의향이 있다”라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>다만 69%는 지원자의 보상 기대치를 따라잡는 데 대한 부담을 드러냈다. 이에 대응해 초봉 인상뿐 아니라 복지·혜택 확대, 채용 공고에 연봉 범위를 명시하는 방식 등을 준비하고 있다.</p> <p>연봉 프리미엄이 붙을 수 있는 역량은 다음과 같다.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI/머신러닝, 데이터 사이언스</li> <li>사이버보안</li> <li>클라우드 컴퓨팅, 클라우드 보안, 클라우드 아키텍처</li> <li>소프트웨어 및 애플리케이션 개발</li> <li>데이터 분석, BI, 리포팅</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%82%ac%eb%ac%b4%ec%8b%a4-%eb%b3%b5%ea%b7%80-%ec%a0%95%ec%b1%85%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c-%eb%b6%88%eb%a7%8c%ea%b3%bc-%ea%b0%88%eb%93%b1-%ec%a6%9d%ea%b0%80">사무실 복귀 정책으로 불만과 갈등 증가</h2> <p>IT 관리 솔루션 기업 아이반티(Ivanti) 보고서에 따르면, IT 전문가의 64%는 지난 12개월 동안 ‘사무실 복귀’ 압박을 경험했다고 답했다. 엄격한 사무실 복귀 의무화뿐 아니라 경영진의 권고 형태까지 포함한 수치다. 유연성을 중시하는 흐름 속에서 사무실 복귀가 인재 이탈과 사기 저하를 촉발할 수 있다는 우려도 커지고 있다.</p> <p>기업이 사무실 복귀를 추진하는 이유로는 생산성 개선(41%)과 더 강한 기업 문화(37%)가 주로 언급됐다. 사이버보안을 이유로 드는 사례도 많지만, IT 전문가의 절반 이상(56%)은 보안만으로 엄격한 RTO를 정당화하기에는 부족하다고 봤다. 또 경영진이 RTO로 생산성을 높이려는 것과 달리, 근로자의 82%는 재택근무가 사무실 근무와 “동등하거나 더 생산적”이라고 답했다.</p> <p>그럼에도 더 높은 연봉이 제시된다면 사무실 복귀 의향도 높아진다는 조사 결과도 나왔다. 로버트 하프에 따르면, 직원의 75%는 연봉이 인상된다면 사무실 복귀 의사가 높아진다고 답했고, 이 가운데 69%는 “10% 이상”의 인상이 있어야 고려하겠다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>사무실 복귀 이후의 ‘유지’도 과제로 떠올랐다. 아이반티 설문 응답자의 48%는 ‘리센티즘(resenteeism)’을 느낀다고 답했다. 일에 대한 불만이 크지만 여러 이유로 회사를 떠나지 않고 버티는 상태를 뜻한다. 37%는 ‘프리젠티즘(presenteeism)’을 한다고 말했다. 생산성을 내기 위해서가 아니라 ‘출근해 일하는 모습을 보이기 위해’ 사무실에 나오는 현상이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai%ea%b0%80-it-%ec%a7%81%eb%ac%b4-%ec%a7%80%ed%98%95-%ec%9e%ac%ed%8e%b8%ec%97%85%ec%8a%a4%ed%82%ac%eb%a7%81%ec%9d%b4-%ec%b5%9c%eb%8c%80-%ea%b3%bc%ec%a0%9c">AI가 IT 직무 지형 재편…업스킬링이 ‘최대 과제’</h2> <p>세계경제포럼(WEF)의 ‘일자리의 미래 보고서 2025’는 고용주 60%가 2030년까지 AI가 비즈니스를 변화시킬 것으로 예상한다고 밝혔다. 또 고용주 63%가 역량 격차를 “비즈니스 전환의 최대 장벽”으로 본다고 했으며, 85%는 직원 업스킬링에 우선순위를 두겠다고 답했다. 역량 확보 방식과 관련해 70%는 신규 채용할 계획이고, 40%는 역량 중복으로 인력을 축소할 계획이라고 답했다. 50%는 “축소되는 역할에서 성장하는 역할로 인력을 전환”할 계획이라고 답했다.</p> <p>현장에서도 직원들의 AI 활용은 빠르게 확산 중이다. 채용 플랫폼 인디드(Indeed)의 ‘Workforce Insights Report 2025’에 따르면, 응답자의 80%는 생성형 AI를 활용해 하루에 최소 1시간을 절감한다고 답했다. 또 기술직 종사자의 37%는 지난 2년 동안 생성형 AI 때문에 자신의 역할이 “재정의되거나 재구성됐다”고 밝혔다. AI가 단순·반복 업무를 더 많이 대체하면서, 기업은 ‘AI 시대의 직무’에 맞게 IT 역할을 다시 설계하고 있다.</p> <p>이에 따라 조직은 프롬프트 엔지니어링, AI 기초 등 직원들이 AI를 효과적으로 활용해 생산성과 효율을 높일 수 있는 교육 과정을 늘리는 추세다. 업스킬링은 ‘AI 워크슬롭(AI workslop)’ 같은 함정도 피하는 데 도움이 된다. AI 워크슬롭은 직원이 AI를 부적절하게 사용해 결과물 품질이 떨어지고, 결국 동료가 AI 생성 콘텐츠를 다시 고치거나 편집하느라 일이 더 늘어나는 상황을 가리킨다. AI 투자 성과를 극대화하려면, 기업 내부에서 교육과 업스킬링 기회를 꾸준히 제공하는 전략이 중요해질 전망이다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[파일럿은 성공, 확장은 실패···전문가들이 본 ‘에이전틱 AI의 생존 조건’]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135647/%ed%8c%8c%ec%9d%bc%eb%9f%bf%ec%9d%80-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%b5-%ed%99%95%ec%9e%a5%ec%9d%80-%ec%8b%a4%ed%8c%a8%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ec%a0%84%eb%ac%b8%ea%b0%80%eb%93%a4%ec%9d%b4-%eb%b3%b8-%ec%97%90.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135647/%ed%8c%8c%ec%9d%bc%eb%9f%bf%ec%9d%80-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%b5-%ed%99%95%ec%9e%a5%ec%9d%80-%ec%8b%a4%ed%8c%a8%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ec%a0%84%eb%ac%b8%ea%b0%80%eb%93%a4%ec%9d%b4-%eb%b3%b8-%ec%97%90.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>‘에이전틱 AI’는 최근 기업 기술 분야에서 가장 주목받는 용어가 됐다. 벤더는 스스로 판단하고 행동하는 시스템을 내세우며, AI를 단순한 보조 도구에서 실행 주체로 끌어올리겠다고 약속하고 있다. AI 투자에서 가시적인 성과를 내야 한다는 압박을 받는 CIO에게 이런 제안은 매력적으로 들릴 수밖에 없다. 그러나 이런 기대와 달리, 현장에서는 프로젝트를 잠시 멈추는 기업도 늘고 있다.</p> <p><a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-06-25-gartner-predicts-over-40-percent-of-agentic-ai-projects-will-be-canceled-by-end-of-2027?" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">가트너(Gartner)</a>는 2027년 말까지 에이전틱 AI 프로젝트의 40% 이상이 중단될 것으로 내다봤다. 가트너의 시니어 디렉터 애널리스트 아누슈리 베르마는 그 배경이 복잡하지 않다고 설명했다. 베르마는 “현재 진행 중인 에이전틱 AI 프로젝트 대부분은 초기 단계의 실험이나 개념 증명(PoC) 수준에 머물러 있다. 과도한 기대에 의해 추진되거나 실제로는 적절하지 않은 영역에 적용되는 사례가 많다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>가트너는 또 다른 문제로 이른바 ‘에이전트 워싱(agent washing)’을 지목했다. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4119297/how-to-get-your-enterprise-architecture-ready-for-agentic-ai.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank">에이전틱 AI에 대한 관심</a>이 높아지자, 기존 챗봇이나 생성형 AI 어시스턴트를 단순히 ‘에이전트’로 리브랜딩하는 사례가 늘었다는 것이다. 하지만 리브랜딩이 실제 성과로 이어지는 경우는 많지 않다. 베르마는 “현재 모델은 복잡한 비즈니스 목표를 자율적으로 달성하거나, 미묘한 지시를 장기간에 걸쳐 일관되게 수행할 만큼 충분히 성숙하거나 자율적이지 않다. 그 결과 상당수 에이전틱 AI 제안은 뚜렷한 가치나 투자 대비 수익(ROI)을 보여주지 못하고 있다”라고 진단했다.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"> srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all 1800w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=768%2C513&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=1024%2C684&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=1536%2C1026&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=1240%2C826&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=1044%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1044w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=252%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 252w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=126%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 126w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=719%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 719w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=539%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 539w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Anushree-Verma-senior-director-analyst-Gartner.jpg?resize=374%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 374w" width="1024" height="684" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><p>Anushree Verma, senior director analyst, Gartner</p>
</figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">Gartner</p></div> <p>실제로도 파일럿 단계를 넘어 실제 운영 환경에 들어가서야 괴리가 드러나는 경우가 많다. 상당수 파일럿 프로젝트가 본격적인 배포로 이어지지 못하면서 비용은 계속 늘고 있다. 동시에 경영진은 추가 투자를 정당화할 근거를 요구하고 있다. 그 결과 프로젝트를 중단하거나 아예 취소하는 사례도 점차 증가하는 추세다.</p> <p>다만 앞으로 나타날 대규모 프로젝트 중단 흐름은 기술 자체의 실패라기보다, 기대 수준과 운영 현실 사이의 간극에서 비롯된 결과일 가능성이 높다. 기업은 초기 데모에서 보였던 모습과 달리, 실제 환경에 자율성을 적용하기가 훨씬 더 어렵고 비용도 많이 든다는 사실을 체감하고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%8c%8c%ec%9d%bc%eb%9f%bf-%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c%ec%a0%9d%ed%8a%b8%ea%b0%80-%ed%98%84%ec%8b%a4%ec%9d%84-%eb%b0%98%ec%98%81%ed%95%98%ec%a7%80-%eb%aa%bb%ed%95%a0-%eb%95%8c">파일럿 프로젝트가 현실을 반영하지 못할 때</h2> <p>초기 단계에서 에이전틱 AI는 대체로 유망해 보인다. 적용 범위가 좁고 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3611247/when-is-data-too-clean-to-be-useful-for-enterprise-ai.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank">데이터가 정제</a>돼 있으며, 사람의 감독도 강하게 이뤄지는 조건에서는 시스템이 유능하고 효율적인 것처럼 보이기 쉽다. 그러나 실제 운영 환경에 들어가면 조건이 그대로 유지되기 어렵다.</p> <p>베르마는 가치 설정 방식 자체가 초기 경고 신호가 될 수 있다고 짚었다. 그는 “여전히 시간 절감이나 개인 생산성 향상만을 논한다면 고객이 투자한 비용을 정당화하기 어렵다. 에이전틱 시스템은 재무, 인사, 보안, 운영 등 구체적인 기능 영역에서 실질적인 비즈니스 성과와 연결돼야 한다. 그렇지 않으면 경영진의 검증을 통과하기 어렵다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>클라우드 기반 소프트웨어 기업 블랙라인(BlackLine)의 CTO 제러미 웅 역시 벤더 입장에서 비슷한 흐름이 나타났다고 전했다. 웅은 “파일럿 프로젝트는 대체로 인상적인 결과를 보여준다. 격리된 환경에서는 기대 이상의 성과가 나오기도 한다”라고 말했다. 그러나 문제는 확장 단계다. 문서 형식은 제각각이고, 예외 상황은 빠르게 늘어나며 사용자 행동도 일관되지 않다. 웅은 “확장 단계에서 대부분의 프로젝트가 무너진다”라고 강조했다.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"> srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all 1800w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=1240%2C826&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=1046%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1046w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=252%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 252w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=126%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 126w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=720%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 720w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=540%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 540w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Jeremy-Ung-CTO-BlackLine.jpg?resize=375%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 375w" width="1024" height="683" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><p>Jeremy Ung, CTO, BlackLine</p>
</figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">BlackLine</p></div> <p>에이전틱 시스템이 실제 업무 프로세스에 깊이 통합되면 되돌리기는 훨씬 어려워진다. 자율 프로세스가 일관되지 않은 결과를 낼 경우, 기업은 단순히 무엇이 잘못됐는지에 그치지 않고 시스템이 어떤 추론 과정을 거쳐 그 결론에 도달했는지까지 파악해야 한다. 이런 가시성이 확보되지 않으면 롤백은 위험해지고 시간도 오래 걸린다.</p> <p><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4082282/preparing-your-workforce-for-ai-agents-a-change-management-guide.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank">변화 관리</a>는 또 다른 부담일 수 있다. 웅은 “지금은 처음으로 인력과 AI 에이전트를 동시에 관리해야 하는 시기”라고 말했다. 자율 시스템을 감독하도록 사람을 교육하고, 시스템을 어디까지 신뢰해야 하는지 기준을 세우는 작업은 많은 조직이 예상했던 것보다 훨씬 까다로운 과제인 것으로 나타났다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%9d%94%eb%93%a4%eb%a6%ac%eb%8a%94-%eb%b9%84%ec%9a%a9-%eb%aa%a8%eb%8d%b8">흔들리는 비용 모델</h2> <p>파일럿 프로젝트에서 가치를 확인하더라도, 확장 단계에서는 경제성이 발목을 잡는 경우가 많다. 에이전틱 시스템은 기존 기업용 소프트웨어와는 전혀 다른 방식으로 자원을 소모한다. 하나의 자율 작업이 여러 단계의 추론과 도구 호출, 재시도, 검증 과정을 연쇄적으로 유발할 수 있다. 웅은 “워크플로우가 복잡해질수록 처리 과정에서 더 많은 토큰이 소모된다. 에이전틱 워크플로우로 갈수록 독립적인 작업을 수행하는 데 더 많은 자원을 소비한다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>사용량에 따라 자원 소비가 급격히 바뀌는 구조로 인해 비용 변동성은 커지고 예측이 어려워진다. 토큰 기반 과금은 인프라 용량이 아니라 실제 사용량에 따라 요금이 달라진다. 고정적인 인프라 비용에 익숙한 재무 조직 입장에서는 관리가 쉽지 않은 구조다. 이사회 역시 AI 비용이 명확한 수익을 전제로 한 투자라기보다 한도가 보이지 않는 운영비처럼 보이는 이유에 대한 설명을 요구하고 있다.</p> <p>베르마는 현재 많은 기업이 에이전틱 시스템에 생성형 AI의 비용 가정을 그대로 적용하고 있다고 지적했다. 그는 “기업이 단순한 LLM 비용 기준에 의존하고 있지만, 에이전트는 다르다. 오케스트레이터와 거버넌스 계층, 여러 개의 에이전트가 추가되면 비용은 매우 빠르게 증가한다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>결과적으로 일부 조직은 적용 범위를 의도적으로 축소했으며, 또 다른 기업은 비용 통제 체계가 어느 정도 자리 잡을 때까지 확장을 전면 중단했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9d%b4%ec%82%ac%ed%9a%8c-%eb%85%bc%ec%9d%98-%ec%82%ac%ed%95%ad%ec%9d%b4-%eb%90%9c-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8b%b1-ai">이사회 논의 사항이 된 에이전틱 AI</h2> <p>에이전틱 AI 프로젝트가 점점 규모를 키우고 비용도 늘어나면서, 논의 역시 IT 부서를 넘어 이사회로 옮겨가는 추세다. 이 변화는 많은 조직에 부담으로 작용하고 있다.</p> <p>자동화와 달리, 에이전틱 AI는 하위 조직에 위임하기 어려운 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4107490/%EC%97%90%EC%9D%B4%EC%A0%84%ED%8B%B1-ai-%EC%8B%9C%EB%8C%80-%EC%A0%84%ED%86%B5%EC%A0%81%EC%9D%B8-it-%EB%A6%AC%EC%8A%A4%ED%81%AC-%EA%B4%80%EB%A6%AC%EA%B0%80-%ED%9D%94%EB%93%A4%EB%A6%AC%EB%8A%94.html" target="_blank">리스크</a>가 있다. 자율 시스템이 의사결정을 내리고, 실제로 행동하며, 고객이나 재무 시스템과 직접 상호작용하기 때문이다. 기업의 법적 책임과 직결될 수 있다는 의미다. 그 결과 CIO는 시스템의 작동 여부를 넘어, 의사결정 과정을 설명하고 책임질 수 있는지까지 점검받고 있다.</p> <p>베르마는 많은 프로젝트가 이 지점에서 흔들린다고 분석했다. 그는 “현재의 거버넌스와 리스크 통제 체계는 에이전틱 시스템에 맞춰 정교하게 설계돼 있지 않다. 특히 여러 에이전트가 서로 상호작용하고 다양한 애플리케이션에 접근하는 구조에서는 통제가 더 복잡해진다”. 자율성이 높아질수록 누가 어떤 조건에서 해당 행동을 승인했는지, 어떤 안전장치가 적용됐는지 같은 기본적인 거버넌스 질문에 답하기가 더 어려워진다”라고 강조했다.</p> <p>이사회는 책임 소재에 대해서도 보다 명확한 기준을 요구하고 있다. 에이전트가 잘못된 결정을 내렸다고 해서 모델이 책임지는 것은 아니다. 최종 책임은 해당 시스템의 도입을 승인한 경영진에게 돌아간다. 따라서 기업은 에이전틱 AI를 실험적 혁신이 아니라, 재무 시스템이나 사이버보안 통제와 같은 수준의 검증과 통제를 요구받는 핵심 인프라로 다뤄야 하는 상황이다.</p> <p>이 같은 변화로 인해 많은 조직이 전환점을 맞고 있다. 작동 원리를 명확히 설명하지 못하거나 경제적 타당성을 입증하지 못하는 프로젝트는 더 이상 관성적으로 유지되기 어렵다. 경영진의 공식 검토를 거치면서 상당수 프로젝트가 중단되고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9e%90%ec%9c%a8%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc-%ed%98%84%ec%8b%a4%ec%9d%98-%eb%b3%b5%ec%9e%a1%ec%84%b1%ec%9d%b4-%eb%a7%8c%eb%82%a0-%eb%95%8c">자율성과 현실의 복잡성이 만날 때</h2> <p>일반적인 인식과 달리, 에이전틱 AI의 핵심 문제는 모델 정확도가 아니다. 더 근본적인 과제는 단편화, 예외, 불확실성이 뒤섞인 실제 운영 환경에 자율 시스템을 배치하는 일이다.</p> <p>SAS의 응용 AI 및 모델링 부문 부사장 우도 스글라보는 “어려운 문제는 모델링 자체가 아니다. 에이전트를 실제 운영 환경에 투입하는 과정이 더 큰 과제”라고 설명했다. 스글라보는 기업 환경에 부분적인 장애와 통합 지연, 각종 예외 상황이 상존하고 있다면서, 자율 시스템이 이런 환경에서 작동할 경우 작은 변수도 빠르게 누적되며 복잡성이 커진다고 분석했다.</p> <p>사람은 경험과 판단을 바탕으로 이런 상황에 대응한다. 그러나 에이전트는 그렇지 않다. 스글라보는 “사람은 직관을 갖고 있는 반면 에이전트는 뭔가 이상하다는 감각을 인지하지 못한다”라고 말했다. 에이전트가 한 번도 접해보지 못한 상황에 놓일 경우 환각 가능성은 높아지며, 때로는 심각한 결과로 이어질 수 있다는 지적이다.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"> srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all 1800w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=1536%2C1025&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=1240%2C826&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=1045%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1045w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=252%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 252w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=126%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 126w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=719%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 719w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=540%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 540w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Udo-Sglavo-VP-of-applied-AI-and-modeling-SAS-1.jpg?resize=375%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 375w" width="1024" height="683" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><p>Udo Sglavo, VP of applied AI and modeling, SAS</p>
</figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">SAS</p></div> <p>사람이 개입하는 ‘휴먼 인 더 루프(Human-in-the-Loop)’ 설계가 중요한 이유도 여기에 있다. 스글라보는 “SAS가 수행한 거의 모든 구축 사례에서 사람의 개입이 필요했다”라고 언급했다. 자율성은 시스템이 일상적인 업무를 처리하고 예외 상황을 식별해 알리는 방식으로 작동할 때 가장 효과적이며, 중대한 결정을 시스템이 독립적으로 내리도록 하는 구조는 아직 위험 부담이 크다는 것이다.</p> <p>설명 가능성과 감사 가능성 역시 도입의 핵심 요건으로 떠오르고 있다. 스글라보는 “시스템이 행동한 이유를 설명할 수 없고 의사결정 과정을 재구성할 수 없다면 고객은 해당 시스템을 사용하지 않을 것”이라고 말했다. 특히 규제 산업에서는 의사결정 이후에도 오랜 기간 책임을 소명해야 하는 만큼, 요구 수준이 더욱 높다고 그는 강조했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%8b%a4%ec%a0%9c-%eb%b3%91%eb%aa%a9%ec%9d%b4-%eb%90%9c-%ea%b1%b0%eb%b2%84%eb%84%8c%ec%8a%a4">실제 병목이 된 거버넌스</h2> <p>에이전틱 AI가 운영 단계에 가까워질수록, 제약 요인은 지능 자체가 아니라 거버넌스로 옮겨가고 있다. AI 서비스 기업 액셀러레이트(Accelirate)의 CEO 아흐메드 자이디는 거버넌스를 사람, 프로세스, 기술로 나눠 설명했다. 먼저 기술 측면에서 기업은 확률적으로 작동하는 시스템에 접근 통제와 가드레일을 적용하는 데 어려움을 겪고 있다. 자이디는 “구조화된 시스템에서도 접근 통제를 설계하는 일은 쉽지 않다. 환각 가능성이 있는 LLM에 각종 도구 사용 권한까지 부여하는 일이기 때문”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>프로세스 거버넌스도 마찬가지로 복잡하다. 수작업 워크플로우에는 암묵적인 점검 절차가 포함되는 경우가 많지만, 자동화는 그렇지 않다. 재설계 없이 자동화만 진행할 경우, 오류를 줄이기보다 오히려 더 빠르게 확산시킬 위험도 있다. 여기에 인력 거버넌스까지 더해진다. 직원 교육, 책임 범위의 재정의, 새로운 실패 유형에 대한 조직 차원의 대비가 모두 요구되고 있다.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"> srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all 1800w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=1240%2C826&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=1046%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1046w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=252%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 252w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=126%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 126w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=720%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 720w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=540%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 540w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Ahmed-Zaidi-CEO-Accelirate.jpg?resize=375%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 375w" width="1024" height="683" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><p>Ahmed Zaidi, CEO, Accelirate</p>
</figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">Accelirate</p></div> <p>자이디는 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4108394/ai-%EB%A6%AC%EC%8A%A4%ED%81%AC%EB%A5%BC-%EA%B8%B0%ED%9A%8C%EB%A1%9C-%EA%B1%B0%EB%B2%84%EB%84%8C%EC%8A%A4%EC%99%80-%ED%98%81%EC%8B%A0%EC%9D%98-%EA%B7%A0%ED%98%95%EC%9D%84-%EB%A7%9E.html" target="_blank">성숙한 거버넌스</a>에 프로젝트를 중단할 수 있는 판단력도 포함된다고 강조했다. 그는 위험 요소가 크고 ROI가 불분명하거나 점차 감소하는 프로젝트의 경우, 빠르게 일시 중단하거나 취소하고 있다고 설명했다. 그는 “프로젝트를 취소했다고 해서 거버넌스가 실패한 것은 아니다. 오히려 거버넌스가 제대로 작동했다는 의미”라고 말했다.</p> <p>자이디에 따르면 반복적으로 나타나는 패턴도 있다. 리스크를 통제하기 위해 추가 통제 장치나 검증 계층, 사람의 감독을 도입하다 보면, 당초 기대했던 수익이 상당 부분 줄어드는 경우가 많다. 그는 이런 상황에서 프로젝트를 중단하는 것이 합리적인 선택이 될 수 있다고 진단했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%82%b4%ec%95%84%eb%82%a8%eb%8a%94-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8b%b1-ai%ec%9d%98-%ec%a1%b0%ea%b1%b4">살아남는 에이전틱 AI의 조건</h2> <p>중단되는 프로젝트가 늘고 있지만, 에이전틱 AI 자체가 후퇴하는 것은 아니다. 대신 적용 범위가 좁아지고 있다. 실제로 살아남는 프로젝트에는 몇 가지 공통점이 있다. 범용 에이전트를 지향하기보다 특정 업무에 집중한다는 점이다. 또 입력과 출력 범위를 통제할 수 있는 제한된 환경에서 운영되며, 성과 역시 추상적인 생산성 향상이 아니라 측정 가능한 비즈니스 지표로 정의된다.</p> <p>베르마는 변화를 분명히 감지하고 있다고 밝혔다. 그는 “기존 애플리케이션에 단계적으로 추가되는 업무 특화형 에이전트로 이동하는 추세”라며 “성공하는 프로젝트는 개인의 효율성 향상에 머무르지 않고, 조직 차원의 실질적인 성과를 만들어내는 사례”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>웅도 같은 견해를 내놨다. 그는 “핵심은 시간을 얼마나 절약했느냐가 아니라 비즈니스에 어떤 성과를 가져오는지다”라고 말했다. 그는 성숙한 도입 사례가 에이전트의 행동을 KPI와 경영진 대시보드에 연계해, 기대에 못 미치는 경우 신속히 방향을 조정할 수 있는 구조를 갖췄다고 덧붙였다.</p> <p>전문가들은 한 가지 공통된 원칙을 강조했다. 자율성을 한 번에 완성하는 것이 아니라 단계적으로 확보해야 한다는 점이다. 중대한 의사결정 지점에는 여전히 사람이 개입해야 하며, 문제가 발생했을 때를 대비한 롤백 경로도 사전에 설계돼 있어야 한다. 거버넌스 역시 사후 대응이 아니라, 상시적으로 작동하는 체계여야 한다.</p> <p>에이전틱 AI 도입의 다음 단계는 이전보다 조용하게 전개될 가능성이 크다. 대대적인 발표는 줄어들고, 일시 중단되는 프로젝트는 늘어나며, 재무 조직과 이사회의 검토는 한층 더 엄격해질 전망이다. 그러나 부정적으로만 해석할 필요는 없다. 에이전틱 AI가 실험 단계를 지나, 책임이 수반되는 영역으로 이동하고 있음을 보여주는 변화다.</p> <p>자이디는 많은 기업이 과거의 교훈을 다시 확인하고 있다고 말했다. 시스템은 사람보다 더 높은 완성도를 요구받는다는 점이다. 기대를 충족하기 위해 필요한 것은 과장된 홍보가 아니라, 통제와 규율이라는 설명이다. 결국 CIO에게 중요한 질문은 에이전트가 행동할 수 있는지 여부가 아니다. 에이전트가 실제로 행동했을 때, 그 결과를 통제하고 설명하며 비용까지 감당할 준비가 돼있는지 여부다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Spring News Roundup: Second Milestone Releases of Boot, Security, Integration, Modulith, AMQP]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/spring-news-roundup-feb16-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/spring-news-roundup-feb16-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/spring-news-roundup-feb16-2026/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771781430362.jpg"/><p>There was a flurry of activity in the Spring ecosystem during the week of February 16th, 2026, highlighting the second milestone releases of: Spring Boot; Spring Security; Spring Integration; Spring Modulith; and Spring AMQP; along with the first milestone releases of Spring Session, Spring for Apache Kafka and Spring LDAP.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How CIOs Connect Security, Cost, And Value To The Board]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/how-cios-connect-security-cost-and-value-to-the-board/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/how-cios-connect-security-cost-and-value-to-the-board/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[What CIOs are working on, Part 4 of 4 Over the past six months of guidance kickoff conversations with CIOs and CTOs, security, cost, and value almost always surface as top-priority initiatives. Leaders know that boards and executive committees care deeply about resilience, regulatory exposure, and technology spend, yet they often lack a simple, credible [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-23]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
