<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Feb 2026 08:06:36 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Gartner Survey Finds 91% of Customer Service Leaders Under Pressure to Implement AI in 2026]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-18-gartner-survey-finds-ninety-one-percent-of-customer-service-leaders-under-pressure-to-implement-ai-in-2026?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-18-gartner-survey-finds-ninety-one-percent-of-customer-service-leaders-under-pressure-to-implement-ai-in-2026?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Customer service and support leaders are facing increased executive expectations to invest in AI, according to a survey by Gartner, Inc., a business and technology insights company.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-18]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How Dropbox Built a Scalable Context Engine for Enterprise Knowledge Search]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/dropbox-context-engine/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/dropbox-context-engine/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/dropbox-context-engine/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771284814159.jpg"/><p>Dropbox engineers have detailed how the company built the context engine behind Dropbox Dash, revealing a shift toward index-based retrieval, knowledge graph-derived context, and continuous evaluation to support enterprise AI at scale</p> <i>By Matt Foster</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-18]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How Dropbox Built a Scalable Context Engine for Enterprise Knowledge Search]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/dropbox-context-engine/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/dropbox-context-engine/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/dropbox-context-engine/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771284814159.jpg"/><p>Dropbox engineers have detailed how the company built the context engine behind Dropbox Dash, revealing a shift toward index-based retrieval, knowledge graph-derived context, and continuous evaluation to support enterprise AI at scale</p> <i>By Matt Foster</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-18]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Uber and OpenAI Retool Rate Limiting Systems]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/uber-openai-rate-limiting/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/uber-openai-rate-limiting/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.infoq.com/styles/static/images/logo/logo_bigger.jpg"/><p>Uber and OpenAI are replacing static rate limits with adaptive, infrastructure-level platforms. Uber’s Global Rate Limiter utilizes probabilistic shedding to manage 80M RPS, while OpenAI’s Access Engine implements a credit waterfall to prevent user interruptions. Both architectures utilize distributed enforcement and soft controls to maintain system stability and service continuity at scale.</p> <i>By Patrick Farry</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[As Agentic Commerce Emerges, Services Providers Are Rewriting Commerce Playbooks End To End]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/as-agentic-commerce-emerges-services-providers-are-rewriting-commerce-playbooks-end-to-end/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/as-agentic-commerce-emerges-services-providers-are-rewriting-commerce-playbooks-end-to-end/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The Forrester Wave™: Commerce Services, Q1 2026 reveals how commerce services providers are rewriting long-standing commerce strategy playbooks and prompting business leaders to reach today’s buyers through AI-powered commerce transformations.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Partner Marketing Automation Platform Investment On The Rise]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/partner-marketing-automation-platform-pmap-investment-on-the-rise/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/partner-marketing-automation-platform-pmap-investment-on-the-rise/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[In Forrester’s Partner Ecosystem Marketing Survey, 2026, 75% of partner ecosystem marketing decision-makers reported their overall technology investments will increase in the next 12 months. Among organizations already investing in a partner marketing automation platform (PMAP), 65% plan to increase their investment. Even more telling, nearly 60% of organizations not currently using partner marketing automation [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Ten Can’t-Miss Experiences For Marketers At B2B Summit North America]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/ten-cant-miss-experiences-for-marketers-at-b2b-summit-north-america/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/ten-cant-miss-experiences-for-marketers-at-b2b-summit-north-america/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The Summit agenda is designed to help marketers meet the challenges and complexities of this moment — but the overall experience delivers so much more. Here’s a sneak preview.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Moonshot AI Releases Open-Weight Kimi K2.5 Model with Vision and Agent Swarm Capabilities]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/kimi-k25-swarm/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/kimi-k25-swarm/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/kimi-k25-swarm/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771079384813.jpg"/><p>Moonshot AI released Kimi K2.5, their latest open-weight multimodal LLM. K2.5 excels at coding tasks, with benchmark scores comparable to frontier models such as GPT-5 and Gemini. It also features an agent swarm mode, which can direct up to 100 sub-agents for attacking problems with parallel workflow.</p> <i>By Anthony Alford</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Build The Experience AI Can’t: Announcing Forrester’s 2026 CX Events]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/build-the-experience-ai-cant-announcing-forresters-2026-cx-events/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/build-the-experience-ai-cant-announcing-forresters-2026-cx-events/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[As every brand races to deploy the same AI tools, the differentiating factors will be the people using those tools and the experiences they create. Our 2026 CX events will equip you to build experiences that win trust and lasting loyalty.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The ‘Genesis’ gamble: Creating order from chaos in the age of AI]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132853/the-genesis-gamble-creating-order-from-chaos-in-the-age-of-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132853/the-genesis-gamble-creating-order-from-chaos-in-the-age-of-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Your board is going to ask you a question in the next twelve months, if they haven’t already: “What’s our AI strategy, and why should we believe it’s enough?”</p> <p>I’ve been in those rooms. I’ve been asked those questions. And I’ve also watched other CTOs and CIOs give answers that sound reasonable in the moment but miss the magnitude of the stakes. They talk about copilots and chatbots and efficiency gains. They present roadmaps with timelines and metrics like “Hours Saved”. They frame AI as a technology initiative, when what’s really on the table is something closer to an existential bet.</p> <p>AI is not just another technology cycle. It’s a bet that we can unlock productivity gains large enough to fundamentally change the trajectory of our organizations and the broader economic system they operate within.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">The bet most boards are missing</h2> <p>In November, the US launched the “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/11/launching-the-genesis-mission/">Genesis Mission</a>,” A Manhattan Project-scale effort to harness AI for scientific discovery. It involves the Department of Energy integrating 17 national labs, decades of federal data, and the world’s most powerful supercomputers into an AI platform designed to double research productivity within a decade. That’s not a small pilot program. That’s not an experiment. That’s the federal government placing a very large bet that AI is the most consequential productivity technology since electrification.</p> <p>This isn’t really a technology bet. It’s an economic one. And that distinction should fundamentally change how you think about your own AI investments.</p> <p>The Genesis Mission isn’t just about faster science. It’s a policy response to a deeper economic problem most boards never see: the economic system we’re operating in increasingly depends on productivity breakthroughs that haven’t materialized yet.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-economic-context-your-board-hasnt-been-told">The economic context your board hasn’t been told</h2> <p>Economist and former IMF consultant, Richard Duncan has spent decades studying what he calls “<a href="https://richardduncaneconomics.com/interview-creditism/" rel="nofollow">creditism</a>.” His thesis will make you uncomfortable: we don’t live in a capitalist economy anymore. Since the U.S. left the gold standard in the early 1970s, global economic growth has been driven primarily by the continuous expansion of credit.</p> <p>You don’t need to agree with Duncan’s framing in full to see the pattern. What matters is the direction of travel, not the label.</p> <p>Consider the scale of the shift. Total U.S. debt was $1 trillion in 1964. Last year, it crossed $100 trillion, a hundredfold increase in roughly sixty years. That expansion funded venture capital, enabled cloud infrastructure, created unicorn startups, and underwrote the digital economy most of us have spent our careers building. Every enterprise system I’ve ever architected runs on top of this structure. It’s the water we swim in.</p> <p>But credit based systems have a constraint: credit must keep expanding. When it doesn’t, instability follows. Duncan <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Money-Revolution-Finance-American-Century/dp/1119856264" rel="nofollow">documents this pattern repeatedly</a>. Credit contraction reliably precedes recession.</p> <p>We saw it in 1930. A credit bubble popped, policymakers stepped back, and <a href="https://www.federalreservehistory.org/essays/great-depression" rel="nofollow">the economy shrank by 30%</a>. <a href="https://www.stlouisfed.org/the-great-depression/curriculum/economic-episodes-in-american-history-part-3" rel="nofollow">Unemployment hit 25%</a>.</p> <p>In 2008, we faced a similar moment. This time, the government intervened with trillion-dollar deficits and the Fed created trillions more through quantitative easing. That kept the system alive, but it didn’t solve the underlying problem. It bought us time.</p> <p>Time for what?</p> <p>Time to <a href="https://richardduncaneconomics.com/our-economic-and-political-problems-look-set-to-multiply/" rel="nofollow">grow our way out of the problem</a>. Time to generate productivity gains large enough that the debt becomes sustainable. Time to create real economic expansion, not just more credit layered on top of the last cycle.</p> <p>That pressure is no longer abstract. It’s landing directly on your desk.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-this-lands-on-your-desk">Why this lands on your desk</h2> <p>For decades, economists have tracked <a href="https://www.bls.gov/opub/mlr/2021/article/the-us-productivity-slowdown-the-economy-wide-and-industry-level-analysis.htm" rel="nofollow">declining productivity growth</a>. Despite massive investments in technology, overall output per worker has stagnated. At the enterprise level, the pattern is painfully familiar: more researchers produce fewer breakthroughs, drug approvals have declined, and R&amp;D efficiency has deteriorated across industries.</p> <p>I’ve been on both sides of this. I’ve led large-scale transformations, and I’ve been the person other CTOs call when the results don’t match the investment. It’s why I’ve spent so much time helping shape industry standards through the DevOps Institute, the FinOps Foundation and the CIO Executive Council.</p> <p>The pattern is always the same: companies pour eight figures into digital transformation, cloud migration, SRE or DevOps maturity, only to present incremental improvements to a skeptical board. The technology worked. The systems stabilize. Costs may even come down. But the productivity needle barely moved. I’ve lost count of how many times I’ve had that hushed conversation over quiet sips of rarefied bourbon, trying to help them figure out what to tell their board.</p> <p>AI is different. Not because of the hype, but because of the mechanism. When AI can analyze patterns across decades of data, design experiments, run simulations, and surface insights that would take humans years to find, you’re not optimizing existing processes. You’re operating on a different curve entirely.</p> <p>The Genesis Mission is a $100 billion bet that this different curve is real. That AI accelerated discovery in energy, materials science, biotech, and quantum computing can generate the productivity breakthroughs the economy needs. Washington is treating AI as the technology that might actually move the needle on growth.</p> <p>Which brings us back to your board meeting. The question isn’t whether AI will transform your industry. The question is whether you’ll be the one doing the transforming or the one getting transformed.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-pattern-underneath-it-all">The pattern underneath it all</h2> <p>The name “Genesis” isn’t an accident.</p> <p>The credit system Duncan describes looks stable on the surface, but it contains the seeds of its own collapse. The question is whether we can create enough genuine productive capacity before the next contraction hits.</p> <p>I’m not making a theological claim. I’m making a practical one. Every major initiative I’ve ever led started as chaos: competing stakeholders, unclear requirements, legacy decisions that take time to unwind. The work was creating order from those challenges. Turning noise into signal, ambiguity into architecture. AI lets us do it at a scale we couldn’t before.</p> <p>That’s what the Genesis Mission is betting on. Not faster chatbots. The capacity to build something real that can bear the weight of the system we’ve constructed.</p> <p>That’s not just government policy. That’s a pattern you should be replicating in your own organization.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-this-means-for-your-ai-strategy">What this means for your AI strategy</h2> <p>Here’s what I’d actually tell you if we were working side by side:</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="stop-treating-ai-as-a-line-item-in-your-modernization-budget">Stop treating AI as a line item in your modernization budget</h3> <p>It’s a platform bet on par with your cloud migration. Maybe bigger. If the macro thesis is right, if AI is the technology that enables genuine productivity gains at the scale the economy needs, then underinvesting is an existential risk. Not because competitors will ship features faster, but because the companies that figure out AI-native operations will have structural advantages that compound over time.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="think-bigger-than-insights">Think bigger than insights</h3> <p>The Genesis Mission isn’t summarizing PDFs. It’s simulating physics, designing experiments, running scenarios that would take human researchers years. Your AI strategy shouldn’t be summarizing meetings. It should be simulating your supply chain before you change it. Modeling customer behavior before you launch. Testing pricing strategies in silico before they hit the market. The companies treating AI as a faster way to read documents are missing the point. The real leverage is using your proprietary data to simulate futures your competitors can’t see.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="finally-build-for-continuous-learning">Finally, build for continuous learning</h3> <p>Simulation requires people who can ask the right questions. But, we’re automating faster than we’re reskilling. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4075662/the-quiet-crisis-why-your-ai-cost-savings-are-creating-tomorrows-problems.html">That’s an unseen form of technical debt and it will come due</a>. The Genesis Mission gets this right: its AI architecture runs experiments, evaluates outcomes, and improves continuously. That’s not a chatbot. That’s an operational system.</p> <p>The same principle applies to your organization. Without the infrastructure and observability to measure what works and feed learnings back into the system, you’re building on sand. Without investing in your people’s ability to learn alongside the tech, you’re optimizing for the short term.</p> <p>I could be wrong about this. Maybe AI plateaus. Maybe the productivity gains don’t materialize at scale. But I’ve been doing this long enough to know that the bigger risk is usually inaction.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-new-beginning">A new beginning</h2> <p>Duncan frames the choice starkly. With the right investments, we may grow our way out of the credit trap. Without them, history suggests long term stagnation, instability, and conflict. That’s not alarmism. It’s precedent.</p> <p>The Genesis Mission is the government’s attempt to make the right bet. To create a new beginning. To leverage unique federal assets and emerging AI capabilities to create genuine productive capacity.</p> <p>Your job is to make the same bet at your scale.</p> <p>I think about the ripple effects of these decisions constantly. The choices you make in the next twelve months will compound. They’ll affect whether your engineers feel like they’re building something that matters. Whether your company is positioned to thrive or scrambling to catch up. Whether the people who trusted you with their careers made the right bet. That’s the weight of the decision.</p> <p>Because when your board asks what your AI strategy is and why they should believe it’s enough, “we’re being thoughtful and deliberate” is not an answer that will age well.</p> <p>Invest like it matters. Because it does.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The 10 Profit Leaks Your Digital Employee Plugs Immediately]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/the-10-profit-leaks-your-digital-employee-plugs-immediately/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/the-10-profit-leaks-your-digital-employee-plugs-immediately/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Sandeep Dhall &#38; Ievegen Gartman The following list isn&#8217;t about fixing ten small problems. It&#8217;s about eliminating an entire category of inefficient work from your business. This is how you achieve real scale. This <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/the-10-profit-leaks-your-digital-employee-plugs-immediately/" title="The 10 Profit Leaks Your Digital Employee Plugs Immediately">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The 10 Profit Leaks Your Digital Employee Plugs Immediately]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/17/the-10-profit-leaks-your-digital-employee-plugs-immediately/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/17/the-10-profit-leaks-your-digital-employee-plugs-immediately/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Sandeep Dhall &#038; Ievegen Gartman The following list isn&#8217;t about fixing ten small problems. It&#8217;s about eliminating an entire category of inefficient work from your business. This is how you achieve real scale. This [...]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Busy, Trusted, and Stuck: The Structural Trap of Enterprise Architects]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/17/busy-trusted-and-stuck-the-structural-trap-of-enterprise-architects/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/17/busy-trusted-and-stuck-the-structural-trap-of-enterprise-architects/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[How reliable architects end up firefighting instead of architecting—and why working harder rarely fixes the plateau]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Busy, Trusted, and Stuck: The Structural Trap of Enterprise Architects]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.eatransformation.com/p/busy-trusted-and-stuck-the-structural-trap-of-enterprise-architects]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.eatransformation.com/p/busy-trusted-and-stuck-the-structural-trap-of-enterprise-architects]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[How reliable architects end up firefighting instead of architecting&#8212;and why working harder rarely fixes the plateau]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Will AI Eat Your Revtech Stack?]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/will-ai-eat-your-revtech-stack/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/will-ai-eat-your-revtech-stack/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[For RevOps leaders, the challenge isn’t predicting which of the narratives on what the future holds is right — it’s avoiding reactive decisions based on incomplete signals.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AIは「新しいメディア」になる——博報堂ＤＹホールディングスCAIOが描く創造性が拡張する未来（後編）]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132547/ai%e3%81%af%e3%80%8c%e6%96%b0%e3%81%97%e3%81%84%e3%83%a1%e3%83%87%e3%82%a3%e3%82%a2%e3%80%8d%e3%81%ab%e3%81%aa%e3%82%8b-%e5%8d%9a%e5%a0%b1%e5%a0%82%ef%bd%84%ef%bd%99%e3%83%9b%e3%83%bc-2.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132547/ai%e3%81%af%e3%80%8c%e6%96%b0%e3%81%97%e3%81%84%e3%83%a1%e3%83%87%e3%82%a3%e3%82%a2%e3%80%8d%e3%81%ab%e3%81%aa%e3%82%8b-%e5%8d%9a%e5%a0%b1%e5%a0%82%ef%bd%84%ef%bd%99%e3%83%9b%e3%83%bc-2.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p><strong>挑戦したくなるビジョンを描け——メンバーの視座を引き上げる言葉の力</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——仕事をする上で心に残っているアドバイスはありますか？</p> <p>グローバルな研究開発体制を推進していたときに、右腕として支えてくれたノルウェー人の研究者からもらった言葉はとても印象に残っています。</p> <p>彼は20代で工科大学の教授になったほどの天才的な研究者で、ビジネスの知見にも長けていました。彼とは日常的に、<strong>「グローバルで活躍できるのはどんな人材か」「これからの時代のリーダーに求められる素養は何か」</strong>といったことをよく議論していました。</p> <p>当時、私が率いていた研究開発組織は前例のないものでした。世界5カ国・8拠点にメンバーが所属し、そのうち95％以上が外国籍。しかも研究領域も実に幅広く、ユビキタスやデジタルサイネージのようなデバイス分野から、データマイニングや自然言語処理といったデータ活用領域、さらにはロボティクスやドローンといったハードウェア領域までをカバーしていました。</p> <p>これほど多様な領域を束ねるのは容易ではなく、<strong>「どうすれば研究を実際のビジネスインパクトにつなげられるのか」</strong>という問いに対する答えを探しながら、試行錯誤を続けていました。</p> <p>そんなある日、悩んでいた私に彼がかけてくれた言葉は、私のコミュニケーションを大きく変えてしまうほどのインパクトがあるものでした。</p> <p><strong>「もしも森さんが巨大な船をつくりたいのであれば、人々を集めて木材を切らせて運ばせて、どう組み立てるか——といった、『タスクを割り振るような作業』から入ってはいけない。そうではなく、『果てしなく続いていく広大な海への憧れ』を語るべきです」</strong></p> <p>これはサン＝テグジュペリの言葉を引用したものでした。この言葉の意味するところは、<strong>「リーダーの役割とは単にタスクを指示することではなく、『長期的なビジョンを示すこと』にある。そしてそのビジョンは、メンバー一人ひとりが『挑戦したい』と心から思える、希望に満ちたものでなければならない」</strong>ということだったのです。</p> <p>このアドバイスを受けてから、私のコミュニケーションのあり方が変わりました。常に<strong>「メンバーの視座をどう引き上げるか」</strong>を意識するようになったのです。</p> <p>たとえばミーティングでは、<strong>「今、私たちが取り組んでいるこの仕事は、社会にどんな価値をもたらすのか」「この取り組みで世の中をどう変えていけるのか」</strong>といった話を意識的に語り続けるようになりました。</p> <p>ビジョンを共有することで、人は自分の役割の意味を理解し、挑戦するエネルギーが湧いてくる。そうした考え方が、今の博報堂ＤＹグループで掲げている<strong>「人間中心の</strong><strong>AI」</strong>という理念にもつながっています。あの時の言葉は、私のリーダーシップの礎になったと言っても過言ではありません。</p> <p><strong>企業と生活者の未来をデザインする——「人間中心の</strong><strong>AI</strong><strong>」に込めた情熱</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——CAIOとして、どのようなところにやりがいを感じますか？</p> <p>CAIOの役割や領域は意外に広くて、<strong>「</strong><strong>AIをいかに自社のシステムやサービス、プロダクトに組み込むか」</strong>というところが<strong>「いかに</strong><strong>AIを使って内部のシステムの生産性を上げていくか」「業務プロセスを改善していくか」「社員一人ひとりのスキルを高めていくか」</strong>といったところにもかかわってきます。</p> <p>さらには、そうした内部の話だけではなくて、<strong>「新しい視点の新しい取り組み」</strong>をどう始めていくか、つまり<strong>「新規事業をどうつくっていくか」</strong>といったことも考えなければなりません。</p> <p>こうした取り組みを成功に導くためには、AIスタートアップやビッグテック企業といかに戦略的にアライアンスを組むかが重要になります。彼らと連携しながら、新しい技術やサービスを共創し、そこから新たなビジネスを立ち上げていくことが求められるのです。</p> <p>そのため、CAIOというのは内部のことも分かっている必要がありますし、業界動向や市場の変化といったことを踏まえたビジネスの知見も必要です。もちろんAIというのはとても急速に変化しているので、時代の先を見据えたリーダーシップも重要です。そういう意味ではとても魅力的なものがあると思っています。</p> <p>そうした中で、最も重要なのはビジョンだと思っています。</p> <p>さらに視野を広げて考えると、<strong>「</strong><strong>AIは社会をどう変えていくのか」「AIが私たちのビジネスや存在そのものをどう変えるのか」「その変化の中で私たちはどうあるべきか」</strong>といった未来のシナリオを明確に描き、示していくことが何より大切になるからです。それがあるからこそ、<strong>「短中期的に何をやるべきか」</strong>が分かってくると思います。</p> <p>今後もものすごいスピードで進化し続けていくAIの変化をしっかり追いかけながらも、自社ならではの強みを見極め、それを土台に<strong>「本当に価値を生み出す</strong><strong>AI戦略」</strong>を見つけ出し、実行していくことが重要です。そうした取り組みこそが、AIによって企業を変革していく<strong>ジャーニー</strong>なのだと感じています。</p> <p>そして、その道のりにCAIOとして関わり、貢献できることに、私は大きなやりがいを感じています。</p> <p><strong>ビジョンを共有できる人が、チームを動かす——現代リーダーの条件</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——CAIOに必要な資質とは何でしょうか？</p> <p>ビジョンを描き、それを日々の仕事と結びつけてメンバーと共有する力が、リーダーにとって最も重要だと思います。現代的な言葉でいえば、パーパス（存在意義）やアスピレーション（志）を明確に示し、<strong>「自分たちは何のために、どこを目指して働いているのか」</strong>を常に語り続けることです。</p> <p>加えて、いまの時代は社会も価値観も大きく変化しており、リーダーシップのスタイル自体も多様化してきています。かつてリーダーとは、先頭に立って方向を示す<strong>「導く人」</strong>でした。しかし、デジタル技術が広く普及した現代では、誰もが発信者となり、膨大なアウトプットを生み出せるようになりました。</p> <p>その結果、今、企業に問われているのは<strong>「量」</strong>ではなくアウトプットの質をどう高めるか、<strong>「質」</strong>の高いアウトプットをどうやって見つけ出していくかです。だからこそ多くの企業が、ヒエラルキー型の組織から、多様な人材がフラットに連携し、分散しながらも価値を生み出すチームづくりへと舵を切りつつあるのです。</p> <p>こうした環境の中で、リーダーに求められる役割も変わってきています。先頭に立つだけでなく、コーチ、サーバント、カタリストのように、メンバーと伴走し、支え、能力を引き出すタイプのリーダーシップが重要になっています。</p> <p>それはたとえば、メンバーの隣に寄り添いながら信頼関係を築く<strong>「横につくリーダーシップ」</strong>や、環境や仕組みを整え、背中からチームを支える<strong>「後ろにいるリーダーシップ」</strong>などです。</p> <p>大切なのは、自分自身の個性やチームの状況に合わせて、どのリーダーシップスタイルが最も効果的かを見極めることです。そして最も重要なのは、<strong>「ビジョンを日々共有し続けること」「チームが主体的に、創造的に動き続けるためにどう働きかけるか」</strong>という点に尽きると思っています。</p> <p><strong>「なぜ自分がやるのか」を問うことから、リーダーシップは始まる</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——これからCAIOを目指す人材に求められるスキルは何でしょうか？</p> <p>アドバイスとしてお伝えしたいのは、<strong>「自分にとって大切な価値観をどう見つけていくか」</strong>ということです。</p> <p>これまでお話ししてきたように、目指すべきビジョンやパーパスは、決して一朝一夕で見つかるものではありません。<strong>「どうやって自分のビジョンやパーパスを見つけようと努力し続けるか」</strong>——その過程こそが大切だと思っています。</p> <p>AIやデジタルツールが進化した今、<strong>「情報があるから簡単に見つけられるのでは」</strong>と思うかもしれません。しかし、そうしたツールが示すのはあくまで過去のデータに基づいた分析結果です。未来へ向かう羅針盤を描くためには、自分の内側にある価値観を見つめることが欠かせません。</p> <p>ビジョンやパーパスの出発点は、常に自分自身の内側にあります。<strong>「何をやるのか」「誰のためにやるのか」「なぜ自分がやるのか」「なぜ今やるのか」</strong>——こうした根源的な問いを自分に投げかけ、心の声に耳を傾ける。その積み重ねが、自分の価値観を形づくっていくのだと思います。</p> <p>また、リーダーは一人で働く存在ではありません。</p> <p>共に働くメンバー一人ひとりの内なる価値観や声に耳を傾け、それに光を当てることも大切です。そのためには、日常の業務だけでなく、価値観を語り合い、共有する場が必要です。</p> <p>例えば、困難なプロジェクトを共に乗り越える中で生まれる連帯感や、懇親会の延長で夜通し語り合うような経験も、決して無駄ではありません。そうした深い対話の中でこそ、相手の価値観に触れ、自分の価値観と結びつけていくことができるのだと思います。</p> <p>こうしたプロセスは、一見、遠回りに思えるかもしれません。しかし、内省と対話を積み重ねる以外に、本当に掲げたくなるビジョンやパーパスは見つかりません。だからこそ、<strong>「この道しかない」</strong>と信じて歩み続けることが大切だと思っています。</p> <p><strong>博報堂ＤＹグループを「</strong><strong>AI</strong><strong>ドリブンな組織」へ</strong><strong>——</strong><strong>「人の創造性」を高める新たなステージへの挑戦</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——今後の展望と取り組みをお教えください。</p> <p>足元の取り組みと並行して、中長期的なスパンで見据えているテーマがあります。</p> <p>中長期的な視点で見ると、今後5年ほどのスパンの中で、AIはAGI（汎用人工知能）に向かう道筋をたどっていくと考えています。その重要なマイルストーンの一つが<strong>「世界モデル」</strong>と呼ばれる技術です。この世界モデルを自社で開発し、あるいは積極的に活用していくことには、ぜひ挑戦していきたいと思っています。</p> <p>現在の生成AIや大規模言語モデル（LLM）は、<strong>「これができる」「ここまで自動化できる」</strong>といった<strong>できること</strong>の側面が強く打ち出されています。一方で、実は<strong>「子どもでも自然にできるのに、</strong><strong>AIにはうまくできない」と</strong>いう課題も、まだ数多く残されたままです。人間から見るとごく当たり前に感じられる推論や状況理解が、AIにとっては依然として難しい。この<strong>「技術的な限界」</strong>が、非常にわかりやすい形で横たわっているのが現状です。</p> <p>AAAI（The Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence）というトップレベルの学会のサーベイでも、研究者の約76％が<strong>「現在の</strong><strong>AIは、このままではAGIにはならない」</strong>と回答しています。つまり、<strong>「越えなければならない壁はすでに見えているが、その乗り越え方についてはまだ誰も明確な答えを持っていない」</strong>という認識が、研究者のあいだでは共有されているのです。</p> <p>世の中的には<strong>「</strong><strong>AGIの時代はすぐそこまで来ている」</strong>というムードもありますが、研究の現場ではむしろ<strong>「いま見えている技術の延長線だけでは到達できない」</strong>という冷静な見方も根強くあります。その壁に真正面から向き合い、新しい地平を切り開こうとするアプローチのひとつが、世界モデルです。</p> <p>世界モデルは、そうした技術的な限界を突破する可能性を秘めているだけでなく、私たちの業界にとって非常に重要なポイント——すなわち、クリエイターやデザイナーが持つ暗黙知や感性をどう取り込むか、というテーマにも直結してきます。トップブランドの世界観やストーリーを深く理解し、その文脈の中で本当に役に立つAIをつくれるようになれば、AIは単なる効率化のツールではなく、<strong>「ブランド体験を共につくるパートナー」</strong>へと進化していきます。</p> <p>さらにこの道は、メタバースやデジタルツイン、シミュレーションといった、これまでAIとは別物として語られてきたテクノロジー群との融合にもつながっていきます。現実世界とデジタル空間がより密接に結びつく中で、AIがその<strong>頭脳</strong>として機能し、さまざまな体験やコミュニケーションをデザインしていく。その延長線上に、私たちの業界における<strong>「</strong><strong>AIを新しいメディアにしていく」</strong>というテーマが見えてきます。</p> <p>AIそのものがメディアとなり、生活者とブランド、企業と社会を結びつける新しい接点になっていく——。</p> <p>その世界を実現するためにも、博報堂ＤＹグループが持つクリエイティビティやブランド理解、生活者発想のノウハウをフル動員しながら、世界モデルをはじめとした新たな技術に挑んでいきたいと考えています。</p> <p>そして、その挑戦を通じて、博報堂ＤＹグループ自体を真にAIドリブンな組織へとトランスフォーメーションさせていくことが、私にとっての大きなテーマです。</p> <p>こうした中長期的な技術開発への挑戦を視野に入れながら、足元ではより具体的な<strong>全社変革</strong>にも取り組んでいます。まず一つ目の大きな目標は、博報堂ＤＹグループ全体でのAIトランスフォーメーションを完遂させることです。</p> <p>これまですでに、1万人以上のAIプロフェッショナル人材の育成を進めてきました。さらに、経営層に対してもAIの理解を深めてもらうために、若手社員が教師役となって経営層にAIを教える<strong>「</strong><strong>AIメンタリング」制度</strong>を導入し、トップレベルの知識とスキルを経営判断に生かしてもらう仕組みをつくっています。</p> <p>経営層と若手社員をペアにすることには大きな意味があります。若手社員はAIを日常的に使いこなしている世代であり、同時にAIに潜むリスクや懸念点もよく理解しています。この若手と経営層をペアにすることで、双方向の学びが生まれます。</p> <p>両者はオンラインで常時つながり、毎週もしくは隔週で対面セッションも行います。若手は<strong>家庭教師</strong>として社長や会長、副社長、役員といった経営層に<strong>「課題」</strong>を出し、それを実際にやってもらいます。</p> <p>経営層にとっても、このプロセスは単なるスキル習得にとどまりません。AIを体感的に理解する中で、<strong>「</strong><strong>AIをこう活用してほしい」「AIがこう進化するなら、我々のビジネスはこう変わらなければならない」</strong>といった経営的な洞察や戦略的視点が生まれていきます。その視座を若手に共有することで、若手の理解も一段と深まっていくのです。</p> <p>さらに興味深いのは、その“間”にいる部長や部門長の変化です。<strong>「社長と</strong><strong>AIの話をしたらしいな。その資料を見せてくれ」</strong>と、声をかける人が増え、結果的に中間層のAIに対する意識も変わっていきます。AIメンタリング制度は、経営層と若手の関係だけでなく、組織全体のAIリテラシーを底上げするダイナミズムを生み出しているのです。</p> <p>加えて、全社員がAIを活用して業務を刷新するBPR（Business Process Reengineering）にも取り組んでいます。<strong>「</strong><strong>AIを前提にした働き方」</strong>を全社に定着させ、誰もがAIを使いこなして生産性を高められる組織やプロセスを実現していく——。これを1〜2年というスピード感で進めていく必要があると考えています。</p> <p>同時に、お客さま向けのサービスの高度化にも注力していきます。これまでAIが先行して活用されてきたデジタルマーケティング領域にとどまらず、クリエイティブ、デザイン、ブランディングといった<strong>人の創造性</strong>が求められる領域でも、AIを活用して新しい価値を生み出していくことが重要です。AIを単なる効率化の手段としてではなく、人の創造性を拡張し、より良いアウトプットを導くパートナーとして生かしていく方向です。</p> <p>一方で、AI技術は日々進化しており、今日導入した技術が翌月には別の新技術に置き換わることも珍しくありません。ですから、単に技術を追いかけるのではなく、自分たちの中にあるノウハウの本質的な価値を見極め、それをAIとどう組み合わせるかがより重要になります。</p> <p>博報堂ＤＹグループとしても、AIを活用してサービスを継続的に進化させるために、技術の更新だけでなく、人と組織の知見を磨き続けることを徹底していきたいと考えています。</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why SaaS cost optimization is an operating model problem, not a budget exercise]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132844/why-saas-cost-optimization-is-an-operating-model-problem-not-a-budget-exercise.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132844/why-saas-cost-optimization-is-an-operating-model-problem-not-a-budget-exercise.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>When I was brought into a large digital transformation program as a subject matter expert, the mandate was clear before my laptop even opened: <em>“SaaS costs had become a concern, and leadership wanted to move quickly to rein them in.”</em></p> <p>The CFO had flagged ballooning subscription spend. Business leaders complained about overlapping tools. Procurement wanted to renegotiate contracts. From the outside, it looked like a familiar problem with an obvious solution — reduce licenses, consolidate vendors and stabilize spending.</p> <p>Early on, it became clear that SaaS cost optimization wasn’t really a financial problem. It was an operating model problem. And treating it purely as a budget exercise was about to make things worse.</p> <p>By the time I joined the program, the decision had already been made. SaaS costs were considered excessive, and leadership had acted quickly. Licenses were reduced, several platforms were slated for retirement and aggressive targets were set to bring spending down within the quarter.</p> <p>On paper, the initiative looked decisive. Early dashboards showed immediate savings, and leadership felt confident the problem was being addressed.</p> <p>What I walked into, however, was the aftermath. Teams were already adjusting to changes they hadn’t fully anticipated. Some employees no longer had access to tools embedded deeply in their daily workflows. Others were rebuilding lost functionality manually, while a few quietly adopted new, unapproved tools to fill the gaps — a pattern that often follows rapid tool consolidation efforts, as noted by Harvard Business Review in its <a href="https://hbr.org/2021/09/collaboration-overload-is-sinking-productivity" rel="nofollow">analysis of collaboration overload</a>.</p> <p>What stood out wasn’t resistance to cost discipline — it was confusion. People weren’t sure which platforms were still supported, who owned decisions going forward or how work was supposed to flow now. Productivity issues surfaced quickly, but they didn’t appear in SaaS spend reports. They showed up in longer cycle times, missed handoffs and growing frustration across teams.</p> <p>This wasn’t a failure of intent. It was the predictable outcome of treating SaaS cost optimization as a financial correction rather than an operating decision. The organization had moved fast to reduce spend, but without a clear understanding of dependencies, ownership and how work actually happened across systems.</p> <p>The cost problem was real — but the operational cost of fixing it the wrong way was becoming just as visible.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="saas-sprawl-is-rarely-accidental">SaaS sprawl is rarely accidental</h2> <p>When CIOs ask why SaaS costs spiral, the answer is rarely “poor discipline.” It’s usually structural.</p> <p>In the engagement I described, SaaS sprawl had accumulated over years for understandable reasons:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Business units bought tools to move faster.</li> <li>IT teams enabled experimentation during growth phases.</li> <li>Mergers brought duplicate platforms.</li> <li>Pandemic-era urgency favored speed over standardization.</li>
</ul> <p>No one made a single bad decision. Hundreds of reasonable decisions added up to an unreasonable outcome.</p> <p>When we conducted a portfolio review, we found well over a hundred SaaS applications in active use across the organization. A significant portion had overlapping functionality. Several had no clear business owner. A handful were mission-critical — but poorly documented or understood outside the teams that used them.</p> <p>Cutting costs without first mapping ownership, dependency and usage was like pulling wires out of a live control panel.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-real-driver-of-saas-waste-unclear-ownership">The real driver of SaaS waste: unclear ownership</h2> <p>One moment crystallized the problem for me.</p> <p>During a review session, I asked a simple question about one of the highest-cost platforms: <em>“Who owns this product?”</em></p> <p>The room went quiet.</p> <p>IT assumed the business owned it. The business assumed IT managed it. Procurement negotiated the contract. Security reviewed access annually. No one was accountable for adoption, value realization or lifecycle decisions.</p> <p>This lack of accountability wasn’t unique to that tool — it was systemic. Best-practice guidance on SaaS governance consistently emphasizes the importance of assigning a clearly named owner for every application, accountable for cost, security, compliance and ongoing value.</p> <p>Without that ownership, redundancy and unmanaged spend tend to persist across portfolios (as outlined in <a href="https://abnormal.ai/blog/saas-governance-best-practices)" rel="nofollow">this overview of SaaS governance best practices</a>.</p> <p>That tool wasn’t expensive because it was misused — it was expensive because it was ownerless.</p> <p>This is where many SaaS cost initiatives stall. CIOs focus on licenses and contracts, but the real issue is the absence of a product mindset. SaaS platforms behave like products, but many organizations manage them like utilities.</p> <p>Without clear ownership:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Usage decays quietly.</li> <li>Redundant tools creep in.</li> <li>Contracts auto-renew.</li> <li>No one feels responsible for retiring platforms.</li>
</ul> <p>Cost optimization fails not because leaders don’t try hard enough, but because no one is accountable for value.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-savings-create-downstream-costs">When “savings” create downstream costs</h2> <p>In another phase of the program, leadership decided to eliminate a niche workflow tool used by operations teams. The savings were modest, but the platform wasn’t widely understood, so it became an easy target.</p> <p>Within weeks, exception rates increased. Manual rework grew. Managers spent more time coordinating tasks informally. None of this showed up in the SaaS budget — but it showed up in cycle time and morale.</p> <p>A frontline manager told me, <em>“We didn’t realize how much that tool did until it was gone.”</em></p> <p>These downstream impacts are rarely captured in license reports, but they’re well documented. The hidden costs of SaaS sprawl — including security exposure and operational drag — often <a href="https://www.block64.com/blog/the-hidden-costs-of-saas-sprawl-why-its-happening-and-how-bad-its-getting" rel="nofollow">outweigh the savings achieved through blunt consolidation efforts</a>.</p> <p>This is the hidden danger of treating SaaS as interchangeable. Not all tools deliver value at scale, but the ones that do often embed themselves deeply into how work gets done. Removing them without redesigning the process creates invisible costs that finance dashboards never capture.</p> <p>True optimization requires understanding what breaks when a tool disappears.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="reframing-saas-cost-optimization-as-an-operating-decision">Reframing SaaS cost optimization as an operating decision</h2> <p>The turning point came when we paused the cost-cutting exercise and reframed the effort. Instead of asking <em>“How do we spend less?”</em> we asked:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Which platforms directly support critical workflows?</li> <li>Where do we have duplication without differentiation?</li> <li>Who is accountable for outcomes enabled by each tool?</li> <li>What capabilities must remain stable as we simplify?</li>
</ul> <p>We created a lightweight classification model:</p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Systems of record</strong> — protected, stable, tightly governed</li> <li><strong>Systems of differentiation</strong> — actively owned and optimized</li> <li><strong>Systems of experimentation</strong> — time-bound and sunset-driven</li>
</ol> <p>This allowed leadership to cut with intention instead of urgency. Tools without owners were flagged. Experimental platforms were given expiration dates. Core systems were protected from blunt reductions.</p> <p>Costs declined more slowly — but sustainably.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="governance-is-not-bureaucracy-when-its-done-right">Governance is not bureaucracy — when it’s done right</h2> <p>One of the most common objections I hear when SaaS governance comes up is that it will slow teams down. In theory, fewer controls feel like freedom. In practice, the absence of governance often creates more friction — unclear decisions, duplicated effort and constant rework.</p> <p>In this program, introducing governance wasn’t about adding process for its own sake. It was about clarifying ownership, decision rights and expectations. We established simple rules: every SaaS platform needed a named owner, usage and value had to be reviewed ahead of renewals, and new tools required a basic justification tied to an existing gap.</p> <p>None of this required a heavy PMO or extensive documentation to get started. What it required was discipline. And once those guardrails were in place, teams actually moved faster. Decisions that previously stalled due to ambiguity became easier to make. Redundant tools stopped creeping in.</p> <p>This aligns with broader research showing that structure and clarity don’t suppress innovation — they enable it. As <em>Harvard Business Review</em> has noted, well-designed processes and governance mechanisms help organizations innovate more effectively by <a href="https://hbr.org/2018/04/good-process-design-is-good-for-innovation" rel="nofollow">reducing friction and uncertainty, not increasing them</a>.</p> <p>In other words, governance wasn’t the obstacle. It was the enabler that allowed the organization to simplify its SaaS environment without breaking how work got done.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-cios-can-do-differently">What CIOs can do differently</h2> <p>From this and similar engagements, a few lessons stand out:</p> <p><strong>First, don’t start with procurement.</strong> Start with visibility. Map ownership, usage and dependency before touching contracts.</p> <p><strong>Second, assign product ownership.</strong> Every SaaS tool needs someone accountable for value, not just uptime.</p> <p><strong>Third, protect what works.</strong> Blunt cuts damage credibility. Preserve platforms that truly enable productivity.</p> <p><strong>Fourth, design for exit.</strong> If a tool is experimental, define when and how it will be retired.</p> <p><strong>Finally, treat optimization as continuous.</strong> SaaS cost discipline isn’t a one-time initiative — it’s an operating habit.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-bigger-lesson">The bigger lesson</h2> <p>The most effective SaaS cost programs I’ve seen weren’t about spending less. They were about focusing more. Fewer platforms, clearer ownership and stronger alignment between technology and work.</p> <p>In the end, the organization I worked with didn’t just reduce costs — it reduced noise. Leaders spent less time debating tools and more time improving outcomes.</p> <p>That’s the shift CIOs need to make. SaaS cost optimization isn’t about cutting subscriptions. It’s about designing an environment where technology earns its place.</p> <p><em>The views expressed are my own and do not represent the views of Deloitte or its clients.</em></p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Leapwork Research Shows Why AI in Testing Still Depends on Reliability, Not Just Innovation]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/leapwork-ai-testing/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/leapwork-ai-testing/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/leapwork-ai-testing/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771070027501.jpg"/><p>Leapwork recently released new research showing that while confidence in AI-driven software testing is growing rapidly, accuracy, stability, and ongoing manual effort remain decisive factors in how far teams are willing to trust automation.</p> <i>By Craig Risi</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Publishes Codex App Server Architecture for Unifying AI Agent Surfaces]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/opanai-codex-app-server/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/opanai-codex-app-server/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/opanai-codex-app-server/en/headerimage/OpenAI-Codex-App-Server-Header-1771326172649.jpeg"/><p>OpenAI has recently published a detailed architecture description of the Codex App Server, a bidirectional protocol that decouples the Codex coding agent's core logic from its various client surfaces. The App Server now powers every Codex experience, including the CLI, the VS Code extension, and the web app, through a single, stable API.</p> <i>By Eran Stiller</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Harness AI for HR Transformation]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/hr-transformation]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/hr-transformation]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[HR is at a crossroads: reinvent itself to deliver business value in the AI era or risk becoming irrelevant. CHROs need to act—now.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI’s energy wake-up call]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132833/ais-energy-wake-up-call.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132833/ais-energy-wake-up-call.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For the last couple of years, enterprises have doubled and tripled down on investments in AI-related initiatives. The board-level leadership at the Global 1000 enterprises has high expectations of the value that can be unleashed through the power of AI in growing the business as well as driving efficiencies. CIO and CAIO organizations have spent a lot of time and energy on addressing constraints such as data availability, governance and change management to enable value realization through AI initiatives. For the most part, enterprises have assumed unconstrained access to AI infrastructure through hyper-scalers. The exponential reduction in token costs has enabled broader adoption of AI use cases within enterprises.</p> <p>As generative AI, agentic systems and real-time inference move from pilots into production, CIO’s and enterprise AI leaders would be well advised to be cognizant of another constraint: energy availability and its impacts AI cost, scale and risk. Power, cooling and physical infrastructure and have not been commonly discussed within CIO organizations as a potential constraint.</p> <p>This article outlines AI’s energy wake-up call and why CIOs should pay attention to the impact of energy on AI while building their longer-term AI strategy.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ais-demand-for-power">AI’s demand for power</h2> <p>According to <a href="https://www.bain.com/insights/how-can-we-meet-ais-insatiable-demand-for-compute-power-technology-report-2025/" rel="nofollow">a study by Bain and Company</a>, AI Data centers and their commensurate needs for power are growing exponentially and are pushing towards 100 Gigawatts of new power demand in the US by 2030. For reference, the data center power demand in 2025 is about 30 Gigawatts and this represents a 35% CAGR over the next 5 years.</p> <p>Hyper-scalers are investing billions of dollars and are racing to build data centers. Investment in data centers are expected to reach $ 1 trillion within three years, according to <a href="https://www.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/industry/power-and-utilities/data-center-infrastructure-artificial-intelligence.html" rel="nofollow">a study by Deloitte</a>.</p> <p>However, they face several challenges, such as:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Grid stress.</strong> AI data centers can create large, concentrated clusters of 24 by 7 power demand, causing grid stress. Building new transmission lines can take between 7 and 10 years.</li> <li><strong>Sources of power are constrained.</strong> Currently, most of the demand is fueled by natural gas. There are significant supply challenges with other traditional sources, such as coal and renewable sources, such as wind and solar. Nuclear capacity has not been developed in the US for several decades, adding to the potential energy shortage.</li> <li><strong>Cooling requirements.</strong> Data centers use several cooling techniques, such as liquid cooling, air cooling, etc. The massive cooling requirement poses an enormous stress on water requirements. This also creates contention for water use by citizens in the municipality, agricultural needs, etc. and in some parts of the country have already <a href="https://wsbt.com/news/local/st-joseph-county-council-denies-rezoning-of-land-for-data-center-votes-7-2-marathon-meeting-hours-long-public-opinion-13-billion-dollar-project-amazon-new-carlisle-approval-process-plan-commission-st-joseph-county-indiana" rel="nofollow">created a political backlash</a>.</li> <li><strong>Regulatory constraints</strong>. In some states and municipalities, the permitting process may take a long time with a lot of uncertainties.</li> <li><strong>Equipment shortage.</strong> The data centers and their power infrastructure are dependent on several components — from steel and copper to switchgear and transformers. In many instances, the demand for these goods far exceeds the supply.</li> <li><strong>Talent shortage.</strong> The data center industry needs more trade skills, such as electricians and construction workers and there is a big gap between supply and demand.</li>
</ul> <p>There is also a concern about the ROI and economics of the aggressive data center and AI infrastructure build-out. Most of the hyper-scaler and AI infrastructure companies, such as Google and Microsoft, are moving from being asset-light to asset-heavy companies, raising concerns about their long-term valuations.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="dual-requirements-between-training-and-inference">Dual requirements between training and inference</h2> <p>Data centers and AI infrastructure will also have to deal with different requirements — power-hungry training needs versus latency-critical inference. Training workloads need high power densities and advanced liquid cooling techniques. Inference workloads need lower power densities, but low latency is critical and this would mean co-location with the applications and data workloads. In addition, inference workloads require creating a high-volume “always-on” background load.</p> <p>According to <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/technology-media-and-telecommunications/our-insights/the-next-big-shifts-in-ai-workloads-and-hyperscaler-strategies?cid=soc-web" rel="nofollow">a McKinsey study</a>, AI compute is moving towards an inference-heavy future with training and inference needs being approximately 50-50 by 2030.</p> <p>Data centers will have to align with this reality and combine both training and inference capabilities within the same campus.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mitigation-initiatives">Mitigation initiatives</h2> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-government-and-industry-partnership">1. Government and industry partnership</h3> <p>The industry has worked aggressively with the Federal Government to heighten the awareness of the energy needs for AI and is working on several strategies to mitigate this constraint. Power generation is one area where the US is playing catch-up with China, and there is a concern that this might make all the difference when it comes to winning the AI race.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Nuclear renaissance.</strong> The administration’s stated policy is to <a href="https://www.energy.gov/ne/articles/9-key-takeaways-president-trumps-executive-orders-nuclear-energy#:~:text=On%20May%2023%2C%20President%20Trump%20announced%20four,security%2C%20and%20reinvigorate%20the%20nuclear%20industrial%20base" rel="nofollow">unleash American energy through a series of investments, public-private partnerships and deregulation</a>. Innovations such as on-site generation and micro-grids are being adopted with support from the Department of Energy (DOE). DOE has taken numerous <a href="https://www.energy.gov/ne/articles/9-key-takeaways-president-trumps-executive-orders-nuclear-energy" rel="nofollow">actions</a> to <a href="https://www.hunton.com/insights/legal/recent-nuclear-executive-orders-to-accelerate-us-nuclear-renaissance" rel="nofollow">accelerate the development of next-generation</a> nuclear technology. Small Modular reactors and advanced nuclear technologies are being supported through the DOE’s programs. Significant investments are being made in research to <a href="https://www.publicpower.org/periodical/article/nuclear-renaissance" rel="nofollow">harness nuclear fusion</a>.</li> <li><strong>Regulatory changes.</strong> There are also <a href="https://www.ferc.gov/news-events/news/ferc-directs-nations-largest-grid-operator-create-new-rules-embrace-innovation-and" rel="nofollow">regulatory initiatives at the Federal and state levels</a> to insulate residential rate payers from significant cost increases due to data center power usage to <a href="https://www.energypolicy.columbia.edu/how-does-announcement-on-data-centers-could-impact-the-grid/" rel="nofollow">prevent backlash from average citizens</a>.</li>
</ul> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-innovation-and-investments">2. Innovation and investments</h3> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Chip design.</strong> Several architectural techniques, such as in-memory, wafer-scale and photonic, are being developed to drive down energy consumption.</li> <li><strong>Software techniques.</strong> Several software techniques can <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2023/new-tools-available-reduce-energy-that-ai-models-devour-1005" rel="nofollow">dramatically reduce energy consumption during AI model training</a> without requiring new hardware infrastructure. One example of such a technique is “Hyperparameter optimization and early stopping.”</li> <li><strong>Advanced cooling solutions.</strong> These include “Direct to chip liquid cooling” and “immersion cooling,” which have the potential to reduce energy consumption significantly.</li> <li><strong>Investments.</strong> Electric and gas utility capex is expected to <a href="https://www.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/industry/power-and-utilities/data-center-infrastructure-artificial-intelligence.html" rel="nofollow">surpass US $1 trillion cumulatively within the next five years (2025–2029)</a>, and most of this is driven by AI demand.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-cios-should-take-into-consideration">What CIO’s should take into consideration</h2> <p>CIO’s need to be aware of the above-mentioned correlation between energy constraints and the future availability of AI capacity and take this into account as part of their longer-term AI roadmap. Here are some of the practical steps that the CIO’s should consider:</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="incorporate-the-impact-of-energy-into-their-ai-roi-models">Incorporate the impact of energy into their AI ROI models</h3> <p>Power and cooling costs can materially change the economics of AI initiatives over time.</p> <p>In traditional enterprise IT, power costs were a background consideration. In the AI world, the impact of power and cooling is in the critical path.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="demand-energy-transparency-from-vendors">Demand energy transparency from vendors</h3> <p>CIO’s should ask cloud and colocation partners about regional constraints, power sourcing and expansion timelines. Data Centers designed before large-scale GPU adoption might have limitations to scalability.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="coordinate-beyond-it">Coordinate beyond IT</h3> <p>CIO’s should involve Facilities, procurement, finance and sustainability teams to seek their inputs and they can help impact AI success.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="plan-for-resilience-not-just-scale">Plan for resilience, not just scale</h2> <p>If all AI workloads live in one environment, risk is concentrated. Hybrid models become more relevant for energy predictability and risk management.</p> <p>Mission-critical AI systems may justify on-site generation or microgrid investments.</p> <p>As enterprises move towards adopting AI at scale, CIO’s, CAIO’s and other leaders should pay close attention to the data center economics that is driven significantly by energy considerations. This will enable them tune their AI strategy to ensure that there is more predictability in costs and enable them to deliver the ROI that the business expects.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Does AI Make the Agile Manifesto Obsolete?]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-agile-manifesto-debate/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-agile-manifesto-debate/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-agile-manifesto-debate/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1770724261142.jpg"/><p>Capgemini's Steve Jones argues AI agents building apps in hours have killed the Agile Manifesto, as its human-centric principles don't fit agentic SDLCs. While Forrester reports 95% still find Agile relevant, Kent Beck proposes "augmented coding" and AWS suggests "Intent Design" over sprint planning. The debate: Is Agile dead, or evolving for AI collaboration?</p> <i>By Steef-Jan Wiggers</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[7 tips for shedding a back-office IT mentality]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130957/7-tips-for-shedding-a-back-office-it-mentality.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130957/7-tips-for-shedding-a-back-office-it-mentality.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The CIO role is constantly evolving. Proof can be found in the way IT leaders now routinely interact with a wide range of customers, partners, vendors, and other business-focused parties. Still, old views can be hard to shake, particularly when other C-level leaders continue to view the CIO position as a strictly back-office operation.</p> <p>Are you doing all you can to establish your reputation as a true front-facing leader? Here are seven tips that will help you shed your back-office status forever.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-build-strong-cross-functional-collaboration-experiences-and-skills">1. Build strong cross-functional collaboration experiences and skills</h2> <p>A back-office mentality tasks CIOs with keeping systems running versus becoming a strategic productivity and innovation driver, says Sam Sabet, CTO at audio products firm Shure. He notes that recent research conducted by market research firm IDC, sponsored by Shure, found that CIOs with a back-office IT mindset tend to underinvest in collaboration and the workplace experience.</p> <p>“Collaboration is then simply seen as something nice to have and, as a result, the organization struggles to translate IT investments into real ROI,” he says.</p> <p>Sabet says that successful CIOs partner closely with business unit leaders, ensuring that technology is aligned with outcomes. They will also readily collaborate with HR and workplace teams to better understand the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/220442/what-is-employee-experience-your-key-to-talent-retention-and-recruitment.html">employee experience</a>, and work with technology partners who comprehend collaboration as an ecosystem.</p> <p>“Organizations that embrace cross-functional collaboration are more likely to outperform their peers,” he adds.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-exert-leadership-with-a-focus-on-business-outcomes">2. Exert leadership — with a focus on business outcomes</h2> <p>An IT back-office happens when IT operates purely as a support function and a cost center with a generic user experience perspective rather than focusing on specific, business-enabling experiences, says <a href="https://isg-one.com/about-us/people/ola-chowning" rel="nofollow">Ola Chowning</a>, a partner at technology research and advisory firm ISG.</p> <p>CIOs with back-office IT mentalities are typically more concerned with stability, incident management resolution, and uptime rather than on innovation, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2092145/secrets-of-business-driven-it-orgs.html">improving business outcomes</a>, and <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/193734/secrets-of-successful-business-it-co-creation.html">operating as a business partner</a>, Chowning states. She notes that back-office mentality is often characterized by functional segregation incorporating an infrastructure that’s separate from applications with no end-to-end accountability or outcome focus.</p> <p>“As a result, the CIO often works in an order-taker mode, rather than having a consistent seat at the table and discussing how technology can support the business’s direction and strategy,” she says.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-work-to-strengthen-your-enterprise-influence">3. Work to strengthen your enterprise influence</h2> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alfredobernal/" rel="nofollow">Alfredo Bernal</a>, CTO at public relations firm M Booth, agrees that a back-office IT mentality treats technology as a support function primarily focused on uptime, tickets, and cost control rather than as a driver of growth and competitive advantage. “In this model, success is defined by stability and risk avoidance, not by business outcomes,” he says.</p> <p>The dangers of such a mindset are significant. “Shadow IT and fragmented tools proliferate, competitors move faster by embracing automation and AI, and the CIO gradually loses influence at the executive table,” he says. Over time, IT is viewed as a cost center rather than a strategic partner, making it more vulnerable during budget reviews and organizational change.</p> <p>In addition to initiating a pivot to business-driven IT, CIOs stuck in back-office purgatory should also seek ways to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4059033/8-ways-cios-undermine-their-enterprise-influence.html">elevate their influence across the enterprise</a>.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-seek-competitiveness">4. Seek competitiveness</h2> <p>To shed a back-office IT mentality, technology must be viewed as a source of competitive advantage, says <a href="https://euristiq.com/author/pavlotkhir/" rel="nofollow">Pavlo Tkhir</a>, CTO at software development company Euristiq. Otherwise, IT will continue to emphasize keep-the-lights-on goals and metrics over transforming the business.</p> <p>“I’ve seen this in companies where IT decisions are made solely based on minimizing risk and cost savings, rather than customer impact or growth,” he says.</p> <p>The signs of a back-office mentality are quite noticeable among CIOs: a focus on uptime and SLAs instead of business outcomes, a lack of participation in product discussions, a fear of experimentation, and a chronic “we’re not ready” mentality, Tkhir says. The danger is that the business eventually begins to bypass IT, leading to the emergence of outsourced vendors and disparate solutions. Eventually, security risks, costs, and technical debt increase, and IT loses its credibility.</p> <p>CEOs, product leaders, and even engineering teams can help CIOs get back on track, especially when IT begins to speak the language of the business, such as feature delivery speed, revenue impact, and customer retention, Tkhir says. “The only way to prevent a return to back-office thinking is by integrating IT into the company’s strategy and regularly measuring its contribution — not in servers and tickets, but in business results.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-look-outward">5. Look outward</h2> <p>CIOs often have an inward-looking mindset where success is measured by boxes checked and processes completed, rather than achieving meaningful business outcomes, says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sumeet-chabria-a683617/" rel="nofollow">Sumeet Chabria</a>, an executive instructor at Carnegie Mellon University’s Heinz College.</p> <p>“You see it when IT operates as a silo focusing on ‘tech for tech’s sake’ without connecting delivery to business priorities,” he explains. “The CIO stops spending time with business executives, and in return, the business stops viewing IT as a partner and starts treating it like a vendor.”</p> <p>In an AI and digital economy, a back-office mentality is an existential threat, Chabria warns. “A back-office mentality creates a culture where people get promoted for compliance rather than impact,” he says. “This erodes brand value and causes top performers to leave because they can’t see the connection between their work and the company’s success.”</p> <p>To become a true front-facing leader requires a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4085392/5-business-concepts-it-leaders-should-master.html">strong knowledge of business fluency</a>, Chabria says. “A CIO must understand core value drivers and P&amp;L as well as the CEO does.” He adds that the CIO should also have an enterprise mindset. “Tying compensation to business results forces the right orientation.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-align-with-how-the-organization-at-large-operates">6. Align with how the organization at large operates</h2> <p>Back-office mentality arrives when IT is viewed primarily as a cost center, focused on maintenance, risk avoidance, and internal support, rather than as a strategic driver of revenue and productivity, agrees <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-torgerson-lucid/" rel="nofollow">David Torgerson</a>, Lucid Software’s vice president of technology and security.</p> <p>“In this mindset, IT decisions are reactive, compliance-driven, and disconnected from business outcomes,” he states. “Security, AI, and infrastructure investments are treated as boxes to check instead of essential tools for growth.”</p> <p>Getting back on track requires collaboration beyond IT alone, Torgerson says. “CIOs can benefit by working closely with teams across the organization to ground decisions in real workflows and to measure how long it actually takes to identify and respond to risk,” he advises.</p> <p>Torgerson also suggests asking questions focused on risk and payoff. “This means shifting away from a ‘don’t trust anything’ approach and moving toward clearly defined validation processes that reflect modern collaboration.” It also means reassessing industry certifications based on demand, maturity, and value, and recognizing that no single use case will justify investment on its own. “Staying aligned with how the organizations operates is also critical,” he adds.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-build-business-acumen">7. Build business acumen</h2> <p>If colleagues don’t include you in business activities because you’re viewed as “technical,” that’s a warning sign, says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesstanger/" rel="nofollow">James Stanger</a>, chief technology evangelist at CompTIA, a nonprofit trade group that provides vendor-neutral training and certifications.</p> <p>Stanger states he recently witnessed a large Australian bank focus solely on technical implementation of a data collection project. “The CIO confessed that she hadn’t taken adequate measures to understand the business need of the project,” he says. “As a result, the project wasn’t able to address customer expectations as much as expected.”</p> <p>As a CIO, think of yourself as a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3966301/customer-centric-it-strategies-for-delivering-winning-customer-experiences.html">customer-oriented guardrail or rumble strip</a>, Stanger suggests. “Once you see colleagues failing to think in terms of the customer, put mechanisms in place so that these individuals are nudged, shaken, or otherwise brought into the right mentality.”</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI isn’t the risk — not being able to explain it is]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132817/ai-isnt-the-risk-not-being-able-to-explain-it-is.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132817/ai-isnt-the-risk-not-being-able-to-explain-it-is.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-the-emerging-tech-conversation-feels-incomplete">Why the emerging tech conversation feels incomplete</h2> <p>I keep hearing the same emerging tech story repeated: better models, smarter copilots, more autonomous agents. The demos look impressive, but they often miss what is happening inside real organizations.</p> <p>From where I sit, the challenge is no longer whether AI works. It is whether we can run it responsibly once it is embedded in day-to-day operations.</p> <p>Many organizations have already moved beyond experimentation. AI is shaping customer interactions, internal workflows, operational decisions and risk exposure. That changes the conversation. It is not about potential anymore. It is about accountability.</p> <p>When something goes wrong, the questions are simple and direct:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Why did the system recommend this action?</li> <li>Why did it flag this person, case or transaction?</li> <li>Why did an automated workflow trigger that decision?</li> <li>Who owns the outcome when AI is part of the chain?</li>
</ul> <p>These questions rarely appear during a pilot. They surface during incidents, audits, escalations and senior stakeholder reviews, when trust is on the line. In those moments, “the model decided” is not a real answer. Neither is “we cannot see inside it”.</p> <p>That is why I think the most important “emerging” topic is not the next wave of AI capability. It is the control layer that makes AI safe to adopt at scale.</p> <p>Explainability sits at the centre of that. Not as a specialist feature, but as an enterprise requirement CIOs will increasingly be expected to own. If AI is going to influence decisions that affect customers, money or compliance, we need to explain what happened and why, in plain language, with evidence we can stand behind.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">How AI quietly became a decision-maker</h2> <p>A lot of AI content still frames adoption as a future state, but in most organizations I work with, it is already here. Not as a single system labelled AI, but as a layer embedded into everyday processes.</p> <p>AI rarely arrives with a big launch moment. It shows up in small ways that feel harmless at first: a recommendation that nudges an outcome, a model that prioritizes one case over another, a chatbot that changes what a customer does next.</p> <p>Over time, those small decisions become operational reality.</p> <p>In many businesses, AI is no longer just generating insights. It is influencing actions. Even when a human approves the final step, AI is often shaping the direction of the outcome.</p> <p>That is where accountability starts to shift.</p> <p>When AI sits inside workflows that touch customers, finance or compliance, the impact is no longer purely technical. It becomes a business outcome that leaders have to defend.</p> <p>The pattern is familiar: a pilot proves value, adoption accelerates, AI spreads into more systems, then the first serious challenge arrives through a complaint, an audit or an unexpected failure. That is when the organization realizes the AI is not simply supporting decisions, it is shaping them at scale.</p> <p>CIOs are usually pulled in at the moment clarity is needed most. Stakeholders want to know what happened, why it happened and what controls exist to prevent a repeat. Traditional IT governance struggles here because AI does not behave like conventional software. It can degrade over time, behave inconsistently across edge cases and produce confident outputs even when it is wrong.</p> <p>Deploying AI is not the hard part anymore. Operating it with discipline is. Explainability is one of the controls that makes that possible.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a>Why explainable AI is emerging now</h2> <p>Explainable AI has been around for years, but it is only recently becoming unavoidable at the leadership level. What has changed is not the idea. It is the pressure around it.</p> <p>In the last 12 to 24 months, I have seen explainability shift from a “nice to have” to something stakeholders actively ask for. AI is no longer limited to isolated pilots. It is running in production, across multiple functions and often influencing customer outcomes. That creates a simple expectation: if a decision affects a person, a transaction or a business-critical process, the organization should be able to explain what happened and why.</p> <p>Three forces are driving this.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Governance and regulatory expectations are catching up.</strong> CIOs are being asked to demonstrate oversight, not just performance. Even when specific rules do not apply to a given use case, the direction is clear. Frameworks like the <a href="https://artificialintelligenceact.eu/ai-act-explorer/" rel="nofollow">EU AI Act</a> are pushing organizations towards stronger accountability and more defensible decision-making.</li> <li><strong>AI systems are becoming more interconnected.</strong> Many deployments now combine models, retrieval, workflow automation, business rules and human approvals. When outcomes are shaped by multiple components, it becomes difficult to explain decisions after the fact unless explainability is designed in from the start.</li> <li><strong>The tolerance for <em>mostly right</em> is shrinking.</strong> Early pilots can absorb a few errors. Production systems cannot. If AI influences customer service, fraud detection, HR screening, pricing or compliance workflows, small failure rates become serious issues at scale.</li>
</ul> <p>Explainability can no longer be treated as a technical detail to address after the model is built. When AI influences outcomes tied to customers, revenue, compliance or operational risk, the question stops being “does it work?” and becomes “can we stand behind it?” That shift makes explainability a leadership responsibility, not just a data science concern.</p> <p>For CIOs, explainability now sits alongside core enterprise controls such as security, privacy, resilience and auditability, aligned with expectations around transparency and accountability reflected in the <a href="https://www.oecd.org/en/topics/sub-issues/ai-principles.html" rel="nofollow">OECD AI Principles</a>. In practice, it shapes what gets approved for production, how systems are governed across their lifecycle, and the decisions made in procurement and architecture. The priority is evidence that supports audits, investigations and stakeholder confidence, not just accuracy.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">The agentic effect on opacity and risk</h2> <p>Agentic systems raise the stakes because they do more than generate answers. They plan, choose actions, call tools and move work forward across systems. That is powerful, but it also changes the risk profile.</p> <p>With a traditional application, you can usually trace a failure back to a specific rule, input or component. With agentic systems, the path is rarely that clean. Decisions can be shaped by multiple steps, multiple prompts, changing context and external data sources. Two runs of the same workflow can produce different outcomes, even when the goal is the same.</p> <p>This is where opacity becomes a real operational issue and why explainable AI has moved from academic interest to practical necessity, as outlined in work from the <a href="https://aiethics.turing.ac.uk/modules/explainability/?modulepage=safety-explanation">Alan Turing Institute</a>.</p> <p>If an agent triggers an action that affects a customer, a payment or a compliance workflow, you need to know what led to that decision. Not in vague terms, but with enough detail to investigate, explain and correct it. Without that, incidents become harder to diagnose, teams lose confidence and leaders end up limiting adoption to avoid risk.</p> <p>I have also seen a second-order problem appear with agentic systems: responsibility gets blurred.</p> <p>When an outcome is driven by a chain of automated steps, ownership can become unclear. Was it the model? The prompt? The retrieval layer? The workflow design? The data source? The integration? The person who approved the rollout? In an enterprise environment, those questions matter because they drive accountability, remediation and future governance.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-i-believe-cios-should-prioritize-next">What I believe CIOs should prioritize next</h2> <p>If explainability is going to matter in practice, it has to show up in delivery, not just in governance documents. I do not think this is solved by one policy or one specialist team. It comes down to a few choices that shape what gets built, what gets approved and what gets scaled.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>First, I would separate systems that inform from systems that act. A tool that summarizes information is one thing. A system that triggers actions in production is another. The closer it gets to real outcomes, the higher the bar for control and evidence.</li> <li>Second, I would require traceability by default. When a system produces an output, I would want to know what it used to reach that conclusion. What data was involved, what context was pulled in, what logic was applied and what happened next. This is not about paperwork. It is about being able to investigate quickly when something looks wrong.</li> <li>Third, I would treat explainability as part of the build, not something to bolt on later. If you only start asking for explanations after an incident, you are already behind. It needs to be designed in, tested properly and checked over time as the environment changes.</li> <li>Fourth, I would make ownership explicit. Every workflow needs a named business owner and a named technical owner. When an outcome is challenged, it should be obvious who is accountable for the behavior, the controls and the fix.</li> <li>Finally, I would focus on communication as much as engineering. Explainability is only useful if the people who manage risk can understand it. The goal is not to impress specialists. The goal is to give decision makers enough clarity to approve, challenge or stop a system with confidence.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">From AI capability to AI credibility</h2> <p>For the last couple of years, the focus has been on capability. Bigger models, faster delivery, more automation, more autonomy. That progress is real and it has unlocked serious value.</p> <p>But I think the next phase will be defined by credibility.</p> <p>CIOs will not be judged on whether they can deploy new systems. They will be judged on whether those systems can be trusted, governed and defended when challenged. That is a different standard and it changes what “good” looks like.</p> <p>In that world, explainability is not a constraint. It is an enabler. It is what allows teams to scale adoption without relying on blind trust. It gives leaders a way to approve use cases with confidence, respond to incidents with evidence and improve systems based on facts rather than assumptions.</p> <p>If I were advising my team as a CIO today, I would not tell them to slow down. I would tell them to build the control layer as they scale. That means designing for traceability, defining ownership and making sure decisions can be explained in plain language.</p> <p>Because the real risk is not that AI will be too weak. The risk is that it will be deployed faster than the organization can control it.</p> <p>And once trust is lost, it is very difficult to win back.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[La IA en la atención al cliente: ni el ahorro ni el servicio será el esperado]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4133056/la-ia-en-la-atencion-al-cliente-ni-el-ahorro-ni-el-servicio-sera-el-esperado.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4133056/la-ia-en-la-atencion-al-cliente-ni-el-ahorro-ni-el-servicio-sera-el-esperado.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>El temor a que la IA sustituya los puestos de trabajo humanos es una de las principales preocupaciones de muchos empleados en todo el mundo. Una de las razones que se suelen esgrimir para justificar la sustitución de empleados por la IA es la percepción de que el uso de la inteligencia artificial para desempeñar una función será más rentable. Esta suposición está teniendo un impacto en diversos sectores, ya que las grandes empresas tecnológicas estadounidenses, en particular, están recortando un gran número de puestos de trabajo, alegando los avances de la IA y la automatización.</p> <p>Sin embargo, un reciente <strong>informe de Gartner</strong> cuestiona esta suposición. Al menos en el ámbito del servicio de atención al cliente, los analistas de Gartner predicen que el coste de la IA generativa por solución de problema superará los 3 dólares en 2030. Este cálculo incluye todos los costes incurridos al responder a una consulta de un cliente, por ejemplo. Según Gartner, esto haría que <strong>el uso de la IA generativa fuera más caro que el coste de muchos empleados de centros de atención telefónica en ubicaciones extraterritoriales</strong>.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="los-costes-de-la-ia-se-disparan">Los costes de la IA se disparan</h2> <p>Los analistas de Gartner citan las siguientes razones por las que los costes de la IA para las organizaciones de atención al cliente se dispararán:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Aumento de los costes de los centros de datos</li> <li>Las subvenciones actuales de los proveedores de IA para las cargas de trabajo acabarán cediendo paso al afán de lucro.</li> <li>Casos de uso cada vez más complejos que consumen más recursos y requieren especialistas altamente cualificados.</li>
</ul> <p>“Los responsables de atención al cliente están decididos a utilizar la IA para reducir costes, pero el retorno de esas inversiones está lejos de estar garantizado”, según dice Patrick Quinlan, director senior de análisis de Gartner, en un comunicado sobre los resultados. “La automatización total será prohibitivamente cara para la mayoría de las organizaciones; en su lugar, las organizaciones líderes utilizarán la IA para impulsar la participación de los clientes en lugar de para reducir costes”, predice.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mejora-de-la-experiencia-del-cliente-con-la-ia">Mejora de la experiencia del cliente con la IA</h2> <p>Incluso sin tener en cuenta la desfavorable relación de costes, los expertos de Gartner creen que el servicio de atención al cliente no podrá funcionar sin la interacción humana a largo plazo. Más bien al contrario: predicen que los cambios normativos relacionados con la IA aumentarán el volumen de servicios prestados en un 30% para 2028. Esto llevaría a muchos clientes a ejercer su derecho a una persona de contacto humana y a optar por no utilizar un agente de IA.</p> <p>Como resultado, Quinlan estima que las empresas podrían verse obligadas a «recontratar agentes humanos, posiblemente en mayor número o con un salario más alto que el que pagaban anteriormente. Si no se mantiene un nivel adecuado de personal, la experiencia del cliente podría deteriorarse, ya que los clientes tendrían que esperar mucho tiempo para hablar con una persona».</p> <p>Dado el aumento de los costes de la IA generativa, Gartner prevé un cambio estratégico en los próximos años: la mayoría de las empresas abandonarán sus esfuerzos por reducir costes mediante la automatización y perseguirán otros objetivos. Para aquellos que utilizan la IA no solo para resolver problemas, sino también para crear valor a lo largo de todo el recorrido del cliente, esto supone una clara oportunidad de diferenciación, según la empresa.</p> <p>“Los responsables de atención al cliente recurrirán a la IA para mejorar la experiencia del cliente”, según Quinlan. “Mirarán más allá de la optimización de costes y se fijarán en otras ventajas, como el aumento del valor del ciclo de vida del cliente, la tasa de recompra y la fidelidad a la marca”.</p> <p>Dado que los clientes esperarán un servicio proactivo y personalizado, los pioneros en este ámbito han obtenido una clara ventaja competitiva.</p> <p>La IA en el sector de la atención al cliente tiene margen de mejora</p> <p>Sin embargo, Gartner reconoce que pasará algún tiempo antes de que la IA pueda mejorar de forma sostenible la experiencia del cliente en el servicio de atención al cliente. Según Emily Potosky, directora sénior de investigación de servicio y asistencia al cliente de Gartner, la tecnología aún no está lo suficientemente madura. No puede sustituir por completo la experiencia, la empatía y el criterio de los empleados humanos.</p> <p>“Confiar únicamente en la IA ahora es prematuro y podría tener consecuencias no deseadas”, afirma la analista. Una de esas consecuencias es que la mitad de las empresas que despidieron a empleados para sustituirlos por IA volverán a aumentar la contratación de personal en 2027.</p> <p>Una encuesta de Gartner de octubre de 2025 refuerza esta predicción: de los 321 ejecutivos de servicio y asistencia al cliente encuestados, solo el 20 % había reducido realmente su plantilla debido a la IA. Sin embargo, la mayoría afirmó que su plantilla se mantenía estable porque ahora atendían a más clientes.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI in customer service: Not the cost-saver you think]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130943/why-ai-is-not-a-cost-saving-model-in-customer-service.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130943/why-ai-is-not-a-cost-saving-model-in-customer-service.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The fear that AI will replace human jobs is a major concern for many employees worldwide. One reason often given for job displacement via AI is the perception that use of artificial intelligence to perform a role will be more cost-effective. This assumption is having an impact on various industries, as large US tech companies in particular cut large numbers of jobs, citing the advancements of AI and automation.</p> <p>But a <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-01-26-gartner-predicts-genai-cost-per-resolution-for-customer-service-will-exceed-offshore-human-agent-costs-by-2030" rel="nofollow">recent report from Gartner</a> challenges this assumption. At least in the area of ​​customer service, Gartner analysts predict that the cost of generative AI per problem solution will exceed $3 by 2030. This calculation includes all costs incurred in answering a customer inquiry, for example. According to Gartner, this would make use of gen AI more expensive than the cost of many call center employees in offshore locations.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-costs-are-exploding">AI costs are exploding</h2> <p>Gartner analysts cite the following as the reason why AI costs for customer service organizations will explode:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Rising data center costs</li> <li>Current AI ​​provider subsidization of workloads thus far eventually giving way to the profit motive</li> <li>Increasingly complex use cases that consume more resources and require highly qualified specialists</li>
</ul> <p>“Customer service leaders are determined to use AI to reduce costs, but return on those investments is far from guaranteed,” Patrick Quinlan, Gartner senior director analyst, explained in a release about the findings.</p> <p>“Full automation will be prohibitively expensive for most organizations; instead, leading organizations will use AI to drive customer engagement rather than to cut costs,” he predicts.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="improved-customer-experience-with-ai">Improved customer experience with AI</h2> <p>Even without considering the unfavorable cost ratio, Gartner experts believe that customer service will not be able to function without human interaction in the long term. Quite the contrary: They predict that regulatory changes related to AI will increase the volume of supported services by 30% by 2028. This would lead many customers to exercise their right to a human contact person and opt against an AI agent.</p> <p>As a result, Quinlan estimates that companies may even be forced to “rehire human agents, possibly at higher numbers or at a higher salary than they previously paid. Failure to maintain appropriate staffing levels could lead to deterioration of the customer experience, with customers waiting for long periods to speak to a human.”</p> <p>Given the rising costs of gen AI, Gartner anticipates a strategic shift in the coming years: Most companies will abandon their efforts to reduce costs through automation and pursue other goals instead. For those who use AI not only to solve problems but also to create value along the entire customer journey, this presents a clear differentiation opportunity, according to the firm.</p> <p>“Customer service leaders will turn to AI to improve the customer experience,” according to Quinlan. “They’ll look beyond cost optimization to other benefits, such as increasing customer lifetime value, repurchase rate and brand loyalty.”</p> <p>Since customers will expect proactive and personalized service, pioneers here have gained a clear competitive advantage.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-in-the-customer-sector-has-room-for-improvement">AI in the customer sector has room for improvement</h2> <p>Gartner acknowledges, however, that it will be some time before AI can sustainably improve the customer experience in customer service. According to Emily Potosky, senior director of research for customer service and support at Gartner, the technology is not yet mature enough. It cannot fully replace the expertise, empathy, and judgment of human employees.</p> <p>“Relying solely on AI now is premature and could lead to unintended consequences,” the analyst said. One such consequence is that half of all companies that laid off employees to replace them with AI will increase their hiring of people again by 2027.</p> <p>A <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-12-02-gartner-survey-finds-only-20-percent-of-customer-service-leaders-report-ai-driven-headcount-reduction" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Gartner survey from October 2025</a> reinforces this prediction: Of the 321 customer service and support executives surveyed, only 20% had actually reduced staff due to AI. The majority, however, stated that their headcount remained stable because they were now serving more customers.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI is about to get really weird. CIOs better be prepared.]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4131846/ai-is-about-to-get-really-weird-cios-better-be-prepared.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4131846/ai-is-about-to-get-really-weird-cios-better-be-prepared.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>When it comes to what AI has in store for your everyday working CIO, “disconcerting” might not be a strong enough word. IT leaders must be prepared for every disconcerting scenario they can imagine.</p> <p>For example, at the risk of distracting you from my own pearls of wisdom and brilliant insights, I suggest you stop reading further and first soak in “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/12/business/media/ai-defamation-libel-slander.html" rel="nofollow">Who Pays When A.I. Is Wrong?</a>” from the New York Times. And don’t just skim it. Read it, because as CIO you’re going to find yourself dealing with issues like these — and likely very soon.</p> <p>The very short version: Wolf River Electric’s customers were cancelling contracts. Why? Because Google searches revealed that the Minnesota-based solar contractor had settled a lawsuit with the state attorney general over deceptive sales practices. One problem: The lawsuit never happened.</p> <p>So, Wolf River Electric sued Google on the grounds that Google’s search results were defamatory and seriously damaging.</p> <p>Which doesn’t seem unreasonable, not that I claim expertise in the ins and outs of libel law. Google, after all, developed the search tools, deployed them, and managed every element of the search ecosystem that caused the damage.</p> <p>As Google doesn’t provide a warranty on the accuracy and reliability of its search results, it would seem to be insulated from liability. But lawsuit or no lawsuit, Google would probably prefer not to shine a spotlight on its unwillingness to defend its search accuracy. The situation is, in any event, the sort of thing lawyers will love to debate.</p> <p>CIOs, less so.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-this-matters-to-it-leaders">Why this matters to IT leaders</h2> <p>The courts will eventually sort this out, so we’ll leave the judiciary in peace, trusting it to do its job of deciding who should owe whom what. As CIO this might strike you as a spectator sport, rather than something that will hit you where you live.</p> <p>But you aren’t off the hook just yet.</p> <p>Imagine your IT team is tasked with deploying some sort of AI evaluation system for your company’s customers, using one or another of the currently popular AI ecosystems as its platform.</p> <p>Then something goes amiss, and your customers, having trusted your system, experience some sort of damage, and the lawyers get involved.</p> <p>Who’s at fault for the damage? The AI tools vendor? Whoever provided the LLM? Your software quality assurance team?</p> <p>Or maybe it’s nobody, because the risk of imperfect results is intrinsic to software and always has been.</p> <p>It’s hard to predict how the legal issues would play out. It’s easier to predict how blame would be allocated within a typical business organization.</p> <p>As usual, if technology is involved, IT would be left holding the bag.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-curious-case-of-mervyn-voldemort">The curious case of Mervyn Voldemort</h2> <p>But never mind all that. The train to AI Weirdsville is only just now leaving the station. So, try this on for size:</p> <p>Someone dies — someone wealthy, influential, and prominent. They leave behind enough content of various forms — speeches, essays, blog posts, video clips, and so on — to be repurposed as a large language model.</p> <p>The technology exists, right now give or take a year or so, to build a generative AI that could read in the decedent’s content and output new, original content with substance and style that’s indistinguishable from the decedent’s style (for written content), or voice (for deepfake audio and video).</p> <p>Now, put these capabilities in the hands of a volitional AI — an AI that doesn’t just figure out how to achieve a goal, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4106778/what-agentic-ai-really-means-for-it-risk-management.html">but that sets the goals it achieves</a>. What do we have? We have enough elements for an AI to pass a “reverse Turing test” — to be indistinguishable from a living human being.</p> <p>And if it’s a volitional AI it’s hard to avoid concluding that, given its abilities or likely abilities to:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Set its own goals</li> <li>Mimic someone who was, once upon a time, a real human being</li> <li>Find ways to dodge typical information security countermeasures</li>
</ul> <p>We’re on the verge of a volitional AI claiming the recent decedent’s identity as its own. The only missing piece of this unnerving puzzle is volitional AI. With it in the mix we can imagine an AI laying claim to all its carbon-based predecessor’s assets, relationships, rights, and privileges.</p> <p>Nobody would have to program this “avatar in real life.” That’s one of the aspects of volitional AI that’s so concerning: The volitional AI we’re imagining would decide it wants to assume a recently deceased person’s identity, and whose identity it would be advantageous to assume; scour the decedent’s opus for vulnerabilities, build its own LLM out of that individual’s life’s work, and then … welcome to the world of AI-based immortality.</p> <p>Because let us say that Mervyn Voldemort has just died. His heirs will find themselves challenged to explain how Voldemort’s estate thinks it owns Voldemort’s property when a living, breathing — well, not actually breathing — entity that passes every test of identity as well or better than Voldemort’s executor can.</p> <p>Sound farfetched? I’d thought so too: This column started life as a satire.</p> <p>But even as satire, it should draw CIOs’ attention. Because even without the punchline, it should, I hope, convince you that as your company pokes around the AI perimeter, you and your team need to be alert to worrisome but possible unintended consequences — including those of the “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/There_are_unknown_unknowns" rel="nofollow">unknown unknowns” nature</a>.</p> <p>Especially, CIOs should put into place mechanisms for spotting business requests for plausibly achievable AI-related projects that are, at the same time, seriously bad ideas.</p> <p>AI is furthering the war on reality — one that reality looks to be losing, with no obvious reason for optimism in sight. AI-driven strangenesses like this fable merely highlight the need for all of us to be alert to the potential risks.</p> <p>There’s no methodology you can fall back on; no “best practices” to keep you out of trouble.</p> <p>Something you might at least try on for size: Your company’s strategic planning framework is probably built on some version of TOWS — threats, opportunities, weaknesses, and strengths. Make sure its strategic planners don’t just get excited about AI’s evolving capabilities.</p> <p>In parallel, make even more sure they gain a healthy dose of fear.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Global AI Regulations Fuel Billion-Dollar Market for AI Governance Platforms]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-17-gartner-global-ai-regulations-fuel-billion-dollar-market-for-ai-governance-platforms?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-17-gartner-global-ai-regulations-fuel-billion-dollar-market-for-ai-governance-platforms?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The cost of unmanaged AI risk is escalating. According to Gartner, by 2030, fragmented AI regulation will quadruple and extend to 75% of the world’s economies, driving $1 billion in total compliance spend.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[GlassFish 8.0 Delivers Compatibility with Jakarta EE 11, Enhanced Security and Improved Data Access]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/glassfish-8-released/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/glassfish-8-released/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/glassfish-8-released/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771252732288.jpg"/><p>After 15 milestone releases, the Eclipse Foundation has released version 8.0 of GlassFish featuring support for virtual threads; enhanced application security; and improved data access. GlassFish 8.0 is a compatible implementation of Jakarta EE 11. Ondro Mihályi, Java Champion and co-founder of OmniFish, spoke to InfoQ about GlassFish 8.0.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
