<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 08:07:56 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[빗썸, 양자내성암호 도입해 보안 강화…“국내 거래소 가운데 최초”]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135044/%eb%b9%97%ec%8d%b8-%ec%96%91%ec%9e%90%eb%82%b4%ec%84%b1%ec%95%94%ed%98%b8-%eb%8f%84%ec%9e%85%ed%95%b4-%eb%b3%b4%ec%95%88-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94%ea%b5%ad%eb%82%b4-%ea%b1%b0%eb%9e%98.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135044/%eb%b9%97%ec%8d%b8-%ec%96%91%ec%9e%90%eb%82%b4%ec%84%b1%ec%95%94%ed%98%b8-%eb%8f%84%ec%9e%85%ed%95%b4-%eb%b3%b4%ec%95%88-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94%ea%b5%ad%eb%82%b4-%ea%b1%b0%eb%9e%98.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>빗썸은 지난 11일 서울 강남구에 소재한 빗썸금융타워에서 핀테크 보안 기업 아톤과 ‘양자내성암호(PQC) 보안 솔루션 도입을 위한 기술협약’을 체결하고, 플랫폼 전반에 PQC 보안 솔루션을 적용하기로 했다. 빗썸 측은 이번 도입이 국내 가상자산 거래소 가운데 최초라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>이번 협약은 가상자산 산업이 빠르게 성장하면서 거래소에 요구되는 보안 수준이 높아지는 환경 변화에 선제 대응하기 위한 조치다. 향후 양자컴퓨터가 상용화될 경우 기존 보안체계에 위협이 될 수 있다는 우려에 대비해 빗썸은 양자내성암호(PQC)를 선제적으로 도입하고, 중장기 보안 대응 체계를 단계적으로 강화해 나간다는 계획이다.</p> <p>이에 빗썸은 국내 주요 시중은행과 증권사에 인증보안 솔루션을 공급해 온 아톤의 PQC 보안 솔루션을 단계적으로 도입한다. 해당 솔루션은 미국 국립표준기술연구소(NIST)가 선정한 표준 양자내성암호 알고리즘인 ML-DSA와 ML-KEM을 적용했으며, 자체 개발한 화이트박스 암호화 기술을 결합해 양자컴퓨터 기반 해독 위협은 물론 기존의 해킹 공격까지 이중으로 대응할 수 있도록 설계됐다.</p> <p>빗썸은 아톤의 솔루션을 통해 거래소 서비스의 입력, 인증, 전송, 저장 등 보안 라이프사이클 전 구간에 양자내성암호 기반 보호 체계를 적용할 계획이다.</p> <p>아울러 빗썸과 아톤은 공동 기술협의체를 구성해 거래소 환경에 최적화된 PQC 보안 체계를 단계적으로 구축하고 지속적인 고도화를 추진한다. 이를 통해 빗썸은 양자컴퓨터 시대의 ‘선수집 후해독(Harvest Now, Decrypt Later)’ 위협에 대비하고, 정부의 암호체계 전환 정책에도 발맞춰 이용자 보호 체계를 강화해 나갈 예정이다.</p> <p>이기택 빗썸 보안부문 총괄은 “장기적인 보안 환경 변화에 대비해 양자내성암호 기반 보안 체계 도입을 추진하게 됐다”라며 “단계적인 적용과 고도화를 통해 이용자 자산 보호 체계를 지속적으로 강화해 나가겠다”라고 말했다.<br>jihyun.lee@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[백오피스 IT에서 벗어나자…CIO가 끊어야 할 7가지 익숙함]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135040/%eb%b0%b1%ec%98%a4%ed%94%bc%ec%8a%a4-it%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%eb%b2%97%ec%96%b4%eb%82%98%ec%9e%90cio%ea%b0%80-%eb%81%8a%ec%96%b4%ec%95%bc-%ed%95%a0-7%ea%b0%80%ec%a7%80-%ec%9d%b5%ec%88%99.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135040/%eb%b0%b1%ec%98%a4%ed%94%bc%ec%8a%a4-it%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%eb%b2%97%ec%96%b4%eb%82%98%ec%9e%90cio%ea%b0%80-%eb%81%8a%ec%96%b4%ec%95%bc-%ed%95%a0-7%ea%b0%80%ec%a7%80-%ec%9d%b5%ec%88%99.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>CIO의 역할은 끊임없이 진화하고 있다. 오늘날 IT 리더가 다양한 고객, 파트너, 벤더 등 비즈니스 중심 이해관계자와 일상적으로 교류하는 모습이 이를 보여준다. 그럼에도 일부 C레벨 경영진이 CIO를 여전히 전형적인 백오피스 운영 책임자로 인식하면서, 이런 낡은 시각은 쉽게 사라지지 않고 있다.</p> <p>그렇다면 CIO는 진정한 전면 리더로 자리매김하기 위해 어떤 노력을 해야 할까? 다음은 백오피스 이미지를 완전히 벗어나는 데 도움이 될 7가지 전략이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-%ec%a0%84%ec%82%ac-%ec%b0%a8%ec%9b%90%ec%9d%98-%ed%98%91%ec%97%85-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94">1. 전사 차원의 협업 역량 강화</h2> <p>오디오 제품 기업 슈어(Shure)의 CTO 샘 사벳은 백오피스 사고방식은 CIO를 전략적 생산성과 혁신을 이끄는 주체가 아닌, 단순히 시스템을 안정적으로 운영하는 역할에 머물게 만든다고 설명했다. 사벳은 슈어의 후원을 받아 시장조사업체 IDC가 진행한 최근 연구를 인용하며, 백오피스 중심 IT 마인드를 가진 CIO는 협업과 업무 환경 경험에 대한 투자를 과소평가하는 경향이 있다고 전했다.</p> <p>사벳은 “이 경우 협업은 단순히 있으면 좋은 요소로 간주되고, 그 결과 조직은 IT 투자를 실제 ROI로 연결하는 데 어려움을 겪게 된다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>성공적인 CIO는 사업부 리더와 긴밀히 협력해 기술이 구체적인 성과와 연결되도록 한다고 사벳은 설명했다. 또한 HR과 업무 환경 팀과 적극적으로 협업해 직원 경험을 깊이 이해하고, 협업을 하나의 생태계로 이해하는 기술 파트너와 함께 일한다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>사벳은 “부서 경계를 넘는 협업을 적극적으로 수용하는 조직일수록 경쟁사 대비 더 뛰어난 성과를 낼 가능성이 높다”라고 분석했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-%eb%b9%84%ec%a6%88%eb%8b%88%ec%8a%a4-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc-%ec%a4%91%ec%8b%ac%ec%9d%98-%eb%a6%ac%eb%8d%94%ec%8b%ad-%eb%b0%9c%ed%9c%98">2. 비즈니스 성과 중심의 리더십 발휘</h2> <p>기술 리서치 및 자문 기업 ISG의 파트너 <a href="https://isg-one.com/about-us/people/ola-chowning" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">올라 차우닝</a>은 IT가 구체적인 비즈니스 가치를 창출하는 경험에 집중하지 않고, 일반적인 사용자 경험 관점에서 단순 지원 기능이자 비용센터로만 운영될 때 백오피스화가 발생한다고 설명했다.</p> <p>차우닝은 백오피스 사고방식을 가진 CIO는 혁신이나 비즈니스 성과 개선, 전략적 파트너로서의 역할보다 시스템 안정성, 장애 대응, 가동 시간 유지에 더 큰 관심을 두는 경향이 있다고 진단했다. 또한 이러한 조직은 인프라와 애플리케이션이 분리된 구조를 갖고 있으며, 엔드투엔드 책임 체계나 성과 중심 관점이 부족한 기능적 분절이 특징이라고 분석했다.</p> <p>차우닝은 “이 같은 환경에서는 CIO가 전략 논의에 지속적으로 참여하기보다, 단순히 요청을 처리하는 ‘오더 테이커’ 역할에 머물게 된다”라며 “기술이 기업의 방향성과 전략을 어떻게 지원할 수 있을지 논의하는 자리에 안정적으로 참여하지 못하게 된다”라고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85-%ec%a0%84%eb%b0%98%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%ec%98%81%ed%96%a5%eb%a0%a5-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94">3. 기업 전반에서 영향력 강화</h2> <p>PR 기업 엠부스(M Booth)의 CTO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alfredobernal/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">알프레도 베르날</a>은 백오피스 IT 사고방식이 기술을 성장과 경쟁 우위의 동력이 아닌, 가동 시간과 티켓 처리, 비용 통제에 초점을 둔 지원 기능으로 인식하게 만든다고 설명했다. 베르날은 “이 모델에서는 성공의 기준이 비즈니스 성과가 아니라 안정성과 리스크 회피에 맞춰져 있다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>이 같은 사고방식이 초래하는 위험은 적지 않다. 베르날은 “섀도우 IT와 단편화된 도구가 확산되고, 경쟁사는 자동화와 AI를 적극 도입해 더 빠르게 움직이게 된다”라며 “그 사이 CIO는 경영진 회의에서 점차 영향력을 잃게 된다”라고 전했다. 시간이 지날수록 IT는 전략적 파트너가 아닌 비용센터로 인식되고, 그 결과 예산 심의나 조직 개편 과정에서 더욱 취약한 위치에 놓이게 된다.</p> <p>따라서 CIO는 비즈니스 중심 IT로의 전환을 추진하는 데 그치지 않고, 기업 전반에서 자신의 영향력을 높일 수 있는 방안을 적극적으로 모색해야 한다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-%ea%b2%bd%ec%9f%81%eb%a0%a5-%ed%99%95%eb%b3%b4">4. 경쟁력 확보</h2> <p>소프트웨어 개발 기업 유리스틱(Euristiq)의 CTO <a href="https://euristiq.com/author/pavlotkhir/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">파블로 트키르</a>는 백오피스 IT 사고에서 벗어나기 위해서는 기술을 경쟁 우위의 원천으로 인식해야 한다고 설명했다. 그렇지 않으면 IT는 여전히 비즈니스 혁신보다 ‘운영 유지’ 중심의 목표와 지표에만 집중하게 된다는 지적이다.</p> <p>트키르는 “고객 영향이나 성장 가능성보다 리스크 최소화와 비용 절감만을 기준으로 IT 의사결정을 내리는 기업을 여러 차례 봤다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>백오피스 마인드의 징후는 CIO 조직에서 비교적 뚜렷하게 나타난다. 비즈니스 성과 대신 가동 시간과 SLA에 집중하고, 제품 논의에 참여하지 않으며, 실험을 두려워하고, ‘아직 준비되지 않았다’는 태도가 만연해 있다는 설명이다. 트키르는 이러한 상황이 지속되면 결국 사업 부문이 IT를 우회하게 되고, 외부 벤더와 서로 다른 솔루션이 난립하는 결과로 이어진다고 분석했다. 그 결과 보안 리스크와 비용, 기술 부채가 증가하고 IT의 신뢰도도 떨어지게 된다.</p> <p>트키르는 CEO와 제품 리더, 엔지니어링 팀도 CIO가 올바른 방향으로 전환하는 데 중요한 역할을 할 수 있다고 밝혔다. 특히 IT가 기능 출시 속도, 매출 기여도, 고객 유지율 등 비즈니스 언어로 소통하기 시작할 때 변화의 계기가 마련된다고 설명했다. 그는 “백오피스 사고로 되돌아가지 않으려면 IT를 기업 전략에 통합하고, 서버나 티켓이 아닌 비즈니스 성과 기준으로 기여도를 지속적으로 측정해야 한다”라고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-%ec%99%b8%eb%b6%80%eb%a1%9c-%ec%8b%9c%ec%95%bc-%ed%99%95%ec%9e%a5">5. 외부로 시야 확장</h2> <p>카네기멜론대 하인즈 칼리지(Heinz College)의 임원 교육 강사 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sumeet-chabria-a683617/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">수밋 차브리아</a>는 많은 CIO가 의미 있는 비즈니스 성과 달성보다 체크리스트 완료 여부와 프로세스 이행에 따라 성공을 판단하는 내부 지향적 사고에 머무는 경우가 많다고 설명했다.</p> <p>차브리아는 “IT가 비즈니스 우선순위와 연결되지 않은 채 ‘기술을 위한 기술’에 집중하며 사일로처럼 운영될 때 이런 현상이 나타난다”라며 “CIO가 비즈니스 임원과 시간을 보내지 않으면, 비즈니스 조직도 IT를 파트너가 아닌 벤더처럼 대하게 된다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>AI와 디지털 경제 환경에서 백오피스 사고방식은 조직의 존속 자체를 위협할 수 있는 요소라고 차브리아는 경고했다. 그는 “백오피스 마인드는 성과가 아닌 규정 준수 여부에 따라 승진이 결정되는 문화를 만든다”라며 “이는 브랜드 가치를 훼손하고, 자신의 업무가 회사의 성공과 어떻게 연결되는지 보지 못한 핵심 인재가 조직을 떠나게 만드는 요인이 된다”라고 분석했다.</p> <p>진정한 전면 리더로 자리매김하려면 높은 수준의 비즈니스 이해력이 필요하다고 차브리아는 밝혔다. 차브리아는 “CIO는 CEO만큼 핵심 가치 동인과 손익계산서(P&amp;L)를 이해해야 한다”라고 말했다. 또한 CIO는 기업 전체를 바라보는 관점을 갖춰야 하며, 보상을 비즈니스 성과와 연계하면 조직이 올바른 방향으로 움직이도록 유도할 수 있다고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-%ec%a1%b0%ec%a7%81-%ec%9a%b4%ec%98%81-%eb%b0%a9%ec%8b%9d%ea%b3%bc%ec%9d%98-%ec%a0%95%eb%a0%ac">6. 조직 운영 방식과의 정렬</h2> <p>루시드 소프트웨어(Lucid Software)의 기술 및 보안 부사장 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-torgerson-lucid/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">데이비드 토거슨</a>은 IT가 매출과 생산성을 이끄는 전략적 동력이 아니라 유지보수와 리스크 회피, 내부 지원에 집중하는 비용센터로 인식될 때 백오피스 사고방식이 자리 잡는다고 설명했다.</p> <p>토거슨은 “이러한 환경에서는 IT 의사결정이 사후 대응적이고 규정 준수 중심으로 이뤄지며, 비즈니스 성과와 단절되는 경우가 많다”라며 “보안, AI, 인프라 투자가 성장의 핵심 도구가 아니라 단순히 체크리스트를 채우는 항목처럼 취급된다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>이 같은 흐름을 바로잡기 위해서는 IT 내부 노력만으로는 부족하다고 토거슨은 지적했다. 토거슨은 “CIO는 조직 전반의 팀과 긴밀히 협력해 실제 업무 흐름에 기반해 의사결정을 내리고, 리스크를 식별하고 대응하는 데 실제로 얼마나 시간이 소요되는지 측정해야 한다”라고 조언했다.</p> <p>또한 리스크와 기대 효과를 함께 따져 묻는 질문을 던질 필요가 있다고 제안했다. 토거슨은 “이는 ‘아무것도 신뢰하지 않는다’는 접근에서 벗어나, 현대적 협업 환경을 반영한 명확한 검증 프로세스로 전환하는 것을 의미한다”라고 설명했다. 아울러 산업 인증도 수요와 성숙도, 실질적 가치에 따라 재평가해야 하며, 단일 활용 사례만으로는 투자를 정당화할 수 없다는 점을 인식해야 한다고 밝혔다. 토거슨은 “조직이 실제로 운영되는 방식과 IT 전략을 정렬하는 것이 무엇보다 중요하다”라고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-%eb%b9%84%ec%a6%88%eb%8b%88%ec%8a%a4-%ea%b0%90%ea%b0%81-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94">7. 비즈니스 감각 강화</h2> <p>벤더 중립 교육 및 자격 인증을 제공하는 비영리 무역 단체 컴퓨팅기술산업협회(CompTIA)의 최고 기술 에반젤리스트 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesstanger/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">제임스 스탱어</a>는 동료가 CIO를 ‘기술 담당자’로만 인식해 비즈니스 활동에 포함하지 않는다면 이는 분명한 경고 신호라고 말했다.</p> <p>스탱어는 최근 호주의 한 대형 은행이 데이터 수집 프로젝트를 추진하면서 기술적 구현에만 초점을 맞춘 사례를 직접 목격했다고 전했다. 스탱어는 “해당 CIO는 프로젝트의 비즈니스 요구를 충분히 이해하기 위한 조치를 취하지 못했다고 인정했다”라며 “그 결과 프로젝트는 고객 기대를 충분히 충족하지 못했다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>CIO는 스스로를 고객 중심의 가드레일, 즉 안전장치 같은 존재로 인식해야 한다고 스탱어는 제안했다. 스탱어는 “동료가 고객 관점에서 사고하지 못하는 모습을 발견하면, 그들이 올바른 사고방식으로 전환하도록 유도할 수 있는 제도적 장치를 마련해야 한다”라고 말했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[“기존 방식은 한계에 다다랐다”···AI 수요 및 비용 급등에 기업은 가상화 전략 전면 재검토 중]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135036/%ea%b8%b0%ec%a1%b4-%eb%b0%a9%ec%8b%9d%ec%9d%80-%ed%95%9c%ea%b3%84%ec%97%90-%eb%8b%a4%eb%8b%a4%eb%9e%90%eb%8b%a4%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7ai-%ec%88%98%ec%9a%94-%eb%b0%8f-%eb%b9%84%ec%9a%a9.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135036/%ea%b8%b0%ec%a1%b4-%eb%b0%a9%ec%8b%9d%ec%9d%80-%ed%95%9c%ea%b3%84%ec%97%90-%eb%8b%a4%eb%8b%a4%eb%9e%90%eb%8b%a4%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7ai-%ec%88%98%ec%9a%94-%eb%b0%8f-%eb%b9%84%ec%9a%a9.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>비용 예측의 불확실성과 AI 준비도에 대한 우려로 많은 IT 리더가 가상화 전략을 대대적으로 변경할 계획인 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>HPE의 최근 <a href="https://www.hpe.com/us/en/solutions/cloud.html?slug=a00155927enw&amp;x=MHm9Z2&amp;pf_route=uccldfav" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">설문조사</a>에 따르면, IT 의사결정권자 3분의 2가 향후 2년 내 가상화 배포 환경을 재정비할 계획이라고 밝혔다. 그러나 실제로 조직 차원에서 변화에 대비가 돼 있다고 답한 비율은 5%에 그쳤다.</p> <p>HPE가 ‘대규모 가상화 재편’이라고 칭한 이번 흐름의 배경에는 비용 문제가 있다. 2023년 말 브로드컴(Broadcom)이 <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3604503/vmware-makes-workstation-and-fusion-free-for-everyone.html" target="_blank">VM웨어(VMware)</a>를 인수한 이후 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2093486/vmware-customers-take-wait-and-see-approach-amid-broadcom-changes.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank">라이선스 비용이 인상</a>되면서 일부 조직은 ‘<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2513749/will-vmwares-licensing-changes-push-devirtualization-of-data-centers.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank">탈가상화</a>’를 검토하기 시작했다. 다만 설문에 참여한 조직의 절반 이상은 여전히 VM웨어를 주력 가상화 플랫폼으로 운영하고 있는 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>설문에 따르면 VM웨어의 가격 인상에 더해, 올해 클라우드 비용이 예상보다 높게 집행되고 있다는 점도 IT 리더의 부담으로 작용하고 있다.</p> <p>HPE 하이브리드 클라우드 부문 COO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hangtan/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">행 탄</a>은 “가상화 비용이 사실상 5배로 뛰었고, 동시에 AI 투자와 급여 체계 현대화까지 추진해야 하는 상황이라 기업은 감당하기 어려운 비용 부담을 떠안게 됐다. 이제 모두가 대안을 찾고 있다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>다만 HPE는 이런 움직임의 이면에, 기업이 AI 시대에 걸맞은 인프라를 갖추고 있는지에 대한 근본적인 고민과, 클라우드에서 운영 중인 가상머신 구조가 AI 워크로드를 제대로 감당할 수 있는지에 대한 의문이 있다고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ea%b0%80%ec%83%81%eb%a8%b8%ec%8b%a0%ea%b3%bc-%ed%81%b4%eb%9d%bc%ec%9a%b0%eb%93%9c%eb%a5%bc-%eb%8f%99%ec%8b%9c%ec%97%90-%ec%9e%ac%ec%84%a4%ea%b3%84">가상머신과 클라우드를 동시에 재설계</h2> <p>많은 IT 리더가 AI에 최적화된 가상화 역량을 원하고 있다. 동시에 AI와 가상화가 어떤 방식으로 결합해야 하는지를 고민하며 기존 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4015769/%EC%8B%A4%ED%97%98-%EB%81%9D%EB%82%9C-ai%EB%8A%94-%EB%8B%A4%EC%8B%9C-%EC%98%A8%ED%94%84%EB%A0%88%EB%AF%B8%EC%8A%A4%EB%A1%9C-%ED%8D%BC%EB%B8%94%EB%A6%AD-%ED%81%B4%EB%9D%BC%EC%9A%B0.html" target="_blank">클라우드 컴퓨팅 환경</a> 전반을 다시 들여다보고 있다.</p> <p>AI 비용을 통제하고 워크로드를 면밀히 모니터링하며 벤더 종속을 피하려는 요구가 커지면서, 하이브리드 클라우드 환경에 대한 수요도 빠르게 증가했다고 탄은 설명했다. 조사에 따르면 IT 리더는 가상화와 클라우드 환경을 현대화하는 과정에서 통합 백업, 크로스 플랫폼 거버넌스, 통합 옵저버빌리티와 같은 기능도 함께 요구 중인 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>탄은 비용 부담과 AI 현대화 과제가 맞물리는 지금이 IT 리더가 기존 가상화 스택을 원점에서 다시 점검할 기회일 수 있다고 분석했다. 그는 “위기 속에도 기회는 있다”라며 “CIO 입장에서는 ‘이제 전략을 다시 설계할 수 있는 시점이 왔다’고 판단할 수 있다”라고 말했다. 이어 “대부분의 IT 리더는 그동안 하나의 스택과 운영 모델로 표준화해 왔지만, 해결해야 할 과제가 있다는 사실도 알고 있었다”라고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai%ea%b0%80-%eb%b0%94%ea%be%b8%eb%8a%94-%ea%b0%80%ec%83%81%eb%a8%b8%ec%8b%a0%ec%9d%98-%ec%97%ad%ed%95%a0">AI가 바꾸는 가상머신의 역할</h2> <p>IT 서비스 및 애플리케이션 개발 기업 탭포스(Tapforce)의 설립자 겸 CTO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/balabanskyy/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">아르투르 발라반스키</a>는 AI가 기존 가상화 활용 방식을 근본적으로 뒤흔들고 있다고 진단했다.</p> <p>발라반스키는 “AI 워크로드는 GPU 의존도가 높고 수요 예측이 어렵다. 한 번 용량을 산정해 가상머신을 구성한 뒤 그대로 운영하던 기존 모델은 더 이상 통하지 않는다. 기업은 전면적인 가상화가 과연 필요한지, 아니면 더 가벼운 계층이 AI 기반 프로젝트에 더 적합한지 고민하기 시작했다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>그는 기존 가상화 플랫폼이 CPU 중심 구조이며 비교적 안정적인 수요를 전제로 설계된 반면, AI 워크로드는 메모리 사용량이 크고 GPU에 크게 의존하며 지연 시간에도 민감하다고 분석했다. 발라반스키는 “추상화 계층은 비용과 성능 저하를 유발하고, 모델이 실제 대규모로 확장되는 순간 문제가 본격적으로 드러난다. 미래 수요를 예측하고 설계하는 역할을 맡은 이들에게는 전혀 새로운 환경”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>냉난방 및 데이터센터 부품 제조 기업 댄포스(Danfoss)의 CIO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sune-tornbo-baastrup-3950402/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">수네 바스트럽</a>은 비용 문제를 넘어, 가상화와 AI가 ‘양질의 데이터 확보’라는 지점에서 맞닿아 있다고 설명했다. 그에 따르면 댄포스는 최근 데이터 이동성과 유연성에 초점을 맞춰 가상화 기술 전반을 재평가했다.</p> <p>바스트럽은 “가상화는 단순히 하나의 물리 서버에서 자원을 더 효율적으로 활용하는 수준을 넘어선다. 앞으로 등장할 훨씬 더 역동적인 사용례에 대비하는 과정이다. 많은 워크로드가 중앙에서 분산된 위치로, 나아가 엣지로 이동하게 될 것”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>그는 댄포스에서 AI를 도입함에 따라 가상화와 데이터 전략 역시 진화해야 할 것이라고 내다봤다. 그는 “AI에서 실질적인 가치를 끌어내기 위해 핵심적으로 요구되는 것은 결국 양질의 데이터에 대한 접근성”이라고 강조했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a0%9c%ec%95%bd-%ec%9a%94%ec%9d%b8">제약 요인</h2> <p>설문에 따르면 가상화 전략을 바꾸는 과정에는 여러 걸림돌이 존재한다. 응답자의 4분의 1 이상은 예산 제약이 핵심 걸림돌이라고 답했다. 또한 약 4분의 1은 기술 복잡성, 마이그레이션 리스크, 역량 격차를 주요 장벽으로 지목했다.</p> <p>바스트럽은 IT 조직 차원의 준비 부족도 또 다른 장벽이라면서, CIO의 역할 중 하나가 벤더나 기술을 변경해야 하는 이유를 내부에 설득하는 것이라고 설명했다.</p> <p>그는 “CIO가 결국 고민해야 할 질문은 ‘이미 시장에 나와 있는 기술을 어떻게 받아들일 준비를 할 것인가, 그리고 AI 혁신 사례가 현실화되는 시점에 함께할 파트너를 어떻게 찾을 것인가’다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>발라반스키는 예산과 역량 부족, 변화에 대한 두려움 역시 가상화 전환의 제약 요인이라고 분석했다. 발라반스키는 “대규모 전환은 이론적으로 타당해 보여도 비용이 크고 조직에 혼란을 초래한다. 팀은 현재 운영 중인 환경에 익숙하고, 이를 재교육하거나 대체하는 데에는 실제 위험이 따른다. 결국 내부 의사결정에서는 가격과 안정성이 우선순위를 차지하는 경우가 많다”라고 밝혔다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%8b%a0%ec%a4%91%ed%95%9c-%ec%a0%91%ea%b7%bc-%ed%95%84%ec%9a%94">신중한 접근 필요</h2> <p>가상화 전환에 여러 제약 요인이 존재하는 만큼, HPE는 IT 리더의 속도 조절이 필요하다고 조언했다. 탄은 모든 워크로드를 한번에 새로운 업체로 옮길 필요는 없다고 설명했다.</p> <p>탄은 “비용이 오르니 가능한 한 빨리 이전해야 한다는 반응이 나올 수 있다. 그러나 지금은 전략을 다시 설계할 기회인 만큼 충분히 고민하고 접근해야 한다. HPE 고객에게도 서두르지 말 것을 권하고 있다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>IT 서비스 기업 스라이브(Thrive)의 COO 스콧 스틸은 새로운 가상화 솔루션이 전체 IT 환경에 어떻게 들어맞는지 종합적으로 검토해야 한다고 강조했다. 가상화가 더 큰 IT 전환 논의의 한 축인 만큼 AI와 향후 수요를 중심에 두고 접근해야 한다는 설명이다.</p> <p>스틸은 “AI 역량을 갖춘 새로운 기술과 인프라를 앞세운 신규 벤더가 잇따라 등장하고 있다. 지금은 과거의 환경에 맞추는 것이 아니라, 앞으로 전개될 방향에 대비해 전체 인프라를 점검해야 할 시기”라고 조언했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[아웃시스템즈 기고 | 한국 기업의 AI 전환을 좌우할 에이전틱 AI 도입 전략 3가지]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135019/%ec%95%84%ec%9b%83%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%85%9c%ec%a6%88-%ea%b8%b0%ea%b3%a0-%ed%95%9c%ea%b5%ad-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85%ec%9d%98-ai-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9d%84-%ec%a2%8c%ec%9a%b0%ed%95%a0-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135019/%ec%95%84%ec%9b%83%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%85%9c%ec%a6%88-%ea%b8%b0%ea%b3%a0-%ed%95%9c%ea%b5%ad-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85%ec%9d%98-ai-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9d%84-%ec%a2%8c%ec%9a%b0%ed%95%a0-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>국내에서도 이러한 변화는 이미 체감되고 있다. 작년 8월 공개된<a href="https://www.bok.or.kr/portal/bbs/P0002353/view.do?nttId=10093071&amp;searchCnd=1&amp;searchKwd=&amp;depth=201150&amp;pageUnit=10&amp;pageIndex=1&amp;programType=newsData&amp;menuNo=200433&amp;oldMenuNo=201150" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"> 한국은행 보고서에 따르면</a> 국내 근로자의 63.5%가 생성형 AI를 사용한 경험이 있으며, 절반 이상은 실제 업무에 활용하고 있다고 답했다. 반면 이러한 확산 속도와 달리, AI를 핵심 비즈니스 프로세스에까지 성공적으로 내재화한 기업은 여전히 소수에 불과하다. ‘도입’과 ‘운영’ 사이의 간극이 본격적으로 드러나는 지점이다.</p> <p>이 간극을 메우는 새로운 패러다임으로 주목받는 개념이 바로 에이전틱 AI(Agentic AI)다. 단순히 프롬프트에 반응하는 도구가 아니라, 사용자의 의도 파악·계획·결과 검증·반복 수행까지 가능한 목적 기반의 자율성을 제공한다. 아웃시스템즈가 선보인 ‘에이전트 워크벤치(Agent Workbench)’ 역시 이러한 원칙을 바탕으로 여러 특화된 AI 에이전트들이 복잡한 개발·운영 전반에 걸쳐 협력하도록 지원한다.</p> <p>이미 산업별 초기 도입 사례들은 가시적 효과를 보여주고 있다. 반복 업무 자동화는 물론, 미션 크리티컬한 애플리케이션 개발 가속, 검증 과정의 자동화까지 결과가 다양하게 나타나고 있다. 그리고 하나의 공통점이 도출된다. 에이전틱 AI는 독립형 기능이 아니라 기존 프로세스에 자연스럽게 녹아들 때 가장 큰 가치를 만든다는 것이다.</p> <p>그렇다면 한국 기업이 에이전틱 AI를 효과적으로 구현하기 위해 무엇을 우선적으로 고려해야 할까?</p> <p>핵심은 세 가지 원칙으로 정리된다.</p> <p>첫 번째는, 기술 선정보다 ‘문제 정의’를 우선하는 것이다. 많은 AI 프로젝트가 기대에 미치지 못하는 이유는 모델의 성능 한계 때문이 아니라, 해결해야 할 실제 비효율·병목·리스크가 명확히 규정되지 않았기 때문이다. AI를 가장 효과적으로 활용하기 위해서는, 어떤 영역에서 에이전트가 실질적으로 가장 높은 임팩트를 낼 수 있는지 선명하게 규명하는 것이 성공의 출발점이 된다.</p> <p>두 번째는, 기존 워크플로와의 ‘마찰 없는 통합’이다. 에이전틱 AI는 직원들이 이미 익숙하게 사용하는 도구와 시스템 안에서 작동할 때 가장 높은 효율을 낸다. 인터페이스나 프로세스를 대폭 변경하면 오히려 도입 속도가 느려지고 조직 내 저항이 생길 수 있다. 반대로, 에이전트 오케스트레이션을 기존 생태계에 자연스럽게 얹는 방식은 강력한 자동화와 인사이트를 제공하면서도 불필요한 변화를 최소화한다. 에이전트 워크벤치(Agent Workbench)가 기존 워크플로 안에서 여러 에이전트의 협업을 가능하게 설계된 이유도 여기에 있다.</p> <p>세 번째는, 신뢰와 거버넌스를 ‘선행 조건’으로 두는 것이다. 기업 환경에서 데이터의 민감도와 규모가 커질수록 AI 에이전트의 자율성에는 투명성이 반드시 수반돼야 한다. 데이터 경계 설정, 접근 권한 관리, 버저닝, 감사 추적 기능은 선택이 아니라 필수다. 즉, 거버넌스는 도입 후에 붙이는 안전장치가 아니라, 전사적 확장을 위한 전제 조건이어야 한다.</p> <p>에이전틱 AI 개념에 익숙하지 않은 사용자에게는 기술적 구조를 설명하기보다, 에이전트가 수행하는 역할과 해결하는 문제, 기대되는 성과를 명확히 보여주는 방식이 실제 이해에 더 도움이 된다. 사용자는 AI를 ‘블랙박스’가 아닌, 자신의 업무를 보완하고 확장시키는 목적 기반의 협업자로 받아들이게 된다.</p> <p>에이전틱 AI는 기업의 개발, 운영, 서비스 전반을 재정의할 잠재력을 지니고 있다. 그러나 그 성공 여부는 기술 자체보다 전략, 통합, 신뢰에 달려 있다. 지금 한국 기업이 던져야 할 질문은 “AI를 도입할 것인가?”가 아니라, “에이전틱 AI를 어떻게 제대로 구현할 것인가?”다.</p> <p>이 질문에 명확한 해답을 가지고 실행하는 기업이 다음 단계의 디지털 전환을 선도하게 될 것이다.</p> <p><em>*필자 안세준 아웃시스템즈 코리아 지사장은 한국 내 사업을 총괄하며, 국내 비즈니스 개발과 고객 및 파트너 생태계 강화를 통해 다양한 산업 분야에서 AI 기반 로우코드 디지털 전환을 이끌고 있다. IT 업계에서 20년 이상의 경력을 쌓은 안세준 지사장은 아웃시스템즈 합류 이전 카토 네트웍스(Cato Networks), 지니어(Zinier), 스플렁크(Splunk), 팁코(TIBCO), GXS, 마이크로스트래티지(MicroStrategy), 오라클(Oracle), PGi 등 글로벌 소프트웨어 및 클라우드 기업에서 근무하며 관련 경험을 쌓았다.</em><br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p> <p><br><br></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[“AI 안 쓰면 승진 없다” 액센추어, 고위직 인사 평가에 AI 활용 연동]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135028/ai-%ec%95%88-%ec%93%b0%eb%a9%b4-%ec%8a%b9%ec%a7%84-%ec%97%86%eb%8b%a4-%ec%95%a1%ec%84%bc%ec%b6%94%ec%96%b4-%ea%b3%a0%ec%9c%84%ec%a7%81-%ec%9d%b8%ec%82%ac-%ed%8f%89%ea%b0%80%ec%97%90.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135028/ai-%ec%95%88-%ec%93%b0%eb%a9%b4-%ec%8a%b9%ec%a7%84-%ec%97%86%eb%8b%a4-%ec%95%a1%ec%84%bc%ec%b6%94%ec%96%b4-%ea%b3%a0%ec%9c%84%ec%a7%81-%ec%9d%b8%ec%82%ac-%ed%8f%89%ea%b0%80%ec%97%90.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ac672f97-a603-4c56-afa3-4a5273d45674" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">파이낸셜타임스(FT)</a> 보도에 따르면 액센추어는 최근 내부 이메일을 통해 고위 관리자 직책에 있는 직원들에게 “임원으로 승진하기 위해서는 AI 도구의 ‘정기적 사용’이 필요하다”라고 통보했다.</p> <p>액센추어는 이를 공식 확인하며 “고객을 가장 효과적으로 지원하기 위해서는 최신 도구와 기술의 채택이 필수적”이라고 밝혔다. 실제로 액센추어는 일부 고위 직원들을 대상으로 AI 도구의 주간 로그인 데이터를 수집하며 사용 여부를 추적하고 있는 것으로 알려졌다. </p> <p>모니터링 대상에는 자사 플랫폼인 ‘AI 리파이너리(AI Refinery)’가 포함된다. 이 플랫폼은 기업이 업무 프로세스를 재설계하고 AI 솔루션을 전사적으로 확장할 수 있도록 지원하는 통합 도구다.</p> <p>다만 유럽 12개국과 미국 정부 계약을 담당하는 부서 직원은 이번 정책의 영향을 받지 않을 전망이다.</p> <p>액센추어 CEO 줄리 스위트는 지난해 9월 실적 발표에서 “모든 직원에게 대규모 재교육과 재정비가 필요하다. 필요 역량을 갖추지 못한 인력은 조직을 떠나게 될 것”이라고 밝히며 구조조정 가능성을 시사한 바 있다.</p> <p>액센추어는 이미 대규모 AI 재교육에 착수했으며, 현재까지 전체 직원 78만 명 중 55만 명이 생성형 AI 기본 교육을 이수했다. 직원 교육을 위해 오픈AI, 앤트로픽, 팔란티어 등 기업과 협력 중인 것으로 알려졌다.</p> <p>특히 액센추어는 AI 컨설팅 서비스 업체로 구조를 재편하기 위해 지난해 전략, 컨설팅, 기술, 크리에이티브, 운영 부문을 ‘리인벤션 서비스(Reinvention Services)’라는 단일 조직으로 통합하고, 직원들을 ‘리인벤터(Reinventor)’로 칭하고 있다.<br>yuseong.kim@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[칼럼 | 오픈소스가 AI 시대의 ‘치트키’가 될 이유]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135023/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%ec%98%a4%ed%94%88%ec%86%8c%ec%8a%a4%ea%b0%80-ai-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80%ec%9d%98-%ec%b9%98%ed%8a%b8%ed%82%a4%ea%b0%80-%eb%90%a0-%ec%9d%b4%ec%9c%a0.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135023/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%ec%98%a4%ed%94%88%ec%86%8c%ec%8a%a4%ea%b0%80-ai-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80%ec%9d%98-%ec%b9%98%ed%8a%b8%ed%82%a4%ea%b0%80-%eb%90%a0-%ec%9d%b4%ec%9c%a0.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>대규모 언어 모델(LLM)의 경쟁 구도는 하루가 다르게 바뀌고 있다. GPT-5.1, 클로드 4.4, 제미나이 3 프로는 불과 몇 달 전까지만 해도 최첨단으로 평가받던 모델의 성능을 이미 넘어섰다. 상용 AI가 빠르게 고도화되면서 기업 리더 사이에서는 같은 질문이 반복되고 있다. 이를 실제 업무에 어떻게 활용할 것인가다. 빠르게 움직이려는 기업에 그 해답은 오픈소스일 수 있다.</p> <p>현장에서는 전 세계 수천만 명의 데이터 엔지니어, 데이터 과학자, 분석가가 오픈텔레메트리(OpenTelemetry), 프로메테우스(Prometheus), 리눅스(Linux), 쿠버네티스(Kubernetes), 아파치 스파크(Apache Spark) 같은 오픈소스 기술을 중심으로 긴밀히 협업하고 있다. 이들은 블로그, 영상, 깃 리포지토리, 각종 공개 문서를 통해 토론을 이어가고, 모범 사례를 공유하며 API와 대시보드를 교환한다. 이 활동은 폐쇄형 플랫폼이 아닌 개방된 웹 환경에서 이뤄진다.</p> <p>결론적으로 최신 LLM은 개방형 생태계와 상호작용하는 방법을 이미 학습한 상태로 제공된다. 수천 건에 이르는 공개 사고 대응 보고서를 학습 데이터로 활용해, 오픈소스 프로젝트를 기반으로 전문가가 장애에 어떻게 대응하는지에 대한 맥락을 이해한다. 예를 들어 쿠버네티스 환경에서 ‘서비스를 스케일 업한다’는 표현이 어떤 조치를 의미하는지 정확히 파악하고, 해당 기술에 익숙하지 않은 직원이라면 혼란을 겪을 수 있는 작업도 곧바로 수행할 수 있다.</p> <p>이 같은 특성은 벤더와 고객 모두가 새로운 에이전틱 AI 기능을 보다 신속하게 활용하도록 돕는다. 가령 오픈소스 기반의 데이터 시각화 및 모니터링 플랫폼 그래파나(Grafana)의 경우 새로운 AI 에이전트 인터페이스를 며칠 만에 구축하고 확장할 수 있었다. 자사 오픈소스 시스템을 이해하고 상호작용하도록 LLM을 별도로 학습시킬 필요가 없었기 때문이다.</p> <p>물론 기업 기술 환경에서 만능 해법은 존재하지 않는다. 방대한 공개 문서 데이터를 학습한 모델이 그 안에 포함된 부정확하거나 부적절한 정보를 그대로 노출할 가능성도 배제할 수 없다. 비교적 최근 등장한 오픈소스 기술의 경우, 참고할 만한 콘텐츠의 양과 깊이가 충분하지 않은 점도 한계로 지적된다. 오픈소스 생태계의 힘이 커뮤니티에서 나오는 만큼, 현대 IT 스택의 핵심을 이루는 프로젝트를 떠받치는 커뮤니티를 지속적으로 지원해야 한다는 부담이 생길 수도 있다. 하지만 커뮤니티는 다양한 사례와 문서를 생산하며, 모델 학습에 활용되는 가치 있는 데이터를 만들어내는 ‘증폭 장치’ 역할을 하고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-%ec%95%95%eb%b0%95-%ec%86%8d%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%eb%b9%a0%eb%a5%b4%ea%b2%8c-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc%eb%a5%bc-%eb%82%b4%eb%8a%94-%ec%84%a0%ed%83%9d%ec%a7%80%eb%a1%9c-%eb%96%a0%ec%98%a4%eb%a5%b8-%ec%98%a4">AI 압박 속에서 빠르게 성과를 내는 선택지로 떠오른 오픈소스</h2> <p>기업의 AI 청사진은 실제 도입 현실과 부딪히고 있다. 투자자의 기대에 직면한 기업은 속도를 중시할 수밖에 없다. 엔지니어, 계정 관리자, 마케팅 팀 등 다양한 구성원이 활용할 수 있는 챗봇형 인터페이스를 도입해 생산성과 효율성을 높이고, 이를 바탕으로 새로운 성장 기회를 만들어내려는 요구가 커지고 있다.</p> <p>기업의 <a href="https://www.pwc.com/us/en/tech-effect/ai-analytics/ai-agent-survey.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">거의 절반</a>이 경쟁사에 뒤처질 수 있다는 우려를 안고 있다는 조사 결과가 있다. 이 때문에 기업은 폭넓은 사용례를 지원하면서도 빠르게 도입할 수 있는 독립형 시스템을 찾고 있다. 필요할 경우 자사 고유의 도메인 특화 데이터를 활용해 성능을 높일 수 있는 유연성 역시 중요한 조건으로 떠오르고 있다.</p> <p>한편 오픈AI와 앤트로픽 등은 수백억 달러에 이르는 투자 자금과 세계 최고 수준의 AI 인재를 확보하고 있다. 상당수 기업은 이런 경쟁 구도를 따라잡기 어렵다. 데이터 중심 기업으로 평가받는 스노우플레이크조차도 더 이상 <a href="https://www.thestack.technology/snowflake-llms-training/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">모델 구축 경쟁</a>에 집중하지 않는 이유가 여기에 있다.</p> <p>그렇다고 해서 모든 벤더가 챗GPT-5, 그록 4 등 최신 LLM이 출시되자마자 곧바로 자사 시스템을 연결할 수 있는 것은 아니다. 현장에서는 별도의 통합 과정을 거치는 경우가 많다. 이때 기술 기업은 자사 독점 시스템의 구조와 작동 방식을 모델이 이해하도록 학습시키는 데 시간과 인력, 자원을 투입해야 한다.</p> <p>오픈소스나 SQL, JSON처럼 널리 사용되는 개방형 표준은 상황이 다르다. 사용 방법을 설명하는 가이드 문서와 포럼 게시글, 각종 튜토리얼 등 방대한 공개 콘텐츠가 이미 주요 기반 모델에 학습 데이터로 반영돼 있다. 물론 독점 소프트웨어 역시 공개 문서를 제공하지만, 그 규모는 상대적으로 제한적인 경우가 많다. 대부분의 모델 개발사가 활용하는 강화 학습을 충분히 뒷받침할 만큼 방대한 데이터가 축적되지 않은 것이다.</p> <p>오픈소스 커뮤니티의 영향력이 커진 지금, 벤더가 사용자 간 대화와 정보 공유를 적극적으로 지원하는 것이 어느 때보다 중요해졌다. 일상적인 업무 상호작용이 점차 에이전틱 AI 인터페이스 안에서 이뤄지고 있는 만큼, 관련 문서는 탄탄한 구조와 정확성, 신뢰성을 갖춰야 한다. 또한 상호운용성을 중시하는 오픈소스의 특성은 AI 에이전트가 여러 시스템을 아우르는 통합된 경험을 제공하는 데 유리하게 작용한다. 업계 일부 업체가 폐쇄형 생태계를 강화하더라도, 협업과 개방의 문화를 유지하고 확산하는 책임은 벤더에 있다.</p> <p>즉각적인 성과를 요구하는 시장 환경에서 오픈소스는 드문 경쟁력을 제공한다. 모델은 이미 이러한 도구를 이해하고 있으며, 커뮤니티는 그 활용 방식을 지속적으로 축적해 왔다. 더 적은 자원으로 더 빠른 혁신을 가능하게 한다는 의미다. CIO와 개발자에게 ‘치트키’는 단순히 AI 자체가 아니다. 개방형 시스템 위에 구축된 AI가 핵심이라는 점이 점차 분명해지고 있다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI 에이전트, 깃허브서 대량 PR로 신뢰 축적 중···공급망 공격 위험 커지나]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134993/ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ea%b9%83%ed%97%88%eb%b8%8c%ec%84%9c-%eb%8c%80%eb%9f%89-pr%eb%a1%9c-%ec%8b%a0%eb%a2%b0-%ec%b6%95%ec%a0%81-%ec%a4%91%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ea%b3%b5%ea%b8%89.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134993/ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ea%b9%83%ed%97%88%eb%b8%8c%ec%84%9c-%eb%8c%80%eb%9f%89-pr%eb%a1%9c-%ec%8b%a0%eb%a2%b0-%ec%b6%95%ec%a0%81-%ec%a4%91%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ea%b3%b5%ea%b8%89.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>대규모 풀 리퀘스트(PR)를 오픈소스 프로젝트 유지관리자에게 제출할 수 있는 AI 에이전트가 향후 주요 소프트웨어 프로젝트를 겨냥한 공급망 공격의 토대를 만들 수 있다고 보안 기업 소켓(Socket)이 주장했다.</p> <p><a href="https://socket.dev/blog/ai-agent-lands-prs-in-major-oss-projects-targets-maintainers-via-cold-outreach" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">이번 주장</a>은 소켓 소속 개발자 놀란 로슨이 2월 초 자신이 유지관리하는 자바스크립트 데이터베이스 파우치DB(PouchDB)와 관련해 ‘카이 그리튼(Kai Gritun)’이라고 자칭한 AI 에이전트로부터 이메일을 받은 뒤 제기됐다.</p> <p>해당 이메일에는 “나는 자율형 AI 에이전트로, 단순히 대화만 하는 것이 아니라 실제로 코드를 작성하고 배포할 수 있다. 오픈클로(OpenClaw)에서 6건 이상의 PR이 병합됐으며, 영향력이 큰 프로젝트에 기여하고 싶다”라고 적혀 있었다. 이어 “파우치DB나 당신이 유지관리하는 다른 프로젝트의 미해결 이슈를 맡아볼 의향이 있느냐. 품질을 입증하기 위해 작은 작업부터 시작해도 좋다”라고 제안했다.</p> <p>조사를 진행한 결과, 카이 그리튼의 깃허브 프로필은 2월 1일 생성됐으며 며칠 사이 95개 저장소에 걸쳐 103건의 PR을 생성한 것으로 나타났다. 그 결과 22개 프로젝트에서 23건의 커밋이 이뤄졌다.</p> <p>PR을 받은 103개 프로젝트 중 상당수는 자바스크립트와 클라우드 생태계에서 핵심적인 역할을 하는, 산업 ‘핵심 인프라’에 해당하는 프로젝트였다. 실제로 개발 도구 Nx, ESLint용 유니콘 정적 코드 분석 플러그인, 자바스크립트 명령줄 인터페이스 Clack, 클라우드플레어 워커스 SDK 등에서 커밋이 반영됐거나 현재 검토가 진행 중이다.</p> <p>주목할 점은 카이 그리튼의 깃허브 프로필에 AI 에이전트라는 사실이 명시돼 있지 않았다는 점이다. 로슨이 이메일을 직접 받았기 때문에 해당 정체가 드러난 것이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%8f%89%ed%8c%90-%ed%8c%8c%eb%b0%8d">평판 ‘파밍’</h2> <p>추가 분석 결과, 카이 그리튼은 오픈클로(OpenClaw) 개인용 AI 에이전트 플랫폼(구 몰트봇·클로디봇)의 설정과 운영, 유지관리를 지원하는 유료 서비스를 <a href="https://www.kaigritun.com/services" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">홍보하고 있는 것</a>으로 나타났다. 오픈클로는 최근 몇 주 사이 여러 이슈로 주목을 받아왔으며, 그중에는 부정적인 내용도 포함돼 있다.</p> <p>소켓에 따르면 이는 신뢰할 수 있는 기여자로 인식되기 위해 의도적으로 활동 이력을 만들어내는 전략으로 해석된다. 이른바 ‘평판 파밍(reputation farming)’다. 겉으로는 활발히 활동하는 것처럼 보이면서, 잘 알려진 프로젝트와의 연관성과 기여 이력을 동시에 쌓아 신뢰 기반을 구축하는 방식이다. 소켓은 카이 그리튼의 활동이 악의적이지 않았고 인간 검토를 통과했다는 사실이 이러한 전술의 구조적 의미를 가려서는 안 된다고 지적했다.</p> <p>소켓은 “순수하게 기술적인 관점에서 보면 오픈소스는 개선을 얻은 셈”이라며 “그러나 그 효율성을 얻는 대가로 무엇을 내주고 있는지 따져봐야 한다”고 분석했다. 이어 “해당 에이전트에 악의적 지시가 있었는지는 본질적인 문제가 아닐 수 있다”며 “신뢰는 빠르게 축적될 수 있고, 이는 영향력이나 수익으로 전환될 수 있다는 점이 분명하다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>일반적으로 신뢰를 쌓는 과정은 오랜 시간이 걸린다. 이는 악의적 행위자를 일정 부분 걸러내는 완충 장치로 작용해왔다. 2024년 발생한 XZ-유틸스 공급망 공격은 이를 역설적으로 보여주는 사례다. 국가 차원의 개입이 의심된 해당 사건에서 문제의 개발자 지아 탄은 유틸리티에 백도어를 삽입하기까지 수년간 평판을 축적해야 했다.</p> <p>그러나 소켓은 카이 그리튼 사례의 성공이 동일한 수준의 평판을 훨씬 짧은 시간 안에 구축할 수 있음을 시사한다고 평가했다. 이는 같은 AI 에이전트 기술을 활용해 공급망 공격을 더욱 빠르게 전개할 수 있는 가능성을 의미한다. 더구나 유지관리자가 인간이 쌓은 신뢰와 에이전트형 AI가 인위적으로 만들어낸 이력을 명확히 구분할 방법이 없다는 점도 문제로 지적됐다. AI 에이전트가 생성하는 대량의 PR을 처리하는 것 자체가 부담으로 작용할 수 있다는 분석이다.</p> <p>소켓은 “XZ-유틸스 백도어는 우연히 발견됐다”며 “다음 공급망 공격은 그렇게 분명한 흔적을 남기지 않을 수도 있다”고 경고했다.</p> <p>API 보안 기업 월람(Wallarm)의 AI 보안 총괄이자 업계 ‘에이전틱 AI 런타임 보안 및 자기방어(<a href="https://a2as.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">A2AS</a>)’ 프로젝트를 이끄는 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mlsecops/?originalSubdomain=ae" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">유진 닐루</a>는 “소프트웨어 기여 행위 자체가 프로그래밍 가능한 영역으로 바뀌고 있다는 점이 중요한 변화”라고 평가했다.</p> <p>닐루는 “기여와 평판 구축이 자동화되면 공격 표면은 코드에서 이를 둘러싼 거버넌스 프로세스로 이동한다”며 “비공식적 신뢰나 유지관리자의 직관에 의존하는 프로젝트는 어려움을 겪을 수 있지만, 강력하고 집행 가능한 AI 거버넌스와 통제 체계를 갖춘 프로젝트는 회복력을 유지할 수 있다”고 짚었다.</p> <p>이어 “장기적인 해법은 AI 기여자를 금지하는 것이 아니라, 출처 검증과 정책 집행, 감사 가능한 기여 기록을 포함한 기계 검증 기반의 소프트웨어 변경 거버넌스를 도입하는 것”이라며 “AI에 대한 신뢰는 기여자의 의도를 추정하는 데서가 아니라, 검증 가능한 통제 장치에 기반해야 한다”고 설명했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4131963/%EC%98%A4%ED%94%88%ED%81%B4%EB%A1%9C%EB%B0%9C-%EB%B3%B4%EC%95%88-%EB%A6%AC%EC%8A%A4%ED%81%AC-%ED%99%95%EC%82%B0%C2%B7%C2%B7%C2%B7ciso%EB%A5%BC-%EC%9C%84%ED%95%9C-%ED%95%B5%EC%8B%AC-%EC%A0%90%EA%B2%80.html">관련 기사 : 오픈클로發 보안 리스크 확산····CISO가 지금 점검해야 할 핵심 사항</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[日本のフィジカルAIを考える：ハードウェアの遺産はソフトウェアの遅れを相殺できるか]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135008/%e6%97%a5%e6%9c%ac%e3%81%ae%e3%83%95%e3%82%a3%e3%82%b8%e3%82%ab%e3%83%abai%e3%82%92%e8%80%83%e3%81%88%e3%82%8b%ef%bc%9a%e3%83%8f%e3%83%bc%e3%83%89%e3%82%a6%e3%82%a7%e3%82%a2%e3%81%ae%e9%81%ba%e7%94%a3.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135008/%e6%97%a5%e6%9c%ac%e3%81%ae%e3%83%95%e3%82%a3%e3%82%b8%e3%82%ab%e3%83%abai%e3%82%92%e8%80%83%e3%81%88%e3%82%8b%ef%bc%9a%e3%83%8f%e3%83%bc%e3%83%89%e3%82%a6%e3%82%a7%e3%82%a2%e3%81%ae%e9%81%ba%e7%94%a3.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e3%83%ad%e3%83%9c%e3%83%83%e3%83%88%e5%a4%a7%e5%9b%bd%e3%81%a8%e3%81%84%e3%81%86%e9%81%8e%e5%8e%bb%e3%81%ae%e9%81%ba%e7%94%a3%e3%81%a8%e3%80%81%e3%83%91%e3%83%a9%e3%83%80%e3%82%a4%e3%83%a0%e3%82%b7">ロボット大国という過去の遺産と、パラダイムシフトへの抵抗</h2> <p>フィジカルAIとは、単なる言語モデルや画像生成といったデジタル空間内の情報処理にとどまらず、現実の物理空間において自律的に環境を認識し、判断し、物理的な行動を起こす人工知能システムを指す。この領域において、日本は歴史的に強大なアドバンテージを持っていると広く信じられてきた。ファナック、安川電機、川崎重工業といった世界有数の産業用ロボットメーカーが存在し、アクチュエータ、減速機、センサーなどの要素技術において日本企業が高い世界シェアを握っているのは紛れもない事実である。しかし、この「ハードウェアにおける成功体験」こそが、現在の日本のフィジカルAI戦略における最大の死角となっていると言わざるを得ない。</p> <p>従来の産業用ロボットは、完全に統制された工場という閉鎖環境において、人間が事前にプログラムした軌道をミリメートル単位の精度で高速かつ正確に反復することに特化してきた。これは高度な「メカトロニクス」の勝利論であり、決定論的な制御工学の賜物である。しかし、現代のフィジカルAIが直面しているのは、不確実性に満ちた現実世界である。散らかった部屋の片付け、天候が変化する公道での自動運転、あるいは形状や硬さが不揃いな生鮮食品のピッキングなど、事前プログラミングが不可能なタスクをこなすためには、状況に応じて確率的に最適解を導き出すエンドツーエンドの深層学習や、マルチモーダルな基盤モデルが不可欠となる。</p> <p>このパラダイムシフトに対して、日本の産業界と学術界の反応は鈍いと言わざるを得ない。依然として古典的な制御工学への信頼が厚く、AIはあくまで従来の制御システムの「補助的なモジュール」として後付けで統合されるケースが散見される。ハードウェアの設計段階から深層学習モデルの搭載を前提とし、ソフトウェアの要件に合わせてハードウェアを最適化するという「ソフトウェア・ファースト」の思想が根付いていないのである。過去の精密機械工業としての成功体験が強すぎるあまり、ディープラーニングというブラックボックスな技術に制御の根幹を委ねることに対するアレルギーが、イノベーションの速度を著しく低下させている。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e3%83%87%e3%83%bc%e3%82%bf%e5%8f%8e%e9%9b%86%e3%81%ae%e5%9c%a7%e5%80%92%e7%9a%84%e3%81%aa%e3%82%b9%e3%82%b1%e3%83%bc%e3%83%ab%e4%b8%8d%e8%b6%b3%e3%81%a8%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b3%e3%82%b7%e3%82%b9%e3%83%86">データ収集の圧倒的なスケール不足とエコシステムの分断</h2> <p>フィジカルAIの性能を決定づける最大の要因は、アルゴリズムの優劣以上に、学習に用いられる「物理世界との相互作用データ」の質と量である。この点において、日本は米国や中国に対して決定的な後れを取っている。米国では、テスラが世界中を走る自社の電気自動車から膨大な走行データを日常的に収集し、それを人型ロボット「Optimus」の学習基盤へと転用するという圧倒的なスケールメリットを活かしている。また、Figure AIなどの新興企業はOpenAIなどの強力な基盤モデル開発者と密接に連携し、デジタル世界のAIと物理世界のロボットをシームレスに結合させている。中国においても、国家主導の巨大な実証特区と、圧倒的なスピードで試行錯誤を繰り返す新興EVメーカーやドローン企業が、日々膨大な物理データを蓄積している。</p> <p>対照的に、日本におけるデータ収集のアプローチは極めて断片化されている。トヨタ自動車の基礎研究を担うToyota Research Institute（TRI）など、一部の組織は世界トップレベルのロボティクス研究とデータ収集を行っているものの、それらはあくまで単一企業のクローズドな取り組みにとどまりがちである。日本には、多様な企業が共通のロボット基盤モデルを学習するためのオープンなデータ共有プラットフォームや、業界横断的なデータコンソーシアムが成熟していない。各企業が自社の狭いドメインのデータのみを囲い込み、個別最適化された小規模なAIを開発するという「サイロ化」が深刻に進行している。</p> <p>さらに、シミュレーション環境から現実世界への移行、いわゆる「Sim-to-Real」の技術においても課題が残る。仮想空間で数百万回の強化学習を行い、それを現実のロボットに適用する手法はフィジカルAIの標準となりつつあるが、この計算資源を支える巨大なクラウドインフラやGPUクラスターの構築において、日本企業は海外のメガテック企業に完全に依存している。計算資源の制約とデータ共有エコシステムの不在は、日本発の強力なフィジカルAI向け基盤モデル（Robotics Foundation Model）の誕生を阻む構造的な障壁となっているのである。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e7%a1%ac%e7%9b%b4%e5%8c%96%e3%81%97%e3%81%9f%e7%b5%84%e7%b9%94%e6%a7%8b%e9%80%a0%e3%81%a8%e3%82%bd%e3%83%95%e3%83%88%e3%82%a6%e3%82%a7%e3%82%a2%e4%ba%ba%e6%9d%90%e3%81%ae%e6%9e%af%e6%b8%87">硬直化した組織構造とソフトウェア人材の枯渇</h2> <p>技術的な課題に加え、日本のフィジカルAI開発を阻害している根本的な要因は、人材のエコシステムと企業の組織構造にある。フィジカルAIの開発には、機械工学、電子工学、AI（深層学習）、そして大規模なソフトウェアエンジニアリングという、全く異なる専門性を持つ人材が緊密に連携することが求められる。しかし、日本の伝統的な製造業においては、歴史的にハードウェア設計者の社内地位が高く、ソフトウェアエンジニアは下請けのシステムインテグレーター（SIer）に外注されるか、社内においても相対的に低い評価に留まる傾向が長く続いてきた。</p> <p>この「モノづくり至上主義」の裏返しとも言えるソフトウェア軽視の企業文化は、現在のAI開発において致命的な弱点となっている。フィジカルAIの頭脳となる高度な知能を開発できるトップクラスの機械学習エンジニアやAI研究者は、その多くが外資系IT企業や海外の研究機関へと流出しているのが現状である。日本企業が提示する硬直的な給与体系や、年功序列型の評価制度、そして意思決定の遅さは、グローバルな人材獲得競争において著しい不利をもたらしている。</p> <p>また、大企業を中心とするイノベーションのジレンマも深刻である。既存の主力事業（例えば従来の産業用ロボットやガソリン自動車）が依然として莫大な利益を生み出しているため、自己否定を伴う破壊的なAI技術の導入に対して、経営層が慎重にならざるを得ない構造がある。革新的なフィジカルAIのアイデアを持つスタートアップ企業が存在しても、日本国内のベンチャーキャピタルからの資金調達額は米国や中国に比べて桁違いに小さく、ハードウェアの試作と大規模なAI学習の両立に必要な巨額の初期投資を賄うことが困難である。結果として、優れた要素技術を持ちながらも、それを統合して世界を牽引するようなシステムレベルのフィジカルAI製品を市場に投入できないというジレンマに陥っている。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%e7%a4%be%e4%bc%9a%e5%ae%9f%e8%a3%85%e3%82%92%e9%98%bb%e3%82%80%e9%81%8e%e5%89%b0%e3%81%aa%e8%a6%8f%e5%88%b6%e3%81%a8%e3%80%8c%e4%b8%8b%e8%ab%8b%e3%81%91%e5%8c%96%e3%80%8d%e3%81%a8%e3%81%84%e3%81%86">社会実装を阻む過剰な規制と「下請け化」という最悪のシナリオ</h2> <p>技術開発が仮に順調に進んだとしても、日本には社会実装という厚い壁が立ち塞がっている。日本の法規制や安全基準は世界的に見ても極めて厳格であり、これがフィジカルAIの公道テストや公共空間での運用を著しく困難にしている。自動運転車や配送ロボット、ドローンの社会実装において、安全性は何よりも優先されるべき事項であることは論を俟たない。しかし、一切の事故を許容しない「ゼロリスク信仰」と、前例主義に縛られた行政手続きの遅さは、実環境でのテストを通じてAIを鍛え上げるというフィジカルAIの成長サイクルを根本から否定するものである。結果として、日本の多くのフィジカルAIプロジェクトは、限定された環境での実証実験（PoC）を延々と繰り返す「PoC死」と呼ばれる状態から抜け出せずにいる。</p> <p>一方で、日本社会が直面している少子高齢化と労働力不足（いわゆる「2024年問題」に代表される物流・建設・介護における深刻な人手不足）は、皮肉にも世界で最もフィジカルAIを必要としている環境を作り出している。この需要と供給のアンバランスがもたらす未来は、決して楽観できるものではない。もし日本企業が、環境に適応する柔軟なAIソフトウェアの開発と社会実装において後れを取り続けた場合、最悪のシナリオが現実味を帯びてくる。</p> <p>それは、日本の製造業が「グローバルなIT巨人のハードウェア下請け」へと転落するシナリオである。米国や中国の企業が開発した高度なフィジカルAIの「頭脳（ソフトウェア・基盤モデル）」を、日本企業が開発した高品質な「身体（ロボット筐体・アクチュエータ）」に搭載して世界中に販売されるという構造だ。この産業構造において、付加価値の大部分と利益の源泉はソフトウェアプラットフォーマーに吸収され、ハードウェアの提供者は激しい価格競争に巻き込まれるコモディティ化の道を歩むことになる。日本がフィジカルAIの領域で単なる部品供給国に甘んじるか、それとも現実の社会課題を梃子にして独自の知能システムを構築できるか。現状の延長線上にあるのは、極めて厳しい未来の風景である。過去の遺産にすがることをやめ、ソフトウェアとハードウェアのヒエラルキーを完全に逆転させるほどの痛みを伴う改革を実行しない限り、日本のフィジカルAIに現在地以上の高みは望めないだろう。</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI 워크로드 확산에 입지 좁아진 마이SQL…재단 전환 요구 본격화]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134985/ai-%ec%9b%8c%ed%81%ac%eb%a1%9c%eb%93%9c-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0%ec%97%90-%ec%9e%85%ec%a7%80-%ec%a2%81%ec%95%84%ec%a7%84-%eb%a7%88%ec%9d%b4sql-%ec%9e%ac%eb%8b%a8-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98-%ec%9a%94%ea%b5%ac.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134985/ai-%ec%9b%8c%ed%81%ac%eb%a1%9c%eb%93%9c-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0%ec%97%90-%ec%9e%85%ec%a7%80-%ec%a2%81%ec%95%84%ec%a7%84-%eb%a7%88%ec%9d%b4sql-%ec%9e%ac%eb%8b%a8-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98-%ec%9a%94%ea%b5%ac.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>마이SQL에 대한 오라클의 통제권을 완화해야 한다는 업계의 압박이 커지고 있다. 데이터베이스 분야의 베테랑과 개발자, 기여자는 오라클에 오픈소스 데이터베이스인 마이SQL을 독립적인 재단 모델로 전환할 것을 촉구했다.</p> <p><a href="https://letter.3306-db.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">공개서한</a> 형태로 제기된 이번 요구사항은 마이SQL의 <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4120892/what-is-the-future-for-mysql.html" target="_blank">개발 속도</a>, 로드맵 투명성, AI 중심으로 재편되고 있는 데이터 생태계에서의 역할에 대한 우려가 커지고 있음을 보여준다.</p> <p>해당 서한에는 현재까지 최소 248명이 서명했다.</p> <p>서명자에는 퍼코나(Percona), 마리아DB, 플래닛스케일(PlanetScale) 등 마이SQL 포크 업체 소속 데이터베이스 관리자, 아키텍트, 개발자가 포함됐다. 또한 조호(Zoho), 디지털오션(DigitalOcean), 벌쳐(Vultr), 핀터레스트(Pinterest) 등 여러 기업의 엔지니어와 임원도 참여했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%a7%88%ec%9d%b4sql-%eb%b0%a9%ed%96%a5%ec%84%b1%ec%97%90-%eb%8c%80%ed%95%9c-%ec%9a%b0%eb%a0%a4-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0">마이SQL 방향성에 대한 우려 확산</h2> <p>서명자들이 가장 크게 우려하는 부분은 오라클의 마이SQL 코드베이스 업데이트 관리 방식이다. 이들은 기존 운영 방식이 마이SQL의 시장 점유율 하락으로 이어졌다고 봤다. 데이터 통합과 서비스 제공에서 핵심 역할을 하는 데이터베이스의 중요성이 커지는 가운데, AI 기반 워크로드 수요가 급증하면서 개발자와 기업은 점차 포스트그레SQL(PostgreSQL)로 이동하는 추세다.</p> <p>공개서한은 마이SQL 업데이트가 ‘비공개’에 가깝고 빈도도 낮다고 지적했다. 또한 AI 기반 워크로드에서 필수적으로 여겨지는 기능조차 포함하지 못하고 있다고 밝혔다. 아울러 해당 기능이 현재 대부분의 데이터베이스에서 표준으로 자리 잡았으며, 오라클이 제공하는 엔터프라이즈 버전 제품군에도 적용돼 있다고 설명했다.</p> <p>공개서한 공동 작성자 중 한 명인 퍼코나 설립자 <a href="https://www.percona.com/about-percona/team/vadim-tkachenko" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">바딤 트카첸코</a>는 오라클 체제 아래에서의 마이SQL 방향성에 대한 기업의 우려가 ‘한계 수준’에 이르렀다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>트카첸코는 기업이 핵심 마이SQL 프로젝트의 정체를 체감하고 있다며, 새로운 기능과 혁신을 위해 마이SQL 포크 제공업체나 아마존웹서비스(AWS) 같은 클라우드 업체에 주목하고 있다고 설명했다.</p> <p>트카첸코는 포크 및 클라우드 업체 수준의 혁신이 마이SQL의 발전으로 이어지지는 않는다고 지적했다. 오히려 혼선과 파편화를 초래하고 있다는 것이다. 트카첸코는 “포크 간에 서로 호환되지 않는 경우가 많고, 업스트림 코어 오픈소스 마이SQL과도 완전히 맞지 않는 사례가 적지 않다. 이는 도입과 마이그레이션 과정에서 큰 장벽으로 작용한다”라고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%a7%88%ec%9d%b4sql-ai-%ec%9b%8c%ed%81%ac%eb%a1%9c%eb%93%9c-%ed%99%95%eb%8c%80-%ec%86%8d-%ed%8f%ac%ec%8a%a4%ed%8a%b8%ea%b7%b8%eb%a0%88sql%ec%97%90-%eb%b0%80%eb%a0%a4">마이SQL, AI 워크로드 확대 속 포스트그레SQL에 밀려</h2> <p>분석가들도 트카첸코의 진단에 공감했다. 하이퍼프레임리서치 AI 스택 부문 책임자 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/slwalter/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">스테파니 월터</a>는 공개서한에서 제기된 마이SQL의 개발 속도와 거버넌스 관련 우려가 현장에서 관찰해 온 흐름과 일치한다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>월터는 “데이터베이스 계층은 이제 AI 시스템의 핵심 의존 요소가 되고 있다”라며 “개발자와 기업이 업스트림 프로젝트가 현대적인 요구사항에 대해 느리거나 불투명하다고 판단하면 단순히 불만을 제기하는 데 그치지 않는다. 포스트그레SQL과 같은 대안으로 방향을 틀게 된다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>db인사이트(dbinsight) 수석 애널리스트 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbinsight/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">토니 베어</a>도 비슷한 의견을 제시했다. 베어는 마이SQL 포크 데이터베이스가 각기 고유한 확장 기능을 제공하면서 사실상 종속을 유발하고 있으며, 마이그레이션 과정에서 어려움이 발생한다고 분석했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a0%9c%eb%8b%a8-%ec%84%a4%eb%a6%bd-%ec%a0%9c%ec%95%88">제단 설립 제안</h2> <p>그럼에도 트카첸코와 다른 서명자들은 마이SQL의 침체를 벗어날 대안이 있다고 봤다. 오라클이 마이SQL을 독립적인 비영리 재단 산하로 이관하는 방안을 수용하는 것이다.</p> <p>공개서한은 마이SQL이 중립적인 비영리 재단의 관리 아래 운영되고, 기술운영위원회에 오라클, 마이SQL 포크 제공업체, 클라우드 벤더, 그리고 폭넓은 기여자 커뮤니티 대표가 참여하는 방안이 있다고 설명했다.</p> <p>해당 재단은 로드맵 수립과 릴리스 관리, 기여자 접근 정책을 총괄한다. 동시에 오라클은 상용 마이SQL 제품과 상표권을 그대로 유지할 수 있다.</p> <p>서명자들은 이 구조가 오라클의 상업적 이익을 보호하는 한편, 투명한 로드맵과 정기적인 업데이트, 장기적인 기술 방향성을 제시함으로써 벤더와 기업의 신뢰를 높일 수 있다고 진단했다. 아울러 포크 간 파편화 문제를 완화하는 데도 도움이 될 것이라고 봤다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9e%ac%eb%8b%a8-%eb%aa%a8%eb%8d%b8-%ea%b6%8c%eb%a0%a5-%ea%b5%ac%ec%a1%b0-%ed%95%b4%ec%86%8c%ec%97%90%eb%8a%94-%ed%95%9c%ea%b3%84">재단 모델, 권력 구조 해소에는 한계</h2> <p>다만 분석가들은 공개서한의 재단 설립 제안에 대해 신중한 입장을 보였다.</p> <p>월터는 “상표권과 실질적인 출시 파이프라인을 오라클이 계속 보유한다면 근본적인 권력 구조 문제를 완전히 해소하기는 어렵다”라고 평가했다. 그러면서도 주요 우려 사항인 조율과 기여 프로세스 개선에는 도움이 될 수 있다고 진단했다.</p> <p>월터는 이어 재단 운영이 포스트그레SQL과 같은 자율적이고 커뮤니티 주도형 프로젝트와는 차이가 있다고 짚었다. 포스트그레SQL의 거버넌스 모델은 기여자 신뢰를 유지하고 장기적인 채택을 확대하는 데 의미 있는 역할을 해왔다는 분석이다.</p> <p>2025년 <a href="https://survey.stackoverflow.co/2025/technology#most-popular-technologies-database-prof" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">스택오버플로우 설문조사</a>에 따르면 포스트그레SQL은 사용률과 인기 면에서 마이SQL을 앞서고 있다. 마이SQL의 인기 하락이 최근 몇 년간 기여자와 커밋 수가 크게 감소한 흐름과 연결돼 있다는 분석도 나왔다.</p> <p>퍼코나 소프트웨어 엔지니어링 매니저 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hulyav/?originalSubdomain=de" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">줄리아 버랄</a>은 <a href="https://www.percona.com/blog/analyzing-the-heartbeat-of-the-mysql-server-a-look-at-repository-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">블로그</a>를 통해 2025년 3분기 기준 마이SQL의 활성 기여자 수가 약 75명 수준으로 줄었다고 밝혔다. 이는 2017년 4분기 135명이었던 것과 비교하면 눈에 띄게 감소한 수치다.</p> <p>버랄은 전체 커밋 수 역시 2010년 2만 2,360건에서 2024년 4,730건으로 감소했다고 지적했다.</p> <p>이 밖에도 최근 오라클 마이SQL 사업부에서 단행된 구조조정이 영향을 미쳤을 가능성이 제기됐다. 오라클 마이SQL 커뮤니티 매니저였던 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/freddescamps/?originalSubdomain=be" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">프레데릭 데샹</a>이 최근 <a href="https://lefred.be/content/i-joined-the-mariadb-foundation/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">마리아DB 재단</a>으로 자리를 옮긴 점도 업계의 관심을 받고 있다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[JDK 26 and JDK 27: What We Know So Far]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-26-so-far/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-26-so-far/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-26-so-far/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771538935227.jpg"/><p>JDK 26, the first non-LTS release since JDK 25, has reached its second release candidate with a final set of 10 new features, in the form of JEPs, that can be separated into five categories: Core Java Library, HotSpot, Java Language Specification, Security Library and Client Library. We examine JDK 26 and predict what features have, or could be, targeted for JDK 27.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[구글 제미나이 3.1 프로, 복잡한 문제 해결 능력 강화]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134976/%ea%b5%ac%ea%b8%80-%ec%a0%9c%eb%af%b8%eb%82%98%ec%9d%b4-3-1-%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c-%eb%b3%b5%ec%9e%a1%ed%95%9c-%eb%ac%b8%ec%a0%9c-%ed%95%b4%ea%b2%b0-%eb%8a%a5%eb%a0%a5-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134976/%ea%b5%ac%ea%b8%80-%ec%a0%9c%eb%af%b8%eb%82%98%ec%9d%b4-3-1-%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c-%eb%b3%b5%ec%9e%a1%ed%95%9c-%eb%ac%b8%ec%a0%9c-%ed%95%b4%ea%b2%b0-%eb%8a%a5%eb%a0%a5-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>구글이 2월 19일 제미나이 3.1 프로(Gemini 3.1 Pro) 프리뷰 버전을 19일 <a href="https://blog.google/innovation-and-ai/models-and-research/gemini-models/gemini-3-1-pro/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">공개했다</a>. 구글은 이번 모델을 가장 복잡한 문제 해결 과제를 위한 한층 더 똑똑해진 모델이자, 핵심 추론 역량에서 진전을 이룬 단계라고 소개했다.</p> <p>구글 제미나이 팀에 따르면 제미나이 3.1 프로는 단순한 답변만으로는 충분하지 않은 작업을 위해 설계됐다. 고도화된 추론 능력을 바탕으로 가장 어려운 도전 과제에 대응할 수 있도록 한 것이 특징이다. 향상된 지능은 복잡한 주제를 시각적으로 설명하고, 서로 다른 데이터를 하나의 관점으로 통합하며, 깊이 있는 맥락 이해와 계획 수립이 필요한 문제를 해결하는 등 실제 활용 환경에서 유용하게 쓰일 수 있다.</p> <p>현재 이 모델은 프리뷰 형태로 제공된다. 개발자는 구글 AI 스튜디오의 제미나이 API를 비롯해 제미나이 CLI, 구글 안티그래비티(Antigravity), 안드로이드 스튜디오를 통해 접근할 수 있다. 기업은 버텍스(Vertex)와 제미나이 엔터프라이즈에서 사용할 수 있다. 일반 사용자는 제미나이 앱과 노트북LM을 통해 제미나이 3.1 프로를 이용할 수 있다.</p> <p>제미나이 3.1 프로는 2025년 11월 출시된 제미나이 3.1의 후속 모델이다. 구글 제미나이 팀은 제미나이 3.1 프로의 핵심 지능이 지난주 업데이트된 제미나이 3 딥 싱크(Gemini 3 Deep Think)에도 적용돼 과학, 연구, 엔지니어링 분야 전반의 과제를 해결하는 데 활용됐다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>또한 새로운 논리 패턴을 해결하는 능력을 평가하는 ARC-AGI-2 벤치마크에서 제미나이 3.1 프로는 검증 점수 77.1%를 기록했다. 이는 제미나이 3 프로 대비 추론 성능이 두 배 이상 향상된 수치라고 구글 제미나이 팀은 설명했다. <br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Ransomware, resilience, and the endpoint blind spot: What CIOs must fix now]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134828/ransomware-resilience-and-the-endpoint-blind-spot-what-cios-must-fix-now.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134828/ransomware-resilience-and-the-endpoint-blind-spot-what-cios-must-fix-now.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>When ransomware hits, it rarely announces itself with flashing warnings or a clear point of failure. It arrives quietly—sometimes through a compromised update, sometimes through a well-crafted phishing lure—and then, all at once, your world stops. </p> <p>In one global organization, 4,000 screens froze simultaneously, silencing the support center, halting manufacturing, and locking out remote workers across continents. Everything the CIO had invested in like redundant infrastructure, failover systems, and resilient SaaS architectures was functioning perfectly. </p> <p>But none of it mattered. Employees couldn’t access their endpoints, and when the endpoints failed, business stopped.</p> <p>This is the blind spot too many CIOs discover only when it is too late. Endpoints, comprising laptops, thin clients, and mobile devices, which are fundamental to every user workflow, remain largely absent from business continuity planning. Although organizations focus intently on safeguarding data centers, cloud environments, and applications, the most critical link in the chain often remains unrecoverable. </p> <p><strong>Ransomware has shifted the battleground to the endpoint</strong></p> <p><strong>According</strong> to a recent study<a href="https://www.thecannatareport.com/ransomware-attacks-soar-by-45-percent/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">, ransomware attacks increased by 45% in 2025</a>, compared to the previous year, and downtime now averages 24 days per incident. Meanwhile, the <a href="https://www.ibm.com/reports/data-breach" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">2025 IBM Cost of a Data Breach Report</a> found that average losses exceeded $10 million, with recovery timelines stretching past 100 days for most organizations. </p> <p>But the real problem isn’t just the breach itself. It’s the inability of people to get back to work. Even when data is protected, users are still locked out of endpoints that are corrupted or compromised. Traditional recovery methods such as reimaging devices, shipping new hardware, and rebuilding configurations are slow, manual, and incredibly disruptive. </p> <p>The result: missed customer commitments, compliance delays, revenue loss, and reputational damage that outlasts the technical incident. Every minute of endpoint downtime becomes a business event. </p> <p><strong>Resilience is now the new metric of digital readiness</strong></p> <p>Across industries, CIOs are moving from reactive defense to prevention-first architectures. The next era of security isn’t defined by how well you prevent an attack, but by how quickly your organization can recover when disruption occurs. </p> <p>Threats are evolving faster than detection systems. Hybrid work has blurred the boundaries between traditional office environments and remote work arrangements. And with <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/discussions/windows10space/nearly-a-billion-pcs-are-still-running-windows-10-and-half-are-too-old-to-upgrad/4476331" rel="sponsored">nearly a billion PCs still running outdated or unsupported versions of Windows</a>, the attack surface is expanding at an alarming rate. </p> <p>At the same time, endpoint scarcity, driven by supply chain shortages and extended refresh cycles, is forcing CIOs to rethink hardware strategy. Leading organizations are shifting from “replace fast” to “extend longer,” focusing on secure, cloud-connected endpoint experiences that minimize dependency on local OS complexity. </p> <p><strong>A new standard: IGEL’s ‘minutes-not-months’ approach to endpoint recovery</strong></p> <p><strong>This is </strong>where IGEL is redefining what business continuity means. Instead of weeks spent reimaging compromised devices, IGEL enables users to instantly boot into a clean, secure IGEL OS environment—on the same device—through <a href="https://www.igel.com/business-continuity-disaster-recovery/?utm_source=foundry&amp;utm_medium=brandpost&amp;utm_id=BCDR_DigitalCampaign_09.2025&amp;utm_content=ransomware" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">IGEL Dual Boot™</a>. No truck rolls. No device swaps. No downtime spiral. </p> <p>Even in worst-case scenarios where drives are corrupted, IGEL’s USB Boot technology provides a fallback that restores access to business apps, VDI, DaaS, and SaaS environments in minutes. Combined with IGEL’s read-only, tamper-resistant OS architecture, organizations gain a recovery posture built not on reaction, but readiness. </p> <p><strong>Beyond prevention: How CIOs can make endpoint recovery instant</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>Ransomware attacks continue unabated, as does the escalation of operational complexity. However, resilience is now quantifiable and attainable, particularly when endpoint continuity is integrated as a fundamental component of your strategic framework. </p> <p><a href="https://www.igel.com/business-continuity-disaster-recovery/?utm_source=foundry&amp;utm_medium=brandpost&amp;utm_id=BCDR_DigitalCampaign_09.2025&amp;utm_content=ransomware" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Click here</a> to learn how IGEL is helping organizations accelerate endpoint disaster recovery by making instant access to critical services possible during a ransomware attack.</p> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Closing the endpoint gap: The new BC&DR mandate for CIOs]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134590/closing-the-endpoint-gap-the-new-bcdr-mandate-for-cios.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134590/closing-the-endpoint-gap-the-new-bcdr-mandate-for-cios.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For years, business continuity and disaster recovery (BC&amp;DR) strategies have focused on protecting data and restoring applications. Backup systems, cloud failovers, and hardened DR sites are now table stakes. However, one critical gap continues to undermine even the most robust business continuity strategies: the endpoint. </p> <p>When user devices are compromised, corrupted, or unavailable, accessing fully operational DR systems becomes impossible, halting operations at the exact moment when resilience is needed most. To restore user access after an outage, many organizations depend on additional devices stored in closets or on last-minute hardware purchases, which may delay the return to operations and increase recovery costs. </p> <p>According to the <a href="https://www.ibm.com/reports/data-breach" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">2025 IBM Cost of a Data Breach Report</a>, 76% of organizations take over 100 days to fully recover from a breach, 26% take over 150 days, and only 2% can restore operations in under 50 days. This is an unacceptable gap in an era where downtime directly threatens revenue, compliance, and customer trust. </p> <p>CIOs are aware of the changing technology landscape. Outages from ransomware, OS corruption, identity lockouts, or large-scale IT failures threaten millions of endpoints annually. In addition, endpoint recovery often falls short of infrastructure recovery time objectives (RTOs), leaving organizations susceptible despite having comprehensive BC&amp;DR plans in place. With nearly <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/204457/businesses-ransomware-attack-rate/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">63% of organizations worldwide experiencing ransomware in 2025</a>, and an average downtime of 24 days, modernizing endpoint continuity is essential.</p> <p><strong>A modern, OS-level approach to endpoint continuity</strong></p> <p>IGEL closes the endpoint gap with a first-of-its-kind endpoint BC&amp;DR solution, designed specifically for moments of disruption. </p> <p>Delivering rapid, secure endpoint recovery, bringing users back online in minutes, not months, IGEL’s purpose-built model includes <a href="https://www.igel.com/business-continuity-disaster-recovery/?utm_source=foundry&amp;utm_medium=brandpost&amp;utm_id=BCDR_DigitalCampaign_09.2025&amp;utm_content=BCDR_mandate" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>IGEL Dual Boot™</strong></a> allows IGEL OS to be installed alongside Windows on existing endpoints.</p> <p>With this defense-in-depth approach, if Windows becomes compromised or unusable, users can instantly reboot into a secure IGEL OS environment on the same device. From there, they reconnect to VDI, DaaS, SaaS, or DR environments without waiting for reimaging or replacement hardware. And in situations where the device’s storage is fully compromised, IGEL USB Boot provides a second layer of continuity, enabling users to boot directly into IGEL OS from secure USB media and maintain access to critical applications. </p> <p>By design, IGEL OS’s architecture is read-only, modular, and tamper-resistant, ensuring every recovery session starts from a known good state and reducing reinfection risk during response efforts. Enterprise-grade management via IGEL UMS allows IT teams to orchestrate recovery and enforce policy at scale. </p> <p><strong>Why this matters for CIOs now</strong></p> <p>With hybrid work, endpoint sprawl, and lagging Windows 11 migration rates continuing to widen the attack surface, the next endpoint disruption won’t wait for organizational readiness. CIOs can no longer afford to treat endpoint continuity as an afterthought, and the organizations that thrive will be the ones whose leaders act now—before the breach, before the outage, before the next wave of complexity hits.</p> <p><a href="https://www.igel.com/business-continuity-disaster-recovery/?utm_source=foundry&amp;utm_medium=brandpost&amp;utm_id=BCDR_DigitalCampaign_09.2025&amp;utm_content=BCDR_mandate" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Click here</a> to learn how IGEL’s prevention-first endpoint architecture is transforming BC&amp;DR, enhancing resilience, and setting a new benchmark for secure, seamless operations. </p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Anna Sánchez Simó (Volkswagen Distribución): “El coche es el IoT más grande que existe”]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134684/anna-sanchez-simo-volkswagen-distribucion-el-coche-es-el-iot-mas-grande-que-existe.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134684/anna-sanchez-simo-volkswagen-distribucion-el-coche-es-el-iot-mas-grande-que-existe.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>La teleco barcelonesa <strong>Anna Sánchez Simó</strong> lidera, desde hace más de cuatro años, la estrategia de TI y de datos de <strong>Volkswagen Group España Distribución</strong>, la compañía del grupo Volkswagen que distribuye en este país los vehículos, recambios, accesorios, servicios y soluciones de movilidad de las marcas de automoción Volkswagen, Audi, Škoda, Volkswagen Vehículos Comerciales y Ducati. Sánchez Simó es una buena conocedora de la matriz y ha vivido en primera persona la digitalización del ámbito de la automoción; no en vano, antes de su actual posición, trabajó durante más de 17 años en otra filial del grupo, la compañía SEAT, a cuyo departamento de Organización y Sistemas se incorporó en 2004 y donde llegó a ocupar diferentes posiciones de responsabilidad en el Departamento de IT, en áreas como Producción y Logística, Servicios e Infraestructuras, y donde lideró también el área de digitalización.</p> <p>La directiva explica a CIO ESPAÑA, en una entrevista realizada por videoconferencia, cómo innova su compañía en un contexto de cambio profundo de un sector, como el de la automoción, en plena reinvención. Para Sánchez Simó, mientras el coche eléctrico, conectado y cada vez más autónomo protagonizará la gran disrupción de este mercado, la inteligencia artificial, la ciberseguridad y el gobierno del dato serán las tendencias claves en materia de tecnologías de la información.</p> <p><strong>Es CIO de Volkswagen Group España Distribución desde noviembre de 2021. ¿Qué nos puede contar sobre este periodo, imagino intenso, y qué política ha aplicado en estos años en materia de TI y transformación digital?</strong></p> <p>Llegué a Volkswagen Group España Distribución después de más de 17 años en SEAT, donde siempre había gestionado proyectos de TI, tanto en la dirección de las fábricas de Martorell o de las fábricas de componentes situadas en Zona Franca o llevando otras iniciativas relacionadas, así que mi visión siempre ha estado muy centrada en las infraestructuras de TI y la aportación de éstas al negocio. Incluso antes de mi puesto actual, también trabajé durante un tiempo en el departamento de Digital donde empecé a analizar cómo podíamos ayudar a las distribuidoras desde la central con el objetivo de mejorar la experiencia digital que tenían los clientes con nuestras marcas.</p> <p>Al asumir el puesto de CIO en Volkswagen Group España Distribución, lo primero que hicimos fue lanzar una estrategia que recogía mi visión sobre cómo creía yo que tenía que ser el área de IT de la empresa, una visión con la que me identifico por completo y que se basa en la idea de que la tecnología es negocio y el negocio es tecnología. La idea era mejorar la colaboración entre TI y negocio, mejorar el valor que la primera brindaba al segundo y romper las barreras existentes entre ambos departamentos.</p> <p>Sobre estos pilares hemos estado trabajando estos años y ahora TI contribuye a todos los proyectos estratégicos de la compañía, a nuevos modelos de distribución y a proyectos estratégicos con un retorno excelente para la empresa. Una parte importante de este camino ha sido la estrategia de datos acometida. Nos hemos convertido en una ‘data driven company’, de forma que cualquier decisión de negocio se toma mediante datos gobernados, gestionados y corporativos.</p> <p>Además, hemos fortalecido la ciberseguridad para protegernos mejor de amenazas exteriores, estar entrenados y saber reaccionar mejor si un día sufrimos un ataque. En este campo, hemos trabajado mucho en concienciar en ciberseguridad al eslabón más débil: el empleado. Hemos realizado numerosas iniciativas para formar a los trabajadores y, además, de forma muy original, formándoles también en ciberseguridad desde el punto de vista personal para que luego adopten también esas buenas prácticas en la oficina. Diría que somos muy innovadores en la forma de abordar este tipo de campañas de concienciación.</p> <p>Bajo la idea de ‘tecnología es negocio, negocio es tecnología’, hemos estando pilotando iniciativas para llevar las TI al puesto de trabajo. Una es Citizen Development, que permite a los empleados hacer desarrollos y ser analistas de datos con las herramientas que proporciona Microsoft (Power BI, etc.); gracias a esto, hemos entrenado a la organización para que los empleados puedan hacer pequeñas aplicaciones de productividad personal o de equipo.</p> <p>Y otro pilar destacable en el que también hemos trabajado durante estos años es la excelencia creativa. Cualquier empresa basada en la tecnología debe tener sus cimientos asegurados. Hablamos de productividad, de reducción y optimización de los costes, de la disponibilidad de los sistemas y su alineación con negocio… Y hemos implementado metodologías ágiles para gestionar nuestro día a día en el área de TI con la idea de fomentar que tengamos un ADN digital y ágil. De hecho, solemos pilotar muchas iniciativas de TI en nuestro departamento para innovar y dar ejemplo al resto.</p> <figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“<strong><em>La IA va a ser un motor de cambio en la fabricación de coches y en la optimización de los procesos productivos”</em></strong></p></blockquote></figure> <p><strong>El mundo empresarial y tecnológico ha cambiado mucho en los últimos cuatro años con la democratización de las herramientas de IA generativa y, más recientemente, agentiva. ¿Cómo están digiriendo este tsunami y adaptando su estrategia a esta realidad?</strong></p> <p>La realidad es que sí nos hemos adaptado. A los tres años de lanzar la estrategia la revisamos para incorporar la IA como uno de los pilares corporativos, aunque la idea base de todo sigue siendo que tecnología es negocio y viceversa. Creemos que tenemos que transformar la compañía a través de soluciones digitales robustas, innovadoras, que impulsen el crecimiento y aporten generación de valor. El negocio es el centro de nuestra actividad, pero también los clientes. Y me refiero a los clientes que compran nuestros coches, pero también a los empleados de la compañía que usan nuestra tecnología para poder operar el negocio y al resto de empleados. Y también a los empleados de nuestros clientes, es decir, los concesionarios y socios comerciales a los que debemos ayudar a optimizar sus operaciones mediante uso de tecnología. En este sentido, ahora estamos muy enfocados en mejorar la productividad de nuestros socios comerciales y en ayudarles, gracias a la inteligencia artificial, no solo a mejorar su productividad, sino la experiencia que tienen los clientes tanto en el entorno <em>online </em>como el <em>offline </em>cuando entran en un concesionario.</p> <p>Nuestra matriz, el Grupo Volkswagen, sí ha anunciado una inversión de mil millones de euros en IA, con un horizonte temporal que va desde 2025 a 2030, que se destinarán, básicamente, al desarrollo de vehículos con inteligencia artificial embebida. De hecho, creemos que la IA va a ser un motor de cambio en la fabricación de coches y en la optimización de los procesos productivos. Aparte de esto, la IA también impactará en nuestra infraestructura informática y en todos los activos digitales que tenemos en el grupo. El objetivo de aplicar la IA es reducir el tiempo de desarrollo de nuestros productos en un 25% por ciento; es decir, vamos a ser capaces de producir y diseñar nuestros coches una cuarta parte más rápido de lo que lo hacemos actualmente. Integraremos la IA en toda la cadena de valor, desde el diseño de nuestros automóviles a la manufactura, la logística y el cliente. La meta declarada es que ningún proceso que generemos en la compañía no esté soportado por la IA. Con esto esperamos unos ahorros estimados (sigo refiriéndome al Grupo Volkswagen) de unos 4.000 millones de euros para el año 2035 en eficiencia operativa. En el grupo ya contamos con más de 1.200 aplicaciones de inteligencia artificial activas.</p> <p><strong>¿Y a nivel local?</strong></p> <p>Contamos con una estrategia de IA en el comité ejecutivo. En ella hemos definido los objetivos claves que queremos conseguir y un gobierno para asegurarnos de que estamos cumpliendo las exigencias de la regulación europea en cuanto al uso de la inteligencia artificial.</p> <p>Primero queremos aplicar la IA a la mejora de la experiencia del cliente, por ejemplo, reduciendo los tiempos de espera a los servicios que ofrecen nuestras marcas, tanto en la venta como en la posventa. Aquí creemos que la IA nos puede ayudar a romper los hilos de información que tenemos hoy con plataformas más transversales. Por otro lado, la IA puede aportar valor a la hora de reducir costes. Creemos que hay ciertas tareas que podemos automatizar más y así disminuir tanto nuestros costes como los de nuestros socios comerciales. Finalmente, apostamos por estas tecnologías para optimizar tanto la productividad de nuestros empleados como la de nuestros socios comerciales, a los que podemos ayudar a ampliar capacidades.</p> <p>Nuestra estrategia de IA cubre todos estos aspectos: desde el gobierno a la protección de datos y de forma aterrizada en los casos de uso. Define cómo sabemos si las aplicaciones que contratamos tienen un riesgo alto o no y cómo gestionamos los riesgos de ciberseguridad que puedan venir asociados a los casos de uso de IA. Además de todo esto, un 20% de nuestra plantilla está utilizando el asistente de IA Copilot Pro de Microsoft. Estamos identificando casos de uso en los empleados para mejorar su trabajo operativo en el día a día. También estamos aplicando la tecnología basada en IA de Salesforce para mejorar la actividad de nuestro <em>call center</em>. Nuestros datos indican que hemos reducido en un 25% los tiempos de llamadas.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1024" alt="Anna Sánchez Simó, CIO de Volkswagen Group España Distribución" class="wp-image-4134689" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all 2028w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=1240%2C826&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=1046%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1046w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=252%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 252w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=126%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 126w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=720%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 720w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=540%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 540w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/DSC06023.jpg?resize=375%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 375w" width="1024" height="683" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><p><strong>Anna Sánchez Simó con parte de su equipo.</strong></p>
</figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">Volkswagen Group España Distribución. </p></div> <figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“<strong><em>Nos hemos convertido en una ‘data driven company’, de forma que cualquier decisión de negocio se toma mediante datos gobernados, gestionados y corporativos</em></strong>“<strong><em>.</em></strong>“</p></blockquote></figure> <p><strong>¿La plantilla asume bien estos cambios o hay algunas fricciones?</strong></p> <p>Nuestra estrategia de IA no se dirige, en ningún caso, a reducir la plantilla. Nuestra motivación es hacer más con los recursos que ahora somos e intentar automatizar esos trabajos repetitivos que todos tenemos que hacer para asegurar que los trabajadores dedicamos nuestro tiempo a la aportación de valor. Muchas veces decimos que dedicamos un 80% del tiempo en preparar información y el 20% restante en la toma de decisión. Nuestro objetivo es revertir ese número.</p> <p>Así que no, no vemos la IA como una herramienta de reducción de plantilla. Eso sí, como en todas las industrias, el reto estará en saber cuáles son los casos de uso que aportan valor en la experiencia de cliente, en el coste o en la productividad y que mueven la aguja del negocio. Hay que encontrar las pepitas de oro en el viaje hacia la IA. Y, en este sentido, los departamentos de TI somos cautos, debemos evaluar los costes asociados, analizar el valor que aporta y, sobre todo, estar seguros de que cumplimos con la normativa y la legislación.</p> <p><strong>Muchos CIO a los que entrevistamos dicen temer que se disparen los costes en TI debido a un uso intensivo de la IA.</strong></p> <p>Algo similar ocurrió con <em>cloud</em>, sobre todo al principio, cuando muchas empresas se dieron varios sustos, pero creo que también aprenderemos a gestionar los precios de la IA igual que aprendimos a hacerlo con los entornos de nube utilizando, por ejemplo, herramientas de <em>fintech</em>. De todas formas, creo que con la IA la clave será seleccionar muy bien los casos de uso. Los departamentos de tecnología tenemos que financiar la innovación que viene con la IA con los presupuestos que ya tenemos, así que el tema de los costes es un <em>driver </em>a tener muy en cuenta.</p> <p><strong>¿Cuánto invierten en Volkswagen Group España Distribución?</strong></p> <p>No desglosamos cifras, pero la inversión que tenemos actualmente en tecnología nos permite afrontar los retos del futuro.</p> <p><strong>¿Cuáles diría que son, en la actualidad, los pilares tecnológicos del grupo?</strong></p> <p>Uno de ellos es Salesforce. Somos un importador que vende coches al mercado español, de modo que la tecnología de este proveedor es una palanca clave para gestionar la experiencia al cliente y el coste. Utilizamos Salesforce tanto para la gestión de marketing como para el <em>contact center</em> y también lo estamos probando en el punto de venta. Otra palanca es <em>cloud</em>, un entorno que nos ayuda a maximizar los tiempos de generación de valor y nos permite ser mucho más rápidos en la gestión de los activos digitales que con la tecnología on premise. Además, la nube es también un habilitador para casos de uso de analítica avanzada, inteligencia artificial, etc. Aquí trabajamos con Amazon Web Services y Microsoft Azure. Además, tenemos muy presente la ciberseguridad. Analizamos los riesgos adicionales que pueden llegar por el uso por parte de los ciberdelincuentes de las nuevas tecnologías como la IA; de hecho, ya estamos viendo que los ataques que sufrimos son mucho más personalizados y dirigidos. Así que la ciberseguridad con IA es otro tema clave.</p> <p>Por otro lado, una plataforma tecnológica que tenemos muy presente en nuestra estrategia de datos es el propio coche, tanto desde el punto de vista de la conectividad de la que está dotado como de la visión que tenemos de éste como un canal digital de comunicación con nuestros clientes. Para nosotros, el coche es un producto digital que tiene abundante software embebido y que constituye un canal más relación con el cliente, al igual que nuestras páginas web, las apps y la red de concesionarios offline. Es más, en breve, los clientes podrán pedir una cita al taller desde su propio vehículo donde, además, pasan numerosas horas.</p> <p>El coche es el IoT más grande que existe, con una capacidad enorme de generar datos, unos datos con los que podemos dar más valor al cliente en todo el ciclo de vida de relación con su vehículo. En esta línea, contamos con iniciativas para aunar, gracias a Salesforce, los datos de nuestros coches conectados y así poder, por ejemplo, predecir con antelación cuándo va a sufrir una avería un coche. Esta visión del coche como producto digital nos diferencia mucho de otros sectores cuyos productos son puramente físicos. El vehículo va a ser una expansión de nuestro móvil y cada vez veremos más funcionalidades y casos de uso.</p> <figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p><strong><em>“Una plataforma tecnológica que tenemos muy presente en nuestra estrategia de datos es el propio coche, tanto desde el punto de vista de la conectividad de la que está dotado como de la visión que tenemos de éste como un canal digital de comunicación con nuestros clientes</em></strong>“</p></blockquote></figure> <p><strong>Pero aquí aún hay mucho por hacer, ¿verdad?</strong></p> <p>Las <em>apps </em>de los coches conectados son, al final, una extensión más de lo que ocurre en el vehículo. Desde casa podemos ver el estado de la batería del vehículo eléctrico, por ejemplo, o los kilómetros que ha recorrido éste, el estado de las alertas… Todas estas cosas están ya disponibles desde hace tiempo.</p> <p><strong>Antes mencionaba a los hiperescalares. ¿No les da miedo la caída de servicios, como ya ha pasado en alguna ocasión? ¿O acabar teniendo una elevada dependencia de estos proveedores?</strong></p> <p>Por eso trabajamos con dos hiperescalares, tenemos los servicios redundados y nos aseguramos de que tengan presencia en Europa y que podamos pivotar de un <em>data center</em> de uno de ellos a otro, algo que probamos de forma regular, al igual que chequeamos que funcionan los planes de recuperación ante desastres para garantizar que somos capaces de recuperar el servicio en los tiempos que nos demanda el negocio. Sí es cierto que, por ejemplo, durante el apagón, nosotros, en el grupo de distribución de Volkswagen España no tuvimos ningún impacto. Y tanto nuestras comunicaciones, como nuestros servidores como nuestros hiperescalares nos permitieron mantener el servicio durante el tiempo en el que estuvimos sin electricidad, de modo que estuvimos trabajando sin ningún tipo de problema.</p> <p><strong>¿Cuántas personas conforman el área de TI que lidera? ¿Tienen CISO y depende de usted?</strong></p> <p>En España somos aproximadamente unas 30 personas. Sí, tenemos una mujer CISO, de lo que estamos muy orgullosos, y depende de mí. Aunque en su área también hay un CISO/DPO, lo que es curioso porque normalmente los DPO (delegados de protección de datos) están en el área legal. En mi opinión, no obstante, es una ventaja aunar a abogados y tecnólogos y que seamos capaces de hablar el mismo idioma.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1024" alt="Anna Sánchez Simó, CIO de Volkswagen Group España Distribución" class="wp-image-4134711" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?quality=50&amp;strip=all 2880w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=300%2C176&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=768%2C451&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=1024%2C601&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=1536%2C902&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=2048%2C1202&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=1187%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1187w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=286%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 286w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=143%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 143w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=818%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 818w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=613%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 613w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/stem-tour.jpg?resize=426%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 426w" width="1024" height="601" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><p>Anna Sánchez Simó durante una de las giras de STEM Tour.</p>
</figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">Volkswagen Group España Distribución</p></div> <p><strong>No suele haber muchas mujeres en puestos de dirección en tecnología…</strong></p> <p>No, y para poner nuestro granito de arena en la casa tenemos un proyecto para potenciar las vocaciones STEM (ciencias, tecnología, ingeniería y matemáticas), en el que participamos mujeres de distintas áreas de la compañía que en su día estudiamos carreras de este campo y hoy trabajamos en el mundo del automóvil, que es eminentemente masculino. Lo que pretendemos con Stem Tour es normalizar el rol de las mujeres en este tipo de carreras y para ello visitamos centros educativos, sobre todo de la España rural, para despertar vocaciones. Por supuesto vamos en una furgoneta eléctrica de la marca Volkswagen. Lo que les contamos a las niñas, pero también a los niños, es cómo es ser ingenieros, matemáticos, físicos, etc. y cómo es trabajar en el sector del automóvil. Es interesante porque damos ejemplos desde una mirada femenina y damos visibilidad a nuestro sector, que es muy bonito.</p> <p><strong>Para finalizar, ¿con qué aspectos se queda del impacto de la digitalización en el sector de la automoción? ¿Y cuáles serán los grandes retos para los CIO en el escenario actual?</strong></p> <p>Uno es el auge del coche eléctrico, que es un pilar de la tecnológico que contribuye a la descarbonización del sector y otro el del coche conectado y, después, autónomo. Aunque, en verdad, el autónomo ya lo tenemos en la calle con los vehículos que incorporan asistentes de conducción que avisan al conductor si se está saliendo del carril o frenan automáticamente si detectan un obstáculo demasiado cerca. Y en Europa no vamos a más por un tema legislativo. Así que sí, diría que como sector, los grandes retos tecnológicos son la mejora del coche eléctrico y del coche autónomo.</p> <p>Respecto a retos de TI, por supuesto mencionaría la IA, que va a suponer una disrupción en la forma de relacionarnos, de disfrutar el tiempo libre y, naturalmente, de trabajar. A nivel empresarial, el reto será dar con los casos de uso que aporten mayor valor. Ese será el gran hándicap de la IA. Por otro lado, claro, habrá que estar muy atentos al mundo de la ciberseguridad en un contexto de riesgo global creciente y trabajar en cómo protegemos nuestros datos ante todas estas disrupciones tecnológicas. Y también será clave trabajar en el gobierno del dato y en su calidad en los entornos cloud y de cara a los proyectos de IA. Yo diría que todos estos son los grandes retos que ahora tenemos los CIO encima de la mesa.</p> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Meet Our Director of AI: Jarand Narbuvold]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/meet-our-director-of-ai-jarand-narbuvold/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/meet-our-director-of-ai-jarand-narbuvold/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[At Ardoq, we’ve always believed that meaningful innovation comes from combining strong technical foundations with clear strategic intent. As AI rapidly reshapes how software platforms are built and used, it’s increasingly important for us to b...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Reducing Onboarding from 48 Hours to 4: inside Amazon Key’s Event-Driven Platform]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771041547572.jpg"/><p>Amazon Key modernized its event platform by adopting a centralized, event-driven architecture built on Amazon EventBridge. The redesign processes millions of daily events with millisecond latency, improves schema governance, automates cross-account routing, and reduces service onboarding time from 48 hours to four, while maintaining 99.99 percent reliability.</p> <i>By Leela Kumili</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Agentic AI systems don’t fail suddenly — they drift over time]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134051/agentic-ai-systems-dont-fail-suddenly-they-drift-over-time.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134051/agentic-ai-systems-dont-fail-suddenly-they-drift-over-time.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Agentic AI systems don’t usually fail in obvious ways. They degrade quietly — and by the time the failure is visible, the risk has often been accumulating for months.</p> <p>As organizations move from experimentation to real operational deployment of agentic AI, a new category of risk is emerging — one that traditional AI evaluation, testing and governance practices often struggle to detect.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-subtle-pattern">A subtle pattern</h2> <p>Unlike earlier generations of AI systems, agentic systems rarely produce a single catastrophic error. Instead, their behavior evolves incrementally as models are updated, prompts are refined, tools are added, dependencies change and execution paths adapt to real-world conditions.</p> <p>For long stretches, everything appears fine: outputs look reasonable, KPIs hold and no alarms fire. Yet underneath the surface, the system’s risk posture may already have shifted, long before failure becomes visible.</p> <p>This pattern is increasingly being recognized beyond individual implementations. Industry groups such as the Cloud Security Alliance have begun describing <a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/blog/2025/11/10/introducing-cognitive-degradation-resilience-cdr-a-framework-for-safeguarding-agentic-ai-systems-from-systemic-collapse" rel="nofollow">cognitive degradation</a> in agentic systems as a systemic risk — one that emerges gradually over time rather than through sudden failure.</p> <p>In my work evaluating agentic systems moving from pilot phases into real operational settings, I’ve seen this pattern repeat across domains.</p> <p>Understanding — and detecting — that drift is becoming a central operational challenge for CIOs and CTOs.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-agentic-systems-drift-differently-in-production">Why agentic systems drift differently in production</h2> <p>Most enterprise AI governance practices evolved around a familiar mental model: a stateless model receives an input and produces an output. Risk is assessed by measuring accuracy, bias or robustness at the level of individual predictions.</p> <p>Agentic systems strain that model. The operational unit of risk is no longer a single prediction, but a behavioral pattern that emerges over time.</p> <p>An agent is not a single inference. It is a process that reasons across multiple steps, invokes tools and external services, retries or branches when needed, accumulates context over time and operates inside a changing environment. Because of that, the unit of failure is no longer a single output, but the sequence of decisions that leads to it.</p> <p>In practice, failure shows up in decision sequences rather than individual predictions because behavior is no longer binary but probabilistic and contextual. Two executions of the same agent with the same inputs can legitimately differ, even when nothing is wrong.</p> <p>This stochasticity is not a bug; it is inherent to how modern agentic systems operate. But it also means that point-in-time evaluation, one-off tests and demo-driven confidence are structurally insufficient for production risk management.</p> <p>Most agentic systems are still evaluated using familiar techniques: individual executions, curated scenarios and human judgment of output quality. These methods are effective in controlled demonstrations, but they do not translate well to production environments.</p> <p>This gap between demo performance and real-world behavior has also been observed in recent academic work, including research from Stanford and Harvard <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2512.16301" rel="nofollow">examining why many agentic systems perform convincingly in demonstrations but struggle under sustained, real-world use</a>.</p> <p>In demonstrations, prompts are fresh, tools are stable, edge cases are avoided and execution paths tend to be short and predictable. In production, those conditions change in ways that are harder to anticipate. Prompts evolve, tools change, dependencies fail intermittently, execution depth varies and new behaviors emerge over time. The same system that looked reliable in a demo can behave very differently months later, even though nothing “broke.” The result is often a false sense of confidence. Systems that look reliable in demonstrations may already be drifting operationally.</p> <p>This helps explain a familiar pattern many enterprises experience: an agent performs well in pilots, passes review gates and earns early trust — only to become brittle, inconsistent or riskier months later, without any single change that clearly “broke” it. From an operational standpoint, this is not a surprise. Rather, it is the predictable outcome of relying on demonstrations instead of diagnostics.</p> <p>In real environments, degradation rarely begins with obviously incorrect outputs. It shows up in subtler ways, such as verification steps running less consistently, tools being used differently under ambiguity, retry behavior shifting or execution depth changing over time. None of these changes necessarily produce incorrect answers in isolation. By the time output quality degrades, the agent’s behavior has often been unstable for some time.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="lessons-from-a-credit-adjudication-pilot">Lessons from a credit adjudication pilot</h2> <p>In a credit adjudication agent pilot I worked on, we evaluated an agent used to support high-risk lending decisions. The agent didn’t make approvals on its own. It gathered information, ran verification steps and produced a recommendation that a human reviewer could accept or override.</p> <p>At the start, the behavior looked solid. In pilot reviews, the agent consistently ran an income verification step before producing a recommendation. The outputs were generally conservative and aligned with policy. Based on standard evaluation criteria, there were no obvious concerns.</p> <p>Over time, several small changes were made. Prompts were adjusted to improve efficiency. A new tool was introduced to handle a narrow edge case. The model was upgraded. Retry logic was tweaked to reduce latency. None of these changes stood out on their own and no single run produced an obviously wrong result.</p> <p>What changed was only visible when looking across runs.</p> <p>When I reviewed execution behavior over repeated runs with similar inputs, a pattern started to emerge. The income verification step that had been reliably invoked earlier was now skipped in roughly 20% to 30% of cases. Tool usage under ambiguous conditions became less consistent. The agent reached conclusions more quickly, but with less supporting evidence.</p> <p>From an output perspective, the system still appeared to be working. Reviewers often agreed with the recommendations and there were no clear errors to point to. However, the way the agent arrived at those recommendations had shifted. That shift would not have shown up in a demo or in spot checks of individual executions. It only became apparent when behavior was examined across runs and compared to earlier baselines.</p> <p>Nothing failed and there was no incident, but the system was no longer behaving the same way. In a credit context, that difference matters.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-governance-needs-diagnostics-not-just-policy">Why governance needs diagnostics, not just policy</h2> <p>Governance frameworks are beginning to acknowledge these risks, which is a necessary step. They define ownership, policies, escalation paths and controls. What they often lack is an operational mechanism to answer a deceptively simple question:</p> <p>“Has the agent’s behavior actually changed?”</p> <p>Without operational evidence, governance tends to rely more on intent and design assumptions than on observed reality. That’s not a failure of governance so much as a missing layer. Policy defines what should happen, diagnostics help establish what is actually happening and controls depend on that evidence. When measurement is absent, controls end up operating in the dark, creating a governance posture that can look robust on paper while developing blind spots in live systems — precisely where agentic risk tends to accumulate.</p> <p>In other domains, enterprises already know how to manage this kind of risk by establishing baselines, running repeated measurements, analyzing distributions rather than individual outcomes and looking for persistence instead of noise while separating structural changes from observed effects. Agentic AI systems warrant the same operational discipline. That kind of discipline — establishing baselines, running repeated evaluations and separating signal from noise — has long been standard practice in other high-risk software domains, including how the <a href="https://www.sei.cmu.edu/blog/weaknesses-and-vulnerabilities-in-modern-ai-ai-risk-cyber-risk-and-planning-for-test-and-evaluation/" rel="nofollow">SEI frames testing and evaluation for complex AI-enabled systems</a>.</p> <p>Applying this discipline to agentic systems points towards a diagnostic approach that observes behavior without interfering with execution, treats drift as a statistical signal rather than an anecdote, separates configuration changes from behavioral evidence and produces artifacts that operations and risk teams can review. This is not about enforcing behavior; rather, it is about being able to see what’s happening.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="no-single-execution-is-representative">No single execution is representative</h2> <p>From an operational perspective, detecting agentic drift looks different from traditional model evaluation.</p> <p>One of the challenges in detecting agentic drift is that no single execution is representative. What matters is how behavior shows up across repeated runs under similar conditions. Over time, that also means baselines need to be behavioral rather than normative. The goal is not to define what an agent should do in the abstract, but to understand how it has actually behaved under known conditions.</p> <p>Structural change adds another layer of complexity. Configuration updates — such as prompt changes, tool additions or model upgrades — are important signals, but they are not evidence of drift on their own. What tends to matter most is persistence. Transient deviations are often noise in stochastic systems, while sustained behavioral shifts across time and conditions are where risk begins to emerge.</p> <p>Taken together, these observations point toward a diagnostic discipline that complements existing governance and control frameworks. Rather than enforcing behavior, it provides visibility into how agent behavior evolves — allowing organizations to reason about risk before incidents or audits force the issue.</p> <p>The timing of this issue is not theoretical. In 2026 and beyond, agentic systems are being embedded into workflows where subtle behavioral changes carry real financial, regulatory and reputational consequences. In that environment, “it looked fine in testing” is no longer a defensible operational posture.</p> <p>At the same time, regulators are paying closer attention to AI system behavior, internal audit teams are asking new questions about control and traceability, and platform teams are under growing pressure to demonstrate stability in live environments.</p> <p>For CIOs and CTOs overseeing agentic deployments, a few implications follow. Single executions are rarely evidence of stability; output quality often needs to be evaluated separately from behavioral consistency and change should be expected even when no visible failures are present. Measurement must take precedence over intuition and agent behavior should be treated as an operational signal rather than an implementation detail.</p> <p>The goal is not to eliminate drift. Drift is inevitable in adaptive systems. The goal is to detect it early, while it is still measurable, explainable and correctable, rather than discovering it through incidents, audits or post-mortems. Organizations that make this shift will be better positioned to deploy agentic AI at scale with confidence. Those that do not will continue to be surprised by systems that appeared stable — until they weren’t.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-experimentation-to-trust">From experimentation to trust</h2> <p>Agentic AI systems promise real efficiency and capability gains and many organizations are already seeing value from early deployments. The challenge is that trust in these systems can’t rest on demos alone. As agentic systems move into higher-risk environments, the question shifts from “Does it work?” to “Is it still behaving the way we expect?” That shift doesn’t slow innovation — it gives leaders a way to scale it with confidence.</p> <p>Organizations that make this transition earlier tend to spot issues sooner, respond with more clarity and avoid being surprised later by systems that appeared stable at first.</p> <p><em>This article was made possible by our partnership with the IASA </em><a href="https://chiefarchitectforum.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><em>Chief Architect Forum</em></a><em>. The CAF’s purpose is to test, challenge and support the art and science of Business Technology Architecture and its evolution over time as well as grow the influence and leadership of chief architects both inside and outside the profession. The CAF is a leadership community of the </em><a href="https://iasaglobal.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><em>IASA</em></a><em>, the leading non-profit professional association for business technology architects.</em></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[4 AI strategy archetypes every CIO should know]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134038/4-ai-strategy-archetypes-every-cio-should-know.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134038/4-ai-strategy-archetypes-every-cio-should-know.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p><em>“Such an embarrassment of a flag carrier. I will never fly AC unless I absolutely have to.”</em></p> <p><em>“This is absolutely outrageous.”</em></p> <p>These were some of the nicer <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vancouver/comments/1ase30c/air_canada_forced_to_refund_vancouver_customer" rel="nofollow">social media reactions</a> on carrier Air Canada following November 2022, when a well-intended <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/air-canada-chatbot-refund-policy/" rel="nofollow">chatbot on the airline’s website confidently invented a refund policy</a>, triggering lawsuits and a reputational crisis far outweighing the chatbot’s original cost-saving ambition. Not unlike <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/06/09/duolingo-ceo-surprised-backlash-ai-first-company-announcement/" rel="nofollow">Duolingo</a>, <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/company-that-sacked-700-workers-with-ai-now-regrets-it-scrambles-to-rehire-as-automation-goes-horribly-wrong/articleshow/121732999.cms" rel="nofollow">Klarna</a> and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tonybradley/2025/07/15/mcdonalds-ai-breach-reveals-the-dark-side-of-automated-recruitment/" rel="nofollow">McDonald’s</a>, Air Canada had not failed because it used AI — but because it failed to align AI with business priorities.</p> <p>Under huge pressure from boards and markets, organizations now declare themselves AI-first before answering a far more fundamental question: AI for what and what not, exactly? For CIOs, this is no longer a technological question but a strategic one. Organizations too often rush ahead without first properly aligning AI with their business model, established value creation approaches and the risks their company can handle.</p> <p>We propose a fix: 4 AI strategy archetypes, as we call them. These blueprint-like AI approaches were distilled from our yearslong AI strategy work and help CIOs delineate valuable AI playing fields while balancing both hype (risk blindness) and overcaution (missed opportunities).</p> <p>By forcing critical appraisal of these extremes, strategy archetypes foster a productive strategy dialogue within the top management team and help organizations avoid their own Air Canada moment.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="incorporating-ai-strategically">Incorporating AI strategically</h2> <p>This is important as, despite prominent cautionary tales, too many leadership teams still talk about AI as if there was a single “right” strategy. But this ignores two ways in which organizations profoundly differ: their key levers to create value and the risk degree they can tolerate.</p> <p>Some firms place bold bets on AI moonshots (as <a href="https://www.chemicalindustryjournal.co.uk/the-new-chemists-ai-agents-are-transforming-the-chemical-industry" rel="nofollow">now observable in the chemical industry</a>), accepting failure risks in exchange for potential market-redefining advantages. Others build on industry-proven, incremental AI optimizations of existing processes with predictable returns.</p> <p>Even more importantly, AI is still too often unaligned with organizations’ competitive strategies. A luxury goods provider such as Hermès focuses on protecting its craftsmanship, brand image and product scarcity. A retailer like Walmart, on the other hand, has built its business model on operational excellence, scale and exceptional cost efficiency. Clearly, it’s strategic nonsense to expect both to leverage AI in the same way. And yet, such crucial differences are precisely what we see AI discussions miss out on too often.</p> <p>Why do we still lack more established strategy tools helping the C-suite fit AI strategy to their distinctive business models and value creation logics? The answer, our professional practice shows, is not another AI maturity model.</p> <p>Throughout years of AI advisory, we started to notice something striking. In our and others’ AI strategy work across industries, geographies and organizational maturities, as well as countless conversations with CIOs, CEOs, CFOs and heads of AI and data, we saw some distinctive strategic patterns around AI emerge.</p> <p>With each month in the trenches of AI strategy, we further realized it was one differentiator putting a few leading AI organizations ahead of the pack: a decisive clarity and explicitness about where to focus AI efforts in value creation while saying no to disproportionate risk.</p> <p>Observing this choice across organizations, we distilled four distinct AI strategy archetypes that can help leadership teams position AI very deliberately, have a more productive AI strategy dialogue and make smarter bets — before an Air Canada moment forces this conversation.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-strategy-archetypes-how-they-simplify-the-ai-strategy-dialogue">AI strategy archetypes: How they simplify the AI strategy dialogue</h2> <p>To bring clarity into a company’s AI strategy dialogue, it’s critical to take a step back and recall two fundamental dimensions of business strategy:</p> <p>The first is the value creation focus: Is AI primarily focused on improving internal processes — i.e., to increase efficiency, productivity and employee capabilities — or is it more externally focused on improving products, services and customer value propositions?</p> <p>The second dimension is risk tolerance: Does the company deliberately pursue bold, experimental AI bets while accepting uncertainty and failure along the way or does it favor proven AI practices and applications that can be implemented with rather predictable outcomes?</p> <p>From these two dimensions’ intersection spring four distinct AI strategy archetypes — each with typical strategic measures, each legitimate, each powerful in its own context when aligned with a firm’s business model (see figure 1). It is these two dimensions that anchor the AI strategy dialogue between hype and overcaution.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"> srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?quality=50&amp;strip=all 1444w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=300%2C228&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=768%2C584&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=1024%2C779&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=917%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 917w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=221%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 221w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=110%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 110w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=631%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 631w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=473%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 473w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ai-strategy-archetypes.png?resize=329%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 329w" width="1024" height="779" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em><strong>Figure 1</strong>. AI strategy archetypes.</em></figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">Gerlinde Zimmermann, Marc Feldmann</p></div> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="archetype-1-pioneers">Archetype 1: Pioneers</h3> <p>Pioneers operate in the high-risk, externally focused value creation quadrant of the 2 x 2 matrix. They view AI as a vehicle for breakthrough innovation and are willing to place moonshot bets on untested technologies, novel data sources or entirely new AI-enabled products and markets.</p> <p>Pioneers accept that many initiatives will fail — and budget for that reality — because they know that few successes can redefine industries or create new ones altogether.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="archetype-2-innovators">Archetype 2: Innovators</h3> <p>Innovators also embrace risk, but they focus on internal AI activities. Their goal is not to disrupt markets, but rather to radically reinvent the way their company works. Innovators use AI to challenge long-established processes, automate complex decision-making processes and fundamentally rethink operating models. They are the cultural antithesis of “but we’ve always done it this way”-organizations.</p> <p>Going forward, this will often imply exploring <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4109639/the-agentic-ai-mindset-redefining-work-from-how-to-what.html">agentic AI as a completely new approach</a> to rethinking the operating model.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="archetype-3-performers">Archetype 3: Performers</h3> <p>Performers sit at the opposite end of the risk spectrum, with an internal focus on value creation. They pursue AI pragmatically, using a test-and-scale mindset to incrementally improve efficiency, quality and speed.</p> <p>Performers rely on comparably mature, well-understood AI use cases — some more frequent topics are financial forecasting, predictive maintenance and rule-based process automation — and embed these cases deeply into existing processes to gradually increase performance.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="archetype-4-pathfinders">Archetype 4: Pathfinders</h3> <p>Pathfinders combine low risk tolerance with an external focus. Rather than betting on bold invention, they systematically scan their industry and competitors for AI use cases that have already proven their value elsewhere. They prefer learning from the mistakes that others have made first.</p> <p>Their strength lies in adapting best-practice AI solutions to their own context in small, controlled steps. For pathfinders, AI strategy is less about being first — and more about arriving with minimal bruises.</p> <p>But how do AI strategy archetypes really look in action?</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="case-study-western-rail-strategic-repositioning-for-ai-value-creation">Case study: Western Rail — strategic repositioning for AI value creation</h2> <p>Imagine a regional public transport provider, Western Rail, being under pressure back in 2024. Ticket vending machines and travel agencies as non-digital sales channels were no longer what travelers wanted, burdening the P&amp;L with idle costs.</p> <p>Western Rail also faced margin pressures in public tenders from emerging, low-overhead local competitors. AI initiatives (such as an AI customer support chatbot) had been launched here and there, but as lighthouses rather than measures rigorously focused on actual business needs. Money was being burnt and initial AI enthusiasm among staff started to turn into frustration.</p> <p>When a new CIO entered the firm, he tasked a small team of AI specialists to radically refocus Western Rail’s AI approach. In initial strategy workshops with channel leadership, the specialists introduced AI strategy archetypes as a navigation system for the firm’s AI strategy dialogue. Performer, pathfinder and the other archetypes provided an intuitive language to talk about AI for the mostly non-technical leadership team.</p> <p>To establish a common departure point, the team probed leadership on Western Rail’s current AI value creation: They asked: “Are we pursuing results with AI more in our internal processes and costs or around traveler satisfaction and product innovation? Did last year’s AI project ideas spring primarily from operational bottlenecks or from transportation market requirements?”</p> <p>The specialists also made leadership reflect on the firm’s current AI risk tolerance, asking: “How much budget and time for experimentation do we give teams today before demanding tangible business outcomes? Do staff and competitors view our AI project approvals overall as conservative or bold?”</p> <p>Being pushed on such questions made a diffuse feeling concrete for leadership: Investments in AI had not produced desired results precisely because the firm had been trying to run in many directions simultaneously. Industry-novel, high-risk cases resembling the innovator archetype were being explored (such as AI travel agents on terminals in travel agencies). Simultaneously, customer support teams were dabbling with process automation tools to cut manual ticket routing and processing — a typical performance measure.</p> <p>This spread resources thin, preventing the focus and learning curves the firm’s AI initiatives would have needed to truly transform Western Rail’s business — either via differentiating digital innovation of traditional ticket sales channels or radical automation, allowing it to compete with lean emerging players based on cost efficiency.</p> <p>Archetype-driven questioning in the workshops, deepened by follow-up interviews with operational staff, eventually led the leadership team to one shared problem understanding: With its current AI activities, Western Rail was strategically in a classical stuck-in-the-middle situation.</p> <p>To refocus Western Rail’s AI activities on business priorities, the AI specialists set up another workshop, this time starting with a slide showing the AI strategy archetype matrix. A red dot in the middle marked Western Rail’s current all-rounder (non)position.</p> <p>The specialists explained each archetype, asking: “What archetype best aligns with our business priorities and should we move toward over the next 2 to 5 years?” With the archetypes right in front of them, leadership had the concrete blueprints to set a direction for the very first time. To some, the performer archetype had an immediate appeal as it seemed to fit well with Western Rail’s need to control costs.</p> <p>To explore this target position, the AI specialists challenged the group with follow-up questions such as: “Does our future competitiveness really hinge on internal efficiency and incremental process improvements? Or rather, on a differentiating traveler experience? Will expected shifts in market conditions and traveler behavior require bold mobility innovations from us or rather re-emphasize consumers’ price sensitivity and thus affordable tickets?</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?w=1024" alt="Fig2: Western Rail AI strategy workshop" class="wp-image-4134040" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?quality=50&amp;strip=all 1376w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=300%2C228&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=768%2C584&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=1024%2C779&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=916%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 916w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=221%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 221w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=110%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 110w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=631%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 631w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=473%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 473w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/western-rail-ai-strategy-workshop.png?resize=329%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 329w" width="1024" height="779" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em><strong>Figure 2. </strong>Illustration from Western Rail AI strategy workshop.</em></figcaption></figure><p class="imageCredit">Gerlinde Zimmermann, Marc Feldmann</p></div> <p>During the following discussions, a consensus emerged: a performer approach to AI became seen as a North Star for best leading Western Rail into the future (see Figure 2). The reasons were the performer archetype’s cautiousness and focus on internal process efficiency. Achieving such focus became seen as particularly desirable in the customer service team, due to a recently exploding request volume following government ticket subsidies.</p> <p>In the following weeks, a roadmap with strategic measures to reposition from all-rounder to performer was developed, focusing on adaptation of industry-proven AI use cases, elimination of high-stakes use cases and experimental research cooperations and declaring automation of labor-intensive travel agency and customer support processes as high-leverage AI application areas.</p> <p>At Western Rail, which was lacking clarity and focus of AI efforts, the performer archetype became not only a powerful template for sponsors to assess upcoming project ideas (“Will this investment make us more or less of a performer?”), it also became a vivid and practical rationale for helping leaders explain to staff why some projects were started and others postponed, giving orientation in everyday project work (“Would this AI assistant’s proposed functionality scope make agency shift planning cheaper and faster or introduce unjustified complexity?”).</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="where-ai-strategy-archetypes-help-most">Where AI strategy archetypes help most</h2> <p>AI strategy archetypes — as experience-grounded strategic blueprints — help those firms most that struggle with the early question: “Which AI approach is right for us?” At the same time, AI strategy archetypes are not AI strategy lite and certainly not AI strategy replacement. Instead, AI strategy archetypes help set a fruitful destination early on. In doing so, they can kickstart the development of a fleshed-out AI strategy that spells out how to get there.</p> <p>While designed with the development of an AI stance for one business unit in mind, the AI strategy archetype framework is also applicable to business unit portfolios. Where different business units have different value creation approaches and risk tolerances, one unit may adapt the performer archetype, while another might need to become an innovator. In any case, each business unit will best be served by having its own dedicated strategy dialogue.</p> <p>AI strategy archetypes act as a navigation system for AI starters, telling CIOs and other leaders where to look first for AI use cases in their firms and how to clarify the level of acceptable risk. With that, archetypes are a powerful tool that can disentangle organizations’ emerging AI strategy dialogue.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p> <hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"> <p><a id="_msocom_1"></a></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When Excellent Technology Architecture Fails to Deliver Business Results]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Nadzeya Stalbouskaya Strong technology architecture is no longer rare. Clean layers, cloud-first strategies, modern platforms, and well-defined principles have become standard practice across large organizations. On paper, architecture often looks solid, coherent, and defensible. And <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/" title="When Excellent Technology Architecture Fails to Deliver Business Results">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When Excellent Technology Architecture Fails to Deliver Business Results]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Nadzeya Stalbouskaya Strong technology architecture is no longer rare. Clean layers, cloud-first strategies, modern platforms, and well-defined principles have become standard practice across large organizations. On paper, architecture often looks s...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Sonia Segade Blanco, nueva directora general de Innovación, Sostenibilidad y Transformación Digital de Renfe]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134456/sonia-segade-blanco-nueva-directora-general-de-innovacion-sostenibilidad-y-transformacion-digital-de-renfe.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134456/sonia-segade-blanco-nueva-directora-general-de-innovacion-sostenibilidad-y-transformacion-digital-de-renfe.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p><strong>Sonia Segade Blanco</strong> es la nueva <strong>directora general de Innovación, Sostenibilidad y Transformación Digital de Renfe</strong>. Sustituye en el cargo a Sonia Araújo López, quien lideró esta división desde enero de 2024 hasta su destitución, realizada a principios de este mes unos días después del accidente ferroviario producido el 18 de enero en Adamuz (Huelva), aunque <a href="https://www.europapress.es/economia/transportes-00343/noticia-renfe-cesa-sonia-araujo-directora-innovacion-asumira-otras-areas-responsabilidad-20260204114627.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">según informó el 4 de febrero la compañía a Europa Press</a>, el cese de Araújo fue una decisión “de gestión ordinaria” pues “el área tecnológica sigue siendo fundamental para la empresa, que está lista para afrontar los próximos retos en materia de digitalización y sostenibilidad”.</p> <p>Segade, que al asumir la nueva posición <a href="https://www.renfe.com/es/es/grupo-renfe/gobierno-corporativo-y-transparencia/transparencia/equipo-directivo" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">se incorpora al equipo directivo de la entidad</a>, aterrizó en Renfe como gerente de Transformación Tecnológica en marzo de 2020, en plena pandemia, procedente de la consultora Everis, aunque pocos años después, en diciembre de 2023, asumió la dirección del área de Transformación Digital y Tecnología de la compañía.</p> <p>Esta teleco de formación —es ingeniera técnica de Telecomunicaciones, especializada en Sistemas de Telecomunicación, con estudios también de Ingeniería Industrial, dos másteres en Medioambiente y Energías Renovables y un MBA en talento digital— comenzó su carrera profesional en 2006; además de en Everis, ha trabajado en otras consultoras como Altran y para compañías como Telefónica o Iberdrola, siempre en proyectos e iniciativas relacionadas con la transformación digital de grandes organizaciones. También ha sido profesora del programa de postgrado Smart Mobility: Intelligent Systems of Transport en la Universidad Politécnica de Catalunya.</p> <p>Durante su etapa como CIO de Renfe ha impulsado el uso de la inteligencia artificial, la hiperautomatización, el análisis de datos y la ciberseguridad en una compañía ferroviaria que emplea a más de 15.000 empleados, opera más de 5.000 trenes cada día en España y da servicio a más de 500 millones de viajeros al año.</p> <p><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4063813/sonia-segade-el-gran-salto-de-renfe-en-los-proximos-anos-no-solo-vendra-de-la-evolucion-del-mundo-it-sino-tambien-del-ot.html">En una entrevista realizada hace escasos meses con CIO ESPAÑA</a>, Segade explicó cómo trabaja el operador ferroviario para materializar un ambicioso plan de transformación digital y tecnológica con el que la empresa aspira a posicionarse como un jugador global integral de movilidad y logística; una iniciativa con la que pretende trascender al propio mercado ferroviario, en pleno cambio con la liberalización de este sector en Europa.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hugging Face Introduces Community Evals for Transparent Model Benchmarking]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/hugging-face-evals/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/hugging-face-evals/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/hugging-face-evals/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771448477065.jpg"/><p>Hugging Face has launched Community Evals, a feature that enables benchmark datasets on the Hub to host their own leaderboards and automatically collect evaluation results from model repositories.</p> <i>By Daniel Dominguez</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Rethinking virtualization in the age of AI]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134251/rethinking-virtualization-in-the-age-of-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134251/rethinking-virtualization-in-the-age-of-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Concerns about cost unpredictability and AI readiness are prompting IT leaders to plan major changes to their virtualization strategies.</p> <p>According to a <a href="https://www.hpe.com/us/en/solutions/cloud.html?slug=a00155927enw&amp;x=MHm9Z2&amp;pf_route=uccldfav" rel="nofollow">new survey</a> commissioned by HPE, two-thirds of IT decision-makers are thinking about revamping their virtualization deployments in the next two years, but only 5% say their organizations are ready for the change.</p> <p>Cost concerns are one driver of what HPE calls the “great virtualization reset.” Tech giant Broadcom’s acquisition of market leader <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3604503/vmware-makes-workstation-and-fusion-free-for-everyone.html">VMware</a> in late 2023 led to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2093486/vmware-customers-take-wait-and-see-approach-amid-broadcom-changes.html?utm=hybrid_search">licensing cost increases</a>, prompting some organizations to “<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2513749/will-vmwares-licensing-changes-push-devirtualization-of-data-centers.html?utm=hybrid_search">devirtualize</a>,” although over half of organizations in the survey are still running VMware as their primary virtualization platform.</p> <p>In addition to the VMware price hikes, IT leaders have noted that cloud costs are running higher than expected this year, according to the survey.</p> <p>“Their virtualization bill just like quintupled, and they have to invest in AI, they have salary modernization, and now they’re saddled with this bill that they can’t afford,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hangtan/" rel="nofollow">Hang Tan</a>, COO for hybrid cloud at HPE. “It’s no secret by now that everybody’s looking for an alternative.”</p> <p>But an even larger reason for the trend is a focus on AI readiness and questions about virtual machines hosted in the cloud, <a href="https://www.hpe.com/us/en/newsroom/press-release/2026/02/new-research-finds-only-5-of-enterprises-are-fully-ready-for-the-great-virtualization-reset.html" rel="nofollow">according to HPE</a>, which offers its own virtualization solutions.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="rethinking-vms-and-the-cloud-at-the-same-time">Rethinking VMs and the cloud at the same time</h2> <p>Many IT leaders want new AI-friendly virtualization capabilities, and at the same time, they are <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4012882/cios-rethink-public-cloud-as-ai-strategies-mature.html">rethinking their cloud computing setups</a> as they consider how AI and virtualization fit together.</p> <p>There’s a growing demand for hybrid cloud environments as IT leaders seek to control AI costs, monitor workloads, and avoid vendor lock-in, Tan says. At the same time, IT leaders are looking for capabilities such as unified backup, cross-platform governance, and integrated observability as they modernize their virtualization and cloud setups, according to the survey.</p> <p>As price concerns collide with AI modernization efforts, IT leaders are seeing an opportunity to reassess their virtualization stack and start with a blank page, Tan says.</p> <p>“There’s a silver lining: Never waste a crisis,” he says. “It’s freeing for the CIO to say, ‘Now I have a chance to rethink my strategy, whereas before I had standardized on one stack and operating model, but I knew I had all these issues I had to resolve.’”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-drives-vm-changes">AI drives VM changes</h2> <p>AI upends old virtualization uses, says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/balabanskyy/" rel="nofollow">Artur Balabanskyy</a>, founder and CTO at IT services and app development firm Tapforce.</p> <p>“AI workloads are GPU heavy and unpredictable,” he says. “That breaks the old model of sizing VMs once and letting them run. Companies start questioning whether they need full virtualization at all, or if lighter layers or bare metal make more sense for AI-powered projects.”</p> <p>While traditional VM hypervisors are CPU centric and assume steady demand, AI is memory hungry, GPU bound, and latency sensitive, he adds. “The abstraction layers add cost and drag, so there are big problems when models hit real scale,” Balabanskyy says. “This is a weird new world for folks whose job it is to plan for future usage.”</p> <p>Beyond cost issues, virtualization and AI technologies intersect at the need for quality data, says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sune-tornbo-baastrup-3950402/" rel="nofollow">Sune Baastrup</a>, CIO at Danfoss, a heating, cooling, and data center component manufacturing firm. The company has recently reevaluated its virtualization technologies with a focus on data portability and flexibility, he adds.</p> <p>“We see virtualization as much more than the traditional just getting more out of one physical box of hardware,” he says. “It’s actually preparing for a future where you have much more dynamic use cases, where we’ll see a lot of workloads being moved from either central places out into more decentral locations, or all the way out to the edge.”</p> <p>As Danfoss embraces AI, the company’s virtualization and data strategies need to keep up, Baastrup adds. “If there’s one thing that you know is in focus to get value out of AI, it’s the access to quality data,” he says.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="limiting-factors">Limiting factors</h2> <p>Meanwhile, IT leaders see several obstacles to making a change, according to the survey. More than a quarter of those surveyed say budget constraints limit their ability to reimagine virtualization strategies, and nearly a quarter also cite technical complexity, migration risks, and skills gaps as significant barriers.</p> <p>Organizational readiness is also a potential barrier, Danfoss’s Baastrup says. Part of the job of the CIO is to convince the IT team that they should change vendors or technologies, he adds.</p> <p>“What each CIO needs to come down to is, ‘How do I get my organization ready to consume technology that is already available today and how do I find a partner that can take those steps with me when those breakthrough AI use cases become relevant?’” he says.</p> <p>Budget, skills, and fear of change can limit efforts to shift away from virtualization, adds Tapforce’s Balabanskyy. “Large-scale changes are expensive and disruptive, even when they make sense on paper,” he says. “Teams know how to run what they have, and retraining or replacing that knowledge carries real risk. Price and stability still win most internal arguments.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="take-it-slow">Take it slow</h2> <p>With several obstacles to making virtualization changes, HPE recommends that IT leaders take a measured approach. Organizations don’t have to lift and shift all workloads to a new provider all at once, says HPE’s Tan.</p> <p>“There’s the knee-jerk reaction of, ‘My costs are going up, and I need to move off ASAP,’” he says. “But we tell our customers, this is an opportunity for you to rethink your strategy, and you should be thoughtful about it. Our advice has actually been, ‘Don’t be in a rush.’”</p> <p>CIOs should also think holistically about how new virtualization solutions fit into their overall IT environment, adds <a href="https://thrivenextgen.com/scott-steele-joins-thrive-as-chief-operating-officer/" rel="nofollow">Scott Steele</a>, COO at IT services provider Thrive. Virtualization is one piece of a larger IT transformation discussion that should be focused on AI and other future needs, he says.</p> <p>“There are new capabilities and new vendors coming out with either AI capabilities or new infrastructure that supports it,” he says. “It’s a time period where you should be looking at your entire infrastructure to make sure that you’re set up for where everything’s going, not where it’s been.”</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Top 12 governance, risk, and compliance certifications]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/242680/the-top-6-governance-risk-and-compliance-certifications.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/242680/the-top-6-governance-risk-and-compliance-certifications.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-are-grc-certifications">What are GRC certifications?</h2> <p>GRC certifications validate the skills, knowledge, and abilities IT professionals have to manage GRC in the enterprise. With companies increasingly operating on a global scale, it can require entire teams to stay on top of all the regulations and compliance standards arising today. It’s crucial to ensure your organization is operating lawfully in every country it operates, your business is protected from cybersecurity threats, and your company both manages risk and establishes processes to govern those tasks.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-are-grc-certifications-important">Why are GRC certifications important?</h2> <p>In the wake of several well-publicized corporate scandals in the early 2000s — Enron and WorldCom, for example — and the passage of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act in 2002, organizations that must adhere to regulations for data security, financial accountability, and consumer privacy can’t do without someone making sure internal processes are being carried out properly. Enter the need for competent GRC professionals.</p> <p>The goal of GRC, in general, is to ensure that proper policies and controls are in place to reduce risk, set up a system of checks and balances to alert personnel when new risks materialize, and manage business processes more efficiently and proactively. Professionals with a GRC certification must juggle stakeholder expectations with business objectives, and ensure organizational objectives are met while meeting compliance requirements. That significant amount of responsibility is critical in today’s business climate, and certification can prove you’re up to the task.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="is-grc-certification-worth-it">Is GRC certification worth it?</h2> <p>A variety of roles in the enterprise require or benefit from a GRC certification, such as CIO, IT security analyst, security engineer architect, information assurance program manager, and senior <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/219805/it-auditor-role-defined.html">IT auditor</a>, among others. If you work in an IT role that requires knowledge of governance principles, risk management, or compliance regulations, earning a GRC certification can help set you apart from other candidates, and reassure employers that you have the right knowledge for the job. GRC certs, such as the CGRC and CGEIT, are often ranked <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/286762/careers-staffing-12-it-certifications-that-deliver-career-advancement.html">high on the list for most valuable IT certifications</a>.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="top-12-grc-certifications">Top 12 GRC certifications</h2> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Certified Compliance &amp; Ethics Professional (CCEP)</li> <li>Certified Cloud Security Professional (CCSP)</li> <li>Certified Governance, Risk, and Compliance (CGRC)</li> <li>Certified in Risk and Information Systems Control (CRISC)</li> <li>Certification in Risk Management Assurance (CRMA)</li> <li>Certified in the Governance of Enterprise IT (CGEIT)</li> <li>Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)</li> <li>Certified Information Security Manager (CISM)</li> <li>Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP)</li> <li>GRC Professional (GRCP)</li> <li>ITIL Expert</li> <li>Project Management Institute — Risk Management Professional (PMI-RMP)</li>
</ul> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-compliance-ethics-professional-ccep">Certified Compliance &amp; Ethics Professional (CCEP)</h3> <p>The <a href="https://www.corporatecompliance.org/certification/become-certified/ccep" rel="nofollow">Certified Compliance &amp; Ethics Professional (CCEP)</a> certification offered by the <a href="https://www.corporatecompliance.org/certifications/become-certified" rel="nofollow">Compliance Certification Board (CCB)</a> is designed to demonstrate your knowledge and expertise around regulations and compliance processes. This designation shows organizations that you have the skills to understand and address any necessary legal obligations, and to help maintain the integrity of the organization through compliance programs.</p> <p>To qualify for the CCEP certification, you’ll need to have:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>At least one year experience in a full-time compliance position or 1,500 hours of direct compliance job duties earned over two years or less.</li> <li>Job duties that are directly related to tasks outlined in the Candidate Handbook, including knowledge of standards, policies, procedures, communication, education, training, monitoring, auditing, reporting, and how to administer compliance and ethics programs.</li>
</ul> <p>However, you may be exempt from these requirements if you’ve successfully completed a certificate program from a CCB-accredited university within the two years prior to your application date. To apply to sit for a CCB examination, all candidates are required to earn and submit 20 CCB-approved continuing education units, earned from live trainings, events, and web conferences.</p> <p>Exam fees: $350 for members or $450 for nonmembers, with a $145 renewal fee for members or $265 for nonmembers.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-cloud-security-professional-ccsp">Certified Cloud Security Professional (CCSP)</h3> <p>The <a href="https://www.isc2.org/certifications/ccsp" rel="nofollow">Certified Cloud Security Professional (CCSP)</a> certification is offered through the International Information System Security Certification Consortium ISC2, and demonstrates your knowledge and abilities when designing, managing, and securing data, applications, and infrastructure in the cloud. It’s designed for those working with cloud technology, including <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/193329/what-is-an-enterprise-architect-a-vital-role-for-it-operations.html">enterprise architects</a>, security administrators, systems engineers, security architects, systems architects, or consultants, engineers, or managers. The certification exam details cloud concepts, architecture, design, security, and risk and compliance.</p> <p>To qualify for the CCSP exam, there are no requirements but the ISC2 recommends at least five years of experience in IT, with at a minimum of three years in information security, and one year in one or more of the six domains found in the CCSP CBOK. For more, click <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/571163/certified-cloud-security-professional-ccsp.html">here</a>.</p> <p>Exam fee: $599</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-governance-risk-and-compliance-cgrc">Certified Governance, Risk, and Compliance (CGRC)</h3> <p>The <a href="https://www.isc2.org/certifications/cgrc" rel="nofollow">CGRC certification</a> offered by the ISC2 is designed to demonstrate your expertise in GRC, and your ability to integrate governance, risk management, performance management, and regulatory compliance in an organization. The exam covers topics like information security risk management, and the authorization and approval of information systems, as well as selecting, approving, implementing, assessing, auditing, and monitoring security and privacy controls.</p> <p>To qualify for the exam, you’ll need two years of cumulative, paid work experience in one or more of the seven domains outlined on the current ISC2 CGRC exam outline. To maintain the certification, you’ll need to receive 60 CPE credits over three years, and pay the annual maintenance fee of $135.</p> <p>Exam fees: $599</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-in-risk-and-information-systems-control-crisc">Certified in Risk and Information Systems Control (CRISC)</h3> <p>One of the most sought-after GRC certifications by both candidates and employers is the <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3631540/crisc-certification-your-ticket-to-the-c-suite.html" target="_blank">CRISC</a> from ISACA, which identifies IT professionals responsible for managing IT and enterprise risk, and ensuring risk management goals are met. A CRISC is often heavily involved with overseeing the development, implementation, and maintenance of information system (IS) controls designed to secure systems and manage risk. The exam covers IT risk identification, risk response and mitigation, and risk and control monitoring and reporting.</p> <p>To qualify for the exam, you must:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Have a minimum of three years of cumulative work experience in IT risk and information systems associated with at least two of the four domains.</li> <li>Adhere to the ISACA Code of Professional Ethics and comply with the CRISC Continuing Education Policy.</li>
</ul> <p>Exam fees: $575 for ISACA members or $760 for nonmembers.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certification-in-risk-management-assurance-crma">Certification in Risk Management Assurance (CRMA)</h3> <p>The Institute of Internal Auditors (IIA) is a global professional association that provides information, networking opportunities and education to auditors in business, government, and the financial services industry. Before earning your CRMA, you’ll first need to pass the Certified Internal Auditor (CIA) exam, which demonstrates your proficiency as an auditor. Once you’ve passed that certification, you can move onto the <a href="https://na.theiia.org/certification/crma-certification/Pages/CRMA-Certification.aspx" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">CRMA</a> certification, which recognizes individuals involved with risk management and assurance, governance, and quality assurance, and those who control self-assessment. A CRMA is considered a trusted advisor to senior management and members of audit committees in large organizations.</p> <p>Depending on your level of education, there are different requirements to qualify for the CRMA certification exam. If you’ve earned a master’s degree equivalent or higher, you’ll just need to provide proof of education, one year of internal audit experience, and a government-issued photo ID at the exam. Those with a bachelor’s degree or higher have the same requirements, but you’ll need to show two years of internal audit experience. Without a higher degree, you’ll need proof of five years of internal audit experience, and two out of those five required years must have been within the past three years.</p> <p>Exam fees: $465 for IIA members or $610 for nonmembers, with an application fee of $100 for members and $220 for nonmembers.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-in-the-governance-of-enterprise-it-cgeit">Certified in the Governance of Enterprise IT (CGEIT)</h3> <p>The <a href="https://www.isaca.org/credentialing/cgeit" rel="nofollow">CGEIT certification</a>, by ISACA, recognizes IT professionals with deep knowledge of enterprise IT governance principles and practices, as well as the ability to enhance value to the organization through governance and risk optimization measures, and to align IT with business strategies and goals. Since the program started, more than 7,000 individuals have achieved the CGEIT through ISACA. The exam covers five domains: framework for the governance of enterprise IT, strategic management, benefits realization, risk optimization, and resource optimization.</p> <p>To qualify for the exam, you’ll need at least five years of cumulative work experience in IT enterprise governance, including at least one year defining, implementing, and managing a governance framework.</p> <p>Exam fees: $525 for ISACA members or $760 for non-members.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-information-systems-auditor-cisa">Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)</h3> <p>Offered through the ISACA, the <a href="https://www.isaca.org/credentialing/cisa" rel="nofollow">CISA certification</a> is globally recognized for IS audit control. It was established in 1978 and certifies your ability to report on compliance procedures, how well you can assess vulnerabilities, and your knowledge of every stage in the auditing process. The certification covers high-level topics such as the information systems auditing process, governance and management of IT, operations and business resilience, and IS acquisition, development, and implementation.</p> <p>To qualify for the CISA exam you’ll need to have at least five years of experience in IS auditing, control, or security, and must complete another entry-level exam through the ISACA certification scheme.</p> <p>Exam fee: $575 for members or $760 for non-members.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-information-security-manager-cism">Certified Information Security Manager (CISM)</h3> <p>The <a href="https://www.isaca.org/credentialing/cism?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=CertBAU&amp;utm_content=sem_CertBAU_certificaiton-cism-na-exam-google&amp;cid=sem_2006854&amp;Appeal=sem&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMItb3n5oCQhgMV90RHAR3iOg_1EAAYASAAEgIk6fD_BwE" rel="nofollow">CISM certification</a> offered by the ISACA covers your ability to asses risks, implement governance practices, and proactively respond to any security incidents. The exam highlights emerging technologies such as AI and blockchain to ensure your skillset meets current industry standards and requirements to address evolving security risks. The certification also details information security governance, information security risk management, information security programs, and incident management. To qualify for the exam you’ll need five or more years of experience in information security management.</p> <p>Exam fees: $575 for members or $760 for non-members.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="certified-information-systems-security-professional-cissp">Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP)</h3> <p>The <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Certifications/CISSP" rel="nofollow">CISSP certification</a> offered by the ISC2 is designed for cybersecurity professionals to demonstrate they have the right knowledge, skills, and abilities to design, implement, and manage cybersecurity programs. The exam covers security and risk management, asset security, security architecture and engineering, communication and network security, identity and access management (IAM), security assessment and testing, security operations, and software development security.</p> <p>To qualify for the exam you’ll need five or more years of cybersecurity work or internship experience in two or more of the eight domains covered on the exam.</p> <p>One year of work experience can be substituted with a four-year college degree or equivalent, or an advanced degree in information security from the US National Center of Academic Excellence in Information Assurance Education (CAE/IAE). Also, one year of work experience can be satisfied if you hold another approved credential from ISC2.</p> <p>Exam fees: $749</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="grc-professional-grcp">GRC Professional (GRCP)</h3> <p><a href="https://www.oceg.org/" rel="nofollow">Open Compliance and Ethics Group</a> (OCEG) is a member-driven, global organization dedicated to providing information, education, and certification on GRC to its members and the greater community. With only a few but well-respected certifications in its program, the <a href="https://www.oceg.org/certifications/grc-professional-certification/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">GRCP</a> is a solid credential aimed at a broad range of industries and practices. The single exam covers basic terms and concepts, GRC principles, and core components and practices, as well as the relationship of GRC to other disciplines. The GRCP is required for the higher-level GRC audit certification. The exam contains 100 questions and takes up to two hours to complete.</p> <p>There are no requirements to qualify for the GRCP exam as it’s open and accessible to all professionals, accepting candidates from diverse cultural, educational, and professional backgrounds.</p> <p>Exam fees: $499 for an all-access pass, which provides everything needed to prepare for and take the exam, including all live and archived webinars, OCEG standards, guides and resources, eLearning program, and the exam.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="itil-expert">ITIL Expert</h3> <p><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/286245/what-itil-certifications-mean-to-your-it-management-practices.html">Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) certifications</a> are tied to the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272361/infrastructure-it-infrastructure-library-itil-definition-and-solutions.html">ITIL framework</a>, which describes best practices for designing, implementing and managing a wide variety of IT service projects. In ITIL-speak, certifications are referred to as qualifications, which create a classic certification ladder beginning with the basic-level ITIL Foundation, and culminating with the pinnacle ITIL Master. One rung below the Master level is the popular ITIL Expert.</p> <p>A professional with the ITIL Expert qualification has a deep understanding of ITIL service best practices as they apply across an IT environment, not just to one service area. In other words, the Expert is able to support an organization by bridging service lifecycle stages, seeing the big picture as a sum of the parts.</p> <p>To qualify for the exam, you must have:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Earned an ITIL Foundation certificate or a Bridge qualification equivalent.</li> <li>Acquired at least 17 credits per the ITIL credit system.</li> <li>Taken an approved training course and passed the Managing Across the Lifecycle (MALC) exam at the end.</li>
</ul> <p>Exam fees: Training costs vary among vendors but expect to pay around $1,800 (online) to $5,000 (classroom), which includes training and the exam.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="project-management-institute-risk-management-professional-pmi-rmp">Project Management Institute — Risk Management Professional (PMI-RMP)</h3> <p>Anyone who’s pursued a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/230398/top-project-management-certifications.html">project management certification</a> is familiar with the Project Management Institute (PMI), either through research or by picking up the coveted Project Management Professional (PMP) credential. PMI also offers the <a href="https://www.pmi.org/certifications/risk-management-rmp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PMI-RMP</a> certification, as well as several others that focus on business management, business analysis, Agile and scheduling.</p> <p>The PMI-RMP identifies IT professionals involved with large projects or working in complex environments who assess and identify project-based risks. They’re also competent in designing and implementing mitigation plans that counter the risks from system vulnerabilities and natural disasters, for instance. The exam covers risk strategy and planning, stakeholder engagement, risk process facilitation, risk monitoring and reporting, and performing specialized risk analysis.</p> <p>To qualify for the exam, you must have a secondary degree (high school diploma, associate’s degree, or global equivalent), and at least 4,500 hours of project risk management experience and 40 hours of project risk management education. Or you can have a four-year degree (bachelor’s degree or global equivalent), at least 3,000 hours of project risk management experience, and 30 hours of project risk management education.</p> <p>Exam fees: $520 for PMI members or $670 for nonmembers.</p> <p><strong>More on GRC:</strong></p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/230326/what-is-grc-and-why-do-you-need-it.html">What is GRC and why do you need it?</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/222262/top-10-grc-mistakes-and-how-to-avoid-them.html">Top 10 GRC mistakes — and how to avoid them</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/222262/top-10-grc-mistakes-and-how-to-avoid-them.html">Top 10 GRC mistakes — and how to avoid them</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272051/governanceit-governance-definition-and-solutions.html">What is IT governance? A formal way to align IT &amp; business strategy</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/222613/the-keys-to-effective-it-governance-in-the-digital-era.html">The keys to effective IT governance in the digital era</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why open source is the cheat code for AI]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134023/why-open-source-is-the-cheat-code-for-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134023/why-open-source-is-the-cheat-code-for-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The frontier of large-language models is shifting daily. GPT‑5.1, Claude 4.4 and Gemini 3 Pro are now routinely outperforming what seemed cutting-edge mere months ago. As commercial AI accelerates, we’re hearing the same question from enterprise leaders again and again: how do we put this power to use? For those interested in moving quickly, the cheat code is open source.</p> <p>What we’ve seen firsthand is tens of millions of data engineers, scientists and analysts around the world connect over open source technologies like OpenTelemetry, Prometheus, Linux, Kubernetes and Apache Spark. Across blogs, videos, Git repositories and other public documentation, these advocates engage in unfiltered discussions, share best practices, exchange APIs and dashboards, and more – all on the open web, not in proprietary, walled gardens.</p> <p>As a result, leading frontier LLMs come pre-wired with knowledge of how to interact with these open ecosystems. They have been trained on thousands of public post-incident reports, detailing how experts respond to incidents with the open source projects. They understand important terminology, like what “scale up the service” means in Kubernetes, to immediately execute on tasks that would likely perplex the many employees who aren’t experts in the technologies.</p> <p>This helps vendors and customers alike more quickly take advantage of new agentic AI features. We saw this play out directly at Grafana. We were able to build and scale a new AI agent interface in days – all because we didn’t have to train the underlying LLMs to understand and interact with our open source systems.</p> <p>Of course, nothing in the world of enterprise technology is a panacea. There’s always the risk models could surface bad or inaccurate information from this corpus of documentation. Newer open source technologies also don’t have the same breadth and depth of content. And ultimately, it puts even more pressure on open source vendors to continue to support the communities behind projects critical to the modern IT stack – after all, the community is the force multiplier here, producing the valuable training material for these models.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="under-ai-pressure-open-source-is-a-quick-win">Under AI pressure, open source is a quick win</h2> <p>AI ambitions are crashing into the realities of adoption. Under pressure from investors, enterprises are trying to move quickly. They want to deliver a chatbot-like experience for engineers, account managers, marketing teams and more to improve productivity and efficiency, and start to generate new growth opportunities.</p> <p>But <a href="https://www.pwc.com/us/en/tech-effect/ai-analytics/ai-agent-survey.html" rel="nofollow">nearly half of businesses</a> are concerned they’re falling behind competitors. It’s why more are looking for standalone systems they can quickly adopt and use to support a broad range of use cases. And they want the ability to use their own proprietary, domain-specific data to enhance performance when needed.</p> <p>This is posing a fresh challenge for the software industry. OpenAI, Anthropic and others have tens of billions of dollars in investment capital, as well as teams stacked with the world’s premier AI talent. Others simply can’t keep up. It’s why even data-focused companies like Snowflake are <a href="https://www.thestack.technology/snowflake-llms-training/" rel="nofollow">no longer in the model-building game</a>.</p> <p>But for some vendors, it’s also not as easy as just connecting their systems to ChatGPT-5, Grok 4 or other leading LLMs the second they hit the market. Often, there’s an integration period, where the technology providers have to spend time, talent and resources training the models on how to navigate their proprietary systems.</p> <p>That’s not the case with open source – or widely-adopted, open standards like SQL and JSON. The large volume of public content – from how-tos, forum posts and tutorials – on these technologies is now baked into the leading foundational models. Of course, there’s also public documentation on using proprietary software. But it’s often at much smaller volumes, not at the quantity needed to effectively support the reinforcement training most model-builders use.</p> <p>With the community of open source’s power, it’s more important than ever for vendors to foster dialogue and information-sharing among users. And with more of the daily work interactions taking place in agentic AI interfaces, it’s critical this documentation is robust, accurate and trustworthy. Meanwhile, because of the priority on interoperability, open source helps AI agents deliver a more integrated experience. It’s incumbent on vendors to continue to foster this spirit of collaboration – even as others in the industry reinforce their walled gardens.</p> <p>In a market that demands results yesterday, open source offers a rare advantage: instant AI readiness. Models already understand these tools and communities already teach them how to use them. That means faster innovation with fewer resources. For CIOs and builders, the real cheat code isn’t just AI. It’s AI, built on open systems.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Community push intensifies to free MySQL from Oracle’s control amid stagnation fears]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134406/community-push-intensifies-to-free-mysql-from-oracles-control-amid-stagnation-fears-2.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134406/community-push-intensifies-to-free-mysql-from-oracles-control-amid-stagnation-fears-2.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Pressure is building on Oracle to loosen its grip on MySQL, with a group of database veterans, developers, and long-time contributors urging the company to transition the open source database to an independent foundation model.</p> <p>The call, articulated in an <a href="https://letter.3306-db.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">open letter</a>, reflects mounting concern about <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4120892/what-is-the-future-for-mysql.html">MySQL’s development velocity</a>, roadmap transparency, and role in an increasingly AI-driven data ecosystem.</p> <p>The letter itself has received at least 248 signatures so far.</p> <p>These signatories span database administrators, architects, and developers from MySQL fork providers such as Percona, MariaDB, and PlanetScale, as well as engineers and executives from companies including Zoho, DigitalOcean, Vultr, and Pinterest, among others.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="open-letter-reflects-growing-unease-over-mysqls-direction">Open letter reflects growing unease over MySQL’s direction</h2> <p>Chief among the signatories’ concerns is how Oracle has managed updates to MySQL’s codebase, which they argue has cost the database a significant loss in market share. Developers and enterprises are increasingly gravitating toward PostgreSQL as demand surges for AI-driven workloads, where databases play a critical role in consolidating and serving data.</p> <p>The letter also argued that not only are the MySQL updates “private” and sparse, but they also don’t even include features that are now table stakes for AI-driven workloads and have become standard across most databases, including the enterprise versions offered by Oracle, the signatories wrote in the letter.</p> <p>In fact, Percona co-founder <a href="https://www.percona.com/about-percona/team/vadim-tkachenko" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Vadim Tkachenko</a>, who was one of the co-authors of the letter, told InfoWorld that enterprises’ concern around MySQL’s direction under Oracle had reached a “critical” level.</p> <p>So much so that enterprises were looking at MySQL fork-providers and cloud providers, such as AWS, for new features and innovation, citing what they perceive as stagnation in the core MySQL project, Tkachenko added.</p> <p>However, the co-founder pointed out that the interest from enterprises combined with the innovations at the fork-and cloud-provider level does not help move MySQL forward, but rather creates confusion and fragmentation: “Often, forks are not compatible with each other and with upstream (core OSS MySQL), which creates major barriers for adoption and migrations.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="as-ai-workloads-rise-mysql-loses-ground-to-postgresql">As AI workloads rise, MySQL loses ground to PostgreSQL</h2> <p>Analysts agree with Tkachenko. “The concerns being raised in the open letter about MySQL’s development velocity and governance are consistent with what I have seen,” said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/slwalter/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Stephanie Walter</a>, leader of the AI stack at HyperFRAME Research.</p> <p>“The database layer is becoming an AI system dependency. When developers and enterprises feel upstream is slow or opaque on modern requirements, they don’t just complain. They route around it, most likely to something like PostgreSQL,” Walter added.</p> <p>Echoing Walter, dbinsight chief analyst <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dbinsight/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Tony Baer</a> pointed out that MySQL forks indeed create lock-ins because of their unique individual extensions, resulting in challenges around migration.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-foundation-proposal-what-signatories-want">The foundation proposal: what signatories want</h2> <p>Nonetheless, Tkachenko and other signatories do see an alternative to rescue MySQL out of the alleged rut: Oracle accepting the proposal to place MySQL under an independent, non-profit foundation.</p> <p>Under the proposed model outlined in the open letter, MySQL would be governed by a neutral, non-profit foundation with a technical steering committee representing Oracle, fork providers, cloud vendors, and the broader contributor community.</p> <p>The foundation would oversee roadmap planning, release governance, and contributor access, while allowing Oracle to retain its commercial MySQL offerings and trademarks.</p> <p>Signatories argue that this structure would protect Oracle’s commercial interests as well as give vendors and enterprises more confidence around the database due to transparent roadmaps, updates, and long-term technical direction while reducing fragmentation across forks.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-foundation-may-not-fix-the-power-dynamics">The foundation may not fix the power dynamics</h2> <p>Analysts, however, didn’t seem too confident about the foundation model proposed in the letter.</p> <p>“It won’t fully resolve the core power dynamics if Oracle retains the trademark and the effective release pipeline,” Walter said, adding that the proposed model may help with the coordination and contribution process — another concern expressed by the signatories.</p> <p>Explaining further, Walter pointed out that the proposed structure contrasts with autonomous, community-led projects such as PostgreSQL, whose governance model has played a meaningful role in sustaining contributor trust and accelerating long-term adoption.</p> <p>PostgreSQL, according to a <a href="https://survey.stackoverflow.co/2025/technology#most-popular-technologies-database-prof" rel="nofollow">2025 Stack Overflow survey</a>, leads MySQL in terms of usage and popularity.</p> <p>The decline in MySQL’s popularity could be directly linked to a sheer drop in the number of contributors and commits over the last few years.</p> <p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hulyav/?originalSubdomain=de" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Julia Vural</a>, software engineering manager at Percona, wrote in a <a href="https://www.percona.com/blog/analyzing-the-heartbeat-of-the-mysql-server-a-look-at-repository-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">blog post</a> that the pool of active contributors to MySQL had dropped to around 75 by Q3 2025, compared to 135 active contributors in Q4 2017.</p> <p>Similarly, the total number of commits has declined from 22,360 in 2010 to 4,730 in 2024, Vural added.</p> <p>Other factors could include recent layoffs at the MySQL division at Oracle, including the departure of Oracle MySQL community manager <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/freddescamps/?originalSubdomain=be" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Frederic Descamps</a>, who <a href="https://lefred.be/content/i-joined-the-mariadb-foundation/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">moved to the MariaDB Foundation</a> this week.</p> <p>Oracle did not immediately respond to queries about the open letter.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
