<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:06:55 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[“단순 숫자 아닌 리스크 신호”···이사회 눈높이에 맞는 보안 지표는 무엇인가]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137095/%eb%8b%a8%ec%88%9c-%ec%88%ab%ec%9e%90-%ec%95%84%eb%8b%8c-%eb%a6%ac%ec%8a%a4%ed%81%ac-%ec%8b%a0%ed%98%b8%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ec%9d%b4%ec%82%ac%ed%9a%8c-%eb%88%88%eb%86%92%ec%9d%b4.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137095/%eb%8b%a8%ec%88%9c-%ec%88%ab%ec%9e%90-%ec%95%84%eb%8b%8c-%eb%a6%ac%ec%8a%a4%ed%81%ac-%ec%8b%a0%ed%98%b8%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ec%9d%b4%ec%82%ac%ed%9a%8c-%eb%88%88%eb%86%92%ec%9d%b4.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>보안 조직은 숫자의 세계에서 일한다. 대시보드에는 차단된 공격 건수, 피싱 클릭 수, 발견된 취약점, 적용된 패치, 분류된 경고, 종결된 사고 건수가 표시된다. 지난 10년간 사이버 보안 업계는 활동을 점점 더 정밀하게 측정하는 데 능숙해졌다.</p> <p>그러나 전문가들은 이런 측정치가 과연 이사회가 리스크를 관리하는 데 실질적인 도움을 주는지는 여전히 일관되지 않다고 지적한다. 이사와 최고경영진에게 보안 지표 보고의 목적은 노력의 양을 나열하는 데 있지 않다. 조직이 얼마나 노출돼 있는지, 위험이 어떤 방향으로 움직이고 있는지, 사고 발생 시 어떤 결과가 초래되는지를 이해하는 데 있다.</p> <p>의사결정자는 리스크가 증가하는지 감소하는지, 통제가 효과적으로 작동하는지, 예방이 실패했을 때 조직이 피해를 제한할 수 있는지를 알고 싶어 한다. 지표는 이런 질문을 명확히 해줄 때 의미를 갖는다.</p> <p>사이버 보안 기업이 코어라이트(Corelight)의 전략담당가 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/richardbejtlich/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">리처드 베이트리치</a>는 CSO와의 인터뷰에서 “시간은 누구나 이해할 수 있는 보편적인 지표”라며 “문제를 얼마나 빨리 탐지하고, 얼마나 빨리 차단하는지가 핵심이다. 침입 후 체류 시간과 대응 시간, 이것이 전부”라고 말했다.</p> <p>베이트리치는 모든 침입을 막을 수는 없지만, 침입을 얼마나 신속히 인지하고 차단하는지는 측정할 수 있다고 설명했다. 이런 지표는 기술적 배경이 없는 사람에게도 직접적인 영향을 전달할 수 있다. 탐지와 차단 속도는 회피된 비즈니스 손실을 보여주는 대리 지표로 작동한다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9e%ac%eb%ac%b4%ec%a0%81-%eb%85%b8%ec%b6%9c-vs-%ec%9a%b4%ec%98%81-%ea%b0%80%ec%8b%9c%ec%84%b1">재무적 노출 vs. 운영 가시성</h2> <p>보안 컨설팅 기업 파이시스 인터내셔널(Pisces International)의 CTO <a href="https://events.isc2.org/b/sp/mike-hamilton-5798" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">마이크 해밀턴</a>은 이사회 차원의 보안 보고를 철저히 수탁 책임의 관점에서 해석한다. 해밀턴은 지표가 의미를 가지는 경우는 재무적 결과와 직접적으로 연결될 때뿐이라고 본다.</p> <p>해밀턴은 CSO와의 인터뷰에서 “이사회가 관심을 두는 것은 결국 돈”이라며 “복잡한 해외 해커의 버퍼 오버플로 같은 기술적 위협에는 큰 관심이 없다. 재무적 영향이 핵심”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>이어 “CISO는 평균 탐지 시간이나 평균 대응 시간 같은 지표에 관심을 가질 수 있다. 그러나 이사회는 기업 가치를 보호하는 역할을 맡고 있다”며 “탐지 속도, 취약점 관리, 피싱 대응 역량이 중요한 이유는 재무 손실과 규제 리스크, 운영 중단을 줄이기 때문”이라고 설명했다. 해밀턴은 “이사회가 진짜로 알고 싶어 하는 것은 사업에 영향을 주는 부정적 결과의 발생 가능성을 어떻게 낮추고 있는지”라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>반면 리처드 베이트리치는 일정 기간 동안 발생한 침입 건수처럼 운영 기반의 다양한 지표도 이사회가 충분히 이해할 수 있다고 주장한다. 다만 그 수치가 실제 결과와 함께 제시돼야 의미가 생긴다고 강조했다. 베이트리치는 “실제 데이터 유출로 이어진 침해였는지, 아니면 피해 없이 끝난 무단 접근이었는지가 중요하다”고 말했다.</p> <p>또한 “이사회가 설명을 이해하지 못한다고 느낀 적은 없다”며 “다만 배경 설명 없이 기술 용어로만 이야기하면 도움이 되지 않는다”고 덧붙였다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%88%ab%ec%9e%90-%ec%84%b8%ea%b8%b0%ec%9d%98-%ec%9c%a0%ed%98%b9">숫자 세기의 유혹</h2> <p>지표가 지나치게 기술적이지 않고 비즈니스 영향과도 연결돼 있더라도 또 다른 문제가 발생한다. 무엇을 측정하느냐에 따라 정작 중요한 사안이 가려질 수 있다는 점이다.</p> <p>전직 CISO이자 현재 EPSD 고문으로 활동 중인 <a href="https://epsd.io/about/advisors/wendy-nather/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">웬디 네이더</a>는 측정을 곧 이해로 동일시하는 데 경계해야 한다고 지적했다. 네이더는 CSO와의 인터뷰에서 “이사회에 보고할 때는 수치로 셀 수 없더라도 반드시 공유해야 할 사안이 있다”고 말했다.</p> <p>사고 사례, 큰 사고로 이어질 뻔한 근접 사례, 보안 프로그램 운영에 대한 전제를 바꾸는 사건 등이 대표적이다. 네이더는 “보안 프로그램을 관리하는 방식에 대한 가정을 바꾸는 요소라면, 수치화할 수 없더라도 이사회에 보고해야 한다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>정기적인 지표는 예측 가능한 흐름을 만들어낸다. 그러나 이런 예측 가능성이 오히려 이사회에 잘못된 안도감을 줄 수 있다. 네이더는 “지표는 매우 매력적”이라며 “정기적으로 집계할 수 있는 항목에 집중하게 만든다”고 말했다. 그 결과 구조적 리스크나 새롭게 드러나는 취약점이 가려질 수 있다고 경고했다.</p> <p>지표는 조직 전반의 행동에도 영향을 미친다. 피싱 대응 프로그램의 경우 네이더는 실수를 처벌하기보다 신고를 장려하는 지표를 선호한다. 네이더는 “신고를 유도하고, 신고한 직원을 긍정적으로 평가해야 한다”고 밝혔다. 결국 이사회가 무엇을 측정하느냐에 따라 조직의 행동 방식이 달라진다는 설명이다.</p> <p>비즈니스 자문 기업 뉴포트(Newport)의 파트너 <a href="https://newportllc.com/partner/george-tsantes" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">조지 찬테스</a>는 보안 프로그램의 효과를 입증하는 데 과도한 시간이 투입되는 현실을 지적했다. 찬테스는 CSO와의 인터뷰에서 “여러 이사회와 기업을 만나보면 실제로 리스크를 줄이는 일보다 스스로를 증명하는 데 더 많은 시간을 쓰는 경우가 적지 않다”고 말했다.</p> <p>이런 현상은 규제가 강한 환경에서 특히 두드러진다. 보증과 감사 대응 업무에 자원이 집중되면서, 그 자원이 본래 리스크 감소에 투입되지 못하는 경우가 많다. 규제 당국의 지적은 우선순위도 바꿔놓는다. 찬테스는 “기존에 우선순위 20위였던 항목도 규제 기관이 문제 삼으면 곧바로 1순위가 된다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>찬테스는 이사회가 이런 선택과 집중의 변화를 명확히 인지해야 한다고 강조했다. 성숙한 보안 프로그램이라면 입증을 위한 부담을 가능한 한 줄이고, 문서 작성이 아니라 실제 리스크 감소에 역량을 집중해야 한다는 것이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai%ea%b0%80-%ec%9d%b4%ec%82%ac%ed%9a%8c-%ec%b0%a8%ec%9b%90%ec%9d%98-%ec%82%ac%ec%9d%b4%eb%b2%84-%ec%a7%80%ed%91%9c%eb%a5%bc-%ec%9e%ac%ec%a0%90%ea%b2%80">AI가 이사회 차원의 사이버 지표를 재점검</h2> <p>AI 도입이 사이버 보안 운영 전반을 재편하고 있지만, 아직 이사회 차원의 별도 보안 지표 체계가 새롭게 정립된 것은 아니다. 대신 인공지능은 보안 활동을 이사회가 활용할 수 있는 리스크 신호로 전환하는 기존 방식의 취약점을 드러내고 있다.</p> <p>전문가들은 이사회가 아직 인공지능 전용 대시보드를 요구하고 있지는 않다고 말한다. 다만 인공지능이 조직의 노출 범위를 확대하는지, 기존 통제를 약화하는지, 사고 발생 시 피해를 제한하는 역량을 바꾸고 있는지에 대해서는 점점 더 질문하고 있다.</p> <p>코어라이트(Corelight)의 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bernard-brantley/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">리처드 베이트리치</a>는 “아직 결과 기반 지표는 없는 것 같다”고 밝혔다. 베이트리치는 조직이 인공지능 리스크를 측정하기에 앞서 기본적인 거버넌스 신호부터 확보해야 한다고 설명했다. 어디에서 인공지능이 사용되고 있는지, 얼마나 광범위하게 배치됐는지, 공격 표면을 넓히고 있는지 아니면 운영 부담을 줄이고 있는지 등을 먼저 파악해야 한다는 것이다.</p> <p>이 같은 가시성 격차는 이미 많은 보안 책임자에게 우려 요소로 떠오르고 있다. EPSD의 웬디 네이더는 “CISO들과 대화해 보면, 기업 내부에서 어떤 인공지능이 사용되고 있는지 항상 파악할 수 없다는 점을 가장 크게 걱정한다”고 전했다. 이런 인식이 부족하면 이사회는 활동 지표만 보고받은 채, 정작 조직이 새롭게 도입한 리스크를 제대로 이해하지 못하는 상황에 놓일 수 있다.</p> <p>코어라이트의 CISO 버나드 브랜틀리는 인공지능이 새로운 측정 체계를 요구한다기보다 기존 지표에 대한 더 엄격한 관리가 필요하다고 봤다. 브랜틀리는 CSO와의 인터뷰에서 “기존 표준 지표와 다를 필요는 없다”고 말했다. 실제로 인공지능은 초기 침투, 내부 확산, 데이터 유출과 같은 익숙한 보안 과제를 규모와 속도 측면에서 증폭시키는 역할을 한다는 설명이다.</p> <p>이 같은 증폭 효과는 이사회에 전달돼야 할 신호의 성격을 바꾼다. 인공지능 활용이 확대되면 보호 범위가 넓어지고, 그만큼 팀과 통제가 부담을 떠안을 수 있다. 동시에 인공지능 기반 자동화는 대응 시간을 단축할 수 있다. 브랜틀리는 “해당 영역에 에이전트를 도입한 결과 평균 복구 시간(MTTR)을 60% 줄일 수 있었다”고 설명했다. 이사회가 주목해야 할 거버넌스 신호는 인공지능의 존재 자체가 아니라, 그것이 리스크 집중도와 대응 역량, 자원 배분에 어떤 변화를 가져오는지라는 점이다.</p> <p>뉴포트(Newport)의 조지 찬테스는 인공지능 감독을 측정의 문제가 아니라 집행의 문제로 해석했다. 찬테스는 “이사회는 인공지능의 적절한 사용과 부적절한 사용이 있다는 점을 이해해야 한다”고 말했다. 그러나 가시성만으로는 충분하지 않다고 지적했다. 찬테스는 “조직 자산 내 어디에 인공지능 에이전트가 존재하는지조차 파악하기 어렵다”며 “잘못된 인공지능 사용에 대해 제재할 수 없다면, 해당 정책은 실질적인 효력을 갖기 어렵다”고 밝혔다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[MS, VS 코드 깃허브 코파일럿, C++ 코드 이해·CMake 설정 연동 강화]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137092/ms-vs-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c-%ea%b9%83%ed%97%88%eb%b8%8c-%ec%bd%94%ed%8c%8c%ec%9d%bc%eb%9f%bf-c-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c-%ec%9d%b4%ed%95%b4%c2%b7cmake-%ec%84%a4%ec%a0%95-%ec%97%b0%eb%8f%99-%ea%b0%95.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137092/ms-vs-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c-%ea%b9%83%ed%97%88%eb%b8%8c-%ec%bd%94%ed%8c%8c%ec%9d%bc%eb%9f%bf-c-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c-%ec%9d%b4%ed%95%b4%c2%b7cmake-%ec%84%a4%ec%a0%95-%ec%97%b0%eb%8f%99-%ea%b0%95.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>마이크로소프트(MS)가 비주얼 스튜디오 코드(Visual Studio Code, 이하 VS 코드)용 깃허브 코파일럿에 C++ 심볼 맥락과 CMake 빌드 설정 인식 기능을 도입했다.</p> <p>C++ 코드 이해 기능 개선 내용은 19일 <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-symbol-context-and-cmake-build-configuration-awareness-for-github-copilot-in-vs-code/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">발표됐다</a>. 이번 VS 코드용 깃허브 코파일럿 업데이트는 MS의 C/C++ 및 CMake Tools 확장이 제공해온 C++ 인텔리전스를 에이전트 모드에 직접 통합한 것이 특징이다. 에이전트가 호출할 수 있는 도구 형태로 주요 언어 기능과 빌드 시스템 기능을 노출함으로써, 기존 확장에서 제공하던 역량을 그대로 활용할 수 있도록 했다. MS는 개발자가 이미 사용하고 신뢰해온 동일한 심볼 및 빌드 맥락을 기반으로 AI 지원 C++ 워크플로의 일관성과 성능을 높이는 것이 목표라고 설명했다.</p> <p>이 도구는 VS 코드용 C/C++ Extension Pack에 포함돼 배포되는 C/C++ DevTools 확장의 일부로 제공된다. 새롭게 추가된 C++ 코드 이해 도구를 통해 에이전트 모드는 더욱 풍부한 C++ 심볼 맥락에 접근할 수 있게 됐다. 단순한 텍스트 검색이나 파일 검색에만 의존하는 대신, 워크스페이스 전반에서 심볼 단위로 C++ 코드를 분석하고 코드베이스 전반에 걸쳐 지능적으로 코드 편집 작업을 수행할 수 있다.</p> <p>현재 깃허브 코파일럿 챗(GitHub Copilot Chat)에서 사용할 수 있는 C++ 코드 이해 도구는 다음과 같다.</p> <p>• Get symbol definition: C++ 심볼의 정의 위치와 관련 메타데이터를 포함한 상세 정보를 조회한다.<br>• Get symbol references: 특정 심볼이 코드베이스 전반에서 참조되는 모든 위치를 찾아낸다.<br>• Get symbol call hierarchy: 함수에 대한 호출 관계를 분석해, 해당 함수로 들어오는 호출과 외부로 나가는 호출을 모두 파악하고 호출 패턴과 의존성을 이해하도록 지원한다.</p> <p>이 기능을 활성화하려면 VS 코드 사용자 설정에서 ‘Enable Cpp Code Editing Tools’ 옵션을 선택하면 된다.</p> <p>MS는 또한 VS 코드용 깃허브 코파일럿에 CMake 빌드 및 테스트 설정 도구를 통합했다. 이에 따라 깃허브 코파일럿 챗은 <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-vscode.cmake-tools" rel="nofollow">CMake Tools</a> 확장이 식별하고 제공하는 빌드 구성을 활용해, VS 코드에서 이미 선택된 정확한 설정으로 프로젝트를 빌드하고 테스트할 수 있다. MS는 개발자가 에디터에서 사용하는 동일한 CMake Tools 통합 환경과 연동함으로써, 임시적인 명령줄 호출에 의존하지 않고 선택된 타깃, 프리셋, 빌드 상태와 일관성을 유지할 수 있다고 전했다.</p> <p>현재 깃허브 코파일럿 챗에서 활용할 수 있는 빌드 구성 관련 도구는 다음과 같다.</p> <p>• Build with CMake: 활성화된 설정을 기반으로 CMake 프로젝트를 빌드한다.<br>• Run CTests: 현재 활성 테스트 스위트를 기준으로 CTest 테스트를 실행한다.<br>• List Build Targets: CMake 프로젝트에서 사용할 수 있는 빌드 타깃 목록을 제공한다.<br>• List CTest tests: CMake 프로젝트에서 실행 가능한 테스트 목록을 제공한다.</p> <p>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[칼럼 | MCP, 왜 갑자기 경영진의 핵심 의제로 떠올랐나]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137076/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-mcp-%ec%99%9c-%ea%b0%91%ec%9e%90%ea%b8%b0-%ea%b2%bd%ec%98%81%ec%a7%84%ec%9d%98-%ed%95%b5%ec%8b%ac-%ec%9d%98%ec%a0%9c%eb%a1%9c-%eb%96%a0%ec%98%ac%eb%9e%90%eb%82%98.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137076/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-mcp-%ec%99%9c-%ea%b0%91%ec%9e%90%ea%b8%b0-%ea%b2%bd%ec%98%81%ec%a7%84%ec%9d%98-%ed%95%b5%ec%8b%ac-%ec%9d%98%ec%a0%9c%eb%a1%9c-%eb%96%a0%ec%98%ac%eb%9e%90%eb%82%98.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>기술 리더는 새로운 표준이 조용히 등장했다가 어느새 기업 IT 인프라의 일부로 흡수되는 과정을 익숙하게 지켜봐 왔다. 그러나 MCP(Model Context Protocol)는 전혀 다른 흐름을 보이고 있다. 지난 1년 사이 MCP는 생소한 기술 개념에서 벗어나 에이전틱 AI, 거버넌스, 보안 리스크 논의의 중심으로 이동했다. 이는 단순한 과열이 아니라, AI 시스템이 기업 환경과 상호작용하는 방식이 실제로 변화하고 있음을 보여주는 신호다.</p> <p>기술 리더는 새로운 표준이 조용히 등장했다가 어느새 기업 IT 인프라의 일부로 흡수되는 과정을 익숙하게 지켜봐 왔다. 그러나 모델 컨텍스트 프로토콜(Model Context Protocol, MCP)은 전혀 다른 흐름을 보이고 있다. 지난 1년 사이 MCP는 생소한 기술 개념에서 벗어나 에이전틱 AI, 거버넌스, 보안 리스크 논의의 중심으로 이동했다. 이는 단순한 과열이 아니라, AI 시스템이 기업 환경과 상호작용하는 방식이 실제로 변화하고 있음을 보여주는 신호다.</p> <p>지난해 필자가 진행한 사이버 세션 인터뷰에서 보안 업계 베테랑 앤디 엘리스는 대부분의 경영진이 MCP라는 용어를 접하기도 전에 변곡점을 예견했다.</p> <p>엘리스는 당시 “RSA에서 MCP가 큰 화제가 될 것이라고 본다”라며 “클라이언트와 서버 사이에 API를 촘촘히 정의하는 대신, 양쪽에 대형언어모델(LLM)을 두고 무엇을 주고받을지 협상하도록 하는 방식”이라고 설명했다. 이어 “소프트웨어 개발 방식을 근본적으로 바꿀 것이며, 동시에 상당히 두려운 변화가 될 것”이라고 표현했다.</p> <p>이 전망은 현재 정확히 들어맞고 있다. RSA 콘퍼런스 주최 측에 따르면 2026년 발표 제안서 상당수가 MCP를 주제로 다뤘다. 2024년에 등장한 프로토콜이 이 정도 주목을 받는 것은 이론 단계에서 실제 도입 단계로 빠르게 이동하고 있음을 의미한다. 이를 이끄는 동력은 단순한 엔지니어의 호기심이 아니다. MCP는 기업 AI를 연결하는 인프라로 부상하고 있으며, CIO가 반드시 주목해야 할 주요 신기술로 자리 잡고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%86%b5%ed%95%a9%ec%9d%98-%eb%a7%88%ec%b0%b0-ai-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0%ea%b3%bc-%eb%a7%9e%eb%ac%bc%eb%a6%ac%eb%8b%a4">통합의 마찰, AI 확산과 맞물리다</h2> <p>기업이 AI를 도입하는 과정에서 가장 고질적인 장벽은 모델 성능이 아니라 통합의 복잡성이었다. 많은 조직이 야심 찬 파일럿 프로젝트를 시작했지만, 기존 시스템과 AI를 연결하는 데 막대한 API 작업과 불안정한 미들웨어, 전문 개발 역량이 필요하다는 사실을 뒤늦게 확인했다. 엘리스는 MCP가 빠르게 확산된 배경으로 이러한 실질적 효용을 지목했다.</p> <p>엘리스는 “MCP는 번거로운 API 통합 작업 없이 기존 애플리케이션 스택을 서로 연결할 수 있게 해준다”라며 “사실상 범용 커넥터에 가깝다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>이어 “많은 기업이 처음부터 복잡한 AI 시스템을 새로 구축하려 했다”라며 “MCP를 활용하면 기존 애플리케이션을 서로 연결하는 방식으로 접근할 수 있다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>MCP는 AI 에이전트와 애플리케이션이 데이터를 조회하고 기업용 도구와 상호작용할 수 있는 표준화된 방식을 제공한다. 최근 인터뷰에서 RSA 콘퍼런스(RSAC) 연구진은 이를 ‘AI의 USB-C’에 비유하며, 서로 다른 시스템이 맞춤형 통합 없이도 소통할 수 있도록 설계된 연결자라고 표현했다.</p> <p>광범위한 애플리케이션 포트폴리오를 운영하면서 동시에 AI 기반 기능을 빠르게 도입해야 하는 CIO에게 이는 구현 방정식을 바꾸는 요소다. 통합은 맞춤형 엔지니어링 중심에서 설정 중심 방식으로 전환되고, 기존 시스템을 재구축하지 않아도 접근이 가능해진다. 비엔지니어도 데이터 소스를 AI 워크플로에 연결할 수 있다. 현대화가 응집력보다 복잡성만 키운 환경이라면, MCP가 빠르게 확산되는 이유는 분명하다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%8f%84%ec%9e%85-%ec%86%8d%eb%8f%84%ea%b0%80-%ed%86%b5%ec%a0%9c%eb%a5%bc-%ec%95%9e%ec%a7%80%eb%a5%b4%eb%8b%a4">도입 속도가 통제를 앞지르다</h2> <p>여느 AI 기술과 마찬가지로, 실험과 도입의 속도는 거버넌스 통제 체계 구축을 앞지르고 있다. 벤더는 AI 접근을 단순화하기 위해 기업용 제품에 MCP 커넥터를 내장하고 있다. 코딩 어시스턴트는 이미 MCP에 광범위하게 의존하고 있으며, 개발자와 이른바 ‘바이브 코더’는 최소한의 마찰로 시스템을 연결하고 워크플로를 자동화하는 데 이를 활용하고 있다.</p> <p>동시에 AI 에이전트는 설계상 비결정적 특성을 지닌다. 여기에 MCP 도구가 강력한 운영 권한까지 부여할 수 있다는 점이 더해진다. 통합의 용이성과 광범위한 권한이 결합되면서, 조직이 과거 대규모로 관리해본 적 없는 새로운 리스크 프로파일이 형성되고 있다. CIO에게 이는 익숙한 긴장 관계다. 운영 가치는 분명하지만, 통제되지 않은 도입은 구조적 노출로 이어질 수 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%8b%a4%ec%a7%88%ec%a0%81-%ed%99%9c%ec%9a%a9-%ec%82%ac%eb%a1%80%ea%b0%80-%eb%b9%a0%eb%a5%b4%ea%b2%8c-%ed%99%95%ec%82%b0">실질적 활용 사례가 빠르게 확산</h2> <p>MCP는 개념 검증 단계를 넘어 실제 운영 워크플로로 확장되고 있다. 조직은 사고 관리를 위해 여러 시스템에서 데이터를 수집하고, 지원 티켓을 읽어 우선순위를 지정하며, 항목을 내부 추적 시스템으로 이동시키는 데 MCP를 활용하고 있다. 보안, 로깅, 파일 플랫폼을 상호 연계하는 작업에도 적용되고 있다. 코딩 어시스턴트와 AI 기반 업무 자동화 도구 역시 MCP 의존도를 높이고 있다.</p> <p>이러한 활용 사례는 맥락 전환을 줄이고 수작업 데이터 수집을 없애며, 대규모 통합 프로젝트 없이도 AI가 워크플로를 지원할 수 있도록 한다는 점에서 설득력이 있다. 동시에 도입과 함께 거버넌스 체계도 병행 진화해야 하는 이유를 분명히 보여준다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cio%ea%b0%80-%ec%a7%80%ea%b8%88-%ec%a0%90%ea%b2%80%ed%95%b4%ec%95%bc-%ed%95%a0-%ec%a7%88%eb%ac%b8">CIO가 지금 점검해야 할 질문</h2> <p>MCP는 AI 시스템이 기업 환경과 상호작용하는 방식을 통제하는 계층으로 자리 잡고 있다. 이는 경영진 차원의 가시성과 의도적인 정책 결정이 필요하다는 의미다.</p> <p>리더는 먼저 개발 도구와 AI 어시스턴트를 중심으로 MCP가 이미 어디에서 활용되고 있는지 파악해야 한다. 통합을 생성할 권한이 누구에게 있는지, 권한은 어떤 방식으로 부여되고 제한되는지, MCP 서버는 어떻게 인증되고 신뢰가 검증되는지도 점검해야 한다. 통합 전반에 걸쳐 일관된 정책 집행을 보장하려면 거버넌스 정책을 프로토콜 계층에 더 가깝게 설계할 필요가 있다.</p> <p>또한 MCP 도입이 단일 전사 프로젝트를 통해 이뤄지지 않을 가능성도 인식해야 한다. 다양한 도구와 벤더, 조직 전반의 실험이 동시에 진행되면서 점진적으로 확산될 가능성이 높다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9d%bc%ec%8b%9c%ec%a0%81-%ec%9c%a0%ed%96%89%ec%9d%b4-%ec%95%84%eb%8b%8c-%ea%b5%ac%ec%a1%b0%ec%a0%81-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98">일시적 유행이 아닌 구조적 전환</h2> <p>프로토콜이 경영진 의제로 부상하는 일은 드물다. MCP가 예외로 떠오른 이유는 AI 실행, 시스템 통합, 기업 거버넌스가 교차하는 지점에 위치해 있기 때문이다. MCP는 AI가 기업 데이터를 분석하도록 할 뿐 아니라, 기업 시스템 내부에서 실제로 행동할 수 있도록 만든다. 이는 강력하고 혁신적인 변화이며, 동시에 리스크 계산 방식도 바꿔 놓는다.</p> <p>MCP의 확산은 기업 아키텍처가 단순히 데이터를 노출하는 구조에서 벗어나, 지능형 에이전트가 직접 운영할 수 있는 구조로 이동하고 있음을 보여준다. CIO는 도입 속도를 늦출 필요는 없지만, 신원 통제, 거버넌스 정책, 보안 가드레일이 동일한 속도로 진화하도록 관리해야 한다.</p> <p>에이전트가 기업 시스템 전반에서 작동하는 시대에는, 핵심 질문이 AI가 환경에 접근할 수 있는지 여부에서 그 안에서 얼마나 안전하고 책임 있게 운영될 수 있는지로 옮겨가고 있다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[국내 기업 80%, 단절된 데이터가 AI 역량 저하” 세일즈포스 보고서]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137086/%ea%b5%ad%eb%82%b4-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85-80-%eb%8b%a8%ec%a0%88%eb%90%9c-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0%ea%b0%80-ai-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89-%ec%a0%80%ed%95%98-%ec%84%b8%ec%9d%bc%ec%a6%88%ed%8f%ac%ec%8a%a4.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137086/%ea%b5%ad%eb%82%b4-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85-80-%eb%8b%a8%ec%a0%88%eb%90%9c-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0%ea%b0%80-ai-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89-%ec%a0%80%ed%95%98-%ec%84%b8%ec%9d%bc%ec%a6%88%ed%8f%ac%ec%8a%a4.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>보고서에 따르면 국내 기업은 데이터 기반 경영의 중요성을 높게 평가하고 있다. 국내 기업의 약 60%는 스스로를 ‘데이터 중심 조직’으로 평가했으며, 이는 2023년 대비 28%포인트 상승한 수치다. 또한 국내 기업의 75%는 데이터를 활용해 비즈니스 가치를 창출해야 한다는 압박이 증가했다고 응답했다. 국내 기업은 핵심 과제로 실시간 데이터 접근성 확보, 전사적 데이터 리터러시 강화에 이어 ‘AI 역량’을 꼽았으며, 이는 2023년 6위에서 2025년 3위로 급상승했다.</p> <p>데이터의 중요성에 대한 인식과 실제 비즈니스 성과 창출 사이에는 여전히 간극이 존재했다. 국내 데이터 및 분석 부문 선도 기업의 84%는 ‘탄탄한 데이터 기반’이 AI 성공의 핵심 요인이라고 봤지만, 이 중 61%는 데이터를 실제 비즈니스 우선 과제와 연결하는 데 어려움을 겪고 있다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>대표적으로 응답자들은 성과 창출을 저해하는 가장 큰 요인으로 단절된 데이터 구조를 꼽았다. 국내 데이터 및 분석 부문 선도 기업들은 기업 데이터의 15%가 사일로에 갇혀 있거나 접근 및 활용이 불가능한 상태라고 추정했다. 특히 응답자의 66%는 가장 가치 있는 비즈니스 인사이트가 이 접근 불가능한 15%의 데이터 안에 존재한다고 답해 데이터 통합의 시급성을 강조했다. 약 80%의 기업은 단절된 데이터가 AI 역량 저하, 고객 이해 부족, 개인화 한계, 매출 손실을 초래한다고 응답했다.</p> <p>이 같은 데이터 단절을 해결하기 위해 리더들은 투자 전략과 활용 방식을 재설계하고 있다. 전 세계 CIO는 AI 기술 자체보다 전제 조건인 데이터 인프라 및 관리에 4배 더 많은 예산을 배정하고 있다. 국내 기업의 56% 역시 데이터 단절 문제를 완화하기 위해 데이터를 물리적으로 복사하지 않고 연결하는 ‘제로카피(Zero-copy)’ 방식의 데이터 통합 전략을 도입하고 있다.</p> <p>AI 확산에 따른 보안 및 거버넌스 체계의 재정비 필요성도 부각됐다. 글로벌 기업 경영진의 43%만이 공식적인 데이터 거버넌스 프레임워크와 정책을 수립했다고 밝혔으며, 국내 데이터 및 분석 선도 기업의 86%는 AI 도입에 완전히 새로운 거버넌스와 보안 접근 방식이 필요하다고 답했다. 또한 80%는 AI 전략이 성공하려면 데이터 전략 전반의 재정비가 필요하다고 응답했다.</p> <p>세일즈포스는 ‘데이터 360’, ‘인포매티카’, ‘뮬소프트’ 등의 제품을 아우르는 ‘데이터 파운데이션(Data Foundation)’을 통해 AI 시대에 필요한 통합 데이터 생태계 구축을 지원하고 있다. 핵심 솔루션인 ‘데이터 360’은 제로카피 기술을 통해 데이터를 실시간으로 통합하고 즉시 활용 가능한 데이터로 전환한다. 여기에 데이터의 맥락 파악 및 마스터 데이터 관리(MDM)에 특화된 ‘인포매티카’와 데이터·시스템의 매끄러운 통합 및 멀티 에이전트 오케스트레이션을 담당하는 ‘뮬소프트’가 결합하여, 비즈니스 애플리케이션과 AI 에이전트가 최적의 데이터를 즉각적 활용할 수 있도록 지원한다.</p> <p>데이터 활용 방식 또한 더욱 직관적으로 진화하고 있다. 국내 선도 기업의 96%는 자연어로 데이터를 질의할 수 있다면 업무 성과가 향상될 것이라고 기대했다. 이에 맞춰 세일즈포스는 에이전틱 데이터 분석 플랫폼인 태블로(Tableau)의 ‘태블로 넥스트(Tableau Next)’를 제공하고 있다. 세일즈포스는 태블로 넥스트는 AI 에이전트 기반 분석을 통해 일상적인 업무 흐름 속에서 자연어 기반의 질의응답을 지원하며, 개인화된 인사이트를 제공하여 데이터 기반의 의사결정을 지원한다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>세일즈포스 코리아 박세진 대표는 “AI 시대 데이터는 기업의 생존과 직결된 핵심적인 자산이다. 이번 연구 조사가 시사하듯 기업 내 흩어진 데이터를 통합하고 신뢰할 수 있는 데이터 파운데이션을 구축하는 것이 기업 성장의 핵심 동력이 될 것”이라며 “세일즈포스는 국내 기업들이 산재한 데이터 자산을 통합하고, AI 에이전트와 인간이 유기적으로 공존 및 협업할 수 있는 ‘에이전틱 엔터프라이즈’로의 전환을 적극 지원할 것”이라고 언급했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[‘에버퓨어’로 사명 변경한 퓨어스토리지, 전문가들이 본 향후 전망]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137084/%ec%97%90%eb%b2%84%ed%93%a8%ec%96%b4%eb%a1%9c-%ec%82%ac%eb%aa%85-%eb%b3%80%ea%b2%bd%ed%95%9c-%ed%93%a8%ec%96%b4%ec%8a%a4%ed%86%a0%eb%a6%ac%ec%a7%80-%ec%a0%84%eb%ac%b8%ea%b0%80.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137084/%ec%97%90%eb%b2%84%ed%93%a8%ec%96%b4%eb%a1%9c-%ec%82%ac%eb%aa%85-%eb%b3%80%ea%b2%bd%ed%95%9c-%ed%93%a8%ec%96%b4%ec%8a%a4%ed%86%a0%eb%a6%ac%ec%a7%80-%ec%a0%84%eb%ac%b8%ea%b0%80.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>퓨어스토리지가 지난 23일 사명을 에버퓨어로 변경하고 데이터 분류 기업 1터치를 인수했다고 <a href="https://www.purestorage.com/company/newsroom/press-releases/pure-storage-becomes-everpure.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">발표</a>했다. 단순 스토리지를 넘어, 기업이 AI에 활용할 수 있도록 데이터 관리 역량을 제공하는 기업으로 전환하겠다는 전략이다.</p> <p>에버퓨어로 새롭게 출범한 퓨어스토리지는 기업용 스토리지 시장에서 주요 업체로 평가받고 있다. <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/6908066" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">가트너</a>는 기업용 스토리지 시장 분석을 통해 에버퓨어를 ‘리더’ 부문에서 경쟁사보다 앞선 위치로 선정했다. 기가옴(GigaOm)이 지난해 12월 발표한 <a href="https://portal.gigaom.com/report/gigaom-radar-for-primary-storage-6" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">프라이머리 스토리지 보고서</a>에서도 핵심 기능 부문 최고 등급을 받았고, 신규 기능 부문에서는 공동 2위를 기록했다. <a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS54034425" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">IDC</a>에 따르면 지난해 에버퓨어는 전년 대비 15.5% 성장하며 가장 빠르게 성장한 기업용 스토리지 기업이었다. 이 같은 성장세를 바탕으로 HPE를 제치고 델, 화웨이, 넷앱에 이어 업계 4위로 올라섰다.</p> <p>에버퓨어 디지털 익스피리언스 사업부 총괄 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/prakashdarji/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">프라카시 다르지</a>는 사명 변경 배경에 대해 “스토리지 사업을 중단하는 것은 분명히 아니다. 그동안 데이터 관리 역량을 지속적으로 확대해 왔다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>이런 노력에도 불구하고, 많은 기업이 에버퓨어를 스토리지 업체로만 인식했다. 다르지는 “기존 사명이 사업 확장에 제약으로 작용했다. 앞으로 나아가려는 카테고리 확장 방향을 충분히 담아내지 못했다”라고 전했다. 에버퓨어라는 새 이름은 기존 ‘퓨어’ 브랜드의 인지도에, 구독형 스토리지 제품군 ‘에버그린’의 ‘에버’를 결합한 결과다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a2%8b%ec%9d%80-ai%eb%8a%94-%ec%a2%8b%ec%9d%80-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%ec%8b%9c%ec%9e%91">“좋은 AI는 좋은 데이터에서 시작”</h2> <p><a href="https://www.bcg.com/publications/2025/are-you-generating-value-from-ai-the-widening-gap" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">보스턴컨설팅그룹</a>이 지난해 9월 발표한 설문조사에 따르면, AI 도입을 담당하는 고위 의사결정자 1,250명 가운데 68%는 고품질 데이터에 대한 접근 부족을 AI 도입의 핵심 과제로 꼽았다.</p> <p>이 같은 흐름은 다른 조사에서도 확인된다. <a href="https://investor.cisco.com/news/news-details/2025/Cisco-AI-Research-The-Most-AI-ready-Companies-Outpace-Peers-in-the-Race-to-Value/default.aspx" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">시스코</a>가 지난해 10월 8,000명 이상의 AI 리더를 대상으로 진행한 설문에서, AI 에이전트를 위해 실시간 통합이 가능한 중앙집중형 정제 데이터를 보유한 기업은 35%에 불과한 것으로 나타났다. <a href="https://my.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS53883425" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">IDC</a>는 2027년까지 고품질의 AI 준비 데이터를 우선순위에 두지 않는 기업이 생성형 AI와 에이전트형 솔루션 확장에 어려움을 겪어, 생산성이 최대 15%까지 감소할 수 있다고 전망했다.</p> <p>공급망 컨설팅 기업 서큘러 테크놀로지(Circular Technology)의 글로벌 리서치 및 시장 인텔리전스 총괄 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bgastwirth/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">브래드 개스트워스</a>는 “모든 기업이 AI를 이야기하고 있지만, 대부분은 데이터가 분산돼 있고 체계적으로 정리되지 않아 AI를 도입할 준비가 돼 있지 않다. 에버퓨어가 스토리지를 구조화되고 지능적인 데이터 기반으로 전환할 수 있다면 개념 증명(PoC)에서 실제 운영 AI로 넘어가는 시간을 크게 단축할 수 있을 것”이라고 분석했다.</p> <p>다만 이러한 전환이 쉽지는 않을 전망이다. 개스트워스는 스토리지 하드웨어 기업이라는 기존 인식에서 데이터 플랫폼 기업으로 자리매김하기까지는 수년이 걸릴 수 있다고 내다봤다. 그는 “제품 통합을 완성하는 과제도 있지만, 상업적 측면의 변화도 필요하다. 영업 조직은 새로운 방식으로 가치를 설명해야 하고, 고객은 예산 편성 방식을 바꿔야 하며, 시장에는 이를 입증할 사례가 요구된다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>AI 데이터 플랫폼 자리를 둘러싼 경쟁도 치열하다. 개스트워스는 “차별화는 기술 스택 내 어느 계층에 위치하느냐에 달려 있다. 에버퓨어가 상위에 별도 도구를 덧붙이는 대신, 코어 스토리지 계층에 직접 지능을 내재화할 수 있다면 오히려 구조를 단순화하는 효과를 낼 수 있다”라고 진단했다.</p> <p>기업이 에이전틱 AI를 도입하는 과정에서는 제어 계층을 데이터에 더 가깝게 두는 전략이 도움이 될 수 있다. AI 에이전트는 학습 단계는 물론 RAG 임베딩, MPC 서버 연동 등 다양한 방식으로 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4113707/when-it-comes-to-ai-not-all-data-is-created-equal.html" target="_blank">데이터에 원활히 접근</a>해야 제대로 작동한다. 동시에 각 에이전트가 허용된 데이터에만 접근하도록 통제하는 것 역시 중요한 과제로 떠오르고 있다.</p> <p>ZK리서치(ZK Research) 설립자이자 수석 애널리스트 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zkerravala/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">제우스 케라발라</a>는 “에이전틱 AI로의 전환은 데이터 인텔리전스를 데이터 인프라와 긴밀하게 결합해야 하는 주요 이유”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>케라발라는 2017년 퓨어스토리지 CEO로 찰스 지안카를로가 취임했을 당시를 언급하며, 그가 이미 AI로 인해 데이터센터가 어떻게 진화할지에 대한 비전을 갖고 있었다고 전했다. 케라발라는 “지안카를로는 스토리지가 AI에서 더 큰 역할을 할 수 있다고 봤지만, 이를 위해서는 변화가 필요하다고 판단했다. 이후 추진한 모든 전략은 회사를 진화시키기 위한 방향으로 이뤄졌다”라고 평가했다.</p> <p>케라발라는 1터치 인수가 이 전략의 핵심 축이 될 수 있다고 봤다. 그는 “이번 인수는 기존 스토리지 기반에 다양한 데이터 인텔리전스를 더해준다. 데이터 탐색, 데이터 분류, 그리고 AI에 적합한 데이터 준비 역량이 포함된다. 에버퓨어는 이전까지 이 기능을 충분히 갖추지 못했다”라고 진단했다.</p> <p>에버퓨어의 다르지도 AI 시대에는 데이터 관리 기능이 스토리지와 더욱 밀접하게 결합돼야 한다는 점에 공감하면서, 에버퓨어가 이제 이러한 요구를 충족할 수 있는 위치에 서 있다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>다르지는 “현재 파일이나 오브젝트의 보안은 해당 객체에 연결돼 있으며, 스토리지 시스템의 보안 체계 안에서 관리된다. 특정 에이전트만 구매 주문서를 볼 수 있도록 설정돼 있다면, 스토리지 보안이 곧 AI 보안과 직결된다는 점을 이해하는 것이 중요하다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>예를 들어 한 파일이 특정 금액의 구매 주문서라는 사실과 같은 메타데이터를 함께 관리해야 할 경우, 이 정보는 별도의 데이터베이스에 저장되는 것이 일반적이다.</p> <p>다르지는 “해당 정보를 외부에 따로 저장하면 에이전트는 먼저 데이터베이스를 조회한 뒤 다시 스토리지에 접근해야 한다. 이는 매우 비효율적”이라며 “데이터 분류 정보와 추가 맥락, 보강 정보가 스토리지 계층 바로 옆에 위치한다면 AI가 이를 훨씬 효율적으로 활용할 수 있다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>1터치의 경쟁사는 개인정보 식별 정보(PII) 탐지처럼 특정 영역에 특화된 기능만 제공하는 경우가 많다. 반면 1터치는 보다 유연한 플랫폼을 갖추고 있어, 기업이 자체 요구사항에 맞게 데이터 분류 체계를 조정할 수 있다.</p> <p>기본적으로 프라이버시 보호와 보안을 위해 즉시 사용 가능한 모델이 있지만, 고객은 자체 대규모 언어 모델(LLM)을 포함해 다른 분류기를 적용할 수도 있다. 다르지는 “특정 모델에 종속되지 않고 플러그형으로 연동할 수 있는 구조”라며 “예를 들어 엑스레이 이미지에서 골절 여부를 분류하는 작업도 가능하다. 아키텍처 측면에서 매우 개방적인 구조”라고 밝혔다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[IT 현대화를 가속하는 6가지 전략]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137046/it-%ed%98%84%eb%8c%80%ed%99%94%eb%a5%bc-%ea%b0%80%ec%86%8d%ed%95%98%eb%8a%94-6%ea%b0%80%ec%a7%80-%ec%a0%84%eb%9e%b5.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137046/it-%ed%98%84%eb%8c%80%ed%99%94%eb%a5%bc-%ea%b0%80%ec%86%8d%ed%95%98%eb%8a%94-6%ea%b0%80%ec%a7%80-%ec%a0%84%eb%9e%b5.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>현대화는 CIO의 우선순위로 남아 있다. 많은 IT 임원이 레거시 시스템과 낡은 인프라가 AI 도입과 혁신, 궁극적으로 비즈니스 성장을 가로막는다고 말한다.</p> <p>실제로 CIO는 현대화를 디지털 전환 업무의 핵심 요소로 꼽고 있다. CIO.com의 ‘2025 CIO 현황 보고서’에 따르면, IT 리더의 의제 대부분을 전환 과제가 차지하고 그 비중은 77%에 이른다.</p> <p>하지만 지금의 우선순위는 단순한 현대화가 아니라, 최고 속도의 현대화다.</p> <p>조직 구조 및 전략 자문 회사 Org.Works의 CEO 재닛 셜록은 “기술도 빠르게 움직이지만 사회와 비즈니스 환경은 더 빠르게 움직이기 때문에, 이제는 따라잡기 위해서라도 현대화를 해야 한다”라며, “조직 전체가 더 빠르게 움직일 수 있도록, 현대화는 늘 더 빠른 속도로 진행돼야 한다”라고 강조했다.</p> <p>대부분의 CIO는 도전에 응할 준비가 돼 있다고 말한다. IT 서비스·컨설팅 업체 코그니전트(Cognizant)의 조사에 따르면, 응답자의 약 3/4은 다양한 레거시 현대화 이니셔티브를 2년 안에 완료할 것이라고 믿고 있다. 하지만 전망은 그리 낙관적이지 않은데, 보고서는 조직이 더 빠른 현대화를 추진하는 과정에서 역량 부족부터 예산 제약까지 다양한 도전에 직면한다고 지적했다.</p> <p>수많은 도전 과제에도 불구하고, CIO가 IT 현대화를 가속하기 위해 추진할 수 있는 전략이 있다. IT 현대화 속도를 높이는 데 도움이 되는 6가지 전략을 알아본다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-ai%eb%a5%bc-%eb%af%b8%eb%9e%98%eb%a1%9c-%ea%b0%80%eb%8a%94-%eb%8b%a4%eb%a6%ac%eb%a1%9c-%ed%99%9c%ec%9a%a9%ed%95%9c%eb%8b%a4">1. AI를 미래로 가는 다리로 활용한다</h2> <p>컨설팅 회사 웨스트 먼로(West Monroe)의 수석 파트너이자 기술·경험 프랙티스 책임자 에릭 브라운은 “많은 조직이 AI를 빠르게 활용하기 위해 현대화 속도를 높이려 하지만, 현대화 업무 자체를 가속화하는 데도 AI를 써야 한다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>보통 IT 조직은 레거시 모놀리식 인프라를 분해하고 더 현대적인 인프라와 시스템을 구현하기 전에 문서와 코드를 수작업으로 검토해야 했다. 하지만, 지금은 AI를 활용해 ‘현재 상태를 미래로 옮기는’ 작업을 도울 수 있다.</p> <p>브라운은 “AI는 수백만 줄의 코드를 분석할 수 있다. 저장 프로시저와 ETL 스크립트를 이해하고 데이터를 현대적 플랫폼으로 옮기기 위한 현대적 버전을 만들어낼 수 있다. 수개월 걸리던 고된 수작업을 며칠로 줄인다. 그 효과는 엄청나다”라고, 설명했다. 또, 브라운은 “AI는 속도를 만들기 위한 조직의 지식도 축적한다”라며, “AI는 엄청난 가속기다”라고 덧붙였다.</p> <p>조직이 이런 민첩성을 확보하는 데는 재무적인 유인이 있다. 웨스트 먼로 조사에서 대부분의 리더가 느린 의사결정과 실행 때문에 연간 매출의 1%~5%를 잃는다고 생각하는 것으로 나타났다. 웨스트 먼로는 이를 ‘느림세(slowness tax)’라고 부른다.</p> <p>브라운은 앞으로 수년 동안 AI가 IT 현대화에서 점점 더 중요한 역할을 할 것이라고 본다. 브라운은 AI 에이전트가 언젠가 애플리케이션 내부 리소스를 포함한 IT 환경을 상시 검토해 낡은 요소를 찾아내고, 낡은 요소를 식별하면 최적의 업데이트 방식을 결정한 뒤 업데이트를 실행하며, 사람 개입은 거의 없거나 전혀 없고 사람의 감독만 남는 수준까지 발전할 것이라고 예측했다.</p> <p>브라운은 “AI는 지속적인 현대화를 처리할 놀라운 메커니즘을 제공한다”라며, 에이전틱 AI가 아직 그 수준까지 도달하지 못했다고 인정하면서도 “그렇게 될 것이라고 확신한다”라고 강조했다.</p> <p>현 시점에서는 에이전틱 AI가 가능성을 보여주고 있지만, 레거시 시스템에 적용하는 일은 여전히 도전 과제로 남아 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-%eb%a7%a4%eb%8b%88%ec%a7%80%eb%93%9c-%ec%84%9c%eb%b9%84%ec%8a%a4%ec%99%80-%ec%84%9c%eb%b2%84%eb%a6%ac%ec%8a%a4-%ec%95%84%ed%82%a4%ed%85%8d%ec%b2%98%eb%a5%bc-%ec%b1%84%ed%83%9d%ed%95%9c%eb%8b%a4">2. 매니지드 서비스와 서버리스 아키텍처를 채택한다</h2> <p>캐피털원(Capital One)의 클라우드 거버넌스 부문 부사장 폴 설리번은 “캐피털원은 현대화를 ‘운영 DNA를 지속적으로 정교화해 영구적 진화 상태를 가능하게 하는 것’으로 본다”라고 밝혔다. 설리번은 “목표는 마찰 없는 환경”이라며, “과거에 소프트웨어를 만들고 가치를 제공하던 방식의 무게에 발목 잡히지 않고, AI 기반 역량을 포함한 새로운 역량을 빠르게 제공할 수 있어야 한다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>대표적인 사례로 캐피털원은 최근 애플리케이션 개발에서 서버리스 환경으로 전사적 전환을 단행했으며, 새로운 애플리케이션의 기본값을 매니지드 클라우드 네이티브 컴퓨팅으로 설정했다. 설리번은 “이 변화는 개발자가 직접 운영하는 무언가가 아니라 서비스 집합으로 인프라를 다루게 만들었다”라며, “캐피털원은 수동 관리에서 벗어나, 플랫폼이 차별화되지 않는 무거운 작업을 처리하는 모델로 이동했다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>이런 전환이 더 빠른 혁신과 더 강한 보안 태세, 더 나은 비용 효율성을 가능하게 했으며, 캐피털원은 이런 장점을 고려해 매니지드 서비스와 서버리스 아키텍처 채택을 현대화 가속의 핵심 전략으로 삼고 있다.</p> <p>설리번은 “CIO는 인프라를 관리해야 할 자산 집합으로 보는 관점을 멈추고, 서비스를 통해 전달되는 제품으로 보기 시작해야 한다. 자동화된 거버넌스와 관찰가능성을 여기에 결합하면 혁신을 위한 안전지대를 만들 수 있다”라며, “보안이나 복원력을 훼손할 위험 없이 팀이 빠르게 움직일 수 있게 한다”라고 강조했다.</p> <p>이를 통해 IT 조직은 유지보수에 쓰는 시간을 줄이고 엔지니어링의 창의적 부분에 더 많은 시간을 할애할 수 있다. 설리번은 “개발자는 탁월한 코드를 쓰고 혁신적 애플리케이션을 만드는 데 집중할 수 있어야 한다. 잡무가 줄어들면, 결과물이 더 빨리 나온다”라며, “플랫폼이 배관 작업을 처리하면 엔지니어는 제품에 집중할 수 있고, 실험이 싸고 빨라지는 문화를 만든다”라고 덧붙였다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-%ed%98%84%eb%8c%80%ed%99%94-%eb%ac%b8%ed%99%94%eb%a5%bc-%ea%b5%ac%ec%b6%95%ed%95%9c%eb%8b%a4">3. 현대화 문화를 구축한다</h2> <p>뱅가드(Vanguard)의 재무 자문 서비스 부문 CIO 로런 윌킨슨은 “뱅가드는 속도와 복원력을 가능하게 하는 마이크로서비스 아키텍처를 활용해 시스템을 클라우드로 현대화했다”라고 밝혔다. 윌킨슨은 “성과는 고무적이었다”라며, “웹사이트 경험을 업그레이드하고 새 모바일 앱을 출시했으며, 개선 사항을 매일 지속적 전달하는 방식으로 전환해 팀이 고객 피드백에 더 빨리 대응할 수 있게 됐다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>이런 현대화 이니셔티브를 속도감 있게 추진하려면 조직 목표와의 정렬이 필요하다. 윌킨슨은 “가장 중요한 전략은 조직 최상단에 ‘북극성’를 세우는 일”이라고 표현했다. 윌킨슨은 “현대화는 단순한 기술 이니셔티브로 여겨져서는 안 되며, 비즈니스 이니셔티브여야 한다”라며 “전사적인 방향을 정하고, 기술 기능과 비즈니스 기능 사이의 경쟁 우선순위를 완화할 수 있는데, 이 경쟁 우선순위는 흔한 장애물”이라고 강조했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c%ec%84%b8%ec%8a%a4%eb%a5%bc-%ec%9e%ac%ec%84%a4%ea%b3%84%ed%95%98%ea%b8%b0-%ec%9c%84%ed%95%b4-ai%eb%a5%bc-%eb%8f%84%ec%9e%85%ed%95%9c%eb%8b%a4">4. 프로세스를 재설계하기 위해 AI를 도입한다</h2> <p>뱅가드는 현대화 노력의 일환으로 개발팀에 바이브 코딩을 도입했다.</p> <p>윌킨슨은 “고급 도구를 통합해 엔지니어링, 제품, 디자인팀 사이의 전통적 프로세스를 없앴다. 웹페이지 디자인 프로세스를 40% 가속했고, 프로토타이핑 시간을 2주에서 20분으로 줄였다”라고 밝혔다. 또, “이 변화는 엔지니어링 프로세스를 바꿨을 뿐 아니라, 고객에게 가치를 전달하는 방식 자체를 재구성했다”라고 덧붙였다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-%ec%97%ad%ed%95%a0%c2%b7%ec%b1%85%ec%9e%84%c2%b7%ec%9d%98%ec%82%ac%ea%b2%b0%ec%a0%95-%ea%b6%8c%ed%95%9c%ec%9d%84-%eb%aa%85%ed%99%95%ed%9e%88-%ed%95%9c%eb%8b%a4">5. 역할·책임·의사결정 권한을 명확히 한다</h2> <p>셜록은 “기술과 프로세스에서 누가 어떤 결정을 내리는지 명확하지 않은 기업은 현대화 속도를 낼 수 없다”라며, “팀이 현대화 이니셔티브가 영향을 미칠 플랫폼, 시스템, 역량의 소유 주체를 파악하느라 소중한 시간을 써야 하기 때문”이라고 설명했다.</p> <p>또, 조사 결과를 근거로 “CIO와 최고 AI 책임자가 동급의 동료 관계로 존재하는 조직은 이런 모호함 때문에 속도가 약 25% 악화된다”라고 지적했다.</p> <p>셜록은 “의사결정 책임이 명확하지 않고 여러 팀이나 여러 사람이 어떤 사안의 책임자라고 믿으면, 의사결정이 지연된다. IT 조직은 누가 실제 책임자인지 알아내려 시간을 들여 맴돌아야 한다”라며, “영역 다툼이 발생하면 마찰이 생기고, 마찰이 커뮤니케이션을 지연시키며, 커뮤니케이션 지연이 속도를 늦추고, 결국 배 전체가 느려진다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>셜록은 2022~2024년 랄프 로렌(Ralph Lauren) 최고 디지털·기술 책임자, 2017~2022년 랄프 로렌 CIO를 지내는 등 과거 임원 역할에서 이런 모호함을 겪었다고 말했다. 셜록은 “다른 팀 누군가가 내 팀의 영역을 넘어섰다고 느낄 때마다 회의를 잡고 ‘이건 우리가 하고, 저건 당신이 하자’고 말했다”라며, “‘영역’ 문제가 아니라 ‘명확성’ 문제이며, 함께 더 빨리 움직이기 위해서라고 설명했다”라고 덧붙였다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-it-%ec%95%84%ed%82%a4%ed%85%8d%ec%b2%98%eb%a5%bc-%eb%aa%a8%eb%93%88%ed%98%95%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c-%eb%a7%8c%eb%93%a0%eb%8b%a4">6. IT 아키텍처를 모듈형으로 만든다</h2> <p>프라이스워터하우스쿠퍼스(PwC) 테크놀로지 전략 파트너이자 CIO 프로그램 리더 대니엘 파노프는 “IT는 낡은 부품을 빠르게 교체하는 경주용 자동차의 피트 크루처럼 움직여야 한다”라며, “그렇게 하려면 CIO가 ‘모든 것을 교체할 수 있는’ 모듈형 IT 아키텍처로 가야 한다”라고 강조했다.</p> <p>모듈형 IT 아키텍처는 독립적이고 상호운용 가능한 구성요소로 이뤄지며, 각 구성요소는 별도로 개발·배포·확장할 수 있다. 각 모듈은 명확한 인터페이스와 책임을 갖기 때문에, IT 팀은 전체 스택을 흔들지 않고 역량을 업데이트하거나 교체할 수 있으며, 피트 크루가 레이스카 전체가 아니라 부품만 교체하는 방식과 같다.</p> <p>파노프는 “모듈성이 필요하며, 모놀리식 모델이 다시 스며드는 일은 원치 않는다”라고 말했다. 하지만, “모듈성이 파편화를 의미해서도 안 된다. 핵심은 의존성을 최소화해, 새것을 꽂기 위해 기존 것을 문자 그대로 뽑아낼 수 있게 만드는 일”이라고 설명했다.</p> <p>이런 접근법은 AI 모델과 관련해 특히 유용하다. 파노프는 “혁신 속도가 너무 빨라 오늘의 선도 AI 모델이 내일의 낙오자가 될 수 있다. 조직은 필요할 때 한 모델을 다른 모델로 빠르게 교체할 수 있어야 한다”라고 덧붙였다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI agent platforms could push down SaaS license costs, report argues]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136820/ai-agent-platforms-could-push-down-saas-license-costs-report-argues.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136820/ai-agent-platforms-could-push-down-saas-license-costs-report-argues.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>A suggestion by Anthropic that its Claude Code tool could be used to automate the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/ibm-posts-steepest-daily-drop-since-2000-after-anthropic-says-ai-can-modernize-2026-02-24/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">modernization of an antediluvian programming language, COBOL</a>, still an important sideline for IBM six decades after it was first deployed, sent IBM stock tumbling on Monday.</p> <p>The company suffered a 13.2% drop in its stock price, its biggest fall since the dot com period a quarter of a century ago. </p> <p>But IBM is not the only company suffering because of the AI hype. Across a swathe of SaaS companies, <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4134107/mistral-ceo-over-half-of-companies-software-can-be-replaced-by-ai.html" target="_blank">a state of near panic</a> seems to be spreading as the potential of AI to automate software creation and management starts emerge. Salesforce, Atlassian, ServiceNow, and Snowflake have all seen heavy selling in an event one trading company melodramatically dubbed the “SaaSpocalypse.”</p> <p>But according to a hypothetical scenario in <a href="https://www.citriniresearch.com/p/2028gic" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The 2028 Global Intelligence Crisis</a> proposed by Citrini Research and co-author <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alapashah/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Alap Shah</a> of Lotus Technology Management, things could soon get a lot worse for SaaS companies, and beyond them, for the wider US and global economies.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-thought-exercise">A thought exercise</h2> <p>The report speculates how the rise of AI might look from the vantage point of 2028, barely two years after an imagined peak for the S&amp;P 500 of 8,000 points in October this year.</p> <p>“Productivity was booming. Real output per hour rose at rates not seen since the 1950s, driven by AI agents that don’t sleep, take sick days, or require health insurance,” said Citrini Research in what it termed a thought exercise. But something else was happening as well: “The owners of compute saw their wealth explode as labor costs vanished. Meanwhile, real wage growth collapsed.”</p> <p>As companies chased the higher productivity of AI, they laid off workers. But as workers were laid off, demand for products and services declined, leading companies to chase even more productivity and automation. “In every way, AI was exceeding expectations, and the market was AI. The only problem…the economy was not,” imagines Citrini.</p> <p>The first to feel this pain will be SaaS platforms. In future, AI agents will perform today’s SaaS tasks for enterprises and consumers alike, weakening their appeal and forcing vendors to offer significant customer discounts just to stay afloat.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="subscription-model-in-peril">Subscription model in peril</h2> <p>The attention being given to this downbeat projection arrives closely on the heels of OpenAI’s early February announcement of its new <a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-openai-frontier/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Frontier enterprise agentic platform</a>, reportedly recently touted to investors as a direct rival to SaaS.</p> <p>As consultancy <a href="https://xpert.digital/en/the-big-reckoning/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xpert Digital bluntly put it</a>: “If AI agents take over the work of entire departments in the future, or if companies simply generate their own code, the foundation of the lucrative subscription model will collapse.”</p> <p>Do these troubles for SaaS vendors mean that customers will be able to negotiate better prices for licenses in 2026? And how likely is it that some will jump ship altogether and start using systems from AI companies rather than the AI-enabled software that SaaS companies will try to temp them with?</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="easy-for-ai-to-write-not-easy-to-run">Easy for AI to write, not easy to run</h2> <p>Experts contacted by <em>CIO.com</em> remain skeptical that AI’s triumph will be as simple to achieve as Citrini Research envisions. First, AI’s ability to perform business tasks as well as SaaS platforms do is untested and unproven. Second, even when they approximate what these systems do, none of it will be auditable. And then businesses must factor in AI agent security worries and the question of whether they will even be cost-efficient.</p> <p>“AI makes it dramatically easier to write software. It does not make it easier to run enterprise software. Those are two very different problems, and most of the cost lives in the latter,” said SAVVI AI CEO, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mayam/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Maya Mikhailov</a>.</p> <p>“The moment you internalize building software, you also inherit security, compliance, uptime, integrations, and 24/7 support. It sounds good in theory, but costs and complexity will squarely land on the bottom line,” she added.</p> <p>According to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/collin-hogue-spears/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Collin Hogue-Spears</a>, technical expert at Black Duck Software, there are also questions about AI’s reliability. “<a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4129867/what-cisos-need-to-know-about-clawdbot-i-mean-moltbot-i-mean-openclaw.html">OpenClaw</a> went from zero to 135,000 exposed instances in weeks because it executes workflows fast. It does not produce audit evidence, satisfy license obligations, or generate the compliance documentation that a regulator demands before that code ships,” he said.</p> <p>“AI agents execute tasks,” he noted. “They don’t produce the evidence trail that stands between your company and a regulatory enforcement action. The pattern repeats across every vertical: AI compresses commodity features and expands governance obligations.”</p> <p>That said, SaaS customers should not take any 2026 price increases lying down. The current weakness in this sector is an unusual opportunity. “SaaS vendors face the most credible pricing pressure since cloud computing displaced on-premises licensing, and the negotiation window is open now,” said Hogue-Spears.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Salesforce Consulting Landscape Shows No Sign Of Slowdown]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-salesforce-consulting-landscape-shows-no-sign-of-slowdown/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-salesforce-consulting-landscape-shows-no-sign-of-slowdown/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Salesforce has been the dominant CRM vendor globally for the last 12 consecutive years. Its FY 2025 revenue of $35.7 billion speaks to the sheer volume of its market presence. More than 150,000 customers use Salesforce’s solutions, from SMBs to enterprises, including 90% of the Fortune 500. With the high stakes involved, enterprises often turn [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why ‘assume breach’ is no longer enough: The case for prevention-first security]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136874/why-assume-breach-is-no-longer-enough-the-case-for-prevention-first-security.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136874/why-assume-breach-is-no-longer-enough-the-case-for-prevention-first-security.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The cybersecurity industry has embraced an “assume breach” philosophy that accepts compromise as inevitable and focuses resources on rapid detection and response. This approach results in a security loop familiar to anyone who has worked in IT: monitor systems, detect anomalies, mitigate active threats, and remediate damage. Although it is pragmatic, given traditional endpoint architectures, this reactive cycle imposes crushing operational and financial costs that organizations can no longer afford.</p> <p>The economic burden extends beyond direct security tool expenses. Security teams spend countless hours investigating alerts, responding to incidents, and patching systems, only to repeat the cycle weeks later. Organizations layer antivirus, endpoint detection and response, data loss prevention, and numerous other agents onto endpoints, each of which increases both licensing costs and performance overhead.</p> <p>Zero trust architectures move the security ball farther downfield, by implementing least-privilege access and microsegmentation to limit the blast radius when breaches occur, preventing bad actors from moving laterally across the network. However, zero trust still assumes that attacks will penetrate systems and focuses on containment, not prevention. This acceptance of inevitable compromise leaves organizations in a perpetually reactive mode.</p> <p>Prevention-first architecture offers a fundamentally different path, by eliminating attack vectors before threats can exploit them. Rather than detecting and responding to malicious code after execution, preventive security blocks that code from ever running. Immutable operating systems prevent unauthorized modifications, making it exponentially harder for attackers to establish persistence or install malware. Read-only partitions ensure that even if attackers gain initial access, they cannot alter system files or inject malicious code. Removing local data storage eliminates what attackers can steal, encrypt for ransom, or exfiltrate.</p> <p>The attack surface shrinks dramatically as a result. Traditional operating systems deploy with comprehensive functionality that most users never need, creating thousands of potential vulnerability points. Prevention-first endpoints install only required components, reducing active code by up to 95% compared to general-purpose platforms.</p> <p>“In this model, there’s nothing on the endpoints that can be compromised,” says Jason Mafera, field CTO at IGEL Technology. “It’s like SASE and zero trust for an endpoint.”</p> <p>The operational benefits extend beyond security. Removing layers of security agents reduces licensing costs, eliminates performance overhead, and frees IT teams from constant firefighting. When endpoints rarely fail or require remediation, support costs plummet.</p> <p>And with regulations increasingly mandating zero trust infrastructure, prevention-first endpoints simplify adoption by eliminating entire categories of threats and controls. For organizations exhausted by the endless cycle of detection and response, prevention offers a path to sustainable security that protects more effectively while consuming fewer resources.</p> <p><strong>Experience prevention-first security at IGEL Now &amp; Next 2026</strong></p> <p>For security leaders ready to move beyond assume-breach thinking, IGEL Now &amp; Next 2026 offers a compelling opportunity to see prevention-first architecture in action. The conference runs March 30 through April 2 at the Fontainebleau Miami Beach, with a packed agenda covering zero trust, identity, threat protection, and endpoint security.</p> <p>A session worth prioritizing is “<a href="https://igelevents.cventevents.com/event/cfc8811c-37e5-4bea-ab65-71b05569ca0a/agenda" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Zero Trust in Action – Partner Ecosystems Delivering Positive Outcomes</a>,” on Tuesday, March 31. It examines how IGEL’s partner ecosystems enable customers to translate zero-trust principles into measurable, real-world outcomes. This is exactly the kind of practical insight that helps organizations break the detect-and-respond cycle for good.</p> <p>The conference also features a keynote from General (Ret.) Paul Nakasone, former Commander of U.S. Cyber Command and Director of the NSA, on national cyber resilience. It’s a powerful reminder that prevention-first endpoint strategy is no longer just an IT concern. It is also a business imperative.</p> <p><em>To learn how your organization can secure your endpoints with a preventive security architecture, </em><a href="https://www.igel.com/nowandnext/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><em>register for IGEL Now &amp; Next</em></a><em>, taking place March 30 – April 2, 2026, at the Fontainebleau Miami Beach. </em></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The endpoint RTO gap: Why your disaster recovery plan is incomplete]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136870/the-endpoint-rto-gap-why-your-disaster-recovery-plan-is-incomplete.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136870/the-endpoint-rto-gap-why-your-disaster-recovery-plan-is-incomplete.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Disaster recovery professionals have made incredible progress when it comes to recovering data centers and cloud infrastructure, with many organizations achieving recovery time objectives (RTOs) as short as 20 minutes for mission-critical workloads. But these impressive numbers mask a dangerous weakness. Endpoint recovery times can stretch into weeks or months, creating a business continuity gap that undermines even the most robust back-end recovery systems.</p> <p>“We find that disaster recovery frameworks rarely, if ever, mention the endpoints. Hitting an RTO of 20 minutes for your data center is great, but if all your endpoints still have red screens flashing and saying, ‘Give me bitcoin,’ then what’s the point?” says Jason Mafera, field CTO at IGEL Technology. “That’s a huge gap.”</p> <p>Organizations sometimes resort to scrambling to acquire replacement devices from nearby retail stores or pulling backup laptops from storage closets. This reactive response far exceeds data center RTOs and dramatically extends business disruption. Remote work compounds the challenge further, as recovery of distributed devices across home offices and remote locations adds logistical complexity that extends downtime even more.</p> <p>The traditional recovery approach carries another hidden risk: recompromising systems with the same vulnerabilities that enabled the initial breach. As organizations restore endpoints to their previous configurations, they may reintroduce the weaknesses attackers already exploited. If root causes haven’t been addressed, recovery simply resets the clock until the next incident.</p> <p>“The model of ‘monitor, detect, remediate, and patch over the cracks with a tool’ over and over is broken and unsustainable,” Mafera says. “Instead, endpoints should employ an architecture that takes a preventive security approach by design.”</p> <p>Effective endpoint-inclusive disaster recovery architecture requires that endpoints store no local data, preventing data from being lost or compromised during failures. The operating system should be immutable, stopping malware from making changes that could compromise the device and, consequently, other systems. Identity exists only as a temporary token, leaving no credentials to steal, and malware cannot compromise endpoints that are unable to execute arbitrary code. The principle of least privilege extends beyond network access to the operating system itself, transforming disaster recovery economics by replacing expensive backup endpoint inventories with resilient architectures that rarely fail and recover quickly when they do.</p> <p><strong>See it in action at IGEL Now &amp; Next 2026</strong></p> <p>For IT and security leaders looking to close the endpoint RTO gap, <a href="https://www.igel.com/nowandnext/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">IGEL Now &amp; Next 2026</a> is the place to see these solutions in practice. The conference runs March 30 through April 2 at the Fontainebleau Miami Beach, and the agenda includes sessions that address endpoint continuity directly.</p> <p>For example, “<a href="https://igelevents.cventevents.com/event/cfc8811c-37e5-4bea-ab65-71b05569ca0a/agenda" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>How to Recover from Ransomware in Minutes with IGEL BC&amp;DR</strong></a>,” on Tuesday, March 31, explores how IGEL’s Dual Boot technology enables devices to run IGEL OS alongside Windows, giving IT teams flexible deployment options, extended device life, and instant recovery paths. As a result, organizations can balance cost, security, and user experience without disruption. It is precisely the kind of practical, architecture-first thinking that can finally bring endpoint RTOs in line with the rest of the business continuity stack.</p> <p><em>To learn how your organization can secure your endpoints with a preventive security architecture, </em><a href="https://www.igel.com/nowandnext/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><em>register for IGEL Now &amp; Next</em></a><em>, taking place March 30 – April 2, 2026, at the Fontainebleau Miami Beach. </em></p> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[SASE and SSE have a vulnerable blind spot: The endpoint]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136863/sase-and-sse-have-a-vulnerable-blind-spot-the-endpoint.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136863/sase-and-sse-have-a-vulnerable-blind-spot-the-endpoint.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Enterprises investing millions in Secure Service Edge (SSE) and Secure Access Service Edge (SASE) architectures face an uncomfortable reality. Although these solutions excel at securing network traffic and application access, they offer little protection against threats that originate directly on endpoint devices.</p> <p>The statistics are sobering. Microsoft found that <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/security-insider/threat-landscape/microsoft-digital-defense-report-2023" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">up to 90% of ransomware attacks originate from unmanaged devices</a>. And according to <a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/T815/reports/2025-dbir-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Verizon’s 2025 Data Breach Investigations Report</a>, 60% of attacks involve a human element and the majority of those involve credential abuse (32%), social actions (23%), or interactions with malware (7%). </p> <p>Traditional endpoints are ideal attack vectors because, as all-purpose tools, they run heavy operating systems with local admin rights, writable partitions, and stored credentials. These characteristics create attack surfaces that sophisticated threat actors readily exploit. And as remote work has become commonplace, the difficulty of managing and securing far-flung endpoints outside the firewall has increased.</p> <p>Even with stolen credentials obtained through phishing, attackers can compromise systems before SASE controls ever engage. Multifactor authentication helps, but it is not foolproof when the endpoint itself is compromised. The endpoint is the critical battleground that SSE and SASE solutions simply cannot address.</p> <p>Forward-thinking organizations are closing this gap with preventive endpoint security architectures. Rather than layering additional detection tools onto vulnerable platforms, they are fundamentally reimagining what an endpoint should be.</p> <p>“In this new endpoint security architecture, there’s no local data written to the device, which has a read-only, immutable OS so bad actors can’t make changes,” says Jason Mafera, field CTO at IGEL Technology. “It has hardware-rooted trust, so it’s utilizing hardware security capabilities, and every aspect of the boot system is cryptographically secured modules.”</p> <p>Identity management shifts dramatically in these environments. Instead of being in user accounts with stored credentials, identity exists as tokens. When a session ends, nothing remains on the device that can be stolen or exploited. Organizations can enforce policies requiring connection only from secure endpoints, adding a critical enforcement layer to zero trust architectures.</p> <p>The shift requires rethinking traditional endpoint management. Secure endpoints deploy only what users need. Applications come from attested sources, installed by administrators rather than end users. Supply chain attacks become exponentially harder when endpoints cannot execute arbitrary code.</p> <p><strong>Explore these challenges at IGEL Now &amp; Next 2026</strong></p> <p>For security and IT leaders who want to move from theory to practice on endpoint security, <a href="https://www.igel.com/nowandnext/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">IGEL Now &amp; Next 2026</a> offers an ideal forum. The conference runs March 30 through April 2 at the Fontainebleau Miami Beach, and sessions directly address the SSE and SASE endpoint gap.<br></p> <p>For example, “<a href="https://igelevents.cventevents.com/event/cfc8811c-37e5-4bea-ab65-71b05569ca0a/agenda" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">From Pocket to Perimeter: Accelerating DoW Zero Trust Readiness with IGEL, Cisco, and Asc3nd</a>,” on March 31, explores how the U.S. Department of War transformed standard devices into mission-ready endpoints within a comply-to-connect and zero trust framework. Through standards-based automation, policy-driven orchestration, and endpoint immutability, the team delivered a secure enclave that can pass the most rigorous C2C posture checks while simplifying operations and extending hardware life cycles.</p> <p>The conference also features a keynote from General (Ret.) Paul Nakasone, former Commander of U.S. Cyber Command and Director of the NSA, on national cyber resilience, which is a timely reminder that endpoint strategy has become inseparable from organizational and national security strategy. Only by addressing endpoint security as rigorously as they address network security can enterprises fully realize the value of their SSE and SASE investments. Now &amp; Next 2026 is where those conversations are happening. </p> <p><em>To learn how your organization can secure your endpoints with a preventive security architecture, </em><a href="https://www.igel.com/nowandnext/" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><em>register for IGEL Now &amp; Next</em></a><em>, taking place March 30 – April 2, 2026, at the Fontainebleau Miami Beach. </em></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Strategically Building The Future Of AI With Value: Meet Kevin A. Ogunsua, Principal Analyst For AI Strategy And Value]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/strategically-building-the-future-of-ai-with-value-meet-kevin-a-ogunsua-principal-analyst-for-ai-strategy-and-value/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/strategically-building-the-future-of-ai-with-value-meet-kevin-a-ogunsua-principal-analyst-for-ai-strategy-and-value/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Some people see big rocks as obstacles. I move them, work around them, or build on them. I grew up on a university campus where curiosity wasn’t just encouraged but was ambient. My father was a professor. My mother was both a teacher and a tailor. At home, ideas were debated, patterns were studied, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[ZohoDay 2026: One Stack, More Stakes]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/zohoday-2026-one-stack-more-stakes/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/zohoday-2026-one-stack-more-stakes/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Last week, software provider Zoho hosted its annual ZohoDay analyst event, with several Forrester analysts in attendance. Zoho celebrates its 30th anniversary in 2026 and announced some milestones in its opening session: 1 million customer organizations, 150 million users globally, 19,000 employees globally, and over 60 apps across multiple technology markets. Zoho continues to see [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Apple Researchers Introduce Ferret-UI Lite, an On-Device AI Model for Seeing and Controlling UIs]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/apple-ferret-ui-lite-on-device/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/apple-ferret-ui-lite-on-device/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/apple-ferret-ui-lite-on-device/en/headerimage/apple-ferret-ui-lite-1771958980595.jpeg"/><p>Apple's Ferret-UI Lite is a 3B-parameter model optimized for mobile and desktop screens, designed to interpret screen images, understand UI elements such as icons and text, and interact with apps by, e.g., reading messages, checking health data, and more.</p> <i>By Sergio De Simone</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[SAP: Latest news and insights]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/3487010/sap-latest-news-and-insights.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/3487010/sap-latest-news-and-insights.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>SAP (<a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/SAP/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">NYSE:SAP</a>) is an enterprise software vendor based in Walldorf, Germany. Its cloud and on-premises <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272362/what-is-erp-key-features-of-top-enterprise-resource-planning-systems.html">enterprise resource planning (ERP)</a> software, including S/4HANA, helps organizations manage their business operations and customer relations. The German multinational also offers a vast array of software solutions tailored to specific facets of the enterprise, including data management, analytics, and <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272353/what-is-supply-chain-management-mastering-logistics-end-to-end.html">supply chain management</a>, as well as solutions aimed at specific industry verticals.</p> <p>AI is an area of increasing emphasis for SAP, which has a market cap of $325 billion, making it the <a href="https://companiesmarketcap.com/tech/largest-tech-companies-by-market-cap/" rel="nofollow">13th largest technology vendor</a> in the world.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="latest-sap-news-and-analysis">Latest SAP news and analysis</h2> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-migrations-often-fail-during-planning-phase">SAP migrations often fail during planning phase</h3> <p><em>February 24, 2026</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4130935/sap-migrations-often-fail-at-the-planning-stage.html">Most SAP migrations fail before implementation begins</a>. This is the conclusion of the “The State of SAP Migrations” from ISG, a technology research and advisory firm that surveyed more than 200 business and IT decision-makers from large, international companies with over 1,000 employees.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-emarsys-is-dead-long-live-sap-engagement-cloud">SAP Emarsys is dead, long live SAP Engagement Cloud</h3> <p><em>February 20, 2026</em>: SAP has changed the name of its SAP Emarsys customer experience <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4135328/sap-emarsys-is-dead-long-live-sap-engagement-cloud.html">offering to SAP Engagement Cloud</a>, signalling — at last — its commitment to integrating it into the core of its enterprise infrastructure.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-tosses-some-compatibility-pack-users-a-short-lifeline">SAP tosses some Compatibility Pack users a (short) lifeline</h3> <p><em>January 8, 2026</em>: SAP is throwing a lifeline to customers who are running late on <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4114415/sap-tosses-some-compatibility-pack-users-a-short-lifeline.html">their transition from S/4HANA Compatibility Packs</a> in their data centers. Although usage rights were set to expire at the end of 2025 for most users, SAP has announced a “final” five-month transition period for customers.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-employees-trust-in-leadership-has-diminished-since-the-restructuring">SAP employees’ trust in leadership has diminished since the restructuring</h3> <p><em>December 3, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4100056/sap-employees-trust-in-leadership-has-diminished-since-the-restructuring.html">SAP’s restructuring </a>may have been good for its bottom line, but behind the scenes, it has backfired. The company did what it promised, said Greyhound Research chief analyst Sanchit Vir Gogia. But, he said, “Numbers only tell half the story. Inside the organization, something broke.”</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-touts-microsoft-disaster-recovery-plan-for-europe-analysts-doubt-it-will-work">SAP touts Microsoft disaster recovery plan for Europe; Analysts doubt it will work</h3> <p><em>November 19 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4093483/sap-touts-microsoft-disaster-recovery-plan-for-europe-analysts-doubt-it-will-work-2.html">SAP has cut European deals with Microsoft</a>, Capgemini, and Orange to ostensibly deliver an emergency disaster recovery failover if Microsoft is legally blocked from delivering European services. </p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-to-offer-concessions-to-the-eu-over-antitrust-probe-into-erp-support-practices">SAP to offer concessions to the EU over antitrust probe into ERP support practices</h3> <p>November 7, 2025: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4086612/sap-to-offer-concessions-to-the-eu-over-antitrust-probe-into-erp-support-practices.html">SAP will submit concessions to the European Commission</a> to settle an antitrust investigation into its software licensing and maintenance practices.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="five-takeaways-from-sap-teched-berlin">Five takeaways from SAP TechEd Berlin</h3> <p><em>November 6, 2025</em>: SAP’s TechEd conference this week offered a few surprises, but its focus, predictably, could be spelled in two letters: AI. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4085716/five-takeaways-from-sap-teched-berlin.html">Artificial intelligence was everywhere</a>, as the more than 2,800 in-person delegates and the 20,000-plus online attendees quickly discovered. </p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-shakes-up-its-certification-process">SAP shakes up its certification process</h3> <p><em>November 4, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4084349/sap-shakes-up-its-certification-process.html">SAP is overhauling how IT pros earn certifications </a>in its technologies — with the aim of better aligning credential evaluation with the way IT pros work with SAP products in real-world settings.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-customers-not-sold-on-s-4hana-roi">SAP customers not sold on S/4HANA ROI</h3> <p>November 4, 2025: A huge percentage of <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4082285/sap-customers-not-sold-on-s-4hana-roi.html">SAP customers are wary about the company’s efforts</a> to move its customers away from perpetual licenses to subscription pricing, with most worried about future pricing increases, according to a recent survey.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-and-snowflake-add-zero-copy-sharing-between-their-systems">SAP and Snowflake add zero-copy sharing between their systems</h3> <p><em>November 5, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4085019/sap-and-snowflake-add-zero-copy-sharing-between-their-systems.html">SAP and Snowflake are collaborating </a>to extend SAP Business Data Cloud (BDC) with Snowflake’s data and AI platform, they announced Tuesday at SAP TechEd in Berlin.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="us-supreme-court-rejects-sap-appeal-paving-the-way-for-teradata-antitrust-trial">US Supreme Court rejects SAP appeal, paving the way for Teradata antitrust trial</h3> <p>October 7, 2025: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4068697/us-supreme-court-rejects-sap-appeal-paving-the-way-for-teradata-antitrust-trial.html">The US Supreme Court declined to hear SAP’s appeal </a>in an antitrust case brought by Teradata, allowing the data analytics firm to move forward with claims that the German software maker illegally tied its enterprise applications to its own database technology.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-sets-timeline-to-replace-successfactors-recruiting-module-with-smartrecruiters">SAP sets timeline to replace SuccessFactors recruiting module with SmartRecruiters</h3> <p><em>October 6, 2025</em>: Now that <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4068172/sap-sets-timeline-to-replace-successfactors-recruiting-module-with-smartrecruiters.html">SAP has completed its acquisition of SmartRecruiters</a>, executives are talking about their plans to replace the recruiting module of SuccessFactors, SAP’s cloud-based HR management tool.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="saps-role-aware-joule-assistants-will-partner-with-workers">SAP’s role-aware Joule Assistants will partner with workers</h3> <p><em>October 6, 2025</em>: SAP is rolling out new role-aware Joule Assistants, department-specific clouds, and tools for finance, HR, and supply chain professionals at SAP Connect, its new event for line-of-business leaders. The <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4068160/saps-role-aware-joule-assistants-will-partner-with-workers.html">AI assistants are designed to partner with human workers</a> while managing and orchestrating agents across SAP Business Suite. </p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-targeted-by-eu-antitrust-investigation-of-its-erp-support-services">SAP targeted by EU antitrust investigation of its ERP support services</h3> <p><em>September 25, 2025:</em> SAP’s software support and maintenance services are the target of an antitrust investigation by the European Commission, which is concerned that the company forces customers to buy its services for longer, and for more licenses, than they need. The Commission, which enforces antitrust policy in the European Union, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4063210/sap-targeted-by-eu-antitrust-investigation-of-its-erp-support-services.html">opened a formal investigation</a> into the ways that SAP limits customers’ choices on where and when to buy maintenance and support services for its software.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="amazon-and-sap-partner-on-european-data-sovereignty-platforms-to-offer-better-oversight">Amazon and SAP partner on European data sovereignty platforms to offer better oversight</h3> <p><em>September 24, 2025:</em> Amazon’s AWS European Sovereign Cloud, set to launch in Germany by the end of 2025, is starting to take shape with the <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4062662/amazon-and-sap-partner-on-european-data-sovereignty-platforms-to-offer-better-oversight.html">announcement of SAP’s Sovereign Cloud as its latest partner</a>. The announcement is part of a gradual expansion of the capabilities on offer to organizations looking to invest in the concept of sovereign clouds to meet the challenges posed by AI expansion.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-offers-concessions-to-eu-regulators-to-avert-an-antitrust-probe">SAP offers concessions to EU regulators to avert an antitrust probe</h3> <p><em>September 23, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4061608/sap-offers-concessions-to-eu-regulators-to-avert-an-antitrust-probe-into-erp-practices.html">SAP has reportedly submitted concessions to the European Commission</a>, aimed at resolving antitrust concerns related to its ERP software business practices. The move represents a preemptive effort to avoid a formal investigation that could result in fines of up to 10% of its annual global revenue.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-user-group-calls-for-licensing-clarity">SAP user group calls for licensing clarity</h3> <p><em>September 17, 2025: </em>SAP’s licensing policies are top of mind at the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4058824/sap-user-group-calls-for-licensing-clarity.html">conference of the German-speaking SAP User Group</a> (DSAG) this week. While the cloud is the right way forward, DSAG members need transparency from SAP to allow them to make the move, DSAG chairman Jens Hungershausen said in a pre-event post.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-change-management-still-challenges-enterprises">SAP change management still challenges enterprises</h3> <p><em>September 9, 2025:</em> SAP managers are <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4053731/sap-change-management-still-challenges-enterprises.html">under pressure to speed up change</a> and delivery of return on investment, and some are seeking AI’s help with that, according to the <em>SAP Change Management Index 2025</em>. The survey, commissioned by Basis Technologies, found that 48% of respondents are facing pressure to implement changes more quickly, and 41% to deliver faster return on investment.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-data-sovereignty-service-lets-customers-run-cloud-workloads-inside-their-data-centers">SAP data sovereignty service lets customers run cloud workloads inside their data centers</h3> <p><em>September 2, 2025</em>: <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/4050008/sap-data-sovereignty-service-lets-customers-run-cloud-workloads-inside-their-data-centers.html">SAP Sovereign Cloud On-Site</a> is a new service launched in conjunction with the <a href="https://news.sap.com/2025/09/sap-deepens-european-cloud-sovereignty-offering-unlock-regional-ai-innovation/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">announcement</a> of the global availability of the company’s Sovereign Cloud platform. In practice, this will mean local SAP or SAP certified personnel will manage SAP Sovereign Cloud On-Site workloads in a data center approved by the customer.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="three-critical-patches-for-sap">Three critical patches for SAP</h3> <p><em>August 12, 2025: </em>For its August Patch Tuesday, SAP released <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4038608/august-patch-tuesday-authentication-hole-in-windows-server-2025-now-has-a-fix.html">a series of patches</a>, including three for critical vulnerabilities that each ranked 9.9 on the CVSS scoring scale.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-to-acquire-smartrecruiters-to-enhance-its-successfactors-hcm-suite">SAP to acquire SmartRecruiters to enhance its SuccessFactors HCM suite</h3> <p><em>August 1, 2025</em>: SAP announced it has agreed to<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4032993/sap-to-acquire-smartrecruiters-to-enhance-its-successfactors-hcm-suite.html"> acquire AI-powered talent acquisition firm SmartRecruiters</a> to bolster its SuccessFactors human capital management (HCM) suite.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-seeks-to-cut-80-of-your-data-management-work">SAP seeks to cut 80% of your data management work</h3> <p><em>July 15, 2025: </em>According to Irfan Khan, Chief Product Officer and President of SAP Data &amp; Analytics, the strength of the company’s Business Data Cloud platform is that it can automatically align and synchronize various data sources without ETL or data pipeline management. This will allow customers to reduce the collection, refinement, and quality control tasks that typically account for more than <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4022697/data-is-at-the-center-of-ai-transformation-sap-presents-next-generation-business-infrastructure-with-bdcs.html">80% of the overall data management function</a>, and instead focus more time on AI model training and application, he said.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="us-judge-issues-split-decision-in-antitrust-case-against-sap">US judge issues split decision in antitrust case against SAP</h3> <p><em>July 2, 2025: </em>The judge allowed parts of the case to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4016013/us-judge-issues-split-decision-in-antitrust-case-against-sap.html">proceed to trial</a>, but pushed back against accusations that SAP was inappropriately denying a rival access to customer data.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="saps-rise-rebrand-conceals-cost-changes">SAP’s Rise rebrand conceals cost changes</h3> <p><em>Jun 27, 2025:</em> <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4014135/saps-rise-rebrand-conceals-cost-changes.html" target="_blank">Licensing changes in the wake of SAP’s rebranding</a> of Rise with SAP Premium as Cloud ERP Private could increase costs for CIOs not paying attention to the minutiae of their ERP and AI usage.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-gui-flaws-expose-sensitive-data-via-weak-or-no-encryption">SAP GUI flaws expose sensitive data via weak or no encryption</h3> <p><em>Jun 25, 2025:</em> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4012446/sap-gui-flaws-expose-sensitive-data-via-weak-or-no-encryption.html">Newly disclosed vulnerabilities</a> in SAP GUI for Windows and Java store user data with outdated or no encryption, posing compliance and breach risks for enterprises.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-ibm-slammed-for-role-in-quebec-auto-insurance-board-erp-overhaul-fiasco">SAP, IBM slammed for role in Quebec auto insurance board ERP overhaul fiasco</h3> <p><em>Jun 18, 2025:</em> Investigations into a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4009449/sap-ibm-slammed-for-role-in-quebec-auto-insurance-board-erp-overhaul-fiasco.html">controversial Canadian ERP implementation</a> involving SAP SE and LGS, an IBM subsidiary, took a bizarre turn when the Quebec anti-corruption squad conducted raids at the headquarters of the organization which commissioned the system overhaul.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="upgrade-or-else-sap-warns-as-end-of-s-4hana-compatibility-pack-licensing-nears">Upgrade or else, SAP warns as end of S/4HANA Compatibility Pack licensing nears</h3> <p><em>Jun 4, 2025: </em>SAP S/4HANA customers who rely on functionality in Compatibility Packs have just a few months to transition to native capabilities as the termination of licenses for the decade-old packs looms. The company has imposed a <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4001658/upgrade-or-else-sap-warns-as-end-of-s-4hana-compatibility-pack-licensing-nears.html">hard deadline of December 31, 2025</a>, for most customers to stop using the packs, and will treat their use after that as “commercial non-compliance — a breach of contract.”</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="nearly-half-of-sap-ecc-customers-may-stick-with-legacy-erp-beyond-2027">Nearly half of SAP ECC customers may stick with legacy ERP beyond 2027</h3> <p><em>June 4, 2025: </em>At the end of 2024, only 39%, or about 14,000, of the 35,000 SAP ECC customers had migrated to S/4HANA, according to Gartner. At the current rate of migration, Gartner projects there will still be 17,000 holdouts, or <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4000543/nearly-half-of-sap-ecc-customers-may-stick-with-legacy-erp-beyond-2027.html">nearly half of the ECC customer base</a>, by 2027.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-teams-up-with-alibaba-to-host-cloud-erp-workloads-in-china">SAP teams up with Alibaba to host Cloud ERP workloads in China</h3> <p><em>May 28, 2025: </em>Alibaba Group, the Chinese e-commerce giant and cloud computing infrastructure provider, is adopting SAP’s Cloud ERP Private for its own enterprise infrastructure, and the companies plan to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3997033/sap-teams-up-with-alibaba-to-host-cloud-erp-workloads-in-china.html">jointly sell their services</a>.<br></p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-and-aws-launch-co-innovation-program-to-accelerate-enterprise-ai-adoption">SAP and AWS launch co-innovation program to accelerate enterprise AI adoption</h3> <p><em>May 22, 2025: </em>SAP and Amazon Web Services have launched an <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3993205/sap-and-aws-launch-co-innovation-program-to-accelerate-enterprise-ai-adoption.html">AI Co-Innovation Program</a>, offering dedicated technical resources and cloud credits to help enterprises embed AWS generative AI tools into their ERP systems.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-wants-to-make-ai-ubiquitous-just-dont-ask-about-s-4hana">SAP wants to make AI ubiquitous — just don’t ask about S/4HANA</h3> <p><em>May 22, 2025:</em> For all the talk of marrying SAP’s core business suite with emerging AI power, conspicuously absent from this year’s Sapphire was any talk about the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3992712/sap-wants-to-make-ai-ubiquitous.html">state of S/4HANA</a>, the adoption of which appears to be lagging desired levels at this time.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ibms-massive-sap-s-4hana-migration-pays-off">IBM’s massive SAP S/4HANA migration pays off</h3> <p><em>May 21, 2025:</em> Ann Funai, CIO and vice president of IBM’s Business Platform Transformation, says IBM achieved a 30% reduction in infrastructure-related operational costs since completing its <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3988351/ibms-massive-sap-s-4hana-migration-pays-off.html">migration to SAP’s cloud ERP platform</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-revamps-its-cloud-erp-application-packages">SAP revamps its cloud ERP application packages</h3> <p><em>May 20, 2025: </em>SAP is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3990475/sap-revamps-its-cloud-erp-application-packages.html">repackaging its cloud ERP applications</a> to make it easier for new customers to buy into its ecosystem, and adding AI-based product enhancements for its existing customers.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-goes-all-in-on-agentic-ai-at-sap-sapphire">SAP goes all-in on agentic AI at SAP Sapphire</h3> <p><em>May 20, 2025: </em>At its annual SAP Sapphire conference in Orlando, Florida, the ERP software titan debuted <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3990312/sap-goes-all-in-on-agentic-ai-at-sap-sapphire.html">a slew of new innovations</a>, including AI Foundation, which it calls the AI operating system for SAP business AI, as well as new AI agents across the SAP Business Suite, and an omnipresent Joule copilot that’ll accompany and support users as they move across applications. </p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-road-to-s-4hana-how-cios-are-managing-sap-eccs-end-of-support">The road to S/4HANA: How CIOs are managing SAP ECC’s end of support</h3> <p><em>May 19, 2025: </em>With the deadline for <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3982596/the-road-to-s-4hana-how-cios-are-managing-sap-eccs-end-of-support.html">SAP ECC end of support nearing</a>, CIOs face major decisions, and likely headaches, as they consider whether and how to transform their core ERP systems for a new era.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-netweaver-customers-urged-to-deploy-patch-for-critical-zero-day-vulnerability">SAP NetWeaver customers urged to deploy patch for critical zero-day vulnerability</h3> <p><em>April 25, 2025: </em>The <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3971211/sap-netweaver-customers-urged-to-deploy-patch-for-critical-zero-day-vulnerability.html">unrestricted file upload flaw is likely being exploited</a> by an initial access broker to deploy JSP web shells that grant full access to servers and allow installing additional malware payloads.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="has-oracle-knocked-sap-off-the-erp-throne">Has Oracle knocked SAP off the ERP throne?</h3> <p><em>April 23, 2025: </em>A new study estimates that Oracle became the leading provider of ERP applications in 2024, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3968728/oracle-knocks-sap-off-the-erp-throne.html">stealing a position that SAP had held</a> since the early 1980s.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-defies-the-economic-downturn">SAP defies the economic downturn</h3> <p><em>April 23, 2025: </em>Despite all the economic turbulence, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3968094/sap-defies-the-economic-downturn.html">SAP made a solid start to the new year</a>: Sales and profit are up significantly compared to the same quarter last year.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-customers-on-business-suite-new-strategy-same-old-concerns">SAP customers on Business Suite: New strategy, same old concerns</h3> <p><em>April 10, 2025: </em>Once again, SAP customers must grapple with a new SAP strategy. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3958755/sap-customers-demand-clarity-new-strategy-old-worries.html">Their demands for ‘Business Unleashed’ are familiar</a>: more clarity and consistency, better integration, accessibility for all.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-is-s-4hana-saps-latest-erp-system-explained">What is S/4HANA? SAP’s latest ERP system explained</h3> <p><em>April 2, 2025:</em> S/4HANA can realign and transform business models and processes. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3952085/what-is-s-4hana.html">Here’s what you need to know</a> about SAP’s flagship enterprise resource planning (ERP) system.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-adoption-surges-in-europe-as-enterprises-embrace-cloud">SAP adoption surges in Europe as enterprises embrace cloud</h3> <p><em>March 26, 2025: </em>About 40% of companies in the DACH region are increasing their overall IT budgets, while <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3854348/sap-adoption-surges-in-europe-as-enterprises-embrace-cloud.html">SAP-specific investments are on the rise for 47% of enterprises</a>, according to a German SAP user group.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-customers-struggle-with-s-4hana-migration">SAP customers struggle with S/4HANA migration</h3> <p><em>March 24, 2025:</em> According to a recent Horváth study, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3851772/sap-users-struggle-with-s4-hana-migration.html">more than 60% of companies experience deviations</a> in budget, schedule, and result quality during S/4HANA migration.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-ceo-christian-klein-predicts-manual-data-entry-will-disappear-from-sap-by-2027">SAP CEO Christian Klein predicts manual data entry will disappear from SAP by 2027</h3> <p><em>March 20, 2025: </em>Celebrating the software giant’s 30th anniversary in Korea, Klein announced plans to extend SAP’s AI assistant to the Korean market with <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3850705/sap-ceo-christian-klein-ai-transformation-in-korean-enterprises-will-be-driven-by-business-data-cloud-and-jules.html">bold pronouncements about user productivity</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-introduces-joule-for-developers">SAP introduces Joule for Developers</h3> <p><em>Mar 19, 2025: </em>SAP has added AI capabilities powered by its AI assistant, Joule, to SAP Build Process Automation and SAP Build apps, <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3849011/sap-introduces-joule-for-developers.html">extending the existing AI capabilities</a> in SAP Build Code and ABAP Cloud.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="celonis-sues-sap-for-anti-competitive-data-access-practices">Celonis sues SAP for anti-competitive data access practices</h3> <p><em>Mar 17, 2025:</em> The German startup Celonis has accused the software giant of abusing its market power to hinder competition — in particular, to give its own processing mining solution preferential treatment over third-party offerings.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-patches-severe-vulnerabilities-in-netweaver-and-commerce-apps">SAP patches severe vulnerabilities in NetWeaver and Commerce apps</h3> <p><em>March 12, 2025:</em> The enterprise software vendor <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3844292/sap-patches-severe-vulnerabilities-in-netweaver-and-commerce-apps.html">bundled 25 security patches into its March update</a>, addressing flaws that impact middleware, interfaces, custom apps, and more.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-taps-splunks-simon-davies-to-lead-reorgd-apac-region">SAP taps Splunk’s Simon Davies to lead reorg’d APAC region</h3> <p><em>February 19, 2025:</em> Paul Marriott <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3828602/sap-appoints-simon-davis-as-executive-chairman-apac.html">passes the helm to the former Splunk exec</a> who had previous stints with Salesforce and Microsoft in the region.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-aims-to-unify-data-for-ai-analytics-with-new-business-data-cloud">SAP aims to unify data for AI, analytics with new Business Data Cloud</h3> <p><em>February 13, 2025:</em> With its new Business Data Cloud, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3823989/sap-aims-to-unify-data-for-ai-analytics-with-new-business-data-cloud.html">SAP wants to help enterprises unify data</a> held in its own systems with that in other vendors’ applications: It’s goal is to expedite advanced analytics and AI use cases.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-builds-new-business-suite-in-the-cloud">SAP builds new business suite in the cloud</h3> <p><em>February 13, 2025:</em> SAP is taking more control: From the new Business Suite to the Business Data Cloud and the AI apps, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3823972/sap-builds-new-business-suite-in-the-cloud.html">everything is to be pre-configured in the cloud</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-throws-a-lifeline-to-large-organizations-with-new-ecc-offering">SAP throws a lifeline to large organizations with new ECC offering</h3> <p><em>February 4, 2025:</em> Scheduled for release in 2028, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3816887/sap-throws-a-lifeline-to-large-organizations-with-new-ecc-offering.html">SAP’s new ECC offering</a> will, says analyst, reduce risks, security vulnerabilities, and compliance challenges tied to outdated systems.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-restructures-board-to-emphasize-ai-first-suite-first-strategy">SAP restructures board to emphasize AI-first, suite-first strategy</h3> <p><em>January 29, 2025:</em> SAP is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3811902/sap-reorganizes-executive-board.html">expanding its Executive Board</a> to include the Strategy &amp; Operations division and is appointing an expanded Executive Board consisting of eight additional managers.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-to-give-on-prem-customers-three-year-reprieve-with-a-catch">SAP to give on-prem customers three-year reprieve — with a catch</h3> <p><em>January 27, 2025</em>: Since many migrations to S/4HANA are still stalled, SAP apparently wants to give its customers <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3809226/deadline-for-sap-users.html">more time to make the switch</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="ibm-offers-sap-on-power-users-a-new-way-into-the-cloud">IBM offers SAP-on-Power users a new way into the cloud</h3> <p><em>January 7, 2025: </em>Enterprises running S/4HANA on IBM Power Systems will soon have <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3633218/launch-of-joint-sap-ibm-offering-set-for-q2.html">access to SAP’s RISE managed application offering</a>, which has previously focused on those running the ERP suite on x86 servers.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-customers-still-slow-to-deploy-ai-broadly">SAP customers still slow to deploy AI broadly</h3> <p><em>December 23, 2024</em>: Organizations are interested in leveraging AI to optimize internal processes and analyze data for insights, but <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3629821/sap-customers-still-slow-to-deploy-ai-broadly.html">security, data quality, and governance remain hurdles</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-systems-increasingly-targeted-by-cyber-attackers">SAP systems increasingly targeted by cyber attackers</h3> <p><em>December 13, 2024</em>: A review of four years of threat intelligence data, presented Friday at Black Hat by Yvan Genuer, a senior security researcher at Onapsis, reports a spike in <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3624464/researchers-expose-a-surge-in-hacker-interest-in-sap-systems.html">hacker interest in breaking into SAP ERP systems</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="nearly-25-of-sap-ecc-customers-unsure-about-their-future">Nearly 25% of SAP ECC customers unsure about their future</h3> <p><em>December 6, 2024: </em>The future of SAP architectures is hybrid. But according to a survey conducted by the Financials subgroup of the German-speaking SAP User Group (DSAG), where exactly the journey will go <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3618284/nearly-25-of-sap-ecc-customers-unsure-about-their-future.html">has not yet been decided for many organizations</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-ups-ai-factor-in-its-successfactors-hcm-suite">SAP ups AI factor in its SuccessFactors HCM suite</h3> <p><em>October 28, 2024: </em>The launch by SAP of <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3593358/sap-ups-ai-factor-in-its-successfactors-hcm-suite.html">new AI capabilities in its SuccessFactors HCM (human capital management)</a> suite Monday is a case of “better late to the party than never,” according to an analyst with Info-Tech Research Group.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="riled-by-saps-ai-policy-customers-issue-list-of-demands">Riled by SAP’s AI policy, customers issue list of demands</h3> <p><em>October 22, 2024</em>: SAP’s strategy of offering <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2520751/sap-security-holes-raise-questions-about-the-rush-to-ai.html">AI innovations </a>only in the cloud continues to attract a lot of criticism from its user base. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3570926/riled-by-saps-ai-policy-customers-issue-list-of-demands.html">Here’s what SAP customers would like to see happen</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-good-figures-but-bad-mood">SAP: good figures, but bad mood</h3> <p><em>October 22, 2024</em>: Employee engagement is suffering from the ongoing restructuring at SAP, although the software company reported good figures and has raised its outlook.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-sustainability-tracking-rollout-focuses-on-data-consistency-outlier-detection">SAP sustainability tracking rollout focuses on data consistency, outlier detection</h3> <p><em>October 21, 2024</em>: Enterprise CIOs are under increasing pressure from global regulators to rein in sustainability shortfalls due to partner problems. SAP’s pitch is that most enterprise partners are already using SAP, so it’s in an <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3575293/sap-sustainability-tracking-rollout-focuses-on-data-consistency-outlier-detection.html">ideal position to collect and distribute partner data</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-joins-the-ai-agent-era-but-not-all-customers-may-benefit">SAP joins the AI agent era — but not all customers may benefit</h3> <p><em>October 9, 2024</em>: SAP is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3552891/sap-joins-the-ai-agent-era-but-not-all-customers-may-benefit.html">expanding its generative AI copilot Joule</a> to include AI agents. Deeply embedded in SAP systems, the company’s agents aim to solve increasingly complex tasks.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-launches-collaborative-ai-agents-adds-knowledge-graph">SAP launches collaborative AI agents, adds Knowledge Graph</h3> <p><em>October 8, 2024</em>: SAP’s promised collaboration <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3551017/sap-launches-collaborative-ai-agents-adds-knowledge-graph.html">between its AI copilot, Joule, and other agents</a> will become reality in the fourth quarter of 2024, the company announced at its 2024 TechEd conference Tuesday.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-build-gains-ai-capabilities-to-help-build-autonomous-agents">SAP Build gains AI capabilities to help build autonomous agents</h3> <p><em>October 8, 2024</em>: SAP wants developers to view its <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3551049/sap-build-gains-ai-capabilities-to-help-build-autonomous-agents.html">Build platform</a> as the <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3551049/sap-build-gains-ai-capabilities-to-help-build-autonomous-agents.html">one extension solution for all of SAP’s applications</a>, according to Michael Aneling, chief product officer for SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP).</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-faces-probe-in-the-us-over-alleged-price-fixing-in-government-contracts">SAP faces probe in the US over alleged price fixing in government contracts</h3> <p><em>September 24, 2024</em>: German software giant SAP is under investigation by US officials for <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3539886/sap-faces-probe-in-the-us-over-alleged-price-fixing-in-government-contracts.html">allegedly conspiring to overcharge the US government</a> for its technology products over the course of a decade. The probe, led by the Department of Justice (DOJ), is focused on whether SAP and its reseller, Carahsoft Technology, colluded to fix prices on sales to the US military and other government entities</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-cto-to-step-down-after-inappropriate-behavior">SAP CTO to step down after ‘inappropriate behavior’</h3> <p><em>September 3, 2024</em>: Juergen Mueller is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3502096/sap-cto-to-step-down-after-inappropriate-behavior.html">leaving SAP’s executive board</a>, saying his behavior at a company event was incompatible with company values.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-partners-up-to-make-ai-more-practical">SAP partners up to make AI more practical</h3> <p><em>August 15, 2024:</em> Many companies find it difficult to incorporate AI into their business processes. To change this, SAP wants to <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3486992/sap-partners-up-to-make-ai-more-practical.html">work more closely with the appliedAI initiative</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-patches-critical-bugs-allowing-full-system-compromise">SAP patches critical bugs allowing full system compromise</h3> <p><em>August 14, 2024:</em> <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3486653/sap-patches-critical-bugs-allowing-full-system-compromise.html">Both the vulnerabilities</a> score above 9 on CVSS and can allow access to sensitive data if not patched immediately.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-is-restructuring-its-executive-board">SAP is restructuring its Executive Board</h3> <p><em>July 30, 2024:</em> Head of sales Scott Russell and head of marketing Julia White are <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3478950/sap-is-restructuring-its-executive-board.html">unexpectedly leaving SAP</a>; White will not be replaced.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-restructuring-to-impact-more-jobs-than-expected">SAP restructuring to impact more jobs than expected</h3> <p><em>July 24, 2024:</em> The restructuring at SAP affects <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3477211/sap-restructuring-to-impact-more-jobs-than-expected.html">almost a tenth of its workforce</a>. The company estimates the cost of the internal restructuring at around €3 billion.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-q2-results-reveal-large-orgs-now-firmly-on-the-path-to-ai">SAP Q2 results reveal large orgs now firmly on the path to AI</h3> <p><em>July 24, 2024:</em> <em>It “had a direct impact on our bookings,” company CEO says <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3476900/sap-q2-results-reveal-large-orgs-now-firmly-on-the-path-to-ai.html">during second quarter earnings call</a>.</em></p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-offers-ai-to-all-rise-customers-in-unknown-varying-amounts">SAP offers AI to all Rise customers — in unknown, varying amounts</h3> <p><em>July 19, 2024:</em> Joule AI is now available to all Rise with SAP customers, but <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2520882/sap-offers-ai-to-all-rise-with-sap-customers-in-varying-amounts.html">customers not using SAP Cloud solutions remain out of luck</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-security-holes-raise-questions-about-the-rush-to-ai">SAP security holes raise questions about the rush to AI</h3> <p><em>July 18, 2024:</em> Cloud security firm Wiz has published a detailed report about <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/2520751/sap-security-holes-raise-questions-about-the-rush-to-ai.html">SAP security holes</a>, now patched, that raises alarming questions about the secondary role AI efforts are having on cybersecurity defenses.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-publishes-open-source-manifesto">SAP publishes open source manifesto</h3> <p><em>June 27, 2024:</em> <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2506660/sap-publishes-open-source-manifesto.html">SAP has made five commitments</a> — make consistent contributions to the community, champion open standards, strive to adopt an open-first approach, nurture open source ecosystems, and adopt a feedback-driven approach.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-salesforce-lead-356-billion-enterprise-applications-market-idc">SAP, Salesforce lead $356 billion enterprise applications market: IDC</h3> <p><em>June 21, 2024: </em>The software giants <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2496985/sap-salesforce-lead-356-billion-enterprise-applications-market-idc.html">were neck-and-neck</a> as the overall enterprise software market grew 12% in 2023, said IDC.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-to-buy-digital-adoption-specialist-walkme-for-1-5-billion">SAP to buy digital adoption specialist WalkMe for $1.5 billion</h3> <p><em>June 5, 2024:</em> After Signavio and LeanIX, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2138640/sap-to-buy-digital-adoption-specialist-walkme-for-1-5-billion.html">SAP is acquiring the Israeli provider WalkMe</a> to help user companies with their digital transformation.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="sap-ceo-christian-klein-everything-we-do-contains-ai">SAP CEO Christian Klein: Everything we do contains AI</h3> <p><em>June 5, 2024:</em> SAP CEO Christian Klein <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2138837/sap-ceo-christian-klein-everything-we-do-contains-ai.html">kicked off the company’s Sapphire</a> customer conference with the promise of a real productivity boost from AI.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2138189/sap-adds-more-tools-for-developers-on-its-platform.html">SAP adds more tools for developers on its platform</a></h3> <p><em>June 4, 2024:</em> Behind the scenes, SAP is also using AI to extend the capabilities of its Business Technology Platform.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2138185/sap-embeds-joule-in-entire-enterprise-portfolio-plans-integration-to-other-ais.html">SAP embeds Joule in entire enterprise portfolio, plans integration to other AIs</a></h3> <p><em>June 4, 2024:</em> Joule could communicate with other AIs to complete more complex tasks spanning multiple applications, SAP suggests.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2130251/sap-ai-pact-with-aws-offers-customers-more-gen-ai-options.html">SAP AI pact with AWS offers customers more gen AI options</a></h3> <p><em>May 29, 2024:</em> SAP wants to work more closely with AWS on AI, complementing existing partnerships with Google and Microsoft.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2112245/asug-shift-to-s-4hana-and-ai-are-top-digital-transformation-drivers.html">SAP customers see S/4HANA and AI as top digital transformation drivers</a></h3> <p><em>May 20, 2024:</em> With SAP’s end of mainstream maintenance for SAP Business Suite 7 set for 2027, recent findings from the US SAP user group reveal that companies are increasing focus on shifting to S/4HANA and embracing AI.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2108373/hasso-plattner-stepping-down-signals-another-turning-point-at-sap.html">SAP faces turning point as Hasso Plattner steps down</a></h3> <p><em>May 15, 2024:</em> The departure of CEO Hasso Plattner marks the end of the founding era at SAP, and adds further complexities for the German software multinational as it faces ongoing restructuring efforts, among many other challenges to solve.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2098212/sap-forecasts-clarity-in-the-cloud.html">SAP forecasts clarity in the cloud</a></h3> <p><em>May 7, 2024:</em> After customers and user groups that adopted S/4HANA early accused SAP of bait-and-switch tactics, CIO editor-in-chief in Germany Martin Bayer recently sat with Christian Klein, CEO of the multinational software company, to clear the air on cloud reassurance, using gen AI as a migration accelerant, and positive growth for the future.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2073791/deutsche-telekom-calls-on-sap-for-rise-all-in-one-offer.html">Deutsche Telekom calls on SAP for IT infrastructure move to Rise</a></h3> <p><em>March 22, 2024:</em> <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2073791/deutsche-telekom-calls-on-sap-for-rise-all-in-one-offer.html">Deutsche Telekom will move its SAP infrastructure</a> to Rise with the help of its own IT services subsidiary, T-Systems.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2071481/sap-user-group-s-4hana-usage-is-growing-but-still-in-the-minority.html">SAP user group: S/4HANA usage is growing, but still in the minority</a></h3> <p><em>March 21, 2024:</em> Customers want more information about cloud and AI strategy from the German ERP giant.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2066529/sap-and-nvidia-expand-partnership-to-aid-customers-with-gen-ai.html">SAP and Nvidia expand partnership to aid customers with gen AI</a></h3> <p><em>March 18, 2024:</em> <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2066529/sap-and-nvidia-expand-partnership-to-aid-customers-with-gen-ai.html">SAP is embedding Nvidia’s generative AI foundry service</a> into SAP Datasphere, SAP BTP, RISE with SAP, and SAP’s enterprise applications portfolio to equip customers with greater and more simplified access to the technology.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1311738/sap-enhances-datasphere-and-sac-for-ai-driven-transformation.html">SAP enhances Datasphere and SAC for AI-driven transformation</a></h3> <p><em>March 6, 24:</em> SAP adds new generative AI and data governance features to SAP Datasphere and SAP Analytics Cloud, enabling customers to incorporate non-SAP and unstructured data when creating AI-based planning models and scenarios.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1308053/sap-names-philipp-herzig-as-chief-artificial-intelligence-officer.html">SAP names Philipp Herzig as chief artificial intelligence officer</a></h3> <p><em>February 16, 2024:</em> It’s a small promotion and a change of title for one man, and a sign of a larger change in strategic focus for many others at SAP.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1306745/sap-2024-outlook-5-predictions-for-customers.html">SAP 2024 outlook: 5 predictions for customers</a></h3> <p><em>February 12, 2024:</em> As SAP continues to position itself as a leader in generative AI and innovative technologies, customers must prepare to navigate new service offerings and an inevitable move to SAP RISE.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1306972/sap-has-a-new-succession-plan.html">SAP has a new succession plan</a></h3> <p><em>February 12, 2024:</em> SAP’s board wants to bring former Nokia chairman Pekka Ala-Pietilä on board to succeed founder Hasso Plattner as chairman.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1303774/sap-and-ibm-under-scanner-of-indian-investigative-agency-for-air-india-deal.html">SAP and IBM under scanner of Indian investigative agency for Air India deal</a></h3> <p><em>February 5, 2024:</em> <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1303774/sap-and-ibm-under-scanner-of-indian-investigative-agency-for-air-india-deal.html">Air India failed to adhere to the rules while awarding an ERP contract worth $27 million to SAP India and IBM India</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1302411/sap-offers-big-discount-to-lure-on-prem-s-4hana-customers-to-rise.html">SAP offers big discount to lure on-prem S/4HANA customers to Rise</a></h3> <p><em>January 30, 2024:</em> The restructuring at SAP affects almost a tenth of its workforce. The company estimates the cost of the internal restructuring at around €3 billion.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1297964/sap-announces-2-2b-restructuring-program-thatll-impact-8000-jobs.html">SAP announces $2.2B restructuring program that’ll impact 8,000 jobs</a></h3> <p><em>January 24, 2024:</em> The restructuring program will focus on AI and impact about 7.4% of SAP’s total workforce.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1289836/sap-doubles-down-on-cloud-first-innovation-with-executive-reshuffle.html">SAP doubles down on cloud-first innovation with executive reshuffle</a></h3> <p><em>January 10, 2024:</em> Product engineering head Thomas Saueressig will take on a new role to maximize potential for customers in the cloud, but that’s cold comfort for on-premises users.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1290288/sap-pays-multi-million-fine-for-bribery.html">SAP pays multi-million fine for bribery</a></h3> <p><em>January 11, 2024:</em> With a $220 million fine, SAP is drawing a line under a long-standing investigation by US authorities. The company is alleged to have bribed officials.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/1250898/sap-faces-breakdown-in-trust-over-innovation-plans.html">SAP faces breakdown in trust over innovation plans</a></h3> <p><em>December 5, 2023:</em> The company’s plan to offer future innovations in S/4HANA only to subscribers of its Rise with SAP offering is alienating customers, user conference hears.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/657687/sap-unveils-tools-to-help-enterprises-build-their-own-gen-ai-apps.html">SAP unveils tools to help enterprises build their own gen AI apps</a></h3> <p><em>November 1, 2023:</em> SAP Build Code suite combines new and existing developer tools, while a foundational AI model trained on anonymized customer data will be available to help automate tasks.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/655478/saps-new-generative-ai-pricing-neither-transparent-nor-explainable-yet.html">SAP’s new generative AI pricing: Neither transparent nor explainable yet</a></h3> <p><em>October 12, 2023:</em> The ERP vendor is adding a new pricing tier to its Rise with SAP offering with an opaque mix of bundled and usage-based pricing for generative AI functionality.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/655224/sap-offers-faster-updates-longer-maintenance-for-s-4hana-in-private-clouds.html">SAP offers faster updates, longer maintenance for S/4HANA in private clouds</a></h3> <p><em>October 11, 2023:</em> SAP is offering free migration consultations, more frequent feature releases and two years’ additional maintenance to entice customers to update to S/4HANA Cloud private edition and, ultimately, adopt Rise with SAP.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/653552/sap-prepares-to-add-joule-generative-ai-copilot-across-its-apps.html">SAP prepares to add Joule generative AI copilot across its apps</a></h3> <p><em>September 26, 2023:</em> Like Salesforce and ServiceNow, SAP is promising to embed an AI copilot throughout its applications, but planning a more gradual roll-out than some competitors.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Eye on Innovation: Advancing AI Maturity]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/eye-on-innovation-advancing-ai-maturity/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/eye-on-innovation-advancing-ai-maturity/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Planview's Chief Data Scientist, Dr. Rich Sonnenblick, explores why most AI pilots never scale, and how connected intelligence moves organizations from experiments to enterprise impact.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Thinking About DAM In 2026? Start Here]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/thinking-about-dam-in-2026-start-here/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/thinking-about-dam-in-2026-start-here/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Digital asset management has outgrown its role as a creative team repository. In 2026, richer content demands evolving AI strategies, and rising compute and storage costs are pushing DAM buyers to reassess their needs. This blog highlights three key takeaways from The Forrester Wave™: Digital Asset Management Systems, Q1 2026, to help organizations evaluate modern DAM solutions and prepare for enterprisewide content use.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[El CIO de dos empresas: la ideal y la real]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136653/el-cio-de-dos-empresas-la-ideal-y-la-real.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136653/el-cio-de-dos-empresas-la-ideal-y-la-real.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>El 28 de agosto de 2023, festivo en parte del Reino Unido y uno de los días más intensos del tráfico aéreo del verano, alrededor de 1.500 vuelos fueron cancelados. Aeropuertos colapsados, tripulaciones y aviones fuera de posición, pasajeros atrapados en conexiones imposibles por Europa, y un sector entero exigiendo respuestas. Aerolíneas como Ryanair elevaron la presión públicamente. La <a href="https://www.caa.co.uk/newsroom/news/aviation-regulator-publishes-independent-review-into-august-2023-nats-flight-planning-system-failure" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">autoridad regulatoria británica estimó después que el incidente impactó a más de 700.000 pasajeros</a>, con grandes costes para aerolíneas y aeropuertos. El detonante no fue una tormenta perfecta de eventos. El operador de control de tráfico NATS reveló que el incidente se originó por un plan de vuelo válido que incluía en su ruta dos <em>waypoints</em> o referencias de navegación fuera del Reino Unido que <a href="https://www.nats.aero/news/nats-report-into-air-traffic-control-incident-details-root-cause-and-solution-implemented" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">tenían el mismo nombre</a>.</p> <p>Eso disparó una <strong>excepción crítica</strong>, y tanto el sistema principal como el de respaldo entraron en un modo de seguridad (<strong>fail-safe</strong> en inglés) para evitar presentar información potencialmente incorrecta a los controladores. El resultado fue inmediato: restricción de tráfico y pérdida de automatización, pasando a gestión manual.</p> <p>En ese momento apareció la <strong>empresa real</strong>: la que no se ve en el comité, la que vive por debajo del PowerPoint y no capturan los KPI. En este incidente, lo que más tiempo consumió estaba fuera del guion: <strong>identificar el dato</strong> exacto, retirarlo de forma controlada y volver a operar con garantías.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="la-organizacion-quiere-ver-la-empresa-ideal">La organización quiere ver la empresa ideal</h2> <p>En muchas organizaciones operan <strong>dos empresas</strong> a la vez. Por un lado, la empresa <strong>ideal</strong>: la que se define por <em>roadmaps</em>, KPI y narrativas impecables. Por otro, la empresa <strong>real</strong>: la de las dependencias, integraciones frágiles y excepciones. Es menos visible, pero es la que decide cuando algo falla.</p> <p>El reto es que la organización quiere ver la empresa ideal, porque da <strong>sensación de control</strong> y facilita las decisiones. La empresa real, sin embargo, <strong>no es intuitiva</strong>: está distribuida, cambia con cada integración y no avisa cuando se degrada. Es fácil inclinarse hacia <strong>sesgos humanos</strong>, como la tendencia a infravalorar escenarios negativos hasta que se materializan. Por ejemplo, hace ya décadas, se acuñó el término “<strong><a href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Falacia_de_la_planificaci%C3%B3n" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">falacia de planificación</a></strong>”, que explica el patrón por el que los grandes proyectos se disparan de forma crónica tanto en coste como en plazo.</p> <p>El CIO no escapa a esto. También está sometido a presión por entregar una narrativa de avance y por no ser percibido como freno.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="como-saber-si-las-decisiones-se-toman-desde-la-empresa-ideal">Cómo saber si las decisiones se toman desde la empresa ideal</h2> <p>A pesar de estos sesgos, hay algunas señales que indican que hay un sesgo hacia la empresa ideal, perdiendo la conexión con la real.</p> <p>La primera es cuando la <strong>hoja de ruta se reescribe continuamente. </strong>Si cada trimestre hay que cambiar la planificación, significa que el sistema vive en <strong>modo reacción,</strong> actuando desde la urgencia. Este modo de decidir no es lo mismo que incorporar metodologías ágiles, y puede llegar a confundirse.</p> <p>Otra señal es el <strong>exceso de excepciones</strong>. Estas son inevitables, pero cuando se terminan convirtiendo en la norma son un síntoma de un problema de fondo. Si no se aborda, se empieza a generar <strong>deuda</strong>. Es decir, riesgos y costes que se van acumulando y terminan hipotecando las decisiones futuras.</p> <p>Una señal contraintuitiva se manifiesta cuando los <strong>KPI son correctos, </strong>indican estabilidad y avance, pero al mismo tiempo, cada <strong>cambio</strong> supone un <strong>riesgo</strong> elevado. Esto apunta a que la dirección se siente cómoda con un determinado cuadro de mando, pero en realidad no está alineado con la realidad, y puede ocultar fragilidad y <strong>falta de confianza</strong>.</p> <p>Por último, una señal culturalmente arraigada (y difícil de percibir) es cuando la <strong>continuidad se asume, pero no se pone a prueba.</strong> Es decir, cuando no existe un esquema periódico de prueba de los sistemas. Es fácil <strong>confundir resiliencia</strong> con la <strong>falta de eventos adverso</strong>s. Sin este entrenamiento, la organización cree que está preparada, hasta que llega un incidente.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="el-mapa-y-el-territorio">El mapa y el territorio</h2> <p>Hay una distinción que ayuda a calibrar las señales y facilita un cambio de conversación: el mapa y el territorio.</p> <p>El <strong>mapa</strong> es la <strong>representación</strong>: arquitectura objetivo, planes, KPI, comités y gobierno formal. El mapa es necesario, porque sin él no hay dirección.</p> <p>El <strong>territorio</strong> es la <strong>operación: </strong>dependencias, integraciones, excepciones, capacidades reales de los equipos y coordinación. Es real y está vivo.</p> <p>Cuando no se cuestiona ni actualiza el mapa, aparece una <strong>ilusión de gobierno</strong>: se gobierna la representación del sistema, no el sistema. La energía se concentra en demostrar orden mientras el territorio se vuelve más frágil sin que nadie lo vea a tiempo.</p> <p>El caso del colapso aéreo en el Reino Unido muestra el choque entre ambos. El 28 de agosto era un día crítico para el sistema británico, y contaba con una dotación completa de personal. Y, aun así, una combinación atípica de condiciones obligó a operar en modo manual. En otras palabras: el mapa indicaba resiliencia; el territorio contó otra historia.</p> <p>En ese escenario, la pregunta que el CIO necesita instalar es tan importante como incómoda: <strong>¿estamos gobernando el mapa o estamos gobernando el territorio?</strong></p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tres-movimientos-del-cio-para-que-la-empresa-real-no-sea-una-sorpresa">Tres movimientos del CIO para que la empresa real no sea una sorpresa</h2> <p>Para que la empresa se haga estas preguntas (y no sólo después de un susto), la clave no está en más <em>reporting</em>. Está en instalar <strong>hábitos de gobierno</strong> que hagan visible la <strong>distancia entre mapa y territorio</strong>: entre lo que se planifica y lo que realmente se puede sostener. A continuación, se presentan tres hábitos sencillos que hacen más visible el territorio:</p> <p><strong>1) Definir la empresa mínima viable.</strong> Ese concepto, nacido en el ámbito de la resiliencia, consiste en elegir una columna dorsal de <strong>servicios críticos</strong> y describir sus <strong>dependencias</strong> clave, incluyendo terceros. A partir de ahí, se indica qué ocurre si se degradan y cómo activar un <strong>modo de contingencia</strong> que permita que la operación no se pare.</p> <p><strong>2) Gobernar las excepciones.</strong> El objetivo es que dejen<strong> de ser un favor</strong> urgente y se conviertan en decisiones y aprendizaje de la organización. Para ello, cada excepción debe tener <strong>dueño</strong>, motivo, fecha de caducidad y una <strong>revisión</strong> programada. En la revisión se pueden plantear las opciones de salida: corregir la causa, renovar la excepción asumiendo su coste, o retirarla.</p> <p>3<strong>) Institucionalizar un <em>reality check</em> ejecutivo</strong>. Se trata de establecer una <strong>revisión</strong> periódica de capacidades. Es decir, qué riesgos o fragilidades aumentan, qué dependencias nuevas aparecen y qué incidentes revelan territorio no visible. Y, al menos un par de veces al año, hace falta <strong>ensayar momentos de la verdad</strong>. Es decir, simular una disrupción, practicar el modo manual y comprobar si los procedimientos funcionan bajo presión.</p> <p>En los próximos meses, el <strong>territorio va a cambiar</strong> con la entrada de <strong>agentes de IA</strong>. Habrá más integraciones, más presión por la velocidad y menos tolerancia al fallo. En ese contexto, el CIO tendrá que revisar el mapa. </p> <p></p> <p><em>La próxima tribuna se centrará en una amenaza claramente externa y cada vez más determinante: la dependencia tecnológica. Es decir, cómo se crea de forma inadvertida y qué puede hacer el CIO para recuperar margen de maniobra sin frenar la ambición digital.</em> </p> <hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Sendmarc Releases DMARCbis Fireside Chat Featuring Co-Editor Todd Herr]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136631/sendmarc-releases-dmarcbis-fireside-chat-featuring-co-editor-todd-herr.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136631/sendmarc-releases-dmarcbis-fireside-chat-featuring-co-editor-todd-herr.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>In a recent DMARCbis fireside chat, email authentication leaders discussed upcoming DMARC changes and how teams can plan for 2026. </p> <p><a href="https://sendmarc.com/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;utm_campaign=dmarcbis-fireside-chat" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Sendmarc</a> has released a new fireside chat featuring Todd Herr, Principal Solutions Architect at GreenArrow Email and co-editor of DMARCbis, on the upcoming update to DMARC (Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance). </p> <p>Led by Dan Levinson of Sendmarc, the fireside chat explains how the protocol is progressing through the IETF (Internet Engineering Task Force) standards process and what security and email teams can expect as authentication requirements continue to tighten across the ecosystem. </p> <p><a href="https://sendmarc.com/dmarc/dmarcbis?utm_medium=press-release&amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;utm_campaign=dmarcbis-fireside-chat" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>Users can watch the full discussion on upcoming DMARC changes here.</strong></a></p> <p><a href="https://sendmarc.com/dmarc/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;utm_campaign=dmarcbis-fireside-chat" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">DMARC</a> was originally published in 2015 and has since become a widely adopted control for reducing direct-domain spoofing and improving visibility into legitimate and illegitimate use of an email domain. </p> <p>In the discussion, Herr outlines how DMARCbis reflects lessons learned across years of real-world deployment, including clarifications for changes aimed at improving long-term maintainability. DMARCbis (draft-ietf-dmarc-dmarcbis-41) is intended for Proposed Standard status and, if approved, would obsolete RFC 7489. </p> <p>“I don’t see DMARCbis as a revolution so much as an evolution,” said Herr.” </p> <p><strong>﻿Discussion Themes and Platform Updates</strong></p> <p>The video highlights updates and themes relevant to businesses planning email security initiatives: </p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Record Tag Updates and Deprecations:</strong> Herr discusses tag updates intended to reduce ambiguity and inconsistent implementation, so while DMARC changes, it remains practical to deploy at scale. </li> <li><strong>Clearer expectations for reporting and participation: </strong>The discussion covers what “full participation” looks like in practice, including the operational work required to maintain aligned authentication and useful reporting. </li> <li><strong>Receiver-side policy discovery via DNS tree walk:</strong> DMARCbis introduces a standardized DNS tree walk approach that improves how receivers discover the organizational domain. </li> <li>Levinson noted that some of the world’s most prominent mailbox providers, such as Microsoft, Google, and Yahoo, have “captured a great number of headlines” by <strong>rolling out strict sender requirements</strong> that rely heavily on DMARC, SPF, and DKIM – suggesting authentication is necessary to safeguard email, the single most vital communication channel. </li>
</ul> <p>Herr also addresses common misconceptions, including the idea that publishing DMARC alone guarantees inbox placement. The discussion reinforces that authentication helps mailbox providers evaluate identity and apply reputation, but it doesn’t replace strong sending practices. </p> <p><a href="https://sendmarc.com/dmarc/dmarcbis?utm_medium=press-release&amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;utm_campaign=dmarcbis-fireside-chat" target="_blank" rel="sponsored"><strong>Users can watch the full video here.</strong></a></p> <p><strong>About Sendmarc</strong> </p> <p><a href="https://sendmarc.com/?utm_medium=press-release&amp;utm_source=pr-newswire&amp;utm_campaign=dmarcbis-fireside-chat" target="_blank" rel="sponsored">Sendmarc</a> helps organizations around the world protect their domains from email impersonation by making DMARC deployment and management practical at scale. With an enterprise-first approach, the platform helps large organizations roll out domain protection at scale, reduce phishing and spoofing risk, and maintain control across complex, multi-domain sender ecosystems. </p> <p>Beyond blocking fraud, Sendmarc supports stronger deliverability by helping legitimate communication authenticate correctly and reach inboxes. Enterprises worldwide rely on Sendmarc’s tooling and expertise to move from visibility to enforcement and sustain DMARC compliance over time. </p> <h5 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Contact</strong></h5> <p><strong>Customer Success Director, US</strong></p> <p><strong>Dan Levinson</strong></p> <p><strong>Sendmarc</strong></p> <p><strong>sales@sendmarc.com</strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why Model Context Protocol is suddenly on every executive agenda]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136548/why-model-context-protocol-is-suddenly-on-every-executive-agenda.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136548/why-model-context-protocol-is-suddenly-on-every-executive-agenda.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Technology leaders are used to watching new standards emerge quietly and then disappear into the plumbing of enterprise IT. But <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/4029634/what-is-model-context-protocol-how-mcp-bridges-ai-and-external-services.html">Model Context Protocol (MCP)</a> is following a different trajectory. Over the past year, it has moved from an obscure technical concept into the center of conversations about agentic AI, governance, and security risk, and it’s a shift that reflects not hype, but the practical reality of how AI systems are beginning to interact with enterprise environments.</p> <p>During a Cyber Sessions interview I conducted last year with veteran security executive Andy Ellis, he predicted the inflection point before most executives had encountered the term.</p> <p>“I think MCP is going to be massive at RSA,” he said at the time. “Instead of having an API tightly defined between a client and a server, you put an LLM on either end and let them negotiate what to exchange. It will revolutionize software development – and it’s going to make it really scary.”</p> <p>That prediction now looks spot on. RSA Conference organizers tell me that many of their submissions for 2026 focused on the topic. For a protocol introduced in 2024, that level of attention signals rapid movement from theory to deployment. What is driving this surge is not simply curiosity among engineers. MCP is emerging as a connective infrastructure for enterprise AI, and that makes it an important emerging technology for CIOs to watch.</p> <figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper youtube-video">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="AI Hype and Cyber Buzzwords: What 350 Vendors Got Wrong at Black Hat | Andy Ellis" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PWNi9KvY2v0?start=1620&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="integration-friction-meets-ai-acceleration">Integration friction meets AI acceleration</h2> <p>One of the most stubborn barriers to enterprise AI adoption has not been model performance but integration complexity. Organizations launched ambitious pilots only to discover that connecting AI to existing systems required time-consuming API work, brittle middleware, and specialized development skills. Ellis attributes MCP’s rapid adoption to its basic utility.</p> <p>MCP lets you plug your existing stack of applications together without all of the annoying API integration work. It’s basically a universal connector, said Ellis.</p> <p>“A lot of people started AI projects from scratch, trying to build complex systems out of thin air. MCP lets you plug your existing applications together instead.”</p> <p>The protocol provides a standardized way for AI agents and applications to retrieve data and interact with enterprise tools. In a recent interview, RSAC researchers described it as “the USB-C of AI,” a connector designed to allow disparate systems to communicate without custom integration.</p> <p>For CIOs facing sprawling application portfolios and pressure to deliver AI-enabled capabilities quickly, this changes the implementation equation. Integration shifts from bespoke engineering to configuration, existing systems become accessible without rebuilding them, and even non-engineers can connect data sources into AI workflows. In environments where modernization has produced complexity rather than cohesion, this alone explains why MCP is gaining traction.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mcps-rise-is-inseparable-from-agentic-ai">MCP’s rise is inseparable from agentic AI</h2> <p>MCP’s sudden relevance coincides with the rise of agentic AI, which requires reliable mechanisms for retrieving data and acting within systems. The protocol addresses both needs by creating a standardized method for sharing data with large language models and a standardized way for those models to act on behalf of users.</p> <p>This shift may be even more important than it appears on the surface. Earlier AI integrations often relied on system-level credentials or high-privilege service accounts, creating exposure risks and limiting accountability. MCP enables actions to be performed in the context of the current user, improving traceability but introducing new governance requirements.</p> <p>As RSA researchers explained, “MCP solves two important aspects of agent AI and AI chatbots. It creates a standardized way to share data with an LLM, and it also creates a standard way of having an LLM act on behalf of the current user.”</p> <p>This is what elevates MCP beyond technical convenience. By enabling LLMs to act on behalf of a human or organization, it shifts the core question from what an AI system can see to what it can do – moving MCP out of the engineering domain and into governance, identity, and risk management.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="governance-is-moving-closer-to-the-protocol-layer">Governance is moving closer to the protocol layer</h2> <p>Security researchers are focusing heavily on the risk dimension of MCP adoption. RSA organizers tell me that if MCP-related conference submissions are categorized by emphasis, fewer than 4% fall primarily into the opportunity category. Developers and automation teams have already embraced the benefits; the security community is concentrating on the exposure.</p> <p>The risks are not abstract. MCP tooling can be over-permissioned, untrusted MCP servers can enable data leakage or prompt injection, and malicious tool impersonation or authentication bypass scenarios can create pathways for compromise. One RSA session will demonstrate how an MCP vulnerability could enable remote code execution and full takeover of an Azure tenant.</p> <p>The broader concern is structural. MCP integrations can be created by anyone experimenting with AI tooling, expanding the attack surface beyond enterprise-approved systems to an ecosystem of community-built connectors that may never undergo security review. RSA researchers warn that the relative lack of default security controls, combined with the speed of adoption, means organizations should anticipate destructive incidents that security teams may not see coming.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-adoption-velocity-problem">The adoption velocity problem</h2> <p>As with many AI developments, the speed of experimentation is outpacing the development of governance controls. Vendors are embedding MCP connectors into enterprise products to simplify AI access. Coding assistants already rely on the protocol extensively. Developers and so-called “vibe coders” are using it to connect systems and automate workflows with minimal friction.</p> <p>At the same time, AI agents remain non-deterministic by design, and MCP tooling can grant them powerful operational capabilities. The combination of ease of integration and expansive permissions creates a risk profile that organizations have not previously managed at scale. For CIOs, this is a familiar tension. The operational value is clear, but unmanaged adoption introduces systemic exposure.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="practical-use-cases-are-already-emerging">Practical use cases are already emerging</h2> <p>MCP has moved beyond proof-of-concept environments into operational workflows. Organizations are using it to collect data across systems for incident management, read support tickets and assign priority levels, move items into internal tracking systems, and interconnect security, logging, and file platforms. Coding assistants and AI-augmented task automation tools are increasingly dependent on it.</p> <p>These use cases are compelling because they reduce context switching, eliminate manual data gathering, and allow AI to support workflows without deep integration projects. They also illustrate why governance must evolve in parallel with adoption.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="questions-cios-should-be-asking-now">Questions CIOs should be asking now</h2> <p>MCP is becoming a control layer for how AI systems interact with enterprise environments. That reality requires executive visibility and deliberate policy decisions.</p> <p>Leaders should begin by understanding where MCP is already in use, particularly within developer tools and AI assistants. They should examine who has the authority to create integrations, how permissions are granted and constrained, and how MCP servers are authenticated and trusted. Governance policies may need to move closer to the protocol layer to ensure consistent enforcement across integrations.</p> <p>Equally important is recognizing that MCP adoption may not arrive through a single enterprise initiative. It is likely to emerge through tools, vendors, and experimentation occurring simultaneously across the organization.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-structural-shift-not-a-passing-trend">A structural shift, not a passing trend</h2> <p>Protocols rarely become executive concerns. MCP is becoming one because it sits at the intersection of AI execution, system integration, and enterprise governance. It enables AI to analyze enterprise data and to act within enterprise systems. That capability is powerful and transformative, and it also changes the risk equation.</p> <p>The rise of MCP signals a shift in enterprise architecture from systems that expose data to systems that intelligent agents can operate. CIOs do not need to slow adoption to manage this shift, but they do need to ensure that identity controls, governance policies, and security guardrails evolve at the same pace.</p> <p>Once agents can operate across enterprise systems, the central question is whether AI can access the environment and, if so, how safely and responsibly it can operate within it.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Gartner Predicts Embedded AI in Cloud ERP Applications will Drive a 30% Faster Financial Close by 2028]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-24-gartner-predicts-embedded-ai-in-cloud-erp-applications-will-drive-a-30-percent-faster-financial-close-by-2028?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-24-gartner-predicts-embedded-ai-in-cloud-erp-applications-will-drive-a-30-percent-faster-financial-close-by-2028?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Five emerging themes in cloud enterprise resource planning (ERP) finance applications will shape the future of the finance function through AI and automation, according to Gartner, Inc., a business and technology insights company. Based on these themes, Gartner predicts that finance organizations using cloud ERP applications with embedded AI assistants will see a 30% faster financial close by 2028.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Filin-Matthews Named Chief Architect at McDonalds]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/caf-corner/filin-matthews-named-chief-architect-at-mcdonalds/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/caf-corner/filin-matthews-named-chief-architect-at-mcdonalds/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Wayne Filin-Matthews, a veteran enterprise architect and global technology strategist, has been appointed Vice President of AI Strategy and Chief Architect at McDonald&#8217;s, signaling the company’s continued push to embed artificial intelligence across its operations <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/caf-corner/filin-matthews-named-chief-architect-at-mcdonalds/" title="Filin-Matthews Named Chief Architect at McDonalds">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Filin-Matthews Named Chief Architect at McDonalds]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/filin-matthews-named-chief-architect-at-mcdonalds/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/filin-matthews-named-chief-architect-at-mcdonalds/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Wayne Filin-Matthews, a veteran enterprise architect and global technology strategist, has been appointed Vice President of AI Strategy and Chief Architect at McDonald&#8217;s, signaling the company’s continued push to embed artificial intelligence acr...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Agentic AI Is On The Cusp Of Transforming Financial Services]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/agentic-ai-is-on-the-cusp-of-transforming-financial-services/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/agentic-ai-is-on-the-cusp-of-transforming-financial-services/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Agentic AI surged to the top of enterprise agendas in 2025. Yet while enthusiasm was sky‑high, many organizations struggled to bridge the gap between vendor vision and the practical progress that business and technology leaders expected.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Building Preference Is The Key To Winning B2B Buyers]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/building-preference-is-the-key-to-winning-b2b-buyers/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/building-preference-is-the-key-to-winning-b2b-buyers/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[B2B brand and demand teams have long operated independently of one another. But at a time when buying decisions are made before a formal purchase process even begins, that separation is a major obstacle to growth.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[A cloud-smart strategy for modernizing mission-critical workloads]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136084/a-cloud-smart-strategy-for-modernizing-mission-critical-workloads.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136084/a-cloud-smart-strategy-for-modernizing-mission-critical-workloads.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Cloud adoption has fundamentally changed how enterprises build and deliver technology. For much of the past decade, cloud strategy was framed around a simple mandate: move fast and move to the cloud. That approach helped organizations modernize development practices and accelerate innovation. But in my experience working with mission-critical systems, I’ve seen that applying the same strategy indiscriminately can introduce significant business risk.</p> <p>As enterprises mature in their cloud journeys, many CIOs and senior technology leaders are discovering that modernization is not about where workloads run — it’s about how deliberately they are designed. This realization is driving a shift from cloud-first to cloud-smart, particularly for systems the business cannot afford to lose.</p> <p>A cloud-smart strategy, as highlighted by the <a href="https://cloud.cio.gov/strategy/" rel="nofollow">Federal Cloud Computing Strategy</a>, encourages agencies to weigh the long-term, total costs of ownership and security risks rather than focusing only on immediate migration.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mission-critical-workloads-and-the-need-for-modernization">Mission-critical workloads and the need for modernization</h2> <p>Mission-critical workloads are systems where failure has immediate business consequences: core banking systems, real-time payment systems, identity services, healthcare platforms and large-scale operational systems. These systems are expected to be always available, predictable and trusted. When these systems fail, the impact goes far beyond IT metrics. Revenue is disrupted and customer trust erodes due to system failures. That reality changes how modernization must be approached.</p> <p>Modernizing critical workloads — the core systems that your business relies on — is often a business imperative. Legacy infrastructure can hinder innovation and agility and maintaining old systems (like aging mainframes or siloed on-premises servers) can become increasingly risky and expensive.</p> <p>Modern customers and internal users expect fast, scalable and reliable digital services; legacy systems often struggle to meet those expectations. By updating these workloads to run on modern cloud platforms or architectures, organizations can improve performance and resilience, integrate new capabilities (like real-time analytics or AI) and respond faster to changing needs.</p> <p>However, modernization is not easy — especially for core systems. These workloads tend to be large, complex and deeply intertwined with business processes. In my experience and as echoed by industry peers, organizations face several major challenges when attempting to modernize critical applications:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Complex legacy technology and technical debt</li> <li>Alignment and stakeholder buy-in</li> <li>Unique requirements and integration needs</li> <li>Risk of downtime or disruption</li> <li>Skills and culture change</li>
</ul> <p>Despite these challenges, the cost of doing nothing is high as well. Sticking indefinitely with legacy systems can lead to rising maintenance costs, inability to support new business initiatives, security vulnerabilities and even outages as old hardware fails. Many organizations reach a tipping point where they must modernize to stay competitive.</p> <p>The key is to do it wisely — balancing speed and risk and having a solid strategy in place (roadmap, skills and governance) to navigate the complexity.</p> <p>Depending on your goals and constraints, there are several strategies you can take to modernize a workload. In cloud architecture circles, we often refer to the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/enterprise-strategy/6-strategies-for-migrating-applications-to-the-cloud/" rel="nofollow">6 R’s of migration</a> — common patterns ranging from simply relocating an application as-is, to completely rebuilding it from scratch.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-pitfalls-of-cloud-first-for-always-on-mission-critical-systems">The pitfalls of cloud-first for always-on mission-critical systems</h2> <p>Cloud-first strategies assume that elasticity, managed services and abstraction naturally lead to better outcomes. In practice, I’ve seen several recurring challenges when this mindset is applied to mission-critical workloads. Latency and determinism become harder to guarantee in shared, multi-tenant environments. Cost predictability suffers when steady, always-on workloads are billed as variable consumption. And during outages, reduced visibility into underlying infrastructure can slow diagnosis and recovery — precisely when speed matters most.</p> <p>These challenges do not mean the cloud is unsuitable. They mean it must be used intentionally.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-smart-is-a-strategy-not-a-destination">Cloud-smart is a strategy, not a destination</h2> <p>A cloud-smart strategy aligns workload placement with business risk, performance needs and regulatory expectations rather than ideology. Instead of asking whether a system can move to the cloud, cloud-smart organizations ask where it performs best. This often leads to <a href="https://www.ibm.com/think/topics/hybrid-cloud-architecture" rel="nofollow">hybrid cloud architectures</a> — not as a transitional phase, but as a deliberate long-term model before hosting the entire critical system exclusively in public cloud.</p> <p>One of the most effective modernization approaches I’ve seen is decoupling modernization from migration. Rather than lifting and shifting entire platforms, teams separate core transaction engines from decisioning, orchestration and experience layers. APIs and event-driven integration enable new capabilities around stable cores, allowing systems to evolve incrementally without jeopardizing operational continuity. This incremental approach reduces blast radius, preserves institutional knowledge and allows modernization to proceed without putting the business at risk.</p> <p>Another lesson I’ve learned is that availability alone is not enough. Mission-critical systems must be designed to degrade gracefully.</p> <p>Cloud-smart architectures assume failure and plan for it through:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Active-active or active-standby designs</li> <li>Automated failover and recovery testing</li> <li>Clear fallback paths when dependencies degrade</li>
</ul> <p>Resilience becomes an architectural feature, not an operational afterthought.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-role-of-ai-in-mission-critical-system-modernization">The role of AI in mission-critical system modernization</h2> <p>AI adds both opportunity and complexity to mission-critical modernization. Cloud-smart strategies treat AI as a decision-support layer, not an unquestioned authority. Training and experimentation often benefit from public cloud scale, while production inference is deployed with strict latency, observability and governance controls. Equally important are fallback mechanisms when models are unavailable or uncertain.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-does-cloud-smart-leadership-look-like">What does cloud-smart leadership look like?</h2> <p>For CIOs modernizing mission-critical workloads, cloud-smart leadership means:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Align workload placement with business risk, not platform preference</li> <li>Designing for predictability, not just elasticity</li> <li>Treat mission-critical systems differently from cloud-native products</li> <li>Embrace hybrid architecture as a deliberate operating model until the organization has advanced capability and maturity level to host critical systems in the public cloud</li> <li>Modernize incrementally rather than through disruptive rewrites</li> <li>Design resilience and observability into the architecture from the start</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-repatriation-as-a-sign-of-maturity-not-retreat">Cloud repatriation as a sign of maturity, not retreat</h2> <p>In response to post-migration challenges of hosting in public cloud, many organizations are quietly engaging in <a href="https://thenewstack.io/why-companies-are-ditching-the-cloud-the-rise-of-cloud-repatriation/" rel="nofollow">cloud repatriation</a> — moving specific workloads or parts of workloads out of the public cloud and into environments that offer greater control and predictability.</p> <p>This trend is sometimes framed as a reversal of cloud strategy. In reality, I see it as a natural evolution. Cloud repatriation is rarely about abandoning the cloud altogether. It is about recognizing that certain always-on, latency-sensitive or cost-stable workloads perform better when:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Infrastructure behavior is deterministic</li> <li>Costs are more predictable over long horizons</li> <li>Operational visibility and control are higher</li> <li>Recovery paths are fully owned and tested</li>
</ul> <p>In cloud-smart organizations, repatriation is not a failure — it is an architectural correction based on operational evidence.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="practical-guidance-for-cios">Practical guidance for CIOs</h2> <p>For CIOs modernizing mission-critical workloads, a cloud-smart strategy becomes real through deliberate, repeatable decisions rather than one-time transformation programs. Based on what I’ve seen work in practice, a few guiding actions stand out.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="start-with-business-risk-not-architecture-preference">Start with business risk, not architecture preference</h3> <p>Before discussing platforms or providers, explicitly classify workloads by business impact.</p> <p>What happens if this system is unavailable for minutes, hours or days?</p> <p>How sensitive is it to latency variability?</p> <p>What regulatory, financial or reputational risk does failure create?</p> <p>This framing ensures architectural decisions are driven by business outcomes rather than technology trends.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="decouple-modernization-from-migration">Decouple modernization from migration</h3> <p>Avoid tying modernization success to cloud relocation. Many mission-critical systems benefit from:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Refactoring interfaces and integration patterns</li> <li>Externalizing business rules and decisioning</li> <li>Improving observability and automation</li>
</ul> <p>These changes often deliver more value — and less risk — than immediate platform migration.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="design-hybrid-as-an-operating-model-not-an-exception">Design hybrid as an operating model, not an exception</h3> <p>Treat hybrid architecture as a first-class design choice. This means:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Standardizing identity, security and observability across environments</li> <li>Ensuring consistent CI/CD pipelines regardless of workload location</li> <li>Designing failure and recovery paths that cross environment boundaries</li>
</ul> <p>When hybrid is intentional, it simplifies operations rather than complicating them.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="be-explicit-about-where-repatriation-is-acceptable">Be explicit about where repatriation is acceptable</h3> <p>Cloud-smart organizations normalize the idea that some workloads may move back out of the public cloud.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Define clear criteria for when repatriation is appropriate</li> <li>Treat repatriation as a performance or risk optimization, not a setback</li> <li>Capture lessons learned and feed them back into future placement decisions</li>
</ul> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="engineer-resilience-dont-assume-it">Engineer resilience, don’t assume it</h3> <p>Availability claims are not resilience. CIOs should insist on:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Regular failure testing and recovery exercises</li> <li>Graceful degradation paths for dependent services</li> <li>Clear ownership of recovery time and recovery point objectives</li>
</ul> <p>Mission-critical resilience must be continuously proven, not assumed.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="introduce-ai-with-guardrails">Introduce AI with guardrails</h3> <p>When AI is introduced into critical workflows:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Keep deterministic fallbacks in place</li> <li>Monitor decision quality, not just system health</li> <li>Ensure humans can intervene when confidence thresholds are crossed</li>
</ul> <p>AI should augment mission-critical systems — not become an unexamined single point of failure.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="measure-success-beyond-migration-metrics">Measure success beyond migration metrics</h3> <p>Finally, redefine success metrics.</p> <p>Instead of tracking:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Percentage of workloads migrated</li> <li>Cloud spend reduction alone</li>
</ul> <p>Measure:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Reduction in incident severity</li> <li>Improvement in recovery time</li> <li>Predictability of performance and cost</li> <li>Trust from business and regulatory stakeholders</li>
</ul> <p>These indicators better reflect modernization progress for systems that truly matter.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="final-thoughts">Final thoughts</h2> <p>Modernizing mission-critical workloads is one of the biggest challenges CIOs and executive leadership face. The goal should be to not chase the latest platform, but to build systems that are resilient, adaptable and worthy of trust.</p> <p>Crafting a cloud-smart strategy for modernizing critical workloads is a journey, not a one-time task. It requires a clear vision of where you want to go (business objectives), a realistic assessment of where you are (legacy estate and constraints) and a pragmatic roadmap of how to get there (which workloads to modernize, how and on which platforms — with security, compliance and cost governance built in every step of the way). In my experience, organizations that embrace cloud-smart strategies modernize with confidence — delivering innovation where it matters, while protecting the systems their business depends on every day.</p> <p>By combining technical excellence with business alignment, having a well-defined cloud-smart strategy can turn your organization’s critical systems from potential liabilities into competitive assets.</p> <p><em>The views and opinions expressed in this article are those of the author and are provided in a personal capacity. They do not necessarily reflect the views, policies or positions of any employer, organization or professional body with which the author is affiliated.</em></p> <p><em>This article was made possible by our partnership with the IASA </em><a href="https://chiefarchitectforum.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><em>Chief Architect Forum</em></a><em>. The CAF’s purpose is to test, challenge and support the art and science of Business Technology Architecture and its evolution over time as well as grow the influence and leadership of chief architects both inside and outside the profession. The CAF is a leadership community of the </em><a href="https://iasaglobal.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><em>IASA</em></a><em>, the leading non-profit professional association for business technology architects.</em><em></em></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Institutional sovereignty is the missing layer in AI governance]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136840/institutional-sovereignty-is-the-missing-layer-in-ai-governance.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136840/institutional-sovereignty-is-the-missing-layer-in-ai-governance.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Most enterprises are writing AI policies right now. They are also standing up review boards, model inventories, and risk registers. That’s progress.</p> <p>Then the first real incident happens: An agent changes a configuration. A staff member pastes sensitive data into a tool they were not approved to use. A model output drives a decision nobody can fully explain. As a result, the post-incident review ends up being the same argument every time.</p> <p>Who authorized this</p> <p>Who owned the intent</p> <p>Who is accountable for the outcome</p> <p>When I interview executives and review modernization failures, I keep seeing the same structural pattern: the barriers are constitutional, not technical. Decision rights fragment, continuity breaks, and external actors shape the agenda more than internal governance.</p> <p>AI amplifies that weakness because AI turns decisions into workflows, and workflows into automated action. If you cannot prove authorship and authority in normal operations, you will not be able to prove it once AI enters the loop.</p> <p>That is why I use institutional sovereignty as the missing layer in AI governance. It is a governance model focused on authorship, decision rights, accountability, and continuity, expressed in a way leaders can implement and audit. It also explains why AI adoption often stalls due to non-technical factors such as contractual ambiguity and liability uncertainty.</p> <p>Healthcare makes this painfully visible. One physician leader described the current state like this:</p> <blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“AI, I call it the wild wild west… we are operating in a gun slinging stagecoach environment, where people are doing almost anything they want, and the regulatory environment has to catch up.”</p>
</blockquote> <p>That is not a regulation problem. It is an institutional ownership problem.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="policy-is-not-proof">Policy is not proof</h2> <p>Policies describe what should happen. Proof is what you can demonstrate happened, who caused it, and on what authority.</p> <p>In practice, the gap between policy and proof manifests in three ways.</p> <p>First, intent is not owned. The institution does not define its own modernization agenda, and external parties introduce direction without an internal mandate. That is authorship failure.</p> <p>Second, authority is not bounded. Decision authority is spread across committees, departments, or external partners, creating unclear boundaries and inconsistent governance. That is jurisdiction leakage.</p> <p>Third, oversight becomes theater. Governance bodies exist without enforceable authority. They perform oversight symbolically while real decisions occur outside formal channels.</p> <p>AI makes each of these worse.</p> <p>An AI policy that says “humans remain accountable” is meaningless if you cannot answer a basic operational question: who had the right to delegate this action to the system? This is why governance is a core function in the<a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework" rel="nofollow"> </a><a href="https://www.nist.gov/itl/ai-risk-management-framework" rel="nofollow">NIST AI Risk Management Framework</a>.</p> <p>This need for core governance functions is echoed in other frameworks. For example, the same logic applies in ISO/<a href="https://www.iso.org/standard/42001" rel="nofollow">IEC 42001</a>, which frames AI management as an organizational system rather than a model documentation exercise.</p> <p>Now, add the human reality inside healthcare. A security leader warned that intent is often split between technical goals and executive pressure:</p> <blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“CISO might have their own agenda… The problem is, you might have folks on the board of directors that put pressure on the C suite to say, We want AI to help us reduce staff.”</p>
</blockquote> <p>When intent is neither explicit nor ratified, trust quickly collapses, and people begin to circumvent governance. This risk connects back to broader organizational dynamics.</p> <p>I also see organizations self-block innovation by treating compliance as folklore. A healthcare technology executive put it bluntly:</p> <blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Regulatory compliance is often used as a… artificial barrier… It is a perception… often perceived what the regulatory needs are, but they’re not frequently well understood.”</p>
</blockquote> <p>This kind of authority failure means decisions are vetoed without a cited basis, remediation path, or a named decision owner.</p> <p>Given these patterns, the real question becomes: what is the constitutional layer beneath your AI program? This sets the stage for a more structured approach.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-decision-rights-stack-behind-institutional-sovereignty">The decision rights stack behind institutional sovereignty</h2> <p>Institutional sovereignty defines a constitutional layer of governance using five pillars. If any pillar is weak, sovereignty is incomplete, and the institution becomes vulnerable to dependence on external authority.</p> <p>I apply these pillars to AI governance as a decision rights stack.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-decision-architecture">1. Decision architecture</h3> <p>This is your formal answer to the question of who can decide what.</p> <p>In AI terms, decision architecture must explicitly cover: who can approve a use case, who can approve deployment, who can approve autonomy, who can approve exceptions, and who can suspend or roll back an agent.</p> <p>This is where most AI programs quietly fail. They create an AI committee, but they do not publish a decision map that names owners and defines delegation boundaries.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-risk-authorship">2. Risk authorship</h3> <p>Many dependent institutions allow vendors, regulators, or consultants to define what is urgent, acceptable, or possible. Risk narratives are outsourced, creating a structural dependency.</p> <p>In AI governance, risk authorship means the institution defines its own thresholds for safety, privacy, integrity, and operational impact. You can align with external principles, such as the<a href="https://www.oecd.org/en/topics/ai-principles.html" rel="nofollow"> </a><a href="https://www.oecd.org/en/topics/ai-principles.html" rel="nofollow">OECD AI principles</a>, but you still need an internal doctrine that turns those principles into enforceable decisions.</p> <p>In healthcare, risk authorship must also be honest about the stakes. People do not tolerate vague accountability when harm is possible.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-workflow-authority">3. Workflow authority</h3> <p>AI does not live in a policy binder. It lives in workflows.</p> <p>Many organizations operate on vendor workflows, consultant playbooks, or politically imposed processes. Workflow authority reestablishes institutional control by redesigning governance rituals, approval pathways, and operational workflows.</p> <p>In AI terms, workflow authority means you control where AI can act, what approvals are required, which escalation paths exist, and how exceptions are handled.</p> <p>A former CMIO captured the core problem:</p> <blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The technology has outpaced the people and the process… physicians and health systems are bringing in technology tools… but from a process standpoint, it’s not really clear how the governance works.”</p>
</blockquote> <p>That is the birth of shadow AI.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-data-authorship">4. Data authorship</h3> <p>If you do not own your data definitions, you do not own your truth.</p> <p>AI governance without data authorship becomes performative because you cannot validate outputs, measure drift, or prove provenance.</p> <p>In healthcare, this is magnified by fragmented systems, inconsistent definitions, and the operational reality that data is created by workflows, not by dashboards.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-boundary-control">5. Boundary control</h3> <p>Boundary control is the process of constructing enforceable limits that prevent vendors and external platforms from shaping modernization strategy, controlling evidence, or owning the audit trail.</p> <p>In AI governance, boundary controls cover tool access, third-party integrations, data egress, audit rights, logging requirements, retention requirements, and who owns agent behavior at runtime.</p> <p>This is where governance often dies. If the contract does not provide auditability, exportability, and incident visibility, your internal policy has no teeth.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="two-lived-experiences-that-show-the-gap">Two lived experiences that show the gap</h2> <p>In one health system, I saw a high-risk shadow pilot form almost overnight. Clinicians were exhausted by documentation and adopted an ambient listening tool on their own to reduce after-hours charting. The intent was understandable. The governance path was bypassed.</p> <p>The moment leadership discovered it, everything stopped. Security and privacy had to run a retroactive assessment, clinical leadership had to calm down teams that felt punished for innovation, and the organization lost weeks of momentum.</p> <p>The fix was not to shame people. The fix was to create a sanctioned living lab: a safe-to-fail sandbox with clear data boundaries, mandatory logging, named intent owners, and an explicit stop authority from day one.</p> <p>In another case, we were implementing an enterprise scheduling platform across newly acquired clinics. The executive team chose a standardized system to scale operations. A middle manager informally vetoed the change through quiet resistance. Adoption slowed, teams lost confidence, and the project risk grew.</p> <p>That pattern matters for AI governance because informal authority will override formal policy every time unless decision rights are explicit and enforced. If someone can slow-roll an AI control change, your governance is decorative.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-checklist-leaders-can-implement-this-quarter">A checklist leaders can implement this quarter</h2> <p>Here is the checklist I give CIOs and governance leaders who want AI governance that can survive audits, incidents, and leadership transitions. It is designed to be implementable, not aspirational.</p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Publish a decision rights map for AI.</strong> List the decisions that matter: use case approval, data approval, deployment approval, autonomy approval, exception approval, suspension, and rollback. Assign a single accountable owner for each decision and a backup owner.</li> <li><strong>Define intent ownership as a required field.</strong> For every AI system and agent, record the business intent, the owner of that intent, and the measurable outcome they are accountable for. If you cannot name the intent owner, you do not have a legitimate use case.</li> <li><strong>Establish risk authorship with explicit thresholds.</strong> Write down what not allowed means in your environment. Examples: categories of data that cannot be used, actions that cannot be automated, decisions that require human review. Use<a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/nist.ai.100-1.pdf" rel="nofollow"> </a><a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/nist.ai.100-1.pdf" rel="nofollow">NIST AI RMF</a> as a structure, but keep thresholds internal and enforceable.</li> <li><strong>Require an action log that supports forensic reconstruction.</strong> If an agent can act, you need records that establish what happened, when it happened, where it happened, the source of the event, the outcome, and the identity of the actor. This maps cleanly to audit control expectations like<a href="https://csf.tools/reference/nist-sp-800-53/r5/au/au-3/" rel="nofollow"> </a><a href="https://csf.tools/reference/nist-sp-800-53/r5/au/au-3/" rel="nofollow">NIST SP 800 53 AU 3</a>.</li> <li><strong>Implement reversibility as an architectural rule.</strong> Every agentic workflow must have a defined rollback or compensation mechanism. If rollback is impossible, autonomy must be restricted to recommendations.</li> <li><strong>Put workflow authority into the approval design.</strong> Do not approve the use of AI in the abstract. Approve specific workflow insertions: where the AI reads, where it writes, where it triggers actions, and where a human gates the process. Your workflow maps should show escalation paths and negative authority, meaning what the system is explicitly forbidden to do.</li> <li><strong>Lock down data authorship before model debates.</strong> Define the authoritative sources for the key metrics the AI will touch. Define who owns the meaning of each metric. If that ownership is unclear, the AI project is premature.</li> <li><strong>Use sovereignty blockers as a pre-deployment diagnostic.</strong> Before deploying, look for the constitutional failure modes that predict collapse: authorship failure, mandate distortion, jurisdiction leakage, and stewardship theater. If you see them, fix governance before you scale the AI.</li> <li><strong>Add contract language that matches boundary control.</strong> If you cannot audit, log, export records, or enforce retention, AI governance is dead on arrival. Contracts must match your evidence and accountability requirements.</li> <li><strong>Score your organization on sovereignty maturity.</strong> Use a maturity ladder to identify whether governance is enforceable, stable across leadership transitions, and able to defend institutional priorities against external pressure.</li>
</ol> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-this-works-especially-in-healthcare">Why this works, especially in healthcare</h2> <p>Institutional sovereignty treats AI governance as a constitutional design. That framing matters because the failure modes of AI governance are usually not mathematical problems. They are mandate, jurisdiction, boundary, and continuity problems.</p> <p>Healthcare is safety-critical, cross-generational, and resource-constrained. When governance is unclear, people route around it because pain is real and time is scarce. That is why sovereignty is not an academic layer. It is a prerequisite for trustworthy AI to survive real-world operations.</p> <p>When you solve sovereignty, frameworks and standards become accelerators instead of decorations. The result is simple: you can prove who owned intent, authority, and outcomes when AI enters your workflows.</p> <p>If you want AI governance that survives the real world, build sovereignty first.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Unlocking the ROI of AI: How enterprises can move from experimentation to execution]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136555/unlocking-the-roi-of-ai-how-enterprises-can-move-from-experimentation-to-execution.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136555/unlocking-the-roi-of-ai-how-enterprises-can-move-from-experimentation-to-execution.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Despite the buzz surrounding AI, many organizations struggle to move beyond experimentation and pilot programs to fully scale AI across their enterprises. According to recent industry research conducted by EXL, while 96% of organizations believe scaling their AI initiatives over the next year is very important, companies have successfully integrated AI into less than half their workflows. Less than half report achieving their desired outcomes with AI as well.</p> <p>This gap between ambition and execution is precisely what EXL, a global data and AI company, is addressing with its flagship virtual event, <a href="https://www.exlservice.com/ai-in-action-2026?utm_source=pr_cio_byline&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_term=&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=2026_q1_ai_in_action_global" rel="sponsored">AI in Action 2026</a>. Scheduled to take place across three regions, March 11 for the Americas, March 18 for EMEA, and March 24 for APAC, this event will dive into how agentic AI is reimagining data, intelligence, and enterprise workflows.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The challenges of scaling AI</strong></h2> <p>The promise of AI is undeniable. From streamlining operations to enhancing customer experiences, AI has the potential to transform how businesses operate. However, the journey from proof of concept to enterprise-wide implementation is fraught with challenges.</p> <p>One of the most significant hurdles is embedding AI into existing workflows, many of which need to be redesigned in order to fully take advantage of AI, particularly as agentic AI systems increasingly operate business processes with greater autonomy. According to EXL’s upcoming 2026 Enterprise AI Study, only 45% of organizational workflows currently have AI embedded.</p> <p>Many organizations also find themselves grappling with siloed data and a lack of AI-ready infrastructure, enabling them to embed intelligence into their workflows. This underscores the need for a more strategic approach to AI adoption, one that goes beyond isolated use cases and focuses on scaling AI to deliver consistent, measurable outcomes and to support agentic AI that can continuously learn, adapt, and enhance performance.</p> <p>Another challenge is orchestrating multiple AI agents, autonomous systems capable of making decisions and taking actions without human intervention. While these agents hold immense potential, their deployment requires robust governance frameworks to ensure ethical and responsible use, which is strengthened through shared standards and best practices across our partner ecosystem.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>From ambition to execution</strong></h2> <p>While pilots and proofs of concepts are an important first step, AI’s true potential is unlocked when it becomes part of how work gets done every day, not as a bolt-on or point solution, with agentic AI embedded into core workflows to connect data, intelligence, and action in real-time, supported by integrated partner technologies and co-innovation models.</p> <p>It’s essential to prioritize the most critical workflows and adapt them for the AI era by embedding intelligence at scale, governing AI responsibly, and transforming innovation into lasting business value.</p> <p>AI in Action 2026 is designed to help organizations navigate this complex journey. The event will feature a keynote on innovation, disruption, and business value, delivered by EXL Chairman and CEO Rohit Kapoor and Jon McNeill, former president of Tesla, Inc. and COO of Lyft. McNeill, now the CEO and co-founder of DVx Ventures, brings a wealth of experience in scaling technology-driven businesses.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Practical insights and real-world use cases</strong></h2> <p>One of the standout features of AI in Action 2026 is its focus on practicality. The event is tailored for CXOs, CIOs, CTOs, and technology and data executives who are looking for actionable strategies to scale AI within their organizations, on how to deploy agentic AI to orchestrate data, AI, and workflows at enterprise scale, leveraging solutions developed jointly with leading partners.</p> <p>The agenda includes specialized sessions on:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Reimagining data science and workflows with agentic AI</strong>: Learn how to identify high-impact workflows and reimagine them for the AI era.</li> <li><strong>Getting your data house in order</strong>: Discover how to make data AI-ready and overcome common challenges related to data silos and legacy systems.</li>
</ul> <p>In addition to these sessions, attendees will have the opportunity to see real-world demonstrations. Together, these sessions will provide valuable insights into the strategies, tools, and frameworks that have proven effective in driving ROI from AI investments.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why AI in Action matters</strong></h2> <p>The timing of AI in Action 2026 couldn’t be more critical. As businesses face increasing pressure to innovate and stay competitive, the ability to scale AI has become a key differentiator. However, achieving this requires more than just technology; it demands a holistic approach that orchestrates AI with domain expertise, robust data management, and the ability to execute at scale.</p> <p>By bringing together industry leaders, hyperscalers, technology experts, and real-world practitioners, AI in Action 2026 aims to bridge the gap between ambition and execution. The event is about showcasing the potential of AI <em>and</em> equipping organizations with the tools and knowledge they need to turn that potential into reality, with partners playing a critical role in turning vision into execution.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Looking ahead</strong></h2> <p>As the world becomes increasingly data-driven, the role of agentic AI in shaping the future of business cannot be overstated. However, unlocking the full value of AI requires a shift in mindset, from viewing AI as a standalone solution to embedding it into the very fabric of how work gets done. Agentic AI will serve as the connective layer between data, intelligence, and orchestration—with a strong partner ecosystem ensuring these capabilities scale with confidence.</p> <p>AI in Action 2026 offers a unique opportunity for business and technology leaders to gain practical insights, learn from real-world examples, and connect with peers who are navigating similar challenges. With a focus on moving from experimentation to execution, this event is poised to be a game-changer for organizations looking to scale AI and drive measurable business value.</p> <p>To learn more about AI in Action 2026 and register for the event in the region of your choice, visit <a href="https://www.exlservice.com/ai-in-action-2026?utm_source=pr_cio_byline&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_term=&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=2026_q1_ai_in_action_global">here</a>.</p> <p><strong>About the author:</strong><strong></strong> Vishal Chhibbar is executive vice president, chief growth officer, and head of international growth markets at EXL, a global data and AI company.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why training budgets are now strategic weapons]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136055/why-training-budgets-are-now-strategic-weapons.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136055/why-training-budgets-are-now-strategic-weapons.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Remember when training meant scheduling a conference room, ordering catering, and hoping people would stay awake through PowerPoint slides? Those days are gone. The pandemic didn’t just force us online — it exposed something we suspected but couldn’t prove: our workforce’s skills were decaying faster than any annual training cycle could fix.</p> <p>What replaced that old model isn’t just digital. It’s intelligent, personalized, and tied directly to business outcomes. As we move through FY2026, AI high performers are more than three times more likely than others to say their organization intends to use AI to bring about transformative change, according to <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/quantumblack/our-insights/the-state-of-ai" rel="nofollow">McKinsey’s latest analysis</a>. Corporate learning isn’t a support function anymore. It’s a strategic weapon.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-post-pandemic-truth">The post-pandemic truth</h2> <p>COVID-19 accelerated trends that were already building. Remote work exposed skill gaps that traditional learning couldn’t address. 61% of organizations have adopted or are testing AI within their L&amp;D strategy, yet only 11% feel “extremely confident” in their future skills-building readiness, according to <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/12/04/3199968/0/en/New-2026-L-D-Report-Shows-AI-Adoption-Outpacing-Workforce-Readiness-Critical-Thinking-Leadership-and-Mentorship-Needs.html" rel="nofollow">Globe Newswire’s T&amp;R report</a>. That confidence gap? It’s the space between installing tools and actually transforming how people learn.</p> <p>The shift goes beyond delivery. Learning moved from scheduled events to always-on ecosystems. Completion rates stopped mattering. Business impact started mattering. And suddenly, CIOs who’d been treating learning platforms as HR’s problem realized they needed to own them.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-isnt-experimental-anymore-its-infrastructure">AI isn’t experimental anymore — it’s infrastructure</h2> <p>Every learning platform I architect now has AI at its core. Not as a feature — as the foundation. 77% of businesses say reskilling or upskilling their workforce to work alongside AI is their top strategy, according to the <a href="https://www.weforum.org/press/2025/01/future-of-jobs-report-2025-78-million-new-job-opportunities-by-2030-but-urgent-upskilling-needed-to-prepare-workforces/#:~:text=AI%20is%20reshaping%20business%20models,human%20cost%20of%20technological%20transformation." rel="nofollow">World Economic Forum</a>. Organizations leading in AI adoption don’t just use it for content recommendations. They use it to predict skill gaps before they crater productivity, automate engagement at scale and personalize learning paths based on actual role performance.</p> <p>The data backs this up. Research on AI-powered learning ecosystems from CIO shows how predictive analytics and personalization are reshaping workforce upskilling (<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4108064/ai-powered-learning-ecosystems-a-guide-to-workforce-upskilling.html">CIO analysis</a>). Higher education institutions have validated these approaches too, with AI-based technologies in higher education demonstrating improved outcomes through adaptive learning and intelligent feedback (<a href="https://businessconnectindia.in/ai-based-technologies-in-higher-education/" rel="nofollow">Business Connect India</a>).</p> <p>But here’s what matters: 93% of businesses recognize eLearning as essential for upskilling their workforce, according to research from <a href="https://elearningstats.education/" rel="nofollow">eLearning Stat for Education</a>. When you hit 93% consensus in enterprise tech, you’re past the hype cycle. You’re into infrastructure.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="private-cohorts-where-enterprise-meets-academia">Private cohorts: Where enterprise meets academia</h2> <p>One trend accelerating fast is Business-to-Institution (B2I) learning. Enterprises are partnering with universities to run closed-cohort programs where employees earn stackable credentials while companies get role-ready skills. These aren’t traditional executive education programs. They’re custom learning pathways embedded directly into business systems.</p> <p>The economics work because incentives align. Enterprises get skills that map to actual jobs. Universities gain revenue streams beyond declining undergraduate enrollment. Employees see immediate career value instead of wondering if their degree matters.</p> <p>I’ve written about why on-demand online courses are becoming strategic assets for C-suite leaders (<a href="https://medium.com/@shukla.vishal/why-on-demand-online-courses-are-a-strategic-asset-for-c-suite-leaders-3e166dcb08ba" rel="nofollow">Medium analysis</a>). FY2026 is when this goes from pilot programs to production scale.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-structural-shift-pre-2026-vs-now">The structural shift: Pre-2026 vs. now</h2> <p>The change isn’t incremental. It’s architectural.</p> <figure class="wp-block-table"><div class="overflow-table-wrapper"><table class="has-fixed-layout"><thead><tr><td><strong>Dimension</strong></td><td><strong>Pre-2026 Reality</strong></td><td><strong>FY2026 Standard</strong></td><td><strong>CIO Priority</strong></td><td><strong>Business Impact</strong></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Learning Design</strong></td><td>Static curricula updated annually</td><td>AI-adaptive pathways that evolve with role changes</td><td>Platform flexibility and integration</td><td>Faster skill readiness, reduced time-to-productivity</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Analytics</strong></td><td>Completion metrics, survey scores</td><td>Predictive skill intelligence tied to performance data</td><td>Data integration across HR, LMS and business systems</td><td>Reduced productivity risk, proactive gap closure</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Engagement</strong></td><td>Scheduled training events</td><td>Always-on learning embedded in workflow</td><td>Experience design and mobile-first delivery</td><td>Higher retention, continuous skill building</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Delivery Model</strong></td><td>Open enrollment courses</td><td>Private cohorts and B2I partnerships</td><td>Ecosystem partnerships with universities</td><td>New revenue streams, custom talent pipelines</td></tr><tr><td><strong>AI Usage</strong></td><td>Experimental pilots in L&amp;D</td><td>Embedded intelligence across all learning touchpoints</td><td>Governance, ethics and trust frameworks</td><td>Scalable personalization, automated intervention</td></tr></tbody></table> </div></figure> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="agentic-ai-learning-that-lives-inside-work">Agentic AI: Learning that lives inside work</h2> <p>The next acceleration comes from AI agents — autonomous systems that act on intent, not just instructions. BCG’s analysis on how AI agents are transforming B2B sales (<a href="https://www.bcg.com/publications/2025/how-ai-agents-will-transform-b2b-sales" rel="nofollow">BCG report</a>) points to something bigger than sales automation.</p> <p>In learning ecosystems, AI agents will:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Function as always-on digital coaches</li> <li>Recommend courses based on live project data</li> <li>Coordinate learning across HR, CRM and operational systems</li>
</ul> <p>A quarter of organizations deploying GenAI will use AI agents in 2025, with adoption projected to reach 50% by 2027, according to <a href="https://www.deloitte.com/us/en/about/press-room/deloitte-technology-media-telecom-2025-predictions.html" rel="nofollow">Deloitte Technology 2025 predictions</a>. When learning lives inside work instead of beside it, development stops being something you schedule and becomes something that happens continuously.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-market-is-betting-big">The market is betting big</h2> <p>The numbers tell the growth story. The corporate E-Learning market size is expected to reach USD 401.48 billion in 2025 and grow at a CAGR of 18.36% to reach USD 1048.69 billion by 2030, according to <a href="https://www.snsinsider.com/reports/e-learning-market-1571" rel="nofollow">SNS Insider Report</a> on e-learning market. That’s not linear growth. That’s compound acceleration.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-works-right-now">What works right now</h2> <p>The organizations I work with that are winning treat learning platforms like they treat ERP or CRM — as core enterprise systems that require integration, governance and executive ownership.</p> <p>They’re doing five things consistently:</p> <ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Embedding AI with clear guardrails</strong> <strong>is critical</strong>. Not every learning challenge requires AI, but when organizations deploy it, they must do so intentionally with strong governance. Many leadership teams still underestimate the role AI should play in shaping long-term learning and business strategy, creating a widening gap between organizations that treat AI as foundational and those that approach it tactically.</li> <li><strong>Partnering deeply with academic institutions.</strong> Not just buying courses. Building custom pathways that map to actual business needs and career progression.</li> <li><strong>Investing in private cohorts.</strong> Closed learning communities where employees, partners and customers learn together create network effects that open courses can’t match.</li> <li><strong>Measuring what matters.</strong> Not completion rates. Business outcomes. C-suites will ask for proof of value: reduced risk, faster time-to-competency, higher sales win rates or lower error rates.</li> <li><strong>Treating learning as change management.</strong> AI means change, over and over again, and in the absence of change, fitness, individuals, teams and organizations will continue to struggle. The organizations that build change fitness into their learning architecture will absorb new tools faster than competitors.</li>
</ol> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The era of treating learning as a cost center ended when COVID-19 forced us to prove that digital learning could actually work. What’s emerging isn’t just online training — it’s an intelligent infrastructure where AI predicts skill gaps, personalizes pathways and embeds learning directly into workflows. The question for CIOs isn’t whether to invest in corporate learning platforms, but whether they can afford to lag while competitors turn training budgets into strategic advantages.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Is Your Organization Wired to Resist AI?]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/organizational-entrenchment]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/organizational-entrenchment]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Expose where the problem lies and start fixing it.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The end of AI as an experiment: Designing for what comes next in 2026]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136026/the-end-of-ai-as-an-experiment-designing-for-what-comes-next-in-2026.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136026/the-end-of-ai-as-an-experiment-designing-for-what-comes-next-in-2026.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>After years of building AI-native companies and partnering with Fortune 500 teams through large-scale technology transformations, I’ve watched AI follow a familiar, deceptive path. It starts as a spark of an idea. Then a pilot. Then, almost without ceremony, it becomes part of the machinery that keeps the business running.</p> <p>This transition is no longer subtle.</p> <p>For a long time, enterprise AI lived in a protected space. We kept our proofs of concept (PoCs) separate from systems that carried real operational risk. Experiments ran alongside the business, not inside it. That separation has vanished.</p> <p>Today, AI is embedded in the everyday. It routes our work, prioritizes our actions, and increasingly, makes decisions on our behalf. Much of this is happening quietly, without fanfare, and dangerously often without a clear sense of who is accountable when the logic fails.</p> <p>This is the moment leaders must lean in. When AI stops being an experiment, the question is no longer “Should we adopt it?” The real question is whether your organization is designed to live with it, govern it, and ultimately trust it.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">From momentum to exposure</h2> <p>In the early days of enterprise AI, speed was our primary currency. We moved fast to show progress, focusing on visible wins that looked great in a slide deck. <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/quantumblack/our-insights/the-state-of-ai-in-2024-and-generative-ais-next-act">As McKinsey’s 2024 report on the “Next Act” of Generative AI notes</a>, this momentum was vital for learning what was possible.</p> <p>But that speed masked a harder reality: we weren’t asking how these systems would behave once they were no longer isolated.</p> <p>Modern enterprises are always on. Our systems are hyperconnected, and decisions cascade in milliseconds. AI is no longer on the sidelines; it is the engine under the hood of our routing logic and classification engines. At this point, AI isn’t just a tool; it’s your operating model.</p> <p>This is where many organizations experience what I call the exposure gap. It’s not that the technology suddenly breaks; it’s that governance hasn’t kept up. Ownership is diffuse, oversight is inconsistent and trust is assumed rather than earned.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a>Reliability as the new North Star</h2> <p>We used to define AI success by capability: Can it summarize faster? Can it reduce manual effort? These are yesterday’s metrics.</p> <p>As AI moves into core processes, we must ask: Does it fail gracefully? Does it respond predictably under pressure? Does it introduce silent risks that compound over time? At this stage, reliability matters more than novelty.</p> <p>Every major platform shift undergoes this reckoning. Cloud adoption forced us to rethink availability and fault tolerance. AI is now forcing a similar shift at the decision layer. <a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/focus/tech-trends.html" rel="nofollow">As Deloitte’s Tech Trends 2025 emphasizes</a>, technologies that run the business must move from experimental to exponentially dependable, requiring a complete rethink of the IT stack.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">Architecture for the real world: modular logic</h2> <p>To achieve this trust, we have to rethink how we build. I’ve noticed that the organizations getting this right rely on one core principle: Composability.</p> <p>In many early projects, AI logic was tightly coupled, meaning it was so woven into the software that you couldn’t adjust the AI without breaking the entire workflow. This creates a black box that is impossible to audit.</p> <p>The alternative is treating AI as modular blocks of logic.</p> <p>By building with interchangeable parts, you gain three critical advantages:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Isolated risk:</strong> You can unplug a specific AI module if it drifts, without halting the entire business.</li> <li><strong>Gradual integration:</strong> You can introduce intelligence into one specific step of a workflow rather than a big bang overhaul.</li> <li><strong>Clear boundaries:</strong> You define exactly where AI authority begins and ends.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><a></a>Leadership after the experiment</h2> <p>When AI was an experiment, leaders could afford to push responsibility down to technical teams. Those days are over. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4113214/ai-hits-the-boardroom-what-directors-will-demand-from-cios-in-2026.html">As CIO.com recently highlighted regarding AI in the boardroom</a>, unmanaged AI is now seen as a fiduciary risk. Accountability has moved up.</p> <p>In my conversations with C-suite peers, one realization keeps surfacing: Approving AI tools is the easy part. Owning the behavior of those tools is the real challenge.</p> <p>Diffuse ownership works when systems are optional. It fails when they run at scale. The leaders who are most effective today aren’t chasing the next breakthrough; they are asking quieter, harder questions: Who is responsible when the automation falls short? How do we learn without putting the brand at risk?</p> <p>This isn’t a standoff between innovation and caution. <a href="https://www.accenture.com/us-en/insights/technology/technology-trends-2024" rel="nofollow">Accenture’s Technology Vision 2024 captures this shift well</a>, framing the transition from AI as a standalone capability to a pervasive, human-centric infrastructure. It’s a shift toward stewardship.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">My architect’s blueprint: Moving beyond the pilot</h2> <p>If you are a leader watching AI migrate into your core machinery, your agenda must shift from signing off on pilots to architecting for impact. Based on the transformations I’ve led, here is the stewardship blueprint I recommend for the next 90 days:</p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Stop the ownership vacuum:</strong> The most dangerous AI is the one that belongs to everyone and no one. Move beyond the center of excellence and appoint business model owners. If an AI system makes a catastrophic routing error today, whose phone rings? If you don’t have a single name, you have a structural failure.</li> <li><strong>Mandate decision layer observability:</strong> Traditional IT monitoring (uptime) is useless for AI. You need to log the quality of decisions. Mandate decision logging where every autonomous action is traceable. Establish confidence thresholds — if a model’s certainty drops below a set level, it must automatically trigger a human in the loop.</li> <li><strong>Engineer for graceful failure:</strong> Reliability isn’t the absence of failure; it is the ability to recover without collapse. Perform AI red teaming to see what happens when your logic meets messy real-world data. <a href="https://www.forrester.com/blogs/how-to-build-ai-red-teams-that-actually-work/">This shift toward probabilistic risk modeling</a> is what separates resilient enterprises from those prone to silent failures.</li>
</ol> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">The final reckoning</h2> <p>The era of the AI science project is over. We have entered the era of AI stewardship. Our goal is no longer to prove the technology works — the world knows it does. Our goal is to prove that our organizations are disciplined enough to handle it.</p> <p>Leadership is no longer about chasing the breakthrough; it’s about owning the behavior of the systems we choose to build.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Is the ArchiMate Motivation Layer Useless in Practice?]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/is-the-archimate-motivation-layer-useless-in-practice/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/is-the-archimate-motivation-layer-useless-in-practice/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Why strategic traceability often looks rigorous—but changes very little]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Is the ArchiMate Motivation Layer Useless in Practice?]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.eatransformation.com/p/is-the-archimate-motivation-layer-useless]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.eatransformation.com/p/is-the-archimate-motivation-layer-useless]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Why strategic traceability often looks rigorous&#8212;but changes very little]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Key strategic decisions for your AI-ready data center]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136004/key-strategic-decisions-for-your-ai-ready-data-center.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136004/key-strategic-decisions-for-your-ai-ready-data-center.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The infrastructure demands of modern data centers are undergoing a fundamental shift. As organizations deploy increasingly complex AI/ML models, high-performance computing clusters and real-time analytics platforms, traditional scale-up architectures have reached their limits. For CIOs, CTOs and data center managers, the question is no longer whether to adopt scale-out networking, but how to build it strategically into their overall data center strategy.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-understanding-scale-out-architecture">1. Understanding scale-out architecture</h2> <p>For decades, the default strategy was simple: When you needed more capacity, you bought a bigger box. Scale-out architecture takes a fundamentally different approach by distributing workloads across many interconnected nodes. This aligns naturally with how modern applications actually work. AI training, distributed databases and containerized applications all benefit from horizontal scaling, where adding nodes increases capacity linearly.</p> <p>Both approaches will coexist in most environments. The key is understanding which architecture serves each use case and ensuring your network infrastructure supports both.</p> <p><strong>⚠️ Recommendation:</strong> Scale-out does not automatically mean efficiency. Distributing workloads across more nodes can <em>reduce</em> overall efficiency if you don’t explicitly design for communication, synchronization and latency. In large AI systems, poorly planned scale-out architectures can lead to idle GPUs and XPUs and diminishing returns as clusters grow.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-architecture-and-hardware-choices">2. Architecture and hardware choices</h2> <p>The architecture you choose today will either enable or constrain your AI-factories’ output for years. Smart design starts with building for growth and dynamic changes of AI workloads and use cases, not just current requirements.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="designing-for-flexibility-and-high-availability">Designing for flexibility and high availability</h3> <p>Modern scale-out networks must expand seamlessly without service interruption. This requires design patterns where adding capacity means connecting new nodes, not rearchitecting existing infrastructure. Build robust telemetry, fast failure detection and rapid recovery mechanisms into the architecture from day one.</p> <p><strong>⚠️</strong><strong> Recommendation:</strong> Optimize for architecture, not headline metrics. High port speeds do not guarantee better AI performance. Systems often hit limits due to latency variance and unpredictable behavior under load. Hardware should be evaluated on deterministic performance and consistency, not just peak throughput.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="strategic-hardware-selection">Strategic hardware selection</h3> <p>Hardware choices ripple through your infrastructure for years. High-density switching forms the backbone of scale-out networks. Look for switches offering substantial port density with throughput measured in terabits per second.</p> <p>Modern deployments increasingly require <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3821050/internet-upgrade-upgrade-part-of-a-move-towards-400g-and-800g-connectivity.html">400GE connections with clear upgrade paths to 800GE</a> and beyond. Your hardware must scale to support tens of thousands of nodes without bottlenecks. Evaluate not just headline speeds, but buffer architectures, switching fabrics and how your AI infrastructure handles specific traffic patterns.</p> <p><strong>⚠️</strong><strong> Recommendation:</strong> General-purpose hardware can add hidden overhead. Networking platforms optimized for broad enterprise use cases often carry functionality and architecture that adds latency and power overhead without benefiting AI workloads. Purpose-built designs typically deliver better performance per watt and more predictable behavior.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="future-proofing-your-investment">Future-proofing your investment</h3> <p>As you refresh equipment, you’ll inevitably run multiple generations simultaneously. Ensure newer hardware can coexist with legacy systems without creating performance cliffs or management nightmares.</p> <p>Open standards provide insurance against vendor lock-in and enable true interoperability. Monitor emerging standards like <a href="https://ultraethernet.org/ultra-ethernet-consortium-uec-launches-specification-1-0-transforming-ethernet-for-ai-and-hpc-at-scale/" rel="nofollow">ultra ethernet consortium (UEC) specifications</a> and <a href="https://standards.ieee.org/beyond-standards/ethernet-50th-anniversary/" rel="nofollow">IEEE standards for unified Ethernet</a>. While proprietary solutions may offer short-term advantages, open standards typically provide better long-term flexibility and competitive pricing.</p> <p><strong>⚠️ Watch out:</strong> How standards are applied defines outcomes. Open standards enable interoperability, but real-world results depend on how effectively they are implemented across the system. Evaluate systems holistically, including offload granularity, datapath design and integration with accelerators.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-performance-engineering">3. Performance engineering</h2> <p>Raw bandwidth means little if your network can’t deliver it consistently where needed. Performance engineering in scale-out environments requires attention to traffic patterns, congestion management and latency control.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="traffic-management-and-optimization">Traffic management and optimization</h3> <p>Traditional networks emphasized the north-south data traffic flowing up and down between AI client applications and AI servers. Scale-out architectures focus on east-west traffic between AI server nodes. Dynamic, workload-aware traffic control and load balancing become critical for intelligently spreading flows across available server nodes and communication paths, preventing hotspots.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="congestion-control-for-high-density-environments">Congestion control for high-density environments</h3> <p>When thousands of nodes communicate simultaneously, how you manage congestion determines network performance consistency.</p> <p>Priority flow control (PFC) pauses traffic when buffers fill, which is essential for workloads like Remote Direct Memory Access (RDMA) that cannot tolerate packet loss.</p> <p>Explicit congestion notification (ECN) offers a more sophisticated approach by marking packets when congestion develops, allowing endpoints to reduce transmission rates before buffers overflow. This helps manage congestion with less risk of widespread impact. Modern implementations also support <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JDYrIvgU6HI&amp;t=21s" rel="nofollow">packet trimming</a> during extreme congestion to maintain higher-priority flows.</p> <p>AI and HPC workloads often involve tightly coupled parallel processing, even small network performance variations can significantly impact job completion times.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="managing-latency">Managing latency</h3> <p>Scale-out networks typically exhibit higher latency than scale-up solutions. Physics dictates that traversing multiple network hops takes time. With proper design, you can maintain consistently low latency.</p> <p>Key techniques include proper buffer sizing, careful queue management and strategic placement of latency-sensitive components to minimize hop counts.</p> <p><strong>⚠️ Watch out:</strong> Average latency hides real bottlenecks. Many AI workloads are constrained by worst-case and tail latency, not averages. Latency spikes can directly reduce throughput, violate SLAs and waste GPU/XPU cycles.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-physical-and-financial-realities">4. Physical and financial realities</h2> <p>Network architecture must contend with physical constraints and financial realities that can derail even the best technical designs.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-infrastructure-trilogy-space-power-cooling">The infrastructure trilogy: Space, power, cooling</h3> <p>Conduct honest pre-deployment facility audits. Sometimes physical constraints make hybrid architectures or cloud expansion more practical than purely on-premises scale-out.</p> <p>High-density networking equipment generates substantial heat and consumes significant power. A single high-end switch can draw several kilowatts. Space constraints extend beyond physical rack capacity. High-density connections mean hundreds or thousands of cables that complicate maintenance and airflow. Heat dissipation may require heat containment, in-row cooling or even liquid cooling solutions.</p> <p><strong>⚠️</strong><strong> Watch out:</strong> Networking can become a hidden power tax. Inefficient designs increase power and cooling demands while delivering little additional performance. Evaluate efficiency based on delivered workload output, not port count alone.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="understanding-total-cost-of-ownership">Understanding total cost of ownership</h3> <p>Scale-out networking changes how you think about IT investment. It can create financial flexibility but requires different budgeting approaches.</p> <p>Capital expenditure extends beyond hardware purchase prices. Installation, integration and initial configuration add substantial costs. However, scale-out enables spreading investments across multiple budget cycles.</p> <p>Factor in power and cooling costs that compound over years, plus maintenance contracts, software licensing and personnel costs for specialized skills. Consider developing an AI efficiency index that quantifies how effectively your infrastructure supports revenue-generating AI workloads relative to total infrastructure spend.</p> <p><strong>⚠️ Watch out:</strong> TCO models often ignore utilization loss. Hardware pricing alone does not reflect true cost. Idle GPUs/XPUs caused by communication bottlenecks can substantially increase cost per workload. Include utilization, efficiency and output performance in ROI calculations.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="building-networks-for-the-next-decade">Building networks for the next decade</h2> <p>The shift to scale-out networking represents more than a technology upgrade. It’s a strategic realignment of infrastructure with how modern applications actually work. Distributing workloads across many nodes means individual failures have less impact, but you must design intentionally to realize this benefit. Success requires balancing innovation with stability, flexibility with cost control and immediate needs with future requirements.</p> <p>Organizations that thrive will view network infrastructure not as a static asset but as a dynamic platform that evolves with business needs. Scale-out networking, implemented strategically, provides exactly that foundation.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI "Vibe Coding" Threatens Open Source as Maintainers Face Crisis]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-floods-close-projects/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-floods-close-projects/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/ai-floods-close-projects/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771439339723.jpg"/><p>Daniel Stenberg shut down cURL's bug bounty after AI submissions hit 20%. Mitchell Hashimoto banned AI code from Ghostty. Steve Ruiz closed all external PRs to tldraw. Economic research shows "vibe coding" weakens the user engagement that sustains open source. As developers delegate to AI agents, documentation visits and bug reports collapse—threatening the ecosystem's viability.</p> <i>By Steef-Jan Wiggers</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[From Strategy to Execution: Celebrating Ardoq’s 2025 Partners of the Year]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/from-strategy-to-execution-celebrating-ardoqs-2025-partners-of-the-year/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/24/from-strategy-to-execution-celebrating-ardoqs-2025-partners-of-the-year/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Honoring the partners embedding Ardoq into how organizations plan, prioritize, and execute transformation. Enterprise Architecture has evolved. What was once focused on documentation and governance is now a critical driver of business transfo...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Quesma Releases OTelBench to Evaluate OpenTelemetry Infrastructure and AI Performance]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/quesma-otel-bench-performance-ai/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/quesma-otel-bench-performance-ai/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/quesma-otel-bench-performance-ai/en/headerimage/header-1771767302848.jpeg"/><p>Quesma has launched OTelBench, an open-source suite to benchmark OpenTelemetry pipelines and AI-driven instrumentation. It evaluates collector performance under stress while testing how accurately LLMs handle complex SRE tasks like context propagation. Initial data shows AI agents often achieve success rates below 30%, highlighting the gap between code generation and production observability.</p> <i>By Mark Silvester</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The “Death” Of IT Services Is Greatly Exaggerated]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/news-of-it-services-death-is-greatly-exaggerated/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/news-of-it-services-death-is-greatly-exaggerated/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[We’re seeing a spate of disruptive headlines and predictions around the demise of IT services. With the progress made by AI, specifically in software development, it’s easy to opine that traditional IT services are on their way out. This narrative is fundamentally flawed. Yes, AI-driven automation deflates the unit cost of technology work, but it [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Java News Roundup: JDK26-RC2, Payara Platform, Hibernate, Quarkus, Apache Camel, Jakarta EE 12]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb16-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb16-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb16-2026/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771882551481.jpg"/><p>This week's Java roundup for February 16th, 2026, features news highlighting: the second release candidate of JDK 26; an update on Jakarta EE 12; the February 2026 edition of Payara Platform; a point release of Apache Camel; and maintenance releases of Hibernate Search and Quarkus.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Gartner HR Survey Reveals Australian Job Market Confidence Has Hit a Three-Year Low]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-24-gartner-hr-survey-reveals-australian-job-market-confidence-has-hit-a-three-year-low?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-24-gartner-hr-survey-reveals-australian-job-market-confidence-has-hit-a-three-year-low?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Confidence among Australian employees in the availability of jobs has declined to its lowest level in more than three years, according to Gartner.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-24]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
