<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Mar 2026 08:07:13 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[MySQL 9.6 Changes Foreign Key Constraints and Cascade Handling]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/mysql-foreign-keys/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/mysql-foreign-keys/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/mysql-foreign-keys/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1770991790457.jpg"/><p>MySQL is changing the way foreign key constraints and cascades are managed. Starting with MySQL 9.6, foreign key validation and cascade actions are handled by the SQL layer rather than the InnoDB storage engine. This will improve change tracking, replication accuracy, and data consistency, making MySQL more reliable for CDC pipelines, mixed-database environments, and analytics workloads.</p> <i>By Renato Losio</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-28]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Trump administration bans Anthropic, seemingly embraces OpenAI]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4138822/trump-administration-bans-anthropic-escalating-clash-over-military-use-of-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4138822/trump-administration-bans-anthropic-escalating-clash-over-military-use-of-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The Trump administration on Friday moved to ban the use of products from artificial intelligence company Anthropic by federal businesses, escalating a high-stakes clash over whether private AI makers can limit how the US military uses their systems. Just hours later, Anthropic rival OpenAI’s CEO, Sam Altman, announced that his company had reached a deal to supply the Pentagon with its technology, ostensibly under the same terms that the military had rejected for Anthropic.</p> <p>Calling Anthropic “Leftwing nut jobs,” President Donald Trump said in a <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/116144552969293195" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Truth Social post</a> that he was directing “EVERY Federal Agency” to stop using Anthropic’s technology immediately. At the same time, the Pentagon prepared to designate the company a “supply chain risk,” a label more commonly associated with foreign adversaries’ tech products, such as telecom gear made by China’s Huawei.</p> <p>The decision follows an unusually public dispute between Anthropic and Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth over what the Pentagon called an “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2026/02/27/anthropic-pentagon-lethal-military-ai/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">all lawful purposes</a>” requirement, which means that once the military licenses an AI model, it must be free to deploy it for any lawful mission without being constrained by vendor-imposed safety policies.</p> <p>On X, Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth <a href="https://x.com/secwar/status/2027507717469049070" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">echoed</a> Trump’s criticism, saying “Cloaked in the sanctimonious rhetoric of ‘effective altruism,’ [Anthropic and CEO Dario Amodei] have attempted to strong-arm the United States military into submission – a cowardly act of corporate virtue-signaling that places Silicon Valley ideology above American lives.” He added, “Their true objective is unmistakable: to seize veto power over the operational decisions of the United States military. That is unacceptable.”</p> <p>In a late-night statement, Anthropic <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/statement-comments-secretary-war" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">responded</a> to the Pentagon, saying, “We have not yet received direct communication from the Department of War or the White House on the status of our negotiations.” It also said it believes the designation of supply chain risk “would both be legally unsound and set a dangerous precedent for any American company that negotiates with the government.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-six-month-clock-and-a-scramble-to-replace-claude">A six-month clock and a scramble to replace Claude</h2> <p>Under the plan, according to Axios, the Defense Department <a href="https://www.axios.com/2026/02/27/anthropic-pentagon-supply-chain-risk-claude" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">would sever a contract</a>, worth up to $200 million, with Anthropic, and require defense contractors and other vendors to certify they are not using Anthropic’s Claude model in work tied to the Pentagon. The administration is allowing a six-month window to give agencies and contractors time to transition to alternatives.</p> <p>That transition could be particularly disruptive, because Claude has been used in the military’s classified systems, systems that support some of the Pentagon’s most sensitive intelligence work, weapons development, and operational planning.</p> <p>Defense officials have described Claude as highly capable, and acknowledged that disentangling it from existing workflows would be difficult.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-the-administration-says-it-is-fighting-over">What the administration says it is fighting over</h2> <p>Anthropic argues that certain uses, especially mass domestic surveillance and fully autonomous weapons, should remain out of bounds.</p> <p>CEO Dario Amodei <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/statement-department-of-war" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">said</a> in an impassioned essay that the company cannot remove those guardrails “in good conscience,” warning that current AI systems are not reliable enough for fully autonomous lethal decision-making, and that large-scale surveillance carries significant risks of abuse.</p> <p>The Pentagon argues that the military already operates under its own rules and oversight, and cannot have mission decisions constrained by a vendor’s terms of service, particularly in gray areas where definitions of “surveillance” and “autonomy” can be contested.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-it-could-mean-for-us-national-security">What it could mean for US national security</h2> <p>In the near term, the administration’s move forces the Pentagon to manage a delicate transition: removing Anthropic’s model from classified environments while maintaining continuity for intelligence analysis and planning tasks that had begun to incorporate generative AI.</p> <p>The longer-term implications are broader. The ban signals that access to the federal market, particularly defense, may depend on accepting “all lawful use” terms, potentially reducing the leverage of AI companies that try to impose hard red lines on certain national security applications.</p> <p>It also raises practical questions for AI companies as government vendors. If the government pushes one leading AI provider out of sensitive systems, agencies and contractors may consolidate around a smaller number of alternatives, increasing dependence on whichever firms remain willing and able to operate in classified environments.</p> <p>These dislocations in critical military infrastructure could further pose a national security threat, some argue. US Sen. Mark R. Warner (D-VA), vice chairman of the Senate Intelligence Committee, <a href="https://www.warner.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/pressreleases?id=E1ABB7FA-9DE5-42A3-B7F2-D4D879FA4B00" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">said</a> the efforts by Trump and Secretary Hegseth pose a national security risk. “The president’s directive to halt the use of a leading American AI company across the federal government, combined with inflammatory rhetoric attacking that company, raises serious concerns about whether national security decisions are being driven by careful analysis or political considerations.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="competitors-could-move-in-grok-openai-and-google">Competitors could move in: Grok, OpenAI, and Google</h2> <p>The decision could reshape the competitive landscape.</p> <p>Elon Musk’s xAI <a href="https://www.axios.com/2026/02/23/ai-defense-department-deal-musk-xai-grok" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">has already signed</a> an agreement to bring its Grok model into classified military systems, in a development that positioned xAI as a potential replacement if Anthropic’s relationship with the Pentagon collapsed.</p> <p>However, significant concerns about Grok’s safety and reliability <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/elon-musk-xai-grok-security-safety-government-73ab4f6e" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">have surfaced</a> within parts of the federal government, even as the Pentagon approved it for classified settings, an early indication that “replacement” won’t be a simple matter of switching one model for another.</p> <p>Meanwhile, the Pentagon has been in discussions with OpenAI and Google about expanding their models’ availability from unclassified systems into more sensitive environments, Axios reported. The discussions with OpenAi apparently bore fruit, given that less than seven hours after Trump’s Truth Social post, OpenAI’s Altman <a href="https://x.com/sama/status/2027578508042723599?s=46&amp;t=yxYBta0zhKqvzUP8zCYxjw" rel="nofollow">posted</a> on Twitter, “we reached an agreement with the Department of War to deploy our models in their classified network.”</p> <p>In an apparent about-face, however, the Pentagon appeared to accept from OpenAI the same terms it rejected for Anthropic. “Two of our most important safety principles are prohibitions on domestic mass surveillance and human responsibility for the use of force, including for autonomous weapon systems,” Altman wrote. “The DoW agrees with these principles, reflects them in law and policy, and we put them into our agreement.”</p> <p>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman has also sought to position his company as aligned with Anthropic’s core ethical objections, while still pursuing Pentagon business. Altman had said OpenAI <a href="https://www.npr.org/2026/02/27/nx-s1-5729118/trump-anthropic-pentagon-openai-ai-weapons-ban" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">shares</a> “red lines” against mass surveillance of Americans and weapons that can fire without human oversight, even as it explores a path to work with the Defense Department.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="political-and-industry-backlash-begins-to-surface">Political and industry backlash begins to surface</h2> <p>Even among competitors, the Anthropic fight produced unusual sympathy.</p> <p>Hundreds of employees at Google and OpenAI <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/26/technology/google-deepmind-letter-pentagon.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">backed</a> Anthropic in a petition, underscoring internal tensions across the AI industry over military applications. One factor that could derail the ban on Anthropic is unified AI sector rejection.</p> <p>Peter Madsen, former professor of ethics and social responsibility at Carnegie Mellon University and executive director of the Center for the Advancement of Applied Ethics and Political Philosophy, said in an interview, “Every other AI company should commit to the same ideals as Anthropic so that Trump will have to use an ethical AI firm, not one that will cower to his whims.”</p> <p>Anthropic has said it would cooperate with a transition to avoid disruption to ongoing missions, while noting it had not yet said whether it would challenge the “supply chain risk” designation in court.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-happens-next">What happens next</h2> <p>The administration’s decision sets up several immediate test cases.</p> <p>First, agencies and contractors must determine how deeply Anthropic’s tools are embedded in their operations and how quickly they can migrate without degrading performance or security.</p> <p>Second, rivals will face their own balancing act: how to satisfy Pentagon demands for “all lawful use,” or in the case of OpenAI, walk the fine line of its safety principles, while managing internal and external scrutiny over surveillance, autonomy, and the risk of AI systems behaving unpredictably in high-stakes settings.</p> <p>Finally, the ban raises a fundamental policy question that goes beyond Anthropic: in the race to deploy frontier AI for national security, who sets the boundaries: the government that needs operational flexibility, or the private companies that build and control access to the technology?</p> <p><em>This article has been updated from its original version to reflect the late night announcement by OpenAI that it had reached a deal with the Pentagon.</em></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-28]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
