<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:22:35 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[GlassFish 8.0 Delivers Compatibility with Jakarta EE 11, Enhanced Security and Improved Data Access]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/glassfish-8-released/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/glassfish-8-released/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/glassfish-8-released/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771252732288.jpg"/><p>After 15 milestone releases, the Eclipse Foundation has released version 8.0 of GlassFish featuring support for virtual threads; enhanced application security; and improved data access. GlassFish 8.0 is a compatible implementation of Jakarta EE 11. Ondro Mihályi, Java Champion and co-founder of OmniFish, spoke to InfoQ about GlassFish 8.0.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-17]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Maximizing HR Technology’s Investment Impact: A CHRO’s Guide]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/human-resources/insights/hr-technology-transformation]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/human-resources/insights/hr-technology-transformation]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Discover how to align HR’s AI investments to transformational activites to accelerate impact.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Agoda’s API Agent Converts Any API to MCP with Zero Code and Deployments]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/agoda-api-agent/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/agoda-api-agent/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/agoda-api-agent/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1770265458956.jpg"/><p>Agoda engineers developed API Agent, enabling a single MCP server to access any internal REST or GraphQL API with zero code and zero deployments. The system reduces overhead from multiple APIs, supports AI-assisted queries, and uses in-memory SQL post-processing for safe, scalable data handling across internal services.</p> <i>By Leela Kumili</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Agoda’s API Agent Converts Any API to MCP with Zero Code and Deployments]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/agoda-api-agent/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/agoda-api-agent/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/agoda-api-agent/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1770265458956.jpg"/><p>Agoda engineers developed API Agent, enabling a single MCP server to access any internal REST or GraphQL API with zero code and zero deployments. The system reduces overhead from multiple APIs, supports AI-assisted queries, and uses in-memory SQL post-processing for safe, scalable data handling across internal services.</p> <i>By Leela Kumili</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Breaking the Silos: The Rise of the Open Lakehouse Architecture in 2026]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/artificial-intelligence/breaking-the-silos-the-rise-of-the-open-lakehouse-architecture-in-2026/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/artificial-intelligence/breaking-the-silos-the-rise-of-the-open-lakehouse-architecture-in-2026/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Bala Kalavala, Chief Architect &#38; Technology Evangelist Introduction In the evolving data landscape of 2026, the Open Lakehouse has transitioned from an emerging architectural pattern to the gold standard for enterprise data strategy. By merging the <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/artificial-intelligence/breaking-the-silos-the-rise-of-the-open-lakehouse-architecture-in-2026/" title="Breaking the Silos: The Rise of the Open Lakehouse Architecture in 2026">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Breaking the Silos: The Rise of the Open Lakehouse Architecture in 2026]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/16/breaking-the-silos-the-rise-of-the-open-lakehouse-architecture-in-2026/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/16/breaking-the-silos-the-rise-of-the-open-lakehouse-architecture-in-2026/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Bala Kalavala, Chief Architect &#038; Technology Evangelist Introduction In the evolving data landscape of 2026, the Open Lakehouse has transitioned from an emerging architectural pattern to the gold standard for enterprise data strategy. By merging ...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Giving AI ‘hands’ in your SaaS stack]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132320/giving-ai-hands-in-your-saas-stack.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132320/giving-ai-hands-in-your-saas-stack.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>I love AI copilots. I also don’t trust them with write access.</p> <p>That’s not a philosophical stance. It’s an operator scar. In high-growth startups, helpful automation has a habit of turning into a 2 a.m. incident when it gets too much privilege and not enough supervision. Now we’re wiring large language models to the same systems that run lead-to-cash, billing, provisioning and customer support.</p> <p>I’ve spent the last 15 years building the commerce engine for some of Silicon Valley’s fastest-growing companies. From the early, scrappy days at Eventbrite to architecting the lead-to-cash systems that supported Slack’s IPO and now leading enterprise systems at Gusto, I’ve lived through every phase of the business technology maturity curve.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="moving-from-talk-to-action-without-going-off-the-rails">Moving from talk to action without going off the rails</h2> <p>For most of that time, my job was to build deterministic rails for deterministic trains. If a sales rep updated a contract in Salesforce, we built rigid, unforgiving integrations to ensure that data flowed perfectly into NetSuite and Snowflake. It was binary: it worked or it failed.</p> <h5 class="wp-block-heading">[ <strong>Related</strong>: <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/969119/what-is-sase-a-cloud-service-that-marries-sd-wan-with-security.html">SASE explained</a> ]</h5> <p>But we are now at an inflection point that scares me as much as it excites me. We are moving from the era of chat with your data where AI is a passive oracle to the era of work with your data. We are giving AI agents hands.</p> <p>We are asking these probabilistic models to not just summarize a deal, but to update the record, provision the license and email the customer. We are connecting stochastic reasoning engines to mission-critical systems of record. As someone who has spent sleepless nights worrying about data integrity during financial audits, I can tell you that the potential for <a href="https://genai.owasp.org/llm-top-10/" rel="nofollow">Excessive Agency</a> — an OWASP Top 10 vulnerability where an agent does more than you intended — is the single biggest risk keeping IT leaders up at night.</p> <p>I’m seeing a lot of leaders paralyzed by this risk, while others are recklessly handing out API keys. There is a middle ground. Drawing from my experience stabilizing complex stacks at Gusto and OneTrust, I want to lay out a pragmatic architecture for safe agency — how to let AI take the wheel without driving your GTM stack off a cliff.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-god-mode-trap">The God-mode trap</h2> <p>In the early days of a startup, as I vividly recall from my time at Eventbrite, velocity is everything. You embed technical teams directly into sales ops or CX just to keep the lights on. In that environment, if you were deploying an AI agent today, the temptation would be to create a single Salesforce integration user with system administrator privileges and let the agent run wild.</p> <p>I call this the God-mode anti-pattern and it is catastrophic.</p> <p>If an attacker manages to use an indirect prompt injection — hiding malicious instructions in a calendar invite or a web page the agent reads — that agent essentially becomes a confused deputy. It has the keys to the kingdom. It can delete opportunities, export customer lists or modify pricing configurations.</p> <p>When I joined Gusto to lead business technology, one of my priorities was data trust. You cannot have trust if your non-human actors have unfettered access. We moved away from the wild west of shared credentials toward a model of rigorous identity governance.</p> <p>For AI agents, this means we must treat them as non-human identities (NHIs) with the same or greater scrutiny than we apply to employees.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pillar-1-the-tool-gateway">Pillar 1: The tool gateway</h2> <p>At Gusto, we didn’t just wire systems together; we used middleware like Workato and MuleSoft to create a commerce engine that sanitized data flow. For AI agents, you need a similar architectural buffer. You should never connect an LLM directly to your raw system APIs.</p> <p>Instead, you need a Tool Gateway.</p> <p>Think of this as an air traffic controller. The agent doesn’t see your complex Salesforce schema or your NetSuite SOAP API. It sees a simplified, virtualized set of tools that you define.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Schema virtualization: Instead of giving the agent access to the user object, you give it a tool called onboard_new_customer(name, email). The gateway handles the translation.</li> <li>Semantic validation: This is critical. The gateway checks if the action makes business sense before passing it to the backend. For example, “Is the start date before the end date?” or “Does this discount exceed the 20% threshold?”</li>
</ul> <p>The industry is coalescing around the <a href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/" rel="nofollow">model context protocol (MCP)</a> as a standard for this layer. It provides a universal USB-C port for connecting AI models to your data sources. By using an MCP server as your gateway, you ensure the agent never sees the credentials or the full API surface area, only the tools you explicitly allow.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pillar-2-identity-is-context">Pillar 2: Identity is context</h2> <p>When I was architecting systems at Slack, we constantly dealt with the concept of user context. If a sales rep in London searches for a contract, they should only see UK contracts.</p> <p>AI agents often break this because they use a service account that sees everything.</p> <p>To fix this, we need to lean on the OAuth 2.0 on-behalf-of (OBO) flow. When a user asks an AI agent to “update this deal,” the agent shouldn’t act as the AI; it should exchange the user’s token to act as that specific user.</p> <p>This means the underlying platform (Salesforce, Workday, etc.) enforces its existing permission rules. If the user doesn’t have permission to view executive compensation, the agent acting on their behalf won’t either. This simple architectural decision saves you from having to rebuild your entire authorization model inside the AI layer.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pillar-3-the-dry-run-rule">Pillar 3: The dry-run rule</h2> <p>One of the cultural shifts I drove at Gusto was improving devex (developer experience) and stabilizing our release pipelines with CI/CD tools like Gearset. We treated infrastructure changes with extreme caution.</p> <p>We need to treat AI actions with the same reverence. My rule for autonomous agents is simple: If it can’t dry run, it doesn’t ship.</p> <p>Every state-changing tool (POST, PUT, DELETE) exposed to an agent must support a dry_run=true mode. When the agent wants to update a record, it first calls the tool in dry-run mode. The system returns a diff — a preview of exactly what will change (e.g., “Status will change from Active to Churned”).</p> <p>This allows us to implement a human-in-the-loop approval gate for high-risk actions. The agent proposes the change, the human confirms it and only then is the live transaction executed. This prevents the nightmare scenario we saw with the <a href="https://www.eweek.com/news/replit-ai-coding-assistant-failure/" rel="nofollow">recent failure where an AI recursively deleted a database because it lacked context awareness</a>.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="pillar-4-transactional-safety-nets">Pillar 4: Transactional safety nets</h2> <p>Finally, we have to accept that agents are probabilistic. They will hallucinate. They will retry due to network blips. They will get confused.</p> <p>In the distributed systems we built at Slack and Ethos, we relied on two patterns that are non-negotiable for agentic AI:</p> <ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Idempotency keys: Every time an agent intends to take an action, it must generate a unique ID. If the agent gets confused and tries to create an invoice three times, the gateway sees the same key and ensures the action only happens once. This <a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-httpapi-idempotency-key-header/" rel="nofollow">idempotency key pattern</a> is common in payments, but it is now mandatory for AI.</li> <li>Compensating transactions (sagas): If an agent successfully creates a user in Salesforce but fails to create them in NetSuite, you have a data integrity failure. Since we can’t easily do atomic transactions across different SaaS clouds, we need <a href="https://microservices.io/patterns/data/saga.html" rel="nofollow">compensating transactions</a> effectively with an undo button. If step 2 fails, the system automatically triggers a rollback of step 1.</li>
</ol> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-leadership-perspective">The leadership perspective</h2> <p>Leadership isn’t about being perfect; it’s about being present and navigating challenges with resilience. The same applies to our technology strategy. We cannot wait for AI to be perfect before we use it.</p> <p>At Gusto, by stabilizing our platform and putting these guardrails in place, we were able to ship AI-assisted automations that classify and route incoming tickets, removing manual drudgery for our CX teams and accelerating handling times. We didn’t do it by being reckless; we did it by building a trust architecture first.</p> <p>As CIOs and IT leaders, our job isn’t to say “no” to AI. It’s to build the invisible rails that allow the business to say “yes” safely. By focusing on gateways, identity and transactional safety, we can give AI the hands it needs to do real work, without losing our grip on the wheel.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Harness AI for HR Transformation]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/hr-transformation]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/articles/hr-transformation]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[HR is at a crossroads: reinvent itself to deliver business value in the AI era or risk becoming irrelevant. CHROs need to act—now.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Don’t rip and replace PeopleSoft — pair it with emerging tech instead]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132315/dont-rip-and-replace-peoplesoft-pair-it-with-emerging-tech-instead.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132315/dont-rip-and-replace-peoplesoft-pair-it-with-emerging-tech-instead.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For over a decade, enterprise technology conversations have been dominated by one belief: <em>legacy ERP systems must be replaced for organizations to innovate</em>. Many cloud-first strategies, AI-led transformation programs and digital experience initiatives often begin with the idea that “ERP is holding the business back.”</p> <p>In real enterprise environments, the situation looks very different.</p> <p>In my experience working on ERP modernization initiatives and with IT leaders, PeopleSoft continues to run payroll for hundreds of thousands of employees, close the books, enforce financial controls, support audit cycles and anchor enterprise planning processes. These systems are not peripheral. They are central to how organizations operate and how leaders manage risk.</p> <p>As enterprise technology leaders face growing pressure to adopt emerging technologies such as AI, real-time analytics and intelligent automation, I have seen a consistent pattern emerge. Innovation does not require replacing PeopleSoft. Instead, it requires repositioning it. The result is a growing shift toward a hybrid ERP model, where PeopleSoft remains the authoritative system of record while emerging technologies deliver agility, intelligence and modern experiences around it.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-rip-and-replace-often-fails">Why ‘rip and replace’ often fails</h2> <p>ERP replacement projects are often justified in the language of modernization, but their risks are rarely discussed with the same intensity.</p> <p>In practice, ERP replacement is one of the highest-risk initiatives a CIO can sponsor, especially when it involves payroll, financial close and compliance. Industry research supports what many CIOs already know from experience. According to <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/information-technology/topics/enterprise-resource-planning" rel="nofollow">Gartner</a>, more than 70 percent of ERP projects fail to fully achieve their original business goals and up to 25 percent fail catastrophically when not aligned with strategic priorities.</p> <p>In one PeopleSoft HCM environment I worked with, the greatest risk was not innovation speed but payroll timing and exception handling. Even minor hiccups had a direct employee and compliance impact and made a wholesale replacement impossible.</p> <p>I have seen firsthand how even well-funded ERP replacement programs struggle once they encounter real-world complexity such as customization, regulatory constraints and reporting dependencies.</p> <p>In HR and finance PeopleSoft systems, even minor disruptions can erode employee trust and trigger compliance issues. Extended timelines, cost overruns and reporting regressions are common. This is why many leaders recognize that stability in core systems is not technical inertia. <em>It is business protection</em>.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-cios-are-doing-instead">What CIOs are doing instead</h2> <p>Rather than treating PeopleSoft as an obstacle to innovation, forward-looking enterprise leaders are treating it as an anchor.</p> <p>Across multiple organizations I have worked with, the same hybrid pattern appears.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>PeopleSoft HCM, FSCM and EPM remain the system of record for foundational transactions, compliance and financial integrity.</li> <li>Emerging technologies such as AI overlays, event-driven integration and real-time analytics are introduced outside the core.</li> <li>Innovation is decoupled from stability, enabling modern capabilities without jeopardizing essential operations.</li>
</ul> <p>This model does not delay modernization. It redefines it.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="hybrid-erp-architecture-explained">Hybrid ERP architecture explained</h2> <p>At its core, hybrid ERP is an architectural and governance choice.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-the-erp-core-authority-and-trust">1. The ERP core: Authority and trust</h3> <p>PeopleSoft continues to anchor workforce transactions and payroll, general ledger, payables, receivables, assets and enterprise planning.</p> <p>From a leadership perspective, this layer exists to protect accuracy, auditability and control. Changes occur deliberately, not continuously, because the cost of error is high.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-integration-and-event-layer-responsiveness">2. Integration and event layer: Responsiveness</h3> <p>One of the most effective shifts I have seen is exposing ERP capabilities through APIs and event mechanisms, which makes PeopleSoft more responsive.</p> <p>This enables:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Real-time propagation of transactions</li> <li>Triggered workflows to downstream tools</li> <li>Reduced reliance on batch processing</li>
</ul> <p>This allows PeopleSoft to participate in real-time enterprise workflows without rewriting core logic.</p> <p>Composable, API-first approaches are rapidly taking hold, with industry projections showing 30% adoption of modular architectures in new enterprise applications by 2027, according to <a href="https://www.integrate.io/blog/data-integration-adoption-rates-enterprises" rel="nofollow">Integrate.io</a>.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-intelligence-layer-insight-without-control-loss">3. Intelligence layer: Insight without control loss</h3> <p>AI and advanced analytics increasingly consume ERP data to provide insights such as:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Predictive workforce trends</li> <li>Anomaly detection in financial transactions</li> <li>Scenario forecasting in planning cycles</li>
</ul> <p>In my experience, the most successful CIOs draw a clear boundary. AI advises. ERP decides. Intelligence layers enhance judgment, but they do not bypass financial or HR controls.</p> <p>By 2027, at least <a href="https://threadgoldconsulting.com/research/ai-in-erp-systems" rel="nofollow">50% of AI-enabled ERP systems</a> are expected to incorporate generative AI capabilities. This reinforces the emerging reality that AI is not a replacement for ERP, but an amplifier of its value, as highlighted in recent industry research.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-experience-layer-modern-interaction">4. Experience layer: Modern interaction</h3> <p>User experience is often the major complaint about ERP. Hybrid models solve this without invasive ERP customization.</p> <p>Modern dashboards, workflow tools and manager self-service interfaces can be delivered externally. This option can help alleviate the burden of customizing PeopleSoft itself, which has been a common experience for many organizations after spending years working with fragile customizations.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="peoplesoft-use-cases-that-matter">PeopleSoft use cases that matter</h2> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>HCM. </strong>Hybrid models maintain PeopleSoft payroll and core HR while using analytics platforms to identify attrition risk, skill shortages and hiring bottlenecks.</li> <li><strong>FSCM. </strong>Finance leaders gain real-time visibility into spend and close status without compromising internal controls or audit integrity.</li> <li><strong>EPM. </strong>Scenario modeling and rolling forecasts operate outside the core planning engine, while authoritative planning data remains anchored in PeopleSoft.</li>
</ul> <p>Across all three domains, the pattern holds: PeopleSoft anchors trust; emerging tech accelerates insight<em>.</em></p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-governance-is-the-deciding-factor">Why governance is the deciding factor</h2> <p>In every successful hybrid ERP environment I have seen, governance, not tooling, makes the difference.</p> <p>ERP leaders who succeed define clear boundaries:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>ERP retains transactional authority</li> <li>AI and analytics deliver insights, not uncontrolled write-backs</li> <li>Integration paths are auditable and intentional</li>
</ul> <p>This governance model allows innovation to move faster because the core remains stable. It protects financial integrity and HR compliance while enabling innovation to advance independently.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="common-pitfalls-to-avoid">Common pitfalls to avoid</h2> <p>Poor execution arises when:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI systems are permitted to write directly into core ERP without safeguards</li> <li>Business logic is replicated outside ERP, creating divergence</li> <li>Integration remains batch-oriented, diminishing responsiveness</li> <li>Hybrid strategy is treated as temporary rather than strategic</li>
</ul> <p>These failures are not inherent to PeopleSoft or emerging technology. They are symptoms of architectural ambiguity.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="repositioning-erp-for-the-future">Repositioning ERP for the future</h2> <p>The future of PeopleSoft is not determined by replacement timelines, but instead by <em>relevance and reinvention</em>.</p> <p>In the hybrid model, ERP is no longer perceived as a bottleneck, but as an <em>enterprise anchor with extensible boundaries</em>. Emerging technologies do not diminish ERP’s role; rather, they will reinforce and enhance that role.</p> <p>Based on what I am seeing across large enterprises, the organizations that thrive in 2026 and beyond will not be those that rushed to replace ERP systems. They will be the ones that understood where ERP belongs in a modern architecture and built intelligently around it.</p> <p>Innovation does not require abandoning systems of record. It requires knowing how to let them do what they do best, while embracing what comes next.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The carbon cost of an API call]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132293/the-carbon-cost-of-an-api-call.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132293/the-carbon-cost-of-an-api-call.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Imagine opening your monthly cloud invoice and seeing a 200% spike in a single line item. This is the new reality for AI-native companies. What was once a predictable compute budget has been upended by the massive computational hunger of large language models (LLMs).</p> <p>The financial cost of running LLMs is astonishing. In response, the industry has rushed toward FinOps for AI, the practice of meticulously tracking and optimizing every dollar spent on computation. FinOps is necessary, responsible and a sign of a maturing industry.</p> <p>But tracking dollars is solving yesterday’s problem.</p> <p>The next frontier of competitive advantage lies in a metric that barely registers on most dashboards today: the energy consumption of your AI models. A fundamental shift is underway from FinOps (economic cost) to GreenOps (energy cost). Instead of asking, “How much does this model cost to run?” the critical question is becoming, “What is the carbon intensity of this API call?”</p> <p>This isn’t a philanthropic sidebar; it is the next battleground for regulatory compliance and brand value. Here is why the shift to GreenOps is inevitable, as well as how savvy IT leaders can get ahead of the curve.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-3-forces-making-greenops-mandatory">The 3 forces making GreenOps mandatory</h2> <p>For years, the energy footprint of AI was an academic footnote. Now, three powerful forces are turning it into a commercial imperative:</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-the-regulatory-vise-is-tightening">1. The regulatory vise is tightening</h3> <p>Regulators are turning carbon disclosure into a legal obligation. The EU’s <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32022L2464" rel="nofollow">Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive (CSRD)</a> requires large companies to publish audited greenhouse-gas data starting with FY2024 reports. Crucially, this scope expands to SMEs and non-EU multinationals by 2028.</p> <p>In the United States, California’s <a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=202320240SB253" rel="nofollow">Climate Corporate Data Accountability Act (SB 253)</a> mandates that corporations with over $1 billion in revenue disclose Scope 1, 2 and 3 emissions. Electricity feeding a Google Cloud us-east1 cluster is Scope 2; re-billed SaaS workloads are Scope 3. Either way, they hit the ledger. Companies that fail to report AI-related emissions will face fines and exclusion from enterprise supply chains.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-the-demand-for-ethical-gigawatts">2. The demand for ‘ethical gigawatts’</h3> <p>Procurement teams are beginning to screen vendors based on energy efficiency. Major European players already utilize ESG ratings from EcoVadis to evaluate suppliers.</p> <p>Investors are following suit. Under the EU’s <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32019R2088" rel="nofollow">Sustainable Finance Disclosure Regulation (SFDR)</a>, Article-8 and Article-9 venture funds now request emission baselines before deploying capital. Just as security questionnaires became table stakes a decade ago, carbon emission dashboards are becoming standard in enterprise RFPs. For an AI startup, demonstrating a low-carbon inference stack is no longer a nice-to-have, it is a competitive moat.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-performance-per-watt-as-a-metric">3. Performance-per-watt as a metric</h3> <p> We are entering an era where efficient engineering trumps brute force. An equally accurate model that consumes half the energy is objectively better engineering. Investors and CTOs will soon assess watts-per-inference with the same scrutiny they once applied to daily active users. This efficiency translates directly into higher profit margins and brand prestige.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="decoding-the-carbon-cost-of-an-api-call">Decoding the carbon cost of an API call</h2> <p>Measuring the carbon footprint of a single API call sounds abstract, but GreenOps turns it into a concrete key performance indicator (KPI) based on three variables:</p> <ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Model architecture:</strong> Is it a dense, 100-billion-parameter behemoth or a lean mixture-of-experts (MoE) model that only activates specific neurons?</li> <li><strong>Hardware selection:</strong> Is the inference running on a power-hungry legacy GPU or a specialized AI accelerator chip designed for low-wattage throughput?</li> <li><strong>Carbon intensity:</strong> This is the most overlooked variable. A data center in Sweden (<a href="https://www.datacenters.com/news/are-we-overlooking-the-nordics-europe-s-silent-data-center-powerhouse" rel="nofollow">powered by 98% hydro</a>) might have a carbon intensity of 16g CO₂eq/kWh. The same GPU running in a coal-heavy region of the <a href="https://app.electricitymaps.com/map/3mo/daily" rel="nofollow">US could exceed 800g CO₂eq/kWh</a>, a 50x difference in carbon impact for the exact same compute task.</li>
</ol> <p>A company practicing GreenOps doesn’t just know its cloud bill. It knows that routing job A to a hydro-powered region reduces the carbon cost by 90% without impacting latency.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-practical-example-stopping-the-zombie-retraining-cycles">A practical example: Stopping the zombie retraining cycles</h2> <p>The biggest source of waste in MLOps isn’t always the model itself — it’s the process we use to update it. In standard industry practice, companies often retrain models on a fixed schedule (e.g., weekly) regardless of whether the new data actually improves performance.</p> <p>In my recent research on sustainable MLOps, I developed a new metric called the retraining-efficiency score (RES). Instead of blindly retraining models, RES acts as a green guardrail. It calculates the real-time trade-off between the expected accuracy gain and the carbon cost of training. If the efficiency score doesn’t meet a specific threshold, the retraining job is killed before it burns energy.</p> <p>Across 2,320 controlled experiments on large-scale datasets (including energy grids and retail sales), this approach reduced annual carbon emissions by 47% compared to the industry standard always-promote baseline. Crucially, it achieved this massive carbon reduction while maintaining the same forecast accuracy. This is the essence of GreenOps: using intelligence to eliminate waste, not performance.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-entrepreneurial-opportunity-the-greenops-stack">The entrepreneurial opportunity: The GreenOps stack</h2> <p>This shift presents one of the most significant opportunities in the AI ecosystem. Just as MLOps gave us deployment tools and FinOps gave us cost controls, the GreenOps stack is waiting to be built.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Observability:</strong> We need a Grafana for energy — dashboards that visualize carbon impact alongside latency and accuracy.</li> <li><strong>Efficiency-as-a-service:</strong> There is a market for consultancies that specialize in model quantization, pruning and distillation to reduce energy overhead.</li> <li><strong>Energy Star for AI:</strong> We need a trusted certification body to validate model efficiency. A likely scenario is a joint scheme where technical standards (drafted by <a href="https://www.iso.org/committee/6794475/x/catalogue/p/0/u/1/w/0/d/0" rel="nofollow">ISO/IEC JTC 1/SC 42</a>) are audited by nonprofits like the Green Software Foundation.</li>
</ul> <p>Hugging Face has already set the precedent by adding estimated emissions to model cards, fueled by the CodeCarbon library. The market appetite for these numbers is real.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-verdict">The verdict</h2> <p>The past decade proved AI can work. The next decade must prove it can work sustainably. The founders and architects who grasp this shift will not only build more responsible companies; they will build the most valuable ones. The time to start measuring your carbon cost is now, before your customers or your regulators do it for you.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Are you a Next CIO? Award program celebrates IT’s rising stars]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4127622/are-you-a-next-cio-award-program-celebrates-its-rising-stars.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4127622/are-you-a-next-cio-award-program-celebrates-its-rising-stars.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>No mere back-office operator, today’s successful CIOs accelerate business transformation, strengthen security posture, and increasingly translate AI ambition into real-world outcomes. At the same time, the path from “high performer” to “enterprise technology executive” has become both more urgent and harder to navigate.</p> <p>If there’s a common frustration among ambitious technology leaders, it’s this: performance alone doesn’t always translate into promotion — especially when the target role requires cross-functional influence, board-level communication, and business-strategy thinking.</p> <p>The <strong><a href="https://www-eur.cvent.com/c/abstracts/0607d7fd-2823-4ad9-bf59-791c0eac38cd?utm_medium=foundry_article&amp;utm_source=cio100ll_nextciolandingpage&amp;utm_campaign=cio100ll_nextciolandingpage&amp;utm_term=2/4/2026-11/1//2027&amp;utm_content=foundry_article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Next CIO leadership development and awards program</a></strong> for rising technology executives addresses that gap with a clear, supported pathway from rising leader to future CIO, with public recognition as the surface layer and development and network-building underneath.</p> <p>The program is designed to identify high-potential technology professionals and support their growth toward more senior leadership roles.</p> <aside class="sidebar">
<h3 id="next-cio-at-a-glance">Next CIO at a glance</h3>
<p><strong>What it is:</strong> A year-round leadership development and awards program for emerging technology executives.</p>
<p><strong>Who it’s for:</strong> High-potential IT leaders on a path to roles like CIO/CTO/CDO. <a href="https://custom-eur.cvent.com/7820E393F1ED46AEB5B43D42E3C55D13/files/040f77f4468242b5b4532ceaa5c223ee.docx" target="new" rel="nofollow">Read the FAQ</a> for nomination criteria, deadlines, and eligibility details.</p>
<p><strong>How to enter:</strong> <a href="https://www-eur.cvent.com/c/abstracts/0607d7fd-2823-4ad9-bf59-791c0eac38cd?utm_medium=foundry_article&amp;utm_source=cio100ll_nextciolandingpage&amp;utm_campaign=cio100ll_nextciolandingpage&amp;utm_term=2/4/2026-11/1//2027&amp;utm_content=foundry_article" target="new" rel="nofollow">Nominations for the Next CIO Awards are now open</a>. The submission deadline is March 31, 2026 11:59 PM ET.</p> <p><strong>Where to start:</strong> Join us at CIO 100 Leadership Live: Atlanta, March 5, 2026, where all regional nominees are invited to an exclusive luncheon. <a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio-100-leadership-live-atlanta/?utm_source=db&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=CIOATL_foundry_article" target="new" rel="nofollow">Register now!</a></p></aside><h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="recognition-is-the-headline-readiness-is-the-point">Recognition is the headline; readiness is the point</h2> <p>The Next CIO program will be integrated into the <strong><a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio-100-leadership-live?utm_medium=foundry_article&amp;utm_source=cio100ll_landingpage&amp;utm_campaign=cio100ll_landingpage&amp;utm_term=2/4/2026-11/1//2026&amp;utm_content=foundry_article" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">CIO 100 Leadership Live</a></strong> regional event series, giving rising leaders new opportunities to engage directly with senior CIOs and influential peers. And Next CIO Award winners will be recognized at the annual <strong><a href="https://event.foundryco.com/cio100-symposium-and-awards/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">CIO 100 Symposium &amp; Awards</a></strong>.</p> <p>Not simply a set of sessions, Next CIO is a structured environment where rising leaders can build strategic capability, professional visibility, and community at the same time. The goal is to broaden access to mentorship, reduce barriers to advancement, and support rising talent at a point where leadership trajectory often becomes defined.</p> <p>Next CIO is a <strong>year-round initiative</strong>, built to blend recognition with the kinds of development and connection that leaders often need, but don’t always get, on the way to the top job. The program includes:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Mentoring</strong> with established CIOs</li> <li><strong>Leadership workshops</strong> tailored to professionals approaching their first executive role</li> <li>Access to a growing <strong>peer community</strong> of ambitious technology leaders</li>
</ul> <p>“We are thrilled to launch the program in the United States as part of our ongoing commitment to supporting the CIO community,” Romy Tuin, Foundry’s Global Director of Events Content, said in a statement. “This initiative provides a powerful opportunity to recognize leaders on a strong path to the technology C-suite, while building a network of future CIOs who can develop, refine, and strengthen the skills needed for executive success.”</p>
</div></div></div>
</div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The 7 biggest S/4HANA migration hurdles — and how to overcome them]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130952/the-7-biggest-hurdles-in-s-4hana-migration-and-how-to-overcome-them.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130952/the-7-biggest-hurdles-in-s-4hana-migration-and-how-to-overcome-them.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Organizationally, technically, and culturally, an <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3487010/sap-latest-news-and-insights.html">SAP</a> <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3952085/what-is-s-4hana.html">S/4HANA</a> migration project is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3851772/sap-users-struggle-with-s4-hana-migration.html">complex in many areas</a>. It’s not simply an IT project where data is transferred from one system to another. Rather, it’s a company-wide transformation that affects the entire business.</p> <p>On the path to successful project completion, there are typical stumbling blocks that must be avoided. Here is a look at the most common — and how to navigate them.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-developing-a-realistic-expectation-horizon">1. Developing a realistic expectation horizon</h2> <p>Every migration project begins with an inventory. The company in question must realistically assess its own resources and capacity for change to define a feasible project framework.</p> <p>In practice, a structured approach to this step has proved effective. A combined analysis of process mapping, system inventory, and data evaluation is recommended. Identifying technical dependencies and areas for action early on creates a realistic picture of the initial situation, providing a basis for <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3982596/the-road-to-s-4hana-how-cios-are-managing-sap-eccs-end-of-support.html" target="_blank">the subsequent assessment of the SAP S/4HANA migration strategy</a>.</p> <p>It is equally important that the project team understands the organizational change potential within the company’s business units and assesses the company’s existing know-how and change capability.</p> <p>Early involvement of all stakeholders makes it possible to resolve conflicting expectations. This is a prerequisite for adapting the subsequent transition approach to the maturity level and culture of the company.</p> <p>Based on these findings, it’s then possible to assess which project framework is realistic, for example, whether a phased approach or a big-bang scenario is appropriate. Crucially, the planned approach must align with the company’s actual capacity for change and its available resources. Only then can successful implementation be prepared.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-defining-the-target-image-and-target-design">2. Defining the target image and target design</h2> <p>A second hurdle concerns project preparation. The project team must first define the target state, including all requirements and realistic time management, on a technical and technological basis.</p> <p>Based on this, a system vision is developed and anchored within the company. This includes a description of the system landscape and architecture, as well as all key principles.</p> <p>Different key principles come into play depending on the industry.</p> <p>• <strong>Mechanical engineering:</strong> Focus on modular production processes, integration of CAD and PLM systems, real-time monitoring of production lines, standardized bills of materials, and variant management</p> <p>• <strong>Pharmaceutical industry:</strong> Strict compliance and audit trails, full batch traceability, integrated quality management, validation of processes according to regulatory requirements</p> <p>• <strong>Chemical industry:</strong> Safety and environmental regulations, integrated production and laboratory processes, harmonization of material master data, process safety and traceability of raw materials</p> <p>• <strong>Automotive/vehicle manufacturing:</strong> Just-in-time and just-in-sequence logistics, supplier integration and traceability across the entire supply chain</p> <p>• <strong>Retail/consumer goods:</strong> Omnichannel strategies, efficient merchandise management and warehouse logistics, integrated customer relationship management</p> <p>By clearly defining such key principles, companies align their system vision specifically with industry-specific requirements. They ensure that processes, interfaces, and data structures are optimally supported from the outset.</p> <p>Closely related to this is <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/272222/change-management-change-management-definition-and-solutions.html">change management planning</a>, which involves all employees and familiarizes them with the requirements and the target system. Without early buy-in from specialist departments, IT, and top management, as well as the establishment of a governance structure with clear responsibilities, a shared path to the goal is difficult and the change impact is lost.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-developing-migration-scenarios-flexibly">3. Developing migration scenarios flexibly</h2> <p>A key aspect for the success of an IT project is the flexible development of the migration scenario. Many companies opt for a standard approach without considering their specific requirements. Sometimes this even happens before the target state has been defined. As a result, tools or solutions take priority over the vision.</p> <p>It makes more sense to think from the end result and to develop the migration path in an open-ended manner. Depending on the project, greenfield, brownfield, or selective approaches each have their place.</p> <p>Which scenario is most promising depends on the target vision. Only once the path has been determined can decisions be made about tools and platforms.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-planning-sufficient-test-scope-and-cycles">4. Planning sufficient test scope and cycles</h2> <p>Testing is a crucial project step. It’s far more than just a necessary exercise. On the one hand, testing provides companies with essential groundwork for the go-live; on the other hand, it’s a critical aspect of change management.</p> <p>A successful testing approach encompasses several levels:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Unit and integration tests are used to check technical components and interfaces early on.</li> <li>Functional tests are used to systematically check processes for technical correctness.</li> <li>User acceptance tests (UATs) are a process in which end-users test the target system under realistic conditions and with real-world use cases — a dress rehearsal for the go-live. They bridge the gap between technical implementation and operational use — and create the necessary acceptance for the change.</li>
</ul> <p>Migration tests are particularly important, especially for selective approaches such as Selective Data Transition. Those responsible must ensure data consistency, completeness, and quality before going live.</p> <p>To identify problems at particularly critical points at an early stage, the following procedure is recommended:</p> <p>• <strong>Risk-based test planning:</strong> Identify processes or interfaces that are particularly vulnerable or business-critical and prioritize them in the tests.</p> <p>• <strong>Simulation of exceptional scenarios:</strong> Also test borderline cases, high loads or unusual data constellations to identify possible sources of error.</p> <p>• <strong>Continuous feedback:</strong> Evaluate test results quickly so that corrective actions can be implemented immediately.</p> <p>• <strong>Test managers for critical areas:</strong> Let experienced subject matter experts take responsibility for sensitive modules to ensure well-founded decisions and adjustments.</p> <p>• <strong>Use of special testing tools:</strong> Utilize automated testing suites or data validation tools to consistently monitor sources of error and ensure data quality.</p> <p>Without sufficient testing scope and cycles, as well as early planning of resources, roles, and test participants, delays, inconsistencies, and acceptance problems can arise during the project. Therefore, project teams should prioritize this step from the outset.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-ensuring-early-and-comprehensive-concept-development">5. Ensuring early and comprehensive concept development</h2> <p>Most companies understand the value of conceptual work. However, a truly thorough blueprinting phase before implementation is often lacking. Frequently, the target vision contains gaps, either because individual decisions are deliberately postponed or simply overlooked.</p> <p>However, this means the project plan lags behind reality, and delays due to changes in the project scope during the project, as well as, in the worst case, time-consuming and nerve-wracking problem-solving during the go-live phase, are inevitable.</p> <p>A well-thought-out and complete blueprint facilitates implementation. Consulting firms can provide support as trusted advisors in the development and documentation of clearly defined processes, data objects, roles, and test concepts. Examples of critical details that are often overlooked include:</p> <p>• <strong>Interfaces to adjacent systems:</strong> Are all dependencies correctly documented and tested?</p> <p>• <strong>Data consistency and master data quality:</strong> Which data needs to be cleaned or harmonized before the migration starts?</p> <p>• <strong>Special processes and exceptions:</strong> Are there processes that only occur in certain countries, companies, or departments?</p> <p>• <strong>Regulatory and compliance requirements:</strong> Are all industry-specific regulations taken into account, such as validations in pharmaceuticals or audit trails in financial accounting?</p> <p>• <strong>Role and authorization concepts:</strong> Are all responsibilities clearly defined, including for special cases?</p> <p>By integrating these points early into the blueprint phase, project teams can avoid late surprises, keep the project plan realistic, and make the go-live phase significantly more efficient.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-establishing-stable-project-governance">6. Establishing stable project governance</h2> <p>Constant scope adjustments and departments changing their minds: these are hardly ideal conditions for a successful project. With so-called “scope creep,” the uncontrolled and continuous growth of the project scope, all time and resource plans are thrown into disarray.</p> <p>Robust project governance is therefore essential. It creates clear decision-making processes, defines roles and responsibilities, and ensures consistent management of change requests.</p> <p>This allows new requirements to be systematically evaluated, prioritized, and, if necessary, integrated into the project in a controlled manner — without jeopardizing the overall project. Project stability need not come at the expense of flexibility in implementation. On the contrary, it offers those responsible control and planning certainty.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-setting-a-comprehensive-and-robust-transformation-roadmap">7. Setting a comprehensive and robust transformation roadmap</h2> <p>A successful SAP S/4HANA transformation requires more than a single project. It demands a holistic and robust roadmap. It’s rarely possible to address all modernization needs in a single step. Without clear prioritization, there’s a risk of either tackling too much at once or postponing important issues, thus missing out on the transformation’s opportunities.</p> <p>A transformation roadmap helps to clearly define the core S/4HANA project and to strategically plan follow-up projects, for example, for process harmonization, master data cleansing and governance, or the integration of further systems. It provides orientation and decision-making certainty, for instance, regarding which topics the project team consciously addresses directly and which it will specifically address in later phases.</p> <p>Companies should approach the process of creating a transformation roadmap systematically by first identifying all relevant modernization needs from a technical, organizational, and procedural perspective. This is followed by prioritization based on business impact, dependencies, and urgency. It is recommended to structure milestones into phases, such as core systems, process harmonization, data quality, and integration of other systems, in order to create added value step by step.</p> <p>Additionally, those responsible should keep the roadmap flexible to respond to changes in the business environment or new requirements. Project portfolio planning tools and visualizations support transparency and communication with stakeholders. A continuous review process allows companies to adjust priorities and make progress measurable.</p> <p>On this basis, companies ensure that the transformation is not only technically successful, but also that they position themselves for the future in terms of organization and processes.</p> <p>Overcoming these challenges requires a holistic approach. When companies consider strategy, IT landscape, and innovation capabilities within a comprehensive context, they create the foundation for a successful transformation — and thus the opportunity to generate real added value in the long term.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Proving AI deployment value needs a more strategic approach]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130609/proving-ai-deployment-value-needs-a-more-strategic-approach.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4130609/proving-ai-deployment-value-needs-a-more-strategic-approach.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>You wouldn’t judge the value professional chefs bring to Michelin-starred restaurants by how quickly they chop onions. So why is there such a focus on time saving at work through AI usage?</p> <p>AI tools, from copilots to agentic systems, have the potential to reinvent entire business workflows, impacting business models and changing how enterprises deliver value. Time savings, on the other hand, are easy to measure through employee surveys and analytics collected from heavily monitored activities such as customer care.</p> <p>So taking this easier approach and just trying to do the same activities in less time is not the way to look at this. Longer-term strategic thinking is required, and businesses that examine what they do from the ground up, and consider how AI could allow them to reconfigure these activities to create value for customers, will be the winners in these turbulent times.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cutting-headcount-is-not-a-strategy">Cutting headcount is not a strategy</h2> <p>No company ever shrank to greatness. Sure, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4012162/ai-begins-to-reshape-the-it-job-landscape-as-layoffs-rise.html?utm=hybrid_search">laying off staff in downturns</a> may sometimes be necessary, and deploying AI as a way to do this may bring a short-term bump to the bottom line. But it’s missing the real opportunities AI presents and could actually do longer term damage to a business. <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-03-gartner-predicts-half-of-companies-that-cut-customer-service-staff-due-to-ai-will-rehire-by-2027" rel="nofollow">Gartner predicts</a> half of companies cutting customer service staff due to AI will rehire by 2027. They reason AI is just not mature enough to replace the subtleties and empathy that humans bring to customer interactions. The danger, Gartner argues, is that while immediate cost savings may be attractive, there’s a danger of unintended consequences further down the line.</p> <p>This sentiment is echoed by Ronnie Sheth, CEO of SENEN, a strategic consultancy focused on data and AI. She warns against taking a technology-first approach such as deploying copilots and self-service chatbots without thinking about customer needs and preferences. It’s counterproductive, as a growing number of companies are finding, to handle more customer queries if customer satisfaction levels go down. “To truly realize value, AI initiatives should map directly to strategic business objectives by a defined percentage, not just internal soft metrics such as time saved,” Sheth says.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="focus-on-quality-not-quantity">Focus on quality not quantity</h2> <p>In a world starting to drown in AI-generated slop, the quality of outputs and customer interactions will become ever-more important. Copilots and other AI tools can play a key role in driving quality up, but choosing the right metrics to measure this is key. Founder of technology advisory firm Deep Analysis, Alan Pelz-Sharpe sees the focus on deploying copilots primarily to raise employee outputs as a mistake. “Somebody might write more code, but is it good code and does it actually deliver measurable business value,” he asks. “So if your measurement is tasks completed per hour or headcount, you can argue that you did more, but did you do better, did you deliver enough value to justify the cost and change.”</p> <p>On top of this, he warns of not monitoring for possible negative consequences further down the line. This is particularly true with coding assistants capable of producing code at speed but which, without skilled human oversight, can cause problems weeks or months later as systems become exposed to the harsh realities of business environments.</p> <p>A <a href="https://www.harness.io/state-of-software-delivery" rel="nofollow">2025 survey</a> by Harness of 500 software engineers found that while just over 80% felt AI was useful in their jobs, they were also struggling with a blast radius effect where bad code was going into production faster and with a greater impact. This included debugging with 67% of developers spending more time cleaning up code generated by AI, and 68% spending more time dealing with security vulnerabilities from such code.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="not-business-as-usual">Not business as usual</h2> <p>Despite justified talk of AI bubbles fuelled by some ridiculous investments and valuations of companies unlikely to ever live up to their promises, a revolution is underway. Seeing AI as a bolt-on that can help businesses perform a bit more efficiently is missing a key point. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4104444/8-tips-for-rebuilding-an-ai-ready-data-strategy.html?utm=hybrid_search">How data is gathered, processed, shared, and used</a> is being transformed in terms of speed and quantity but, more importantly, AI is changing how decisions are made on the basis of that data.</p> <p><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4119297/how-to-get-your-enterprise-architecture-ready-for-agentic-ai.html?utm=hybrid_search">As agentic solutions evolve</a>, many roles currently performed by humans will either radically change or disappear altogether. When word processing systems emerged in the 1970s and 1980s, a key measure of their value was how much quicker secretaries and admin assistants could produce written documents. However, the real impact of word processors and the PCs that replaced them has been the transfer of much of this work to executive staff, who now manage their own admin tasks.</p> <p>The impact of AI will be far greater. Enterprises need to rethink how useful their current business processes and, by extension, their business models will be when AI is able to automate or even make current practices redundant. Simply performing current activities quicker is not the way to think about this.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Taming agent sprawl: 3 pillars of AI orchestration]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132287/taming-agent-sprawl-3-pillars-of-ai-orchestration.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132287/taming-agent-sprawl-3-pillars-of-ai-orchestration.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>By early 2026, the novelty phase of AI agents has officially ended and been replaced by a looming systemic liability. If 2025 was the year of the pilots, 2026 is the year of the collision.</p> <p>The velocity of adoption is staggering. Gartner recently predicted that <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2025-08-26-gartner-predicts-40-percent-of-enterprise-apps-will-feature-task-specific-ai-agents-by-2026-up-from-less-than-5-percent-in-2025" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">40% of enterprise applications</a> will feature task-specific AI agents by the end of this year. For the average organization, this translates to a fleet of 50+ specialized agents, becoming the new “Shadow IT” if left unmanaged.</p> <p>For the modern enterprise, the goal is no longer just deployment; it is orchestration.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-agent-sprawl-warning-ais-shadow-it">The “agent sprawl” warning: AI’s shadow IT</h2> <p>We’ve seen this movie before with cloud instances and SaaS apps. Left unchecked, independent agents create a “governance vacuum.” When your marketing agent, supply chain agent, and HR bot all operate in silos, you don’t have an automated workforce; you have a digital riot.</p> <p>Uncoordinated agents lead to “token hemorrhaging”, where redundant API calls and overlapping compute tasks quietly erode ROI. As I noted in “<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4090235/measuring-and-scaling-ai-agent-value-beyond-productivity-gains.html" target="_blank">Measuring and scaling AI agent value beyond productivity gains</a>,” the friction between autonomous speed and legacy governance is one of the primary barriers to AI success in 2026.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-3-pillars-of-ai-orchestration">The 3 pillars of AI orchestration</h2> <p>To prevent chaos, your Agentic Operating System (AOS) must be built on three non-negotiable pillars:</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-conflict-resolution-and-priority-logic">1. Conflict resolution and priority logic</h3> <p>What happens when your <em>cost optimization agent</em> shuts down a server to save budget, while your <em>customer experience agent</em>is scaling up for a product launch? An AOS must move beyond simple loops to implement priority logic. This ensures agent actions align with current quarterly business objectives (QBOs) rather than just local optimizations.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-universal-context-the-memory-layer-and-context-efficiency">2. Universal context (The memory layer) and context efficiency</h3> <p>Agents are often “locally optimal but globally catastrophic” because they lack shared memory. By centralizing context, you eliminate the need for every agent to perform redundant <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/what-is/retrieval-augmented-generation/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation)</a> vector searches. This reduces your total token spend while ensuring the “left hand” always knows what the “right hand” is doing.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-cross-agent-security-and-immutable-audits">3. Cross-agent security and immutable audits</h3> <p>The rise of <a href="https://blog.box.com/protecting-ai-agents-against-prompt-injection" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">agentic prompt injection</a> is real. A low-clearance agent could inadvertently “trick” a high-privilege agent into leaking sensitive data. Identity is the new perimeter. Every hand-off between agents must be authenticated and logged. A centralized AOS acts as a specialized firewall, providing an immutable audit trail of “who” did “what” and “why.” This is essential for maintaining a fiduciary standard in an autonomous environment.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="example-case-study-the-2m-logistics-loop">Example case study: The $2M logistics loop</h2> <p>Consider a global logistics firm that deployed two autonomous agents in early 2025: one for <em>inventory procurement</em> and one for <em>dynamic warehouse pricing</em>.</p> <p>In late Q4, a data lag caused the procurement agent to see a “low stock” signal and over-order high-value components. Simultaneously, the pricing agent saw the incoming surplus and slashed prices to move volume. Because there was no orchestration layer to reconcile these conflicting goals, the firm spent $2M on premium freight to ship items they were essentially selling at a loss. This wasn’t a failure of AI logic—it was a failure of <em>AI orchestration.</em></p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-maestro-framework-a-4-step-blueprint">The “MAESTRO” framework: A 4-step blueprint</h2> <p>How do you build a centralized AOS? The Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) has introduced the <a href="https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/blog/2025/02/06/agentic-ai-threat-modeling-framework-maestro" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">MAESTRO framework</a> (multi-agent environment, security, threat, risk, and outcome) to provide a seven-layer approach to governing these environments. To get started:</p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Inventory &amp; audit:</strong> Map every active agent, its underlying LLM, and its data permissions.</li> <li><strong>Standardize communication:</strong> Implement protocols so agents speak a common language (e.g., semantic routing).</li> <li><strong>Define hierarchy:</strong> Establish a “Master Agent” or controller that holds the final “veto” power over autonomous actions.</li> <li><strong>Centralized logging:</strong> Move all agent telemetry into a single dashboard for real-time visibility into “who” did “what” and “why.”</li>
</ol> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-metric-that-matters-orchestration-efficiency">The metric that matters: orchestration efficiency</h2> <p>In 2024, we measured success by <em>bot count</em>. In 2026, that is a vanity metric.</p> <p>The new North Star is <a href="https://www.ibm.com/think/topics/ai-agent-orchestration" rel="nofollow">orchestration efficiency (OE)</a>. This measures the ratio of successful multi-agent tasks completed versus the total compute cost. High OE means your agents are collaborating; low OE means they are competing for resources.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-bottom-line">The bottom line</h2> <p>Enterprises who fail to implement an orchestration layer by mid-year will spend the rest of 2026 cleaning up “agent collisions” and explaining budget overruns. The era of the lone-wolf bot is over. It’s time to conduct the orchestra.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Google Explores Scaling Principles for Multi-agent Coordination]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/google-agent-scaling-principles/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/google-agent-scaling-principles/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/google-agent-scaling-principles/en/headerimage/google-scaling-agents-principles-1771231654834.jpeg"/><p>Google Research tried to answer the question of how to design agent systems for optimal performance by running a controlled evaluation of 180 agent configurations. From this, the team derived what they call the "first quantitative scaling principles for AI agent systems", showing that multi-agent coordination does not reliably improve results and can even reduce performance.</p> <i>By Sergio De Simone</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Google Explores Scaling Principles for Multi-agent Coordination]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/google-agent-scaling-principles/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/google-agent-scaling-principles/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/google-agent-scaling-principles/en/headerimage/google-scaling-agents-principles-1771231654834.jpeg"/><p>Google Research tried to answer the question of how to design agent systems for optimal performance by running a controlled evaluation of 180 agent configurations. From this, the team derived what they call the "first quantitative scaling principles for AI agent systems", showing that multi-agent coordination does not reliably improve results and can even reduce performance.</p> <i>By Sergio De Simone</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Java News Roundup: JDK 26-RC1, Spring Framework, Open Liberty, EclipseStore, Gradle]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb09-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb09-2026/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-news-roundup-feb09-2026/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771200556463.jpg"/><p>This week's Java roundup for February 9th, 2026, features news highlighting: the first release candidate of JDK 26 and Gradle 9.4; milestone releases of Micrometer Metrics and Micrometer Tracing; beta releases of Open Liberty 26.0.0.2 and EclipseStore 4.0; and maintenance releases of Spring Framework, Micronaut, Quarkus.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AIは「新しいメディア」になる——博報堂ＤＹホールディングスCAIO（最高AI責任者）が描く創造性が拡張する未来（前編）]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132544/ai%e3%81%af%e3%80%8c%e6%96%b0%e3%81%97%e3%81%84%e3%83%a1%e3%83%87%e3%82%a3%e3%82%a2%e3%80%8d%e3%81%ab%e3%81%aa%e3%82%8b-%e5%8d%9a%e5%a0%b1%e5%a0%82%ef%bd%84%ef%bd%99%e3%83%9b%e3%83%bc.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4132544/ai%e3%81%af%e3%80%8c%e6%96%b0%e3%81%97%e3%81%84%e3%83%a1%e3%83%87%e3%82%a3%e3%82%a2%e3%80%8d%e3%81%ab%e3%81%aa%e3%82%8b-%e5%8d%9a%e5%a0%b1%e5%a0%82%ef%bd%84%ef%bd%99%e3%83%9b%e3%83%bc.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p><strong>テクノロジーを信じ、価値を問い続けた</strong><strong>20</strong><strong>年</strong><strong>——</strong><strong>その軌跡が導いた「人間中心の</strong><strong>AI</strong><strong>」</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——これまでのキャリアについて教えてください。</p> <p>私のキャリアの出発点は、新卒で入社したコンサルティング企業でした。最初はシステム開発やアーキテクチャ設計に携わり、その後、2004年からは海外のコンサルティング企業の研究所で研究開発のマネジメントを担当しました。</p> <p>当時は、ブログを中心としたユーザー生成コンテンツ（UGC）が注目を集め始めた時期で、同時に企業が保有するデータをどう分析し、そこからどんな価値を引き出すかというテーマが盛んに議論されていました。私はその流れの中で、AIとインターネットが持つ可能性に強い確信を抱くようになったのです。</p> <p>やがて、<strong>「インターネットは単なる情報発信の手段にとどまらず、企業や社会のシステムをつなぎ、ビジネスをスケールさせる時代が来る」</strong>と感じるようになりました。そこで2006年、そうした未来像を実現するためにインターネット企業に転職し、研究開発をリードするポジションに就きました。</p> <p>世界各地に研究所を設立し、変化の激しいインターネット業界の中で、技術の力でビジネスの成長を支える仕組みづくりに取り組んでいた時期です。</p> <p>一方で、2015年頃からテクノロジーに対する社会的な不安や懸念も顕在化してきました。データ解析におけるプライバシー問題や、AIが<strong>「ブラックボックス」</strong>と化して何をしているのか分からない、といった課題が議論され始めたのです。</p> <p>その流れの中で、私自身も<strong>「これからのテクノロジーは、活用だけでなくガバナンスとの両輪で進めなければ、社会の健全な成長はない」</strong>と考えるようになりました。そこで2020年頃、別のコンサルティング企業に移り、先端技術領域のリーダーとしてガバナンス課題に取り組みました。</p> <p>ただ、ガバナンスを重視しながらも、<strong>「</strong><strong>AIはこの先さらに大きな可能性を切り拓くのではないか」</strong>という予感は常に持っていました。そして2022年、生成AIが登場したことでその思いは確信に変わりました。AIが人間の創造性に与える影響、そしてそれがビジネスの本質的なテーマになることを強く感じたのです。</p> <p>そうした問題意識を深めていた頃、2024年に博報堂ＤＹグループからお声がけをいただき、CAIO（Chief AI Officer）としてジョインしました。博報堂ＤＹグループが掲げる<strong>「生活者を起点としたクリエイティビティプラットフォームへの変革」</strong>というビジョンは、まさに私の考えと一致していました。</p> <p>現在は、<strong>「人間中心の</strong><strong>AI」</strong>や<strong>「人のクリエイティビティを拡張する</strong><strong>AI」</strong>という新たなテーマに挑戦しています。これまで培ってきた研究・開発・ガバナンス・ビジネスの経験を総動員して、AIを人と社会の創造的成長につなげていくことが、今のミッションだと感じています。</p> <p><strong>「研究をビジネスにつなげる」——新たな仕組みづくりへの挑戦</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——これまでのキャリアの中で、特に印象に残っているプロジェクトは？</p> <p>これまでのキャリアの中で最も印象に残っているのは、インターネット企業で手がけた<strong>「研究をビジネスにつなげる仕組みづくり」</strong>のプロジェクトです。グローバルな研究開発体制をゼロから構築し、研究成果を実際の事業成長に直結させることを目指しました。</p> <p>具体的には、世界5カ国・8拠点に研究所を設立し、150名ほどの博士号を持つ優秀なコンピューターサイエンティストを世界中から採用しました。彼らとともに、企業が抱える課題や膨大なデータを分析し、それを起点に最先端の研究テーマに取り組める体制を整えたのです。</p> <p>実際に研究所の立ち上げにあたって、さまざまな大学の先生、あるいはトップの技術者の方々に「<strong>どういう研究所があると、研究や社会、ビジネスにとって良いと思いますか」</strong>と話を伺ってまわったんです。</p> <p>各国の大学教授やトップエンジニアにヒアリングを重ね、<strong>「理想の研究所とは何か」「研究と社会・ビジネスの接点をどうつくるべきか」</strong>を徹底的に議論しました。</p> <p>その中で見えてきたのは、研究の現場には人材やノウハウはあるが、現実の課題やデータがないという構造的な課題でした。一方でビジネス側は誰かに解いてほしい課題が常にあり、データも大量にあるんですね。</p> <p>そこで私は、<strong>「研究者が実際のビジネス課題やデータに自由に触れられる場をつくれば、研究のポテンシャルも広がり、ビジネスも加速するはずだ」</strong>と考えました。つまり、研究とビジネスをダイレクトに結びつけることこそが、次の価値創出につながると確信したのです。</p> <p>この取り組みによって、研究成果は国際的なトップレベルの学会で論文として採択され、同時に実際のサービスやプロダクトへと反映されていきました。クラウドやハイパフォーマンスコンピューティングの基盤技術、スマートフォン向けのサービス、ユビキタス環境でのデジタルサイネージ、ソーシャルメディア分析など、幅広い分野で研究が直接ビジネスの成長を支える仕組みを実現できたのです。</p> <p>さらに時代の進化とともに、AIやディープラーニングの技術も積極的に取り入れ、プロダクトやサービスに統合していきました。このプロジェクトの本質は、単に新技術を導入することではなく、研究から実装、そして事業展開までを一気通貫でつなげるプロセスを確立した点にあります。</p> <p>たとえば、AIを活用した金融分野での<strong>「クリエイティビティスコアリングサービス」</strong>や、ロボティクス領域での<strong>「ドローンによるデリバリー」</strong>など、社会やビジネスに実際のインパクトを与えるプロジェクトも生まれました。</p> <p>研究体制のスケール、ビジネスへの波及効果、そして再現性のある仕組みを確立できたという点で、この経験は私のキャリアの中でも特に大きな成果だったと感じています。</p> <p><strong>アカデミアとビジネス——交わらない</strong><strong>2</strong><strong>つの文化を融合させるまで</strong><strong></strong></p> <p>——これまでのキャリアの中で、最もチャレンジングだった出来事を教えてください。</p> <p>私のキャリアの中で最もチャレンジングだったのは、<strong>「研究をビジネスにつなげる仕組みづくり」</strong>に取り組む中で、アカデミアの文化と、インターネットビジネス特有のスピード感ある文化という、大きく異なる二つの文化を融合させることでした。</p> <p>この取り組みを始めたのは2006年頃。当時、インターネット企業の中で博士号を持つ研究者が活躍することは、まだ珍しい時代でした。</p> <p>アカデミア側には、<strong>「研究者が本当にインターネット企業で働けるのか」</strong>といった文化的な不安があり、一方の企業側にも、<strong>「研究者人材のキャリアパスをどう設計すべきか」「トップレベルの学会で評価された研究を、事業としてどう位置づけるか」</strong>といった課題がありました。まさに両者の間に深い溝があったのです。</p> <p>その溝をどう埋めるかを考え抜いた結果、私は<strong>「既存の企業文化」</strong>と<strong>「研究者のコミュニティ文化」</strong>を融合させた<strong>第</strong><strong>3のカルチャー</strong>をつくる必要があると考えました。</p> <p>その実現に向けて、社内外のコミュニケーションを増やしたり、新しい人事制度や評価体系を導入したりすることで、研究者がビジネスに安心して参加できる環境づくりに徹底的に取り組みました。制度を変えるだけでなく、価値観そのものをすり合わせていくような作業だったと思います。</p> <p>同時に、研究の成果を「Perpetual beta（永遠のベータ版）」として、システムやサービス、プロダクトに継続的に組み込むプロセスを整備しました。研究を一度の成果で終わらせず、常に改善と実装を繰り返す仕組みを組織全体に根づかせたのです。こうしたカルチャーと仕組みの両輪をつくり上げたことが、異なる文化を融合できた最大の要因だったと思います。</p> <p>目に見えない文化の形成と、具体的な仕組みづくりの両方を同時に進めるのは本当に大変で、仕組みが安定して回るようになるまでには5年ほどかかりました。ですが、この経験は現在、CAIOとして取り組んでいる全社的なAIトランスフォーメーションの推進に、大きく生かされていると感じています。</p> <p>AIの導入とは、単にシステムにAIを組み込むことではありません。どうすれば生産性を上げられるのか、業務プロセスをどう変えるのか、そして従業員一人ひとりの働き方をどう良くしていくのか——そうした取り組みのすべてが、最終的には企業文化の変革につながっていきます。</p> <p>AIという新しい文化をどう組織に取り込み、全社的な変革をボトムアップで進めていくのか。その挑戦の原点には、かつて世界中の研究所を立ち上げ、多様な研究者を束ね、価値創出の仕組みを築いたこの経験があるのだと実感しています。</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[What CIOs Are Doing To Evolve Operating Models And Talent]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/what-cios-are-doing-to-evolve-operating-models-and-talent/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/what-cios-are-doing-to-evolve-operating-models-and-talent/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[What CIOs are working on, Part 3 of 4 In previous posts in this series, I covered core modernization and data and AI foundations. In this third part, I turn to the IT operating model and talent. Many organizations run on hybrid models that were never designed: project teams layered over product teams layered over [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-16]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
