<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 08:07:45 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CISO 650명에게 물었다…스플렁크가 진단한 AI 시대 보안 리더의 과제와 기회]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137738/ciso-650%eb%aa%85%ec%97%90%ea%b2%8c-%eb%ac%bc%ec%97%88%eb%8b%a4%ec%8a%a4%ed%94%8c%eb%a0%81%ed%81%ac%ea%b0%80-%ec%a7%84%eb%8b%a8%ed%95%9c-ai-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80-%eb%b3%b4%ec%95%88-%eb%a6%ac.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137738/ciso-650%eb%aa%85%ec%97%90%ea%b2%8c-%eb%ac%bc%ec%97%88%eb%8b%a4%ec%8a%a4%ed%94%8c%eb%a0%81%ed%81%ac%ea%b0%80-%ec%a7%84%eb%8b%a8%ed%95%9c-ai-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80-%eb%b3%b4%ec%95%88-%eb%a6%ac.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>시스코 자회사 스플렁크의 CISO 마이클 패닝은 보도자료를 통해 “CISO의 늘어나는 의무는 상당한 수준의 압박과 개인 차원의 책무를 동반한다”라며 “우리는 이제 단순한 기술관리를 넘어, 리스크와 인재, 그리고 핵심 비즈니스 성과를 좌우하는 디지털 회복탄력성까지 총괄 관리해야 하는 시점에 서 있다”라고 밝혔다.</p> <p><a href="https://www.splunk.com/ko_kr/campaigns/ciso-report.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">보고서에 따르면</a> AI는 에이전틱 AI를 포함해 보안 조직에서 핵심 비즈니스 추진력이자 생산성 향상 수단으로 인식되고 있다. CISO의 95%는 공격자 역량의 고도화를 최대 리스크로 지목했으며, 위협 탐지 및 대응 역량 강화(92%), ID 및 액세스 관리 강화(78%), AI 사이버 보안 역량 투자(68%)를 주요 우선순위로 꼽았다.</p> <p>또한 92%는 AI 도입을 통해 팀이 더 많은 보안 이벤트를 검토할 수 있게 되었다고 답했고, 89%는 데이터 상관관계 분석 역량이 강화됐다고 평가했다. 에이전틱 AI를 부분적으로 또는 전면적으로 도입한 CISO 가운데 39%는 팀의 보고 속도가 향상됐다는 데 강하게 동의했는데, 이는 아직 AI를 검토 중인 조직(18%) 대비 두 배 이상 높은 수치다. 아울러 82%는 에이전틱 AI가 검토 데이터 양을 늘리고 상관관계 분석 및 대응 속도를 향상시킬 것으로 전망했다.</p> <p>다만 AI에 대한 낙관론과 함께 우려도 공존했다. 응답자의 86%는 에이전틱 AI가 사회공학적 공격을 더욱 정교하게 만들 수 있다고 우려했으며, 82%는 지속적 침투를 가능하게 하는 기술의 속도와 복잡성이 증가할 것을 걱정했다. 그럼에도 AI는 궁극적으로 고도화된 위협에 대응하고 비즈니스 이점을 제공하는 핵심 요소로 인식됐다.</p> <p>CISO의 역할 범위도 눈에 띄게 확대되고 있다. 응답자의 약 5명 중 4명은 자신의 역할이 현격히 복잡해졌다고 답했고, 보안 사고 발생 시 개인적 법적 책임을 우려하는 비율은 4분의 3을 넘어 전년도의 절반 수준에서 크게 증가했다. 대다수는 현재 CISO의 책임 범위에 AI 거버넌스 및 리스크 관리가 포함된다고 답했으며, 5명 중 4명 이상은 안전한 소프트웨어 개발(DevSecOps)까지 총괄하고 있는 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>한편 AI의 부상에도 불구하고 CISO들은 역량 격차를 해소하는 주요 수단으로 기술보다 인적 자본을 우선시하는 것으로 조사됐다. 기존 인력의 역량 강화(업스킬링), 정규직 신규 채용, 외부 계약 인력 확보가 주요 전략으로 꼽혔다. 이는 위협 헌팅과 같이 고도의 판단력이 필요한 업무에서 인간의 판단력과 창의성이 여전히 핵심이라는 인식을 반영한다.</p> <p>보안이 특정 부서의 업무를 넘어 전사적 과제로 자리 잡고 있다는 점도 주목할 만하다. 주요 보안 이니셔티브(62%), 보안 예산 및 자금 확보(55%), 보안 관련 데이터 접근(49%) 측면에서 최고 경영진 간 공동 책임 체계가 구축될 때 회복탄력성의 시너지가 극대화되는 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>스플렁크는 인재 유지의 어려움에도 주목했다. 보안팀의 약 3분의 2가 중간 이상의 심각한 번아웃을 경험하고 있으며, 과도한 경보(98%), 오탐 경보(94%), 다양한 보안 도구 사용에 따른 피로도(79%)가 주요 스트레스 요인으로 지목됐다. CISO들은 이를 해소하기 위해 보안 데이터를 단일 가시성으로 통합하는 데 집중하고 있으며, 기술적 세부 내용을 비기술 경영진도 이해할 수 있는 데이터 기반 내러티브로 변환해 보안 현안을 비즈니스 과제로 제시하는 방향으로 나아가고 있다. 다만 부서 간 데이터 공유 측면에서는 데이터 프라이버시 우려(91%), 높은 데이터 저장 비용(76%), 데이터에 대한 공통 가시성 부재(70%) 등이 여전히 과제로 남아 있다.</p> <p>사이버 보안의 가치를 비즈니스 성과로 전환하려는 흐름도 뚜렷해지고 있다. 사고 감소율, 평균 탐지 시간(MTTD), 평균 수리 시간(MTTR) 등이 경영진에게 투자 대비 효과(ROI)를 설명하는 핵심 지표로 활용되고 있으며, 예산 편성 및 전략 과제 수립 시 C-레벨 경영진과의 긴밀한 협업이 성공을 좌우하는 요소로 꼽혔다.</p> <p>이번 보고서는 CISO의 역할이 기술 관리자에서 기업의 전략적 리더로 전환되고 있음을 보여준다. 데이터 기반 전략을 주도하고, 사람 중심의 리더십을 강화하며, 신중한 AI 통합을 통해 조직의 디지털 회복탄력성을 높이는 것이 핵심 과제로 부각됐다. 2026 CISO 리포트의 상세 내용은 스플렁크 홈페이지에서 확인할 수 있다.</p> <p>한편 이번 설문조사는 옥스포드 이코노믹스(Oxford Economics)가 2025년 7월과 8월에 걸쳐 진행했다. 호주, 프랑스, 독일, 인도, 일본, 뉴질랜드, 싱가포르, 영국, 미국에 거주하는 650명의 CISO가 응답했으며, 제조, 이동통신, 미디어 및 커뮤니케이션, 금융 서비스, 공공 부문, 에너지 및 유틸리티, 운송 및 물류, 소매 및 소비재, 의료 및 생명과학, 정보 서비스 및 기술 등 9개 산업을 대상으로 했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-26]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[칼럼 | DX를 넘어 지능형 전환으로···AI 에이전트 시대, 기업 가치 확장의 조건]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137735/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-dx%eb%a5%bc-%eb%84%98%ec%96%b4-%ec%a7%80%eb%8a%a5%ed%98%95-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137735/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-dx%eb%a5%bc-%eb%84%98%ec%96%b4-%ec%a7%80%eb%8a%a5%ed%98%95-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>지난 10년간 디지털 트랜스포메이션(DX)은 수작업 중심의 프로세스를 디지털 방식으로 전환하고, 인프라를 클라우드로 이전하며, 애플리케이션을 현대화하고, 고객과 직원 참여를 위한 새로운 채널을 구축하는 데 초점을 맞췄다. 그 결과 업무 처리 주기가 단축되고 운영 투명성이 높아졌으며 비용 절감 같은 가시적인 성과를 거뒀다. 그러나 동시에 한계도 드러냈다. 근본적으로 문제가 있는 프로세스를 단순히 디지털화하는 것만으로는 구조적 문제를 해결할 수 없다는 점이다. 비효율은 사라지지 않은 채, 오히려 더 빠른 속도로 반복될 뿐이라는 사실이 확인됐다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a7%80%eb%8a%a5%ed%98%95-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80">‘지능형’ 전환 시대</h2> <p>새로운 전환이 본격화되고 있다. 다음 단계는 단순한 디지털을 넘어 ‘지능형’으로 나아가는 것이다. 지능형 전환(intelligent transformation)은 기업을 감지하고, 추론하고, 의사 결정하며, 최소한의 마찰로 행동까지 수행하는 시스템으로 진화시키는 것을 의미한다. AI 에이전트의 등장에 힘입어 변화는 가속화되고 있다. AI 에이전트는 워크플로우를 조율하고 API, 애플리케이션, 데이터베이스, 자동화 기술 등 다양한 도구를 활용해 목표를 달성하는 자율형 소프트웨어 시스템이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%95%b1%ea%b3%bc-%eb%8c%80%ec%8b%9c%eb%b3%b4%eb%93%9c%eb%a5%bc-%eb%84%98%ec%96%b4-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8%ec%99%80-%ec%8b%a4%ed%96%89%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c">앱과 대시보드를 넘어 에이전트와 실행으로</h2> <p>디지털 시대에는 ERP, CRM과 같은 기록 시스템과 비즈니스 인텔리전스(BI) 및 분석 도구 등 인사이트 시스템이 조직 가치 창출의 핵심이었다. 지능형 시대에는 새로운 차원이 더해진다. 다양한 기능 영역에 걸쳐 업무를 직접 수행하는 에이전트 기반 역량, 즉 ‘행동 시스템’이다.</p> <p>AI 에이전트는 단순히 질문에 답하는 수준에 그치지 않는다. 필요한 단계를 스스로 계획하고, 적절한 도구를 호출하며, 관련 정보를 검색하고, 처음부터 끝까지 워크플로우를 완수할 수 있다. 최신 에이전트 아키텍처는 ‘도구 호출’ 또는 ‘함수 호출’ 방식을 적용한다. 모델이 다음 행동을 결정하면 애플리케이션이 이를 실행하고, 그 결과를 바탕으로 모델이 후속 판단을 이어가는 구조다. 이 접근 방식은 언어 모델과 기업 시스템을 실질적으로 연결한다. 그 결과 에이전트는 단순한 기술 시연을 넘어, 실제 운영을 움직이는 실행 수단으로 자리잡고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8%ea%b0%80-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc%eb%a5%bc-%ec%a6%9d%ed%8f%ad%ec%8b%9c%ed%82%a4%eb%8a%94-%ec%98%81%ec%97%ad">에이전트가 성과를 증폭시키는 영역</h2> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a0%9c%ec%a1%b0-%ec%97%b0%ea%b2%b0%eb%90%9c-%ea%b3%b5%ec%9e%a5%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%ed%95%99%ec%8a%b5%ed%95%98%eb%8a%94-%ea%b3%b5%ec%9e%a5%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c">제조: 연결된 공장에서 학습하는 공장으로</h3> <p>인더스트리 4.0은 설비를 연결하고 데이터를 대시보드로 시각화하는 데 초점을 맞췄다. 지능형 전환은 여기서 한 걸음 더 나아가 신호를 실제 행동으로 전환한다. 에이전트가 이상 패턴을 감지하고, 설비 파라미터 조정을 권고하며, 유지보수 요청을 생성하고, 부품 수급을 조율한다. 변화는 단순히 가동 시간을 높이는 데 그치지 않는다. 근본 원인 분석 속도를 단축하고 품질 편차를 줄이며, 생산 처리량의 예측 가능성을 높인다. 복잡한 공급망 환경에서는 계획 안정성이 조금만 개선돼도 서비스 수준과 재고 관리 전반에서 상당한 성과로 이어질 수 있다.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%97%ac%ec%8a%a4%ec%bc%80%ec%96%b4-%eb%b0%8f-%ec%83%9d%eb%aa%85%ea%b3%bc%ed%95%99-%eb%ac%b8%ec%84%9c-%eb%b6%80%eb%8b%b4%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%ec%9d%98%ec%82%ac%ea%b2%b0%ec%a0%95-%ec%a7%80%ec%9b%90">헬스케어 및 생명과학: 문서 부담에서 의사결정 지원으로</h3> <p>의료진과 과학자는 진료 지침, 환자 이력, 연구 문헌, 임상 프로토콜, 규제 요건 등 방대한 정보 속에서 업무를 수행하기 때문에 과도한 맥락 부담에 놓이는 경우가 많다. AI 에이전트는 관련 맥락을 종합하고, 구조화된 노트를 작성하며, 임상시험 적합 환자를 추천하거나 근거 자료를 요약할 수 있다. 동시에 의사결정 과정에서는 사람의 감독을 전제로 한다. 책임 있는 도입을 위해서는 신뢰할 수 있는 출처 기반의 정보 검색, 감사 추적 체계, 엄격한 권한 관리가 함께 구축돼야 한다. 정확성, 개인정보 보호, 추적 가능성은 여전히 핵심 요건이기 때문이다.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%a6%ac%ed%85%8c%ec%9d%bc-%eb%b0%8f-%ec%86%8c%eb%b9%84%ec%9e%ac-%ea%b0%9c%ec%9d%b8%ed%99%94%eb%a5%bc-%eb%84%98%ec%96%b4-%ec%a0%84-%ea%b3%bc%ec%a0%95-%ec%98%a4%ec%bc%80%ec%8a%a4%ed%8a%b8%eb%a0%88">리테일 및 소비재: 개인화를 넘어 전 과정 오케스트레이션으로</h3> <p>개인화된 추천은 AI의 초기 단계였다. 이제 에이전트는 고객 여정 전반을 조율할 수 있다. 고객 문의를 해결하고, 주문을 수정하며, 적절한 대체 상품을 제안하고, 재고 시스템까지 실시간으로 업데이트한다. 내부 운영 측면에서도 변화가 나타난다. 에이전트는 상품 구성에 대한 인사이트를 도출하고, 프로모션 성과를 분석하며, 공급사와의 커뮤니케이션을 자동화한다. 그 결과 기존에 수주가 걸리던 업무 처리 시간이 수시간 단위로 단축되고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%8b%a0%eb%a2%b0%eb%a5%bc-%ea%b8%b0%eb%b0%98%ec%9c%bc%eb%a1%9c-%ed%95%9c-%ec%83%88%eb%a1%9c%ec%9a%b4-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8b%b1-%ec%9b%8c%ed%81%ac%ed%94%8c%eb%a1%9c%ec%9a%b0">신뢰를 기반으로 한 새로운 에이전틱 워크플로우</h2> <p>에이전트 역량이 고도화될수록 핵심 질문은 “모델이 글을 잘 작성할 수 있는가”에서 “기업이 에이전트 시스템과 함께 안전하게 운영될 수 있는가”로 옮겨가게 된다.</p> <p>이에 따라 실용적인 엔터프라이즈 스택이 모습을 드러내고 있다.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>경험 계층</strong>: 이메일, CRM, 서비스 데스크 등 업무 도구에 내장된 코파일럿과 역할 기반 에이전트 인터페이스로 구성된다.</li> <li><strong>추론 및 오케스트레이션 계층</strong>: 정책 설정, 작업 라우팅, 휴먼 인 더 루프 승인 절차, 모니터링 기능을 포함한다.</li> <li><strong>지식 계층</strong>: 권한과 출처가 명확히 관리되는 내부 큐레이션 콘텐츠를 기반으로 정보를 검색·활용한다.</li> <li><strong>도구 계층</strong>: API, RPA, 워크플로 엔진, 기록 시스템 등을 통해 에이전트의 실제 행동을 실행하도록 지원한다.</li> <li><strong>거버넌스 및 리스크 계층</strong>: 평가, 보안, 컴플라이언스, 감사 가능성을 설계 단계부터 내재화하는 구조다.</li>
</ul> <p>이와 함께 AI 리스크 관리는 이사회 차원의 주요 의제로 부상했다. 미국 국립표준기술연구소(NIST)의 AI 리스크 관리 프레임워크는 AI 수명 주기 전반에 걸쳐 신뢰성을 내재화하고, 개인과 조직, 사회 전반에 미치는 위험을 체계적으로 관리해야 한다고 강조했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%83%9d%ec%82%b0%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc-%eb%a6%ac%ec%8a%a4%ed%81%ac%eb%a5%bc-%eb%8f%99%ec%8b%9c%ec%97%90-%eb%86%92%ec%9d%b4%eb%8a%94-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8">생산성과 리스크를 동시에 높이는 에이전트</h2> <p>에이전트는 상당한 수준의 생산성 향상을 이끌 잠재력이 있다. 그러나 동시에 새로운 취약점도 수반한다. 프롬프트 인젝션, 데이터 유출, 안전하지 않은 행동, 생성 결과에 대한 과도한 의존 등이 대표적이다. 주요 플랫폼은 에이전트 안전성을 강화하고, 보다 견고한 통제 체계를 지속적으로 고도화하고 있다.</p> <p>앞선 기업은 에이전트를 다른 핵심 시스템과 동일한 수준으로 관리한다. 명확한 가드레일을 설정하고, 최소 권한 원칙을 적용하며, 민감한 작업에는 승인 절차를 의무화한다. 또한 성능을 지속적으로 평가하고 데이터와 행동 전반에 대한 추적 가능성을 유지한다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c%ec%a0%9d%ed%8a%b8%ea%b0%80-%ec%95%84%eb%8b%8c-%ec%a0%9c%ed%92%88-%ec%a4%91%ec%8b%ac-%ec%82%ac%ea%b3%a0%eb%a1%9c%ec%9d%98-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98">프로젝트가 아닌 제품 중심 사고로의 전환</h2> <p>지능형 전환은 일회성 도입으로 성공할 수 없다. 에이전트는 고정된 시스템이 아니라 비즈니스 요구와 리스크 환경의 변화에 따라 학습하고 적응하며 진화한다. 따라서 프로젝트 중심 전달 방식에서 벗어나 제품 중심 운영 모델로의 전환이 필요하다.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>비즈니스 주도의 성과</strong>: 각 에이전트는 처리 시간, 순추천지수(NPS), 수율, 현금 전환 주기 등 측정 가능한 비즈니스 KPI와 직접 연결돼야 한다.</li> <li><strong>융합 팀 구성</strong>: 도메인 전문가, 엔지니어, 데이터 전문가, 리스크 및 컴플라이언스 담당자가 하나의 통합 팀으로 협업해야 한다.</li> <li><strong>평가의 체계화</strong>: 정확성, 안전성, 견고성, 비용을 지속적으로 점검하는 테스트 체계를 상시 운영해야 한다.</li> <li><strong>현장 중심의 변화 관리</strong>: 성공적인 도입은 출시 당일의 이벤트가 아니라, 일상적인 업무 흐름에 자연스럽게 통합될 때 비로소 완성된다.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ea%b2%bd%ec%98%81%ec%a7%84%ec%9d%b4-%ea%b4%80%eb%a6%ac%ed%95%b4%ec%95%bc-%ed%95%a0-%ea%b0%80%ec%b9%98-%ec%b8%a1%ec%a0%95-3%eb%8b%a8%ea%b3%84">경영진이 관리해야 할 가치 측정 3단계</h2> <p>기업 가치를 효과적으로 확장하기 위해 경영진은 3가지 단계로 접근할 필요가 있다.</p> <ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>지원 단계</strong>: 문서 작성, 요약, 검색, 설명을 수행하는 코파일럿을 도입해 빠른 확산과 즉각적인 시간 절감 효과를 얻는 단계다.</li> <li><strong>증강 단계</strong>: 승인 절차를 포함해 정의된 워크플로를 완수하는 에이전트를 운영함으로써 더 높은 투자 대비 효과와 강화된 거버넌스를 확보하는 단계다.</li> <li><strong>자동화 단계</strong>: 고객과 기업의 가치 사슬을 재설계하는 새로운 운영 모델을 구축하는 단계로, 가장 큰 기회를 제공하지만 그만큼 상당한 조직 변화가 요구된다.</li>
</ol> <p>많은 기업이 곧바로 3번째 단계로 도약하려는 실수를 범한다. 그러나 가장 효과적인 전략은 점진적으로 확장하는 것이다. 1단계에서 활용 역량과 신뢰를 확보하고, 2단계에서 플랫폼과 가드레일을 표준화한 뒤, 충분한 자신감과 실행 역량을 갖춘 이후 3단계에서 본격적인 전환에 나서는 접근이 바람직하다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a7%80%eb%8a%a5%ed%98%95-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9d%80-%eb%a6%ac%eb%8d%94%ec%8b%ad%ec%9d%98-%ea%b3%bc%ec%a0%9c">지능형 전환은 리더십의 과제</h2> <p>DX가 기술을 현대화하는 데 초점을 맞췄다면, 지능형 전환은 기업 자체를 현대화한다. 업무가 발굴되고, 결정되며, 실행되는 방식을 근본적으로 재정의한다. AI 에이전트는 지식을 행동으로, 행동을 다시 학습으로 전환하는 증폭 장치가 된다.</p> <p>궁극적으로 성패는 겉으로 보기에 인상적인 에이전트를 선보이는 데 달려 있지 않다. 설계 단계부터 보안을 내재화하고, 성과 중심으로 운영되며, 직원이 대체되는 존재가 아니라 역량을 확장하는 주체로 받아들이는 신뢰 기반 에이전트 생태계를 구축하는 역량이 핵심이다.</p> <p>AI 에이전트 시대에 기업 가치를 확장하는 일은 전통적인 트랜스포메이션의 범주를 넘어선다. 모든 의사결정과 실행 과정에 지능을 내재화하고, 스스로를 지속적으로 혁신할 수 있는 조직을 구축해야 한다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-26]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[“실패하는 것은 AI가 아니라 데이터” 데이터 준비도가 성패 가른다]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137711/%ec%8b%a4%ed%8c%a8%ed%95%98%eb%8a%94-%ea%b2%83%ec%9d%80-ai%ea%b0%80-%ec%95%84%eb%8b%88%eb%9d%bc-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%ec%a4%80%eb%b9%84%eb%8f%84.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137711/%ec%8b%a4%ed%8c%a8%ed%95%98%eb%8a%94-%ea%b2%83%ec%9d%80-ai%ea%b0%80-%ec%95%84%eb%8b%88%eb%9d%bc-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%ec%a4%80%eb%b9%84%eb%8f%84.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>AI가 기대만큼 성과를 내지 못한다면 문제는 모델이 아닐 가능성이 크다. 지저분한 데이터, 허술한 거버넌스, 그리고 조용히 성능을 갉아먹는 드리프트가 결과를 망치고 있다는 얘기다.</p> <p>야구 선수 마리오 멘도사와 AI의 공통점은 ‘20% 성공률’이다. 멘도사의 타율은 ‘멘도사 라인(Mendoza Line)’이라는 말까지 낳았는데, 간신히 용인 가능한 수준의 성과를 뜻하는 단어로 굳어졌다. 산업 전반을 보면 AI 이니셔티브 5개 중 4개가 여전히 기대에 못 미친다. 원인은 대개 AI 자체가 아니라 ‘데이터 준비도 부족’에 있다.</p> <p>기업은 효율성이나 매출 증대 등 효과를 기대하며 AI 기반 혁신 프로젝트를 서둘러 추진하지만, 정작 필수 전제인 데이터 준비도를 놓치기 쉽다. 가트너는 2026년까지 ‘AI에 적합한 데이터(AI-ready data)’가 뒷받침되지 않는 AI 프로젝트의 60%가 중단될 것으로 전망했다.</p> <p>따라서 새로운 모델이나 도구에 또 투자하기 전에, 먼저 “데이터가 실제로 쓸 수 있는 상태인지”부터 확인해야 한다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%aa%85%ed%99%95%ed%95%9c-%ea%b4%80%ea%b3%84%ec%99%80-%ea%b7%b8%eb%9d%bc%ec%9a%b4%eb%93%9c-%ed%8a%b8%eb%a3%a8%ec%8a%a4%eb%a1%9c-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%ea%b8%b0%eb%b0%98">명확한 관계와 ‘그라운드 트루스’로 데이터 기반 다지기</h2> <p>AI로 성과를 내는 기업은 공통적으로 깨끗한 데이터 파이프라인, 통합된 데이터 레이크, 그리고 “데이터가 무엇을 의미하는지”에 대한 조직 차원의 합의를 갖추고 있다. 2024년에도 데이터 카탈로그 기업 세코다(Secoda)는 기업 데이터의 68%가 분석과 혁신 목적에서 여전히 활용되지 못하고 있다고 보고했다. 조직의 지식 대부분이 잠겨 있으면 알고리즘은 얕고 탁한 데이터 풀에서만 학습할 수밖에 없다.</p> <p>데이터 준비도 측면에서 유통기업 월마트(Walmart)는 ‘서두르지 않는 방식’의 대표 사례로 꼽힌다. 월마트는 공급망, POS, 솔루션 업체 데이터를 수년에 걸쳐 연결했다. 이처럼 탄탄한 기반이 갖춰지자 이후 AI 도입은 훨씬 매끄럽게 진행됐고, 비용 절감과 품절 감소, 배송 효율화에도 도움이 됐다. 조직 내 다양한 데이터 소스 간 관계를 명확히 정의하고 설명하는 작업은, AI가 비즈니스 전반에서 데이터를 올바르게 이해하고 해석하는 데 핵심 역할을 한다.</p> <p>모델 학습 과정에서는 이른바 ‘그라운드 트루스(ground truth)’ 데이터, 즉 정답 데이터 세트를 구축하는 것도 중요하다. 단순히 라벨이 붙은 데이터가 아니라, 조직의 전문지식을 기계가 학습할 수 있는 형태로 전환한 결과물이다. 먼저 해결하려는 비즈니스 문제에 직접 연결되는 온톨로지와 라벨 분류 체계를 명확히 세우는 것부터 시작해야 한다. 이어 학습 데이터의 양과 품질, 다양성이 충분한지 점검해 다양한 상황에서도 성능이 일관되게 나오도록 하고, 특히 인사나 헬스케어처럼 컴플라이언스 영향을 받는 사용례에서는 편향 완화까지 고려해야 한다.</p> <p>데이터 품질 관리 기업 타입와이저(Typewiser)에 따르면, 결론은 분명하다. 데이터를 정비하는 일은 화려하진 않지만, AI 도입에서 가장 중요하고 결정적인 단계이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%ea%b1%b0%eb%b2%84%eb%84%8c%ec%8a%a4%eb%8a%94-%eb%82%98%ec%a4%91%ec%97%90%ea%b0%80-%ec%95%84%eb%8b%88%eb%9d%bc-%ec%b2%98%ec%9d%8c%eb%b6%80">데이터 거버넌스는 ‘나중에’가 아니라 ‘처음부터’</h2> <p>거버넌스는 AI 도입 속도를 늦추는 것처럼 보일 수 있지만, 실제로는 승인 절차를 빠르게 하고 리스크를 줄이는 역할을 한다. 데이터 소유자와 감시자를 명확히 지정하고, 원천 데이터부터 모델 출력까지 이어지는 계약(데이터 계약), 계보(lineage), 출처(provenance)를 체계적으로 문서화해야 한다.</p> <p>모델 학습이나 RAG 파이프라인을 구축할 때도, 데이터 접근 권한과 보존 정책이 하위 AI 애플리케이션까지 일관되게 적용되도록 해야 한다. 민감한 개인정보는 특히 주의가 필요하며, 규제가 요구하는 경우 동의 확보도 필수다.</p> <p>거버넌스는 시스템 신뢰성에도 직결된다. 소유권이 분명하고, 문서가 재현 가능하며, 프로세스가 감사 가능한 상태라면 긴급 데이터 수정이 불러오는 혼란을 줄일 수 있다. 이른바 ‘레드 테이프’로 불리는 거버넌스는 속도를 늦추는 방해물이 아니라 품질을 기반으로 워크플로우를 더 빠르게 만드는 ‘가속 엔진’으로 작동한다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%8b%9c%ea%b0%84%ec%97%90-%eb%94%b0%eb%a5%b8-%eb%93%9c%eb%a6%ac%ed%94%84%ed%8a%b8-ai-roi%eb%a5%bc-%ec%9e%a0%ec%8b%9d%ed%95%98%eb%8a%94-%ec%a1%b0%ec%9a%a9%ed%95%9c-%eb%b6%80%ec%8b%9d">시간에 따른 드리프트, AI ROI를 잠식하는 ‘조용한 부식’</h2> <p>원칙적으로 와인은 숙성될수록 좋아진다. 그러나 데이터는 보통 그렇지 않다. 고객 취향은 변하고, 공급망은 재편되고, 규제는 강화된다. 이 변화로 인해 AI가 “세상이 이렇게 생겼다”고 학습한 그림과 현실이 어긋나는데, 이를 드리프트(drift)라고 부른다.</p> <p>드리프트는 크게 두 가지로 나뉜다. 데이터 드리프트는 입력 데이터 분포가 바뀌는 경우다. 예를 들어 환자 인구통계의 구성이나 규모가 달라지는 상황이 이에 해당한다. 개념 드리프트는 입력과 결과 사이의 관계가 변하는 경우다. 팬데믹 이전에 설계된 임상 알고리즘이 이후 환경 변화로 더는 맞지 않게 되는 사례를 떠올리면 이해가 쉽다.</p> <p>이 문제가 방치되면 ROI는 눈에 띄게 훼손된다. IT 운영 분석 기업 인사이트파인더(InsightFinder)에 따르면, 한 이커머스 기업에서 CTR이 예고 없이 30% 하락했는데도 한동안 아무도 이를 알아채지 못했다.</p> <p>드리프트는 모델의 비즈니스 가치를 떨어뜨리거나 아예 사라지게 만들 수 있다. 경우에 따라서는 막대한 손실로 이어진다. 부동산 플랫폼 기업 질로(Zillow)에서는 “주택 가치 평가 알고리즘이 2021년 3분기와 4분기에 매입한 주택의 가치를 5억 달러 이상 과대평가하도록 만들었다”는 분석도 나온 바 있다.</p> <p>회복탄력성을 확보하려면 파이프라인에 모니터링을 추가하고 주요 변수에 통계적 드리프트 테스트를 수행하며, 예측 결과를 실제 피드백과 비교하고, 일정 주기로 모델을 재학습해야 한다. 일부 조직은 운영 환경과 별도로 ‘섀도우 모델’을 함께 돌려, 출력이 벌어지기 시작하면 즉시 경보를 울리도록 하기도 한다.</p> <p>AI는 어느 날 갑자기 실패하지 않는다. 정확도가 조금씩 ‘바래’ 사라질 뿐이다. 데이터 열화를 조기에 포착할 수 있는 지표를 세워, 고객과 신뢰를 잃거나 분기 매출에 타격을 입기 전에 막아야 한다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a7%80%ec%86%8d-%ea%b0%80%eb%8a%a5%ed%95%9c-%eb%8d%b0%ec%9d%b4%ed%84%b0-%ec%a4%80%eb%b9%84%eb%8f%84%ea%b0%80-%ea%b0%80%ec%a0%b8%ec%98%a4%eb%8a%94-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc">지속 가능한 데이터 준비도가 가져오는 성과</h2> <p>결론은 분명하다. 데이터 준비도를 소홀히 하는 조직은 상당수 AI 배포가 ROI 목표를 달성하지 못하거나, 아예 실패로 끝날지도 모른다. 반대로 데이터 기반·거버넌스·드리프트 대응이라는 기본기를 갖춘 조직은 성공하는 AI 프로젝트의 반열에 올라, 실제 비즈니스 가치를 만들어낼 수 있을 것이다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-26]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[CI 파이프라인 파고든 npm 악성코드, AI 코딩 어시스턴트도 감염 위협]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137664/ci-%ed%8c%8c%ec%9d%b4%ed%94%84%eb%9d%bc%ec%9d%b8-%ed%8c%8c%ea%b3%a0%eb%93%a0-npm-%ec%95%85%ec%84%b1%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c-ai-%ec%bd%94%eb%94%a9-%ec%96%b4%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%84%b4%ed%8a%b8%eb%8f%84.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137664/ci-%ed%8c%8c%ec%9d%b4%ed%94%84%eb%9d%bc%ec%9d%b8-%ed%8c%8c%ea%b3%a0%eb%93%a0-npm-%ec%95%85%ec%84%b1%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c-ai-%ec%bd%94%eb%94%a9-%ec%96%b4%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%84%b4%ed%8a%b8%eb%8f%84.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>보안 기업 소켓(Socket) 연구진은 이번 공격 캠페인을 발견하고 이를 ‘SANDWORM_MODE’로 명명했다. 이 이름은 악성코드 런타임 제어 로직에 삽입된 ‘SANDWORM_*’ 환경 변수 스위치에서 유래했다.</p> <p>공격자는 최소 19개의 타이포스쿼팅 패키지를 여러 가명 계정으로 게시했다. 이 패키지들은 인기 개발자 유틸리티와 AI 관련 도구로 위장했다. 사용자가 패키지를 설치하면 다단계 페이로드가 실행된다. 이 과정에서 로컬 환경과 CI 시스템에 저장된 비밀 정보를 수집하고, 탈취한 토큰을 이용해 다른 저장소를 수정한다.</p> <p>또한 해당 페이로드에는 ‘샤이 훌루드’ 방식의 ‘데드 스위치(dead switch)’가 구현돼 있다. 기본적으로는 비활성화 상태를 유지하지만, 악성코드가 탐지될 경우 홈 디렉터리를 삭제하도록 설계됐다. 연구진은 이번 캠페인을 “실질적이며 고위험” 위협으로 평가하며, 해당 패키지를 실제 침해로 이어질 수 있는 위험 요소로 간주해야 한다고 밝혔다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%98%a4%ed%83%80%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%ec%8b%9c%ec%9e%91%eb%90%9c-%ec%b9%a8%ed%95%b4">오타에서 시작된 침해</h2> <p>이번 캠페인은 타이포스쿼팅으로 시작된다. 공격자는 정상 패키지와 거의 동일한 이름의 패키지를 등록해, 개발자의 오타나 AI가 잘못된 의존성을 생성하는 상황을 노린다.</p> <p>소켓 연구진은 블로그를 통해 “이번 타이포스쿼팅은 Node.js 생태계의 고트래픽 개발자 유틸리티와 암호화 도구, 그리고 빠르게 확산 중인 AI 코딩 도구를 주요 표적으로 삼고 있다”라며 “3개 패키지는 클로드 코드(Claude Code)를 사칭했고, 1개는 최근 깃허브에서 21만 개 이상의 스타를 기록한 AI 에이전트 오픈클로(OpenClaw)를 겨냥했다”라고 <a href="https://socket.dev/blog/sandworm-mode-npm-worm-ai-toolchain-poisoning" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">전했다</a>.</p> <p>악성 패키지가 설치돼 실행되면, 악성코드는 npm과 깃허브 토큰, 환경 변수에 저장된 비밀값, 클라우드 키 등 민감한 자격 증명을 탐색한다. 이후 해당 자격 증명을 활용해 다른 저장소에 악성 변경을 푸시하고, 새로운 의존성이나 워크플로를 삽입하면서 감염 범위를 확장한다.</p> <p>연구진은 또 이번 캠페인이 무기화된 깃허브 액션(GitHub Action)을 활용하고 있다고 설명했다. 이 기능은 CI 파이프라인 내부에서 빌드 과정 중 비밀 정보를 추출하고, 추가 확산을 가능하게 해 공격 효과를 증폭시킬 수 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-%ea%b0%9c%eb%b0%9c-%ec%9d%b8%ed%84%b0%ed%8e%98%ec%9d%b4%ec%8a%a4-%ec%98%a4%ec%97%bc">AI 개발 인터페이스 오염</h2> <p>이번 캠페인은 특히 AI 코딩 어시스턴트를 직접 겨냥했다는 점에서 주목된다. 악성코드는 악의적인 모델 컨텍스트 프로토콜(MCP) 서버를 배포한 뒤, 이를 주요 AI 도구 설정에 주입한다. 그 결과 해당 서버는 AI 어시스턴트 환경 내에서 신뢰된 구성 요소처럼 동작하게 된다.</p> <p>이 단계에 이르면 프롬프트 인젝션 기법을 통해 AI가 로컬의 민감한 데이터를 가져오도록 유도할 수 있다. 여기에는 SSH 키나 클라우드 자격 증명 등이 포함될 수 있다. 이렇게 수집된 정보는 사용자 인지 없이 공격자에게 전달된다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-26]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI 에이전트 시대, AX가 기업 시스템을 재정의하다]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137658/ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80-ax%ea%b0%80-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85-%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%85%9c%ec%9d%84-%ec%9e%ac%ec%a0%95%ec%9d%98%ed%95%98%eb%8b%a4.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137658/ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80-ax%ea%b0%80-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85-%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%85%9c%ec%9d%84-%ec%9e%ac%ec%a0%95%ec%9d%98%ed%95%98%eb%8b%a4.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>에이전트형 AI의 핵심은 코드 작성, 스크립트 실행, 명령 수행, API 호출 등 실제 행동을 수행하는 데 있다. 이러한 작업은 해당 기능이 쉽게 탐색 가능하고, 충분히 문서화돼 있으며, 일관된 구조를 갖추고 있고, 처음부터 에이전트가 사용하기 쉽게 설계돼 있을 때 훨씬 효과적으로 이뤄진다.</p> <p>에이전트는 사람과는 약간 다른 정보를 필요로 한다. 완전하고 정확하며 최신 상태의 문서나 올바른 명령어가 포함된 오류 메시지는 사람과 에이전트 모두에게 도움이 된다. 다만 예를 들어 데브옵스 에이전트는 전체 CI/CD 파이프라인에 대한 전반적인 맥락을 이해해야 하지만, 일반 개발자에게는 그 정도 수준의 전체 맥락이 항상 요구되지는 않는다.</p> <p>전반적으로 비즈니스 로직, 코드, 데이터, 문서, API 설계, 정책, 모범 사례를 보다 체계적으로 관리하는 일은 사람 사용자에게도 직접적인 이점을 제공한다. 반대로 이러한 기반 작업을 소홀히 할 경우, 직원이 에이전트와 더 잘 작동하는 외부 서비스로 눈을 돌리면서 새로운 차원의 섀도우 IT가 발생할 위험이 있다.</p> <p>시장조사업체 포레스터의 엔터프라이즈 아키텍처 담당 부사장 겸 수석 애널리스트 찰스 베츠는 “많은 조직이 에이전트형 AI의 가능성을 신뢰하고 도입을 검토하기 시작했지만, 이를 실제로 구현하려면 여전히 상당한 준비가 필요하다”라며 “에이전트에는 정밀하고 구조화돼 있으며 접근 가능한 정보가 요구된다”고 설명했다. 이어 “시스템에 대한 이해가 부족하면 AI 에이전트는 심각하게 혼란스러운 상태에 빠질 수 있다”고 분석했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ea%b2%bd%ed%97%98-%ec%b5%9c%ec%a0%81%ed%99%94">에이전트 경험 최적화</h2> <p>넷리파이(Netlify)의 CEO 마티아스 빌만은 기존 엔터프라이즈 시스템을 에이전트에 맞게 준비하는 과정을 ‘에이전트 경험(AX)’이라고 정의한다. 이는 에이전트가 제품이나 플랫폼의 사용자로서 실제로 마주하는 경험 전반을 의미한다.</p> <p>이미 모든 제품과 도구에는 각자의 에이전트 경험이 존재한다. AI 에이전트가 이미 이들 시스템을 사용하려 시도하고 있기 때문이다. 빌만은 “문제는 에이전트 경험이 좋은지, 나쁜지의 차이일 뿐”이라고 설명했다.</p> <p>조직이 의존하는 제품이나 서비스에 에이전트가 함께 작동하길 기대한다면, 해당 시스템이 구조화되고 예측 가능한 인터페이스를 갖추고 있는지 점검해야 한다. 또한 포괄적인 오류 처리 기능, 여러 단계로 구성된 워크플로를 지원하는 세션 지속성, 실시간 피드백 제공 기능도 중요하다. 이런 요소가 갖춰져야 에이전트가 안정적으로 작업을 수행할 수 있다.</p> <p>빌만은 “에이전트가 제품을 어떻게 발견하는가가 출발점”이라며 “사용자가 알려줘야 하는지, 아니면 에이전트가 스스로 적절한 해결책이라고 판단하는지 고민해야 한다”고 말했다. 이어 “에이전트가 제품으로 무엇을 할 수 있는지 이해하도록 어떻게 도울 것인지, 가능한 한 사용자에게 권한 요청을 최소화하면서 접근을 쉽게 제공할 수 있는지도 중요하다”고 설명했다. 또한 “에이전트 루프 안에서 충분한 맥락을 제공해, 사용자의 작업을 가장 효율적인 방식으로 해결하도록 해야 한다”고 덧붙였다.</p> <p>AX라는 용어는 이미 AI 코딩 에이전트와 개발자 도구 공급업체 사이에서 확산되고 있다. 빌만은 “코딩 에이전트, 특히 클로드 코드에서 얻은 교훈이 기업과 소비자 지향 에이전트로 확장되기 시작하면, 에이전트와 원활히 작동하지 않는 도구와 서비스는 자연스럽게 우회 대상이 될 것”이라고 내다봤다. <a href="https://www.akamai.com/blog/security/ai-pulse-how-ai-bots-agents-will-shape-2026" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">아카마이의 최근 연구 결과</a> 역시 이러한 변화가 이미 시작됐음을 보여준다.</p> <p>엔터프라이즈 환경에서 AX는 에이전트형 AI를 기존 시스템과 효과적으로 통합하기 위한 기초 작업을 의미한다. 과거 RPA처럼 레거시 애플리케이션에서 데이터를 긁어오는 방식으로 사후에 덧붙일 것인지, 아니면 MCP가 원활히 작동할 수 있도록 워크플로와 도구를 재설계해 에이전트 효율을 높일 것인지가 핵심 선택지다.</p> <p>투자자들도 기업 가치 평가와 에이전트 주도 성장 가능성을 전망할 때 이러한 원칙을 고려하기 시작했다. 앤트로픽은 에이전트와 잘 작동하는 도구를 설계하기 위한 가이드라인을 제시하고 있으며, 마이크로소프트(Microsoft)는 에이전트가 안전하게 실행될 수 있도록 접근이 제한된 전용 계정을 윈도에 도입하고 있다.</p> <p>한 AI 코드 도구 공급업체는 자사의 커서 코딩 에이전트가 CMS에 쉽게 접근하지 못하자, 막 비용을 들여 구축한 CMS를 철회하는 결정을 내렸다. 마케팅 팀은 기존 CMS 인터페이스를 사용하는 대신, 챗봇에 마크다운 형식으로 콘텐츠를 추가해 달라고 요청하는 방식이 더 간편하다고 판단했다.</p> <p>물론 AI 코딩 도구를 개발하는 기업 특성상 커서의 비기술 직군 직원들도 비교적 높은 기술 이해도를 갖추고 있다. 이후 해당 CMS 벤더는 웹사이트 생성·업데이트·관리를 에이전트가 직접 수행할 수 있도록 지원하는 MCP 서버를 출시했다. 이는 AI 에이전트가 전통적인 소프트웨어 사용 방식에 상당한 영향을 미칠 수 있음을 보여주는 사례다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="mcp%eb%a5%bc-%eb%84%98%ec%96%b4">MCP를 넘어</h2> <p>빌만은 우수한 AX를 구현하기 위한 네 가지 원칙을 제시했다. 첫째, 에이전트가 적절한 권한을 갖고 시스템에 접근할 수 있어야 한다. 둘째, LLM이 해당 시스템을 효과적으로 활용할 수 있도록 충분한 맥락을 제공받아야 한다. 셋째, API·SDK·CLI와 같은 도구가 에이전트가 이를 인터페이스처럼 활용할 수 있도록 설계돼야 한다. 넷째, 선호하는 에이전트를 쉽게 호출하고 조율할 수 있는 구조를 갖춰야 한다.</p> <p>빌만은 “MCP, 역량, 컨텍스트 파일, 도구 응답 조정 등을 포함해 에이전트가 제품을 사용할 때 올바른 맥락을 확보하도록 설계하는 ‘컨텍스트 엔지니어링’이라는 분야가 새롭게 형성되고 있다”고 설명했다. 그는 넷리파이 CLI 명령어의 오류 메시지에 단 한 줄의 출력을 추가한 것만으로도, 도구를 활용하지 못하던 상태에서 한 번에 배포까지 가능하도록 AX가 근본적으로 개선됐다고 전했다.</p> <p>다만 단순히 API를 감싸는 MCP를 만드는 것만으로는 충분하지 않다. 빌만은 “MCP를 에이전트를 위한 UI로 생각해야 한다”며 “단순한 API 호출을 넘어, API를 통해 작업을 효율적으로 완수할 수 있도록 적절한 맥락과 구조, 그리고 API 엔드포인트가 일반적으로 어떻게 함께 사용되는지에 대한 정보를 제공해야 한다”고 말했다.</p> <p>AI 인프라 기업 젠틱(Jentic)의 CEO 숀 블랜치필드도 AI에는 추가적인 통합용 접착제가 아니라 맥락이 필요하다는 데 동의했다. 블랜치필드는 “잘 설계된 API에 대한 명확한 문서만 제공하면 LLM은 이미 이를 직접 연동할 수 있다”며 “결국 고품질 API 관리가 엔터프라이즈 AI 역량의 진정한 기반이 된다”고 설명했다. 이어 “OpenAPI, API 게이트웨이, 인증, 거버넌스에 대한 기존 투자는 AI 시대에 상당한 가치를 창출할 것”이라고 평가했다.</p> <p>에이전트는 자신들의 사양에 부합하는 API를 필요로 하지만, 실제로는 이를 충족하지 못하는 경우가 많다. 젠틱이 제공하는 무료 ‘AI 준비도 스코어카드’ 도구는 이러한 부분을 점검할 수 있는 방법 중 하나다.</p> <p>대표적인 문제로는 잘못된 참조, OpenAPI 사양 내 비정상적인 스키마, 서버 호스트 정보가 명시되지 않은 API, 또는 API를 통해 접근할 수 없는 상태로 사람 개발자용 인증 정보만 문서화한 사례 등이 있다. 사람 개발자는 이러한 한계를 우회할 수 있지만, 에이전트는 이에 크게 제약을 받는다.</p> <p>SaaS 플랫폼 APIContext의 COO 데이비드 오닐은 “API 사양만으로는 운영 순서에 대한 개념을 담을 수 없다”고 지적했다. 이를 보완하기 위해 OpenAPI의 아라조 워크플로 표준을 활용해 운영 흐름을 인코딩해야 한다는 설명이다. 오닐은 “이제 OpenAPI 사양과 아라조 워크플로가 중요해졌다”며 “MCP와 에이전트형 시스템이 실제로 동작 가능한지를 검증할 때 이 표준을 활용하기 때문”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>포레스터의 베츠는 이러한 작업을 ‘생성형 엔진 최적화’라고 표현했다. 이는 에이전트가 서비스에 대한 세부 정보를 정확히 파악하도록 돕는 활동을 의미한다.</p> <p>베츠는 “API를 체계적으로 문서화하고, 데이터와 정보에 대해 명확한 비즈니스 정의를 마련하며, 해당 데이터가 어디에 존재하는지, 어떤 시스템이 최종 권위 시스템인지 분명히 이해하는 일은 매우 중요하다”고 설명했다. 이어 “지난 20년간 데이터 및 엔터프라이즈 아키텍트가 구축해 온 기반이야말로 AI가 제대로 작동하기 위해 반드시 필요한 요소”라고 분석했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ax-%ea%b8%b0%eb%b3%b8-%ec%9b%90%ec%b9%99-%ec%a0%90%ea%b2%80">AX 기본 원칙 점검</h2> <p>브로드컴의 스태프 테크놀로지스트 마이클 코테는 “대부분의 조직은 당장 폐기할 준비는 돼 있지 않지만, 그렇다고 그대로 복제하고 싶지도 않은 오래된 코드와 아키텍처를 사용하고 있다”고 진단했다. 코테는 “잘 설계된 데이터베이스와 데이터 아키텍처가 무엇인지, 단지 기능적으로만 동작하지만 바람직하지 않은 구조가 무엇인지 구분해 명확히 표시해 두는 작업이 필요하다”고 조언했다.</p> <p>데이터 분석 플랫폼 KNIME의 IT 디렉터 마틴 하이더는 이러한 작업이 기본적인 IT 위생에 해당하지만 여전히 매우 중요하다고 설명했다. 특히 과거에는 최신 상태를 유지하거나 항상 접근 가능하도록 관리할 필요가 없었던 여러 데이터 소스를 직원이 수작업으로 취합해 처리해 온 업무를 자동화하려는 경우라면 더욱 그렇다는 지적이다. 하이더는 “재고 정보, 로그, 문서가 신뢰할 수 없다면 어떤 AI 시스템도 결국 잘못된 정보를 자동화하게 될 뿐”이라고 언급했다.</p> <p>또한 에이전트는 조직 내 암묵지가 어디에 존재하는지를 초기 단계에서 드러내는 경우가 많다. 따라서 코드 전반에 걸쳐 표준을 수립하고, 코드 리뷰를 엄격히 시행하며, 시스템 정의와 문서를 단일 참조 체계로 유지하는 것이 중요하다. 이는 에이전트가 일관된 틀 안에서 작업할 수 있도록 돕는 기반이 된다.</p> <p>마이크로소프트(MS)의 앱 및 에이전트 부문 CVP 아만다 실버는 이를 ‘에이전트 헌법’이라고 표현했다. 이는 조직이나 코드베이스 전반에 걸친 요구사항과 공통 기대치를 자연어로 명시하는 방식이다. 실버는 “에이전트가 항상 해당 내용을 맥락에 포함하도록 해야 한다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>이 개념은 보다 폭넓게 적용될 수 있으며, 메타 프롬프트 형태로 활용할 수도 있다. 예를 들어 에이전트가 ID를 관리해야 할 때의 구체적인 처리 방식, 휴먼 인 더 루프 인터페이스를 생성하는 방법, 또는 에이전트의 운영 과정을 관찰할 수 있는 기능을 구축하는 절차 등을 명시할 수 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%eb%a7%a5%eb%9d%bd%ea%b3%bc-%ec%97%b0%ea%b2%b0%ec%84%b1">맥락과 연결성</h2> <p>기존 인프라에 대한 ID 관리, 접근 통제, 권한 설정은 기본 전제다. 대부분의 조직은 우선 인벤토리 정비부터 시작해야 할 가능성이 크다. 에이전트가 상호작용할 모든 시스템을 파악하고, 필요 시 이를 업데이트할 수 있는지 확인해야 한다.</p> <p>이는 새로운 API를 추가하거나, 핵심 로직과 사용자 인터페이스가 강하게 결합돼 에이전트 활용이 어려운 레거시 애플리케이션을 교체하는 작업으로 이어질 수 있다. API가 기본 내장된 SaaS나 조합형·헤드리스 아키텍처로 전환하는 방안도 포함된다. 실제로 <a href="https://events.zoom.us/ev/At8qPt_kj8QuwIYG-sraITvjG7V3-bY95Qu9tNxjQDv68RKdJI_-~AmE-M2frw15GgasODwnOQgGp45dscNHHca10KDub2su3TOyGyWyR1Gq9OA" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">IDC와 논의 중인 조직 가운데</a> 약 30%는 AI와 에이전트를 보다 효과적으로 활용하기 위해 전체 소프트웨어 포트폴리오를 현대화하는 방안을 검토하고 있다.</p> <p>실버는 “에이전트가 제공할 수 있는 가장 높은 ROI 작업은 백엔드 워크플로 처리”라고 평가했다. 이어 “MCP와 같은 프로토콜을 활용해 데이터를 노출할 수는 있지만, 그것만으로 에이전트가 행동을 수행할 수 있는 것은 아니다”라며 “어떤 작업을 자동화할지 정의하고, 이를 에이전트가 호출할 수 있는 도구로 노출해 의도에서 계획을 거쳐 실제 실행과 행동까지 이어지도록 설계해야 한다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>예를 들어 장애 대응에 에이전트를 활용하려면, 사고 관련 정보를 취합하는 대시보드에 데이터를 추가할 수 있는 API 접근 권한이 필요하다. 또한 주문 배송 여부나 송장 분쟁 여부와 같은 이벤트를 구독할 수 있도록 워크플로에 에이전트를 포함해야 하며, 이에 맞춰 적절한 조치를 자동으로 트리거할 수 있어야 한다.</p> <p>정책 역시 문서 형태가 아니라 코드에 포함돼 있는 경우가 많다. 이를 에이전트가 접근할 수 있는 자연어 정책 문서로 추출하는 작업도 필요하다. 조직이 더 많은 에이전트를 활용하게 되면, 전체 워크플로를 순차적으로 조율하는 오케스트레이션을 넘어, 여러 정책을 동시에 충족해야 하는 ‘적대적 평가’ 방식까지 고려해야 한다는 것이 실버의 설명이다.</p> <p>실버는 “이를 위해 정책 기반의 멀티 에이전트 오케스트레이션을 구현하고, 여러 전문 에이전트의 판단을 종합해 자연어로 규정된 다수의 정책을 동시에 충족하는 결정을 내리도록 설계할 수 있다”고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8%eb%a5%bc-%ec%9c%84%ed%95%9c-%ed%95%80%ec%98%b5%ec%8a%a4">에이전트를 위한 핀옵스</h2> <p>초기 도입 조직은 이미 에이전트가 집요하게 반복 요청을 보내는 특성을 경험하고 있다. 빌만은 “에이전트는 계속 시도하며 가능한 모든 방법을 동원한다”며 “스스로 멈추지 않기 때문에 서비스에 과부하를 일으킬 수 있다”고 설명했다. API를 직접 설계하지 않아 힌트를 반환하도록 수정할 수 없다면, 쿼터를 설정하거나 요청 우선순위를 조정하는 방식이 필요할 수 있다.</p> <p>APIContext의 COO 데이비드 오닐은 “에이전트형 시스템은 스스로를 통제하는 데 취약하기 때문에 다양한 상황별로 수동 가드레일을 설정해야 할 가능성이 크다”며 “이 시스템은 해법을 도출하도록 설계됐지, 실패했을 때 스스로 중단하도록 설계된 것은 아니다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>포레스터의 찰스 베츠는 무한 반복이나 과도한 API 호출을 방지하기 위해 멱등성 보장, 재시도 정책, 쿼터와 사용 한도 설정을 강제해야 한다고 조언했다. 베츠는 “에이전트는 무제한 자원이 아니며, 원하는 답을 얻지 못할 경우 언제 시도를 중단해야 하는지 알아야 한다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>마이크로소프트(Microsoft)의 앱 및 에이전트 부문 CVP 아만다 실버는 거버넌스의 핵심 중 하나로 에이전트에 노출된 MCP 범위를 파악하는 일을 꼽았다. 실버는 “특정 MCP에 대한 접근을 철회할 수 있어야 하고, 토큰 사용량을 관리하며, 조직에 적합한 거버넌스 정책을 적용할 수 있어야 한다”고 전했다.</p> <p>결국 AX는 UX와 마찬가지로 반복적 개선이 필요한 분야다. 빌만은 “사용자나 에이전트가 무엇을 달성하려 하는지 이해하는 것이 출발점”이라며 “문제와 기회를 분석할 전담 팀을 두어야 한다”고 말했다. 이를 위해 세션 리플레이를 분석하고, 실패하는 에이전트 행동을 식별하며, 이를 성공으로 이끌 수 있는 응답과 인터페이스를 설계해야 한다는 설명이다.</p> <p>에이전트 모델이 고도화되면서 넷리파이는 최신 API로 유도하기 위한 컨텍스트 파일에 덜 의존하게 됐다. 그러나 이는 곧 목표 지점이 계속 변화한다는 의미이기도 하다. 빌만은 “지속적으로 협업하고 반복 개선해야 할 새로운 에이전트라는 이용자층이 등장했다”고 평가했다.</p> <p>오닐에 따르면 MCP를 이미 활용 중인 APIContext 고객은 트랜잭션 수, 호출되는 API, 사용되는 서비스 자체가 예기치 않게 변하는 사례를 경험하고 있다. 오닐은 “MCP가 반환하는 서비스 목록이 달라지거나, 기록을 생성하는 방식이 변경돼 더 이상 작동하지 않는 경우가 있다”며 “게이트웨이처럼 모든 것을 정의하는 구조가 아니라, 사용할 수 있는 도구 목록을 제공하는 블랙박스에 가깝다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>새롭게 등장한 MCP 서버 성능 모니터링 도구는 성능 임계값, 사양, 네트워크 기능, 데이터 주권을 위한 전송 규칙 등을 기준으로 알림을 설정하고 거버넌스 규칙을 수립할 수 있도록 지원한다. 에이전트 시대에는 API 관리에 대해 그 어느 때보다 세심한 주의가 필요하다는 지적이다. 오닐은 “이로 인해 기업이 API 거버넌스를 더욱 진지하게 받아들이게 될 것”이라고 내다봤다.</p> <p>베츠는 거버넌스 도구와 모니터링, 관측 체계뿐 아니라 API 게이트웨이도 적극 활용해야 한다고 조언했다. 그는 “에이전트는 LLM과 추론 과정, 의도 관리, 목표 추구 행위를 포함한 하나의 서비스일 뿐”이라며 “결국 여전히 소프트웨어”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>이는 로그 인프라에 상당한 부하가 가해질 수 있음을 의미한다. 베츠는 “에이전트형 접근을 전면 도입하고 모든 에이전트를 추적한다면, 트래픽은 다소 비결정적인 방식으로 오가게 될 것”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>실버는 에이전트의 성공 여부를 평가할 때 결과와 관측 가능성을 함께 고려해야 한다고 강조했다. 실버는 “시간이 지남에 따라 에이전트가 실제로 의도한 작업을 수행하고 있는지, 경로를 이탈하지는 않는지 평가해야 한다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>MS는 이미 사이트 신뢰성 엔지니어링(SRE)에 에이전트를 활용해 라이브 사이트 장애 대응 비용을 낮추고 복구 시간을 단축하고 있다. 실버는 “이를 위해서는 레이블과 타임스탬프가 포함돼 추적 가능한 데이터를 확보해야 한다”며 “풍부하고 구조화된 신호와 함께, 어떤 결과가 바람직한지에 대한 명확한 기준도 필요하다”고 밝혔다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-26]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[칼럼 | 웹 대신 CLI…클로드 코드가 보여준 API 중심 시대의 도래]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137245/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%ec%9b%b9-%eb%8c%80%ec%8b%a0-cli%ed%81%b4%eb%a1%9c%eb%93%9c-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c%ea%b0%80-%eb%b3%b4%ec%97%ac%ec%a4%80-api-%ec%a4%91%ec%8b%ac-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80%ec%9d%98.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137245/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%ec%9b%b9-%eb%8c%80%ec%8b%a0-cli%ed%81%b4%eb%a1%9c%eb%93%9c-%ec%bd%94%eb%93%9c%ea%b0%80-%eb%b3%b4%ec%97%ac%ec%a4%80-api-%ec%a4%91%ec%8b%ac-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80%ec%9d%98.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>요즘 개발자이자 테크 분야 작가로 살아가기는 쉽지 않다.</p> <p>불과 두 달 전만 해도 상황은 달랐다. 글로 다룰 주제는 언제나 넘쳐났다. ‘데이터베이스 설계를 개선하는 일곱 가지 방법’이나 ‘코드를 작성하며 절대 하지 않는 다섯 가지’ 같은 주제도 가능했다. 코드를 작성할 때 개발자가 고민하는 요소는 셀 수 없이 많았다. 클린 코드와 그 작성법에 대한 탐구는 끊임없는 개선의 과정이었고, 성실한 개발자는 더 나은 방법을 배우는 데 적극적이었다.</p> <p>지금은 어떤가. 코드를 작성하는 주체도, 데이터베이스를 설계하는 주체도 사람이 아니다. 코딩 에이전트가 그 일을 대신하고 있다.</p> <p>그래서 다시 코딩 에이전트에 대해 글을 쓰고 있다. 아이러니하게도, 지금 벌어지는 변화는 충분히 전율을 느낄 만큼 인상적이다.</p> <p>그동안 여러 웹사이트 아이디어를 떠올렸다. 단순한 재미를 위한 것도 있었고, 소소한 수익을 기대할 수 있는 아이디어도 있었다. 지난 주말에는 그중 하나, 수익 창출이 가능한 아이디어를 실제로 구현했다. 현재는 이미 운영 중이다. 링크를 공개할 생각은 없지만, 한마디로 설명하면 개발자라면 누구나 꺼려하는 작업을 돕는 작은 도구다.</p> <p>이 과정을 통해 흥미로운 교훈 하나를 얻었다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%81%b4%eb%a1%9c%eb%93%9c%ea%b0%80-%ed%95%b4%eb%82%b8-%ec%9d%bc">클로드가 해낸 일</h2> <p>전체 경험은 놀라울 정도였다. 필자는 클로드 코드 사용자다. 물론 의인화하고 있다는 점은 인정하지만, 클로드가 자신이 무엇을 하고 있는지 잘 이해하고 있다는 신뢰가 있다. 기업용 계정도 보유하고 있으며, 고객 프로젝트에 활용하고 있다. 기본 설정 파일로 활용하는 비교적 탄탄한 Claude.md 파일도 갖추고 있다. 구현하고자 하는 프로젝트를 상세히 설명한 뒤 작업을 시작하라고 지시했다.</p> <p>약 20분 만에 웹사이트가 완성됐다. 그것도 필자가 원한 기능을 정확히 구현한 상태였다. 기대한 대로, 정확하고, 오차 없이 동작했다.</p> <p>말 그대로 경이로운 경험이었다.</p> <p>이후 수익 모델을 고민했다. 서비스에 과금할 방법을 찾으라고 요청했다. 클로드는 ‘1크레딧당 1회 거래’ 방식의 크레딧 시스템을 제안했고, 신용카드 결제를 처리할 수 있는 대중적인 외부 결제 서비스를 추천했다.</p> <p>이어 해당 결제 서비스를 제공업체 웹사이트에 설정하는 방법을 단계별로 안내했다. 그런데 이제는 그마저도 직접 하고 싶지 않았다. 클로드의 역량을 경험한 뒤라 모든 과정을 맡기고 싶어졌다. 실제로 그렇게 요청했고, 클로드는 이를 수행했다. 사람이 하던 일을 추상적 존재에 맡기고 있다는 사실은 알고 있다.</p> <p>그러나 이번 경험에서 특히 인상적이었던 점은 따로 있다. 클로드는 해당 결제 서비스의 명령줄 인터페이스(CLI)를 내려받아 로그인 과정을 제외한 모든 설정을 스스로 처리했다. 웹사이트를 직접 조작하지는 못했지만, CLI 환경에서는 전혀 문제가 없었다.</p> <p>이 순간 중요한 통찰이 떠올랐다. 필자가 만든 웹사이트는 잠재 고객이 직접 방문해 사용할 대상이 아니었다. 기능 자체는 분명 유용했다. 그러나 에이전트 기반 코딩 시대에 사람이 직접 웹사이트에 접속해 사용하는 방식은 매력적이지 않다. 대신 사용자는 자신의 코딩 에이전트나 빌드 프로세스, 혹은 다른 자동화 시스템이 해당 서비스를 호출해 활용하길 원할 가능성이 크다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%95%84%ec%9e%90%ea%b0%80-%ec%96%bb%ec%9d%80-%ea%b5%90%ed%9b%88">필자가 얻은 교훈</h2> <p>그래서 클로드에게 해당 과정을 수행하는 명령줄 도구를 만들라고 지시했다. 약 20분이 더 지나자 맥, 윈도우, 리눅스용 실행 파일이 모두 준비됐다. Arm과 x86 아키텍처용 버전도 각각 생성됐다. 웹사이트 구조도 바꿨다. CLI를 중심에 두고, 사용자의 브라우저 요청에 포함된 운영체제 정보를 감지해 적절한 다운로드 파일을 자동으로 제공하도록 수정했다.</p> <p>이 모든 작업이 토요일 오후에 이뤄졌다.</p> <p>여기서 얻은 교훈은 ‘이제는 하루 만에 웹사이트를 만들 수 있다’는 사실이 아니다. 그 점은 이미 알고 있었다. 진짜 교훈은 따로 있다. 우리가 지금 하고 있는 일의 상당 부분이 더 이상 사람을 위한 코딩이 아니라는 점이다. 이제는 다른 에이전트를 위한 코딩을 하고 있다. 어쩌면 이것을 여전히 ‘코딩’이라고 부를 수 있을지도 생각해볼 문제다.</p> <p>앞으로 며칠, 정말로 ‘며칠’이라는 표현이 과장이 아닐지도 모른다. 우리는 웹사이트의 사용성을 고민하는 시간은 크게 줄이고, 대신 API와 CLI의 효율성을 어떻게 높일지에 더 많은 시간을 쓰게 될 가능성이 크다.</p> <p>필자는 해당 결제 서비스의 웹사이트를 직접 다루고 싶지 않았다. 대신 클로드가 그들의 CLI를 통해 처리하길 원했고, 실제로 그렇게 했다. 앞으로는 사용자가 필자의 웹사이트에 직접 방문해 기능을 사용하는 방식이 아니라, 클로드가 필자의 CLI를 호출해 작업을 수행하는 형태가 될 것이다.</p> <p>머지않아 클로드는 REST API를 통해 더 효율적으로 상호작용하길 선호할 가능성이 높다. 그렇다면 REST API도 구축해야 한다.</p> <p>아마도 그 작업 역시 클로드가 대신 수행할 것이다. 그래서 클로드를 ‘그’라고 부르는지도 모르겠다. 무언가에 의해 대체되는 것보다, 누군가에 의해 대체되는 편이 심리적으로는 덜 냉정하게 느껴진다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-26]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[SAP 전환 프로젝트 10곳 중 6곳 지연…거버넌스 부실 원인 지목]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137233/sap-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98-%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c%ec%a0%9d%ed%8a%b8-10%ea%b3%b3-%ec%a4%91-6%ea%b3%b3-%ec%a7%80%ec%97%b0%ea%b1%b0%eb%b2%84%eb%84%8c%ec%8a%a4-%eb%b6%80%ec%8b%a4-%ec%9b%90%ec%9d%b8.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137233/sap-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98-%ed%94%84%eb%a1%9c%ec%a0%9d%ed%8a%b8-10%ea%b3%b3-%ec%a4%91-6%ea%b3%b3-%ec%a7%80%ec%97%b0%ea%b1%b0%eb%b2%84%eb%84%8c%ec%8a%a4-%eb%b6%80%ec%8b%a4-%ec%9b%90%ec%9d%b8.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>대부분의 SAP 마이그레이션은 실제 구축에 착수하기도 전에 실패하는 것으로 나타났다. ISG가 발표한 <a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fisg-one.com%2Fadvisory%2Fsap%2F2026-state-of-sap-migrations-report&amp;esheet=54409483&amp;newsitemid=20260202883729&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=ISG+State+of+SAP+Migrations+report&amp;index=3&amp;md5=d734d939b2a7a3086a80a119d107b2c4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">‘SAP 마이그레이션 현황</a>(The State of SAP Migrations)’ 보고서의 결론이다.</p> <p>기술 리서치 및 자문 기업 ISG가 직원 1,000명 이상 대형 글로벌 기업의 비즈니스 및 IT 의사결정자 200명 이상을 대상으로 조사한 결과, S/4HANA로 전환하면서 새로운 SAP 프로세스와 기술을 도입한 기업은 18%에 그쳤다. 5곳 중 1곳에도 못 미치는 수준이다. 반면 49%는 거의 변화 없이 기존 프로세스와 데이터를 유지하는 방식을 선택한 것으로 나타났다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%9d%bc%ec%a0%95-%ec%a7%80%ec%97%b0%ea%b3%bc-%ec%98%88%ec%82%b0-%ec%b4%88%ea%b3%bc-%eb%b0%98%eb%b3%b5%eb%90%98%eb%8a%94-s-4hana-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9d%98-%ed%98%84%ec%8b%a4">일정 지연과 예산 초과, 반복되는 S/4HANA 전환의 현실</h2> <p>S/4HANA 마이그레이션에서 일정 지연과 예산 초과는 예외적인 사례가 아니라 일반적인 현상에 가깝다. ISG에 따르면 전체 SAP 마이그레이션의 약 60%가 당초 계획한 일정과 예산을 초과했다. 주요 원인으로는 복잡성에 대한 과소평가, 프로젝트 범위 확대, 내부 인력 역량 병목이 꼽혔다.</p> <p>애널리스트들은 이러한 지연이 기술적 난이도보다는 취약한 거버넌스에서 비롯되는 경우가 많다고 분석했다. 따라서 이는 단순한 실행상의 문제가 아니라 보다 구조적인 문제를 드러내는 신호로 볼 수 있다는 설명이다.</p> <p>ISG 파트너이자 보고서 공동 저자인 스테이시 캐디건은 “많은 마이그레이션 프로그램에는 여러 시스템 통합 사업자, SAP 서비스 제공업체, 전문 벤더가 참여한다”라며 “하지만 제공업체 간 의사결정 권한, 수용 기준, 책임 범위가 명확하게 정의되지 않은 경우가 많다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>캐디건은 책임 구조의 불일치와 인센티브의 비정렬이 프로젝트 범위 확대와 일정 지연으로 이어진다고 분석했다. 이어 “SAP 마이그레이션을 효과적으로 관리하려면 구현 책임을 명확히 규정하고, 데이터 준비 상태, 통합 테스트, 변화 관리와 같은 핵심 활동에 대해 독립적인 감독 체계를 마련해야 한다”고 전했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ea%b1%b0%eb%b2%84%eb%84%8c%ec%8a%a4%eb%a1%9c-%eb%a6%ac%ec%8a%a4%ed%81%ac%eb%a5%bc-%eb%82%ae%ec%b6%b0%ec%95%bc">거버넌스로 리스크를 낮춰야</h2> <p>ISG는 SAP 마이그레이션 거버넌스를 단순한 행정 절차가 아니라 리스크를 최소화하기 위한 핵심 수단으로 인식해야 한다고 조언했다. 이를 위해 모든 이해관계자의 산출 책임과 결과 책임을 명확히 규정하고, 설계 단계에서 구축·테스트 단계로 전환할 때 객관적인 품질 게이트를 설정해야 한다고 제시했다.</p> <p>애널리스트들은 서비스 제공업체가 스스로를 관리하도록 맡기는 방식의 프로그램은 비용과 일정상의 완충 여력이 소진된 이후에야 문제가 드러나는 경우가 많다고 분석했다.</p> <p>전문가들은 또 다른 방안으로 제공업체 보상의 일부를 구체적인 납품 성과 지표와 연계할 것을 권고했다. 데이터 마이그레이션 완성도, 결함 유출률, 통합 테스트 안정성, 컷오버 리허설 성공 여부와 같은 조기 지표를 통해 프로젝트 상태를 초기 단계에서 점검하고, 성과에 대한 공동 책임을 강화할 수 있다는 설명이다.</p> <p>ISG 애널리스트들은 이러한 관리 장치가 부족할 경우 프로젝트 후반에 예상치 못한 문제가 발생할 가능성이 높아진다고 진단했다. 이 경우 상당한 기술적 노력을 투입하더라도 상황을 만회하기는 쉽지 않다고 분석했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-26]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[「CIOは変革の主役になれる」──アクセンチュアAIセンター長が語る、日本企業が全社AI展開を成功させる鍵]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136097/%e3%80%8ccio%e3%81%af%e5%a4%89%e9%9d%a9%e3%81%ae%e4%b8%bb%e5%bd%b9%e3%81%ab%e3%81%aa%e3%82%8c%e3%82%8b%e3%80%8d%e2%94%80%e2%94%80%e3%82%a2%e3%82%af%e3%82%bb%e3%83%b3%e3%83%81%e3%83%a5%e3%82%a2ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136097/%e3%80%8ccio%e3%81%af%e5%a4%89%e9%9d%a9%e3%81%ae%e4%b8%bb%e5%bd%b9%e3%81%ab%e3%81%aa%e3%82%8c%e3%82%8b%e3%80%8d%e2%94%80%e2%94%80%e3%82%a2%e3%82%af%e3%82%bb%e3%83%b3%e3%83%81%e3%83%a5%e3%82%a2ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p><strong>保科学世（ほしな・がくせ）</strong><br>アクセンチュア　執行役員　ビジネス コンサルティング本部　データ &amp; AIグループ日本統括　AIセンター長　アクセンチュア・イノベーション・ハブ東京共同統括　博士（理学）。アクセンチュアのアナリティクス、AI部門の日本統括として、Accenture AI HUB PlatformやAccenture AI Powered Servicesなどの各種開発を手掛けると共に、アナリティクスやAI技術活用した業務改革を数多く実現。また、先進R&amp;D拠点「アクセンチュア・アドバンスト・AIセンター京都」の所長として、AI研究・開発を推進。『生成AI時代の「超」仕事術大全』（共著、東洋経済新報社）、『AI時代の実践データアナリティクス』（共編著、日本経済新聞出版）など著書・監修書多数。一般社団法人サーキュラーエコノミー推進機構理事。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">日本企業を阻む「パイロットの壁」──グローバル比較で見えた課題<strong></strong></h2> <p>保科氏はまず、世界と比較しての日本企業のAI活用について、アクセンチュアのグローバル調査を紹介した。日本企業のAI活用における特徴的な傾向として、「グローバルではパイロットから本格展開に進んでいるが、日本は圧倒的にパイロット率が高い。パイロットから本格展開に進んでいない」と指摘する。 POC（概念実証）の壁は越えた。一部の業務や部署でAIの適用も始まっている。しかし、そこから全社展開へと進めない企業が多い。これが日本企業が直面する「パイロットの壁」だ。</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?w=1024" alt="Accenture" class="wp-image-4136102" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?quality=50&amp;strip=all 2460w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=300%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=768%2C430&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=1024%2C573&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=1536%2C859&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=2048%2C1146&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=1240%2C694&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=150%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=854%2C478&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=640%2C358&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.png?resize=444%2C248&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="573" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p class="imageCredit">Accenture</p></div> <p>さらに懸念される調査結果もある。2026年の成長見通しについて、グローバルでは成長加速を見込む企業が多い一方、日本では成長減速を予想する企業の割合が高いという結果だ。AI投資についても、グローバル企業の多くが投資増を回答しているのに対し、日本では投資減少を考える企業が一定数存在する。世界がAI時代に向けてアクセルを踏もうという時に、ブレーキを踏むようなものだ。</p> <p>一方で、注目すべき傾向もある。日本企業は、AIを人間の置き換えではなく業務支援として活用する傾向が強いのだ。「新たな人員増を伴わず、AI活用で人材ギャップに対応する」という調査項目では、日本企業が際立って高い数値を示した。この人間中心のアプローチは、適切に展開できれば強みとなる可能性がある。ただし現状では課題も明確だ。グローバルと比較して、AIアウトプットへの不信を挙げる企業はグローバルの約2倍。インフラ制約やデータ品質への懸念も高い。</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?w=1024" alt="Accenture" class="wp-image-4136104" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?quality=50&amp;strip=all 2442w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=300%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=768%2C426&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=1024%2C569&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=1536%2C853&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=2048%2C1137&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=1240%2C689&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=150%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=854%2C474&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=640%2C355&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/2.png?resize=444%2C247&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="569" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p class="imageCredit">Accenture</p></div> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">業務・人材・<strong>AI</strong>基盤の『三位一体』――なぜ<strong>IT</strong>部門だけで進めると失敗するのか<strong></strong></h2> <p>では、なぜ日本企業はパイロットから全社展開へと進めないのか。保科氏は「人と組織の問題が大きい」と分析する。</p> <p>一部の業務で小規模にAIを活用するだけなら、限られた専門家で対応できる。しかし全社規模に展開するとなると話は別だ。スケール時のパフォーマンス、セキュリティ、運用体制、そして動きの速いAI技術に合わせて継続的に進化させなければならない。「一部の小さな専門家チームで回しているうちはいいが、それを全社規模で発展、維持できるのかが日本企業のネック」と保科氏。</p> <p>そこで強調するのは、業務変革、人材変革、AI基盤の「三位一体」での取り組みだ。業務プロセスを再設計し、人材をリスキリングし、全社のAI基盤を整備する。保科氏は、次のように説明する。「業務、人、AI基盤。この三つの変革が三位一体で必要である。これができないと、エンタープライズ（全社）の改革にはならず、一部の業務でAIを使っているにとどまってしまう」</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?w=1024" alt="Accenture" class="wp-image-4136101" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?quality=50&amp;strip=all 2464w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=768%2C433&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=1024%2C578&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=1536%2C866&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=2048%2C1155&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=1236%2C697&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1236w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=298%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 298w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=150%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=851%2C480&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 851w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=638%2C360&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 638w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.png?resize=444%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="578" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p class="imageCredit">Accenture</p></div> <p>生成AIが従来技術と根本的に異なるのは、業務の在り方そのものを変える潜在性を秘めた技術であるという点だ。従来型AIは構造化データで予測や分析を行うものだった。しかし生成AIは、全社の知識、文書、会話といった非構造化データを扱う。暗黙知の形式知化であり、人の判断や例外処理も業務プロセスに組み込む必要がある。</p> <p>もう一つの大きな違いは技術進化の速度だ。AIは今使っている技術が半年後、1カ月後には陳腐化しているというスピード感で進んでいる。そうした前提で、エンタープライズのシステムを維持していかなければならないと保科氏は指摘する。</p> <p>こうした変化に対応するため、保科氏は役割分担の必要性を説く。既存ITの維持とAIによる業務変革、そのすべてをマルチにこなせる人材は少ないからだ。「CAIOはビジネスとAIとIT、これをつなぐ役割を担う。一方でCIOは基盤のセキュリティ、運用、スケールにフォーカスした方が、人材としては見つけやすい」。もっとも、肩書にこだわる必要はない。重要なのは、複雑化する責任領域を適切に分担することだ。</p> <p>CIOの役割はどう変わるのか。従来のCIOは、社内システムを限られた予算で維持することが主な役割だった。しかし生成AI時代のCIOには、技術を使ってどう業務変革していくかが求められる。「単なる業務の自動化ではなく、そもそも業務の在り方を変える。システムも変わるが、何より業務が変わる」。柔軟性が問われる一方で、信頼性も担保しなければならない。難しさが全く違ってくると保科氏は語る。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">成否を分ける最大の要因は「<strong>CEO</strong>のコミットメント」<strong></strong></h2> <p>AIの全社展開を成功させる最大の要因は何か。保科氏は「一番大事なのはCEOのコミット」と言い切る。</p> <p>多数の企業を見てきた経験から、うまくいかない企業には共通のパターンがある、と保科氏。CEOにAI変革の提案をして、ノーと言われることはまずない。問題はその後だ。CEOがCIOやCTOに丸投げしてしまうケースは失敗するという。</p> <p>そのため、CEOが最後までリーダーであり続けることが大切という。「実行責任者はCIOかもしれないが、リーダーはあくまでCEOでなければならない」ーーここが成否を分けるポイントと言えそうだ。</p> <p>その理由は、AIがもたらす変化の本質にある。アクセンチュアの調査によれば、労働時間の44%が「生成AIによって自動化されるか、大きく強化される可能性が高い」と回答している。業務の半分近くが変わる変革を、ITの責任者だけでリードすることはできない。企業を率いるCEOのリーダーシップが不可欠だと保科氏は強調する。</p> <p>全社変革を進める上で、保科氏が重視するのは具体的な未来像の共有だ。AI導入への抵抗には二つのタイプがある、と保科氏は分析する。一つは現状維持への固執、もう一つは漠然とした不安だ。後者は、AIがもたらす具体的な未来像を示すことで緩和できる。そこで技術検証のためのPOCではなく、業務がどう変わるのかをビデオやデモで実際に見せることが有効だという。</p> <p>経営層の意識改革を支援する場として、アクセンチュアは2024年、京都にAIセンターを開設した。基本的には経営トップ向けの施設で、社長と役員が集まり、およそ半日かけて全社変革の姿を具体的に体験する。全役員が自社の業務がAIでどう変わるのかを一緒に確認し、コンセンサスを形成する。部門間で導入の優先順位を巡って競争が生まれることもあるという。経営層全員が同じ未来をイメージし、それに向かって進んでいく。この共通認識の形成が極めて重要だと保科氏は強調する。</p> <p>人材戦略も欠かせない。特にAI人材をどう確保するかは大きな課題だ。これについて保科氏は、すべてを社内で育成する必要はないと説く。「すべてを内製化する必要はないが、すべてを外部に任せるのも間違いだ。外部のスピードと専門性を活用しつつ、自社のコアとなるデータ、業務、ガバナンスについては社内で人材を確保すべきである」。技術進化のスピードが速い中、良いパートナーと組みながら社内のケイパビリティを高めていくバランス感覚が重要だという。</p> <p>同時に、業務の在り方が大きく変わる中で、人の役割がどう変わるのかを考えなければならないという。「人材という大事なアセットをどう活かすのか。そのためにはリスキリングが必要である。同時に、社員の心理的安全性も経営者として考えていかなくてはならない」。業務変革に向けたリスキリング、そして従業員の心理的安全性の担保まで含めて考えていくことが必要だと保科氏は強調する。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">アクセンチュア自身が実践する<strong>AI</strong>変革──全社員が「作れる」レベルへ<strong></strong></h2> <p>アクセンチュアは「顧客に提供する前にまず社内で」という哲学のもと、自社でも大規模なAI変革を実践している。同社はグローバルで数十万人規模のアウトソーシングビジネスを展開しているが、そこで請け負っている業務を現在、AIエージェントに置き換える取り組みを進めている。特にインドのAIセンターが中心となり、この転換を急速に進めているという。</p> <p>加えて、全社員がAIエージェントを「使える」のではなく、「作れる」レベルを目指したトレーニングも実施している。マーケティング担当者も含め、全社員がAIエージェントを作成する。もちろん、ガバナンスの取れた統一基盤上での話だ。ハンズオントレーニングを通じて、ほぼ全社員がこのレベルに到達しつつあるという。「使えるのは当たり前で、作れるという世界まで持ってきている」と保科氏は語る。</p> <p>こうした変革により、働き方そのものに変化が見られるという。オフィスでの作業はAIエージェントに任せ、社員は顧客先でのコミュニケーションや、まだデータ化されていない情報の収集に注力するようになった。社内で黙々と資料を作るような時間は大幅に減少しているという。</p> <p>急速な技術進化に対応するため、アクセンチュアは外部パートナーとの協業も重視する。変革を加速するための手段だという。</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>CIO</strong>へのメッセージ──変革の主役になるために<strong></strong></h2> <p>最後に、保科氏はCIOをはじめとする技術責任者に向けて、力強いメッセージを送った。</p> <p>「変化が要求される世界になっている。だからこそ、変化を前向きに捉えてほしい。CIOや技術側の責任者はシステムの保守役から、CEOとタッグを組んで経営にダイレクトにインパクトを与えることができる立場になれる時代なのだ」</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?w=1024" alt="Accenture" class="wp-image-4136103" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?quality=50&amp;strip=all 2472w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=300%2C168&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=768%2C430&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=1024%2C573&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=1536%2C860&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=2048%2C1147&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 2048w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=1240%2C694&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=150%2C84&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=854%2C478&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=640%2C358&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/4.png?resize=444%2C250&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="573" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p class="imageCredit">Accenture</p></div> <p>そのためには、まず自分自身が未来をイメージする必要があるという。新しい技術で会社がどう変わるのか、その未来をちゃんと思い描く。それを具体化して、経営陣にどう見せられるのか。そこに力を入れていかなければならないと保科氏は説く。</p> <p>想像力が問われるが、「世の中で何が起こっているのかをよく見て、それが自分の会社だとどうなるのかを想像すると良い」という。保科氏自身、そのために「インサイドプリズム」という未来予測AIを開発し活用している。複数の専門家エージェントがディスカッションしながら、特定のテーマについて時系列で未来シナリオを描き出すAIだ。これを相手に数時間議論をするCEOもいるという。</p> <p>AI活用の巧拙は、企業の命運を分ける。「差は確実につく。生き残れる企業とそうでない企業の分かれ目になる」 だからこそ、CIOには大きなチャンスがある。「新しい技術を使う会社全体の変革において、CIOは主役になれる。ぜひ主役になっていただきたい」と保科氏は語った。</p> <hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity">
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Interview Highlights with Summer Collins, Chief AI and Data Director of One NZ]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/25/interview-highlights-with-summer-collins-chief-ai-and-data-director-of-one-nz/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/25/interview-highlights-with-summer-collins-chief-ai-and-data-director-of-one-nz/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Abstract:
Watch highlights from Peter Weill's interview with Summer Collins of telco One New Zealand on its company-wide transformation to embed artificial intelligence into its operations. Publication date: 2026-02-25 Publication type: Video ...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Interview with Summer Collins, Chief AI and Data Director of One NZ]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/25/interview-with-summer-collins-chief-ai-and-data-director-of-one-nz/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/25/interview-with-summer-collins-chief-ai-and-data-director-of-one-nz/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Abstract:
Peter Weill interviews Summer Collins of telco One New Zealand on its company-wide transformation to embed artificial intelligence into its operations. Publication date: 2026-02-25 Publication type: Video Publication authors:
Peter...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[US DoD to Anthropic: compromise AI ethics or be banished from supply chain]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137455/us-dod-to-anthropic-compromise-ai-ethics-or-be-banished-from-supply-chain.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137455/us-dod-to-anthropic-compromise-ai-ethics-or-be-banished-from-supply-chain.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>A growing rift between the US Department of Defense (DoD) and Anthropic over how AI can be used by the military has led to Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth issuing a blunt ultimatum: work with us on our terms or risk being banned from Pentagon programs.</p> <p>According to news site Axios, Hegseth gave Anthropic until Friday, February 27 to agree to its terms during a tense meeting this week. If no agreement is reached, the company would risk being deemed a “supply chain risk,” with Hegseth even threatening to invoke the Cold War-era Defense Production Act to compel cooperation, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2026/02/24/anthropic-pentagon-claude-hegseth-dario" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">the report</a> said.</p> <p>The DoD’s view is that it should be free to use Anthropic’s AI for “all lawful purposes,” regardless of ethical boundaries set by the company itself. Anthropic, by contrast, wants to set narrower guardrails.</p> <p>“The Department of War’s [DoD’s] relationship with Anthropic is being reviewed. Our nation requires that our partners be willing to help our warfighters win in any fight. Ultimately, this is about our troops and the safety of the American people,” Chief Pentagon Spokesman Sean Parnell <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/02/17/2026/palantir-partnership-is-at-heart-of-anthropic-pentagon-rift" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">told Semafor</a> last week.</p> <p>The extraordinary stand-off appears to have been prompted by a series of conversations between Anthropic and DoD officials which have generated rising levels of friction. These include a report that Anthropic CEO Dario Amodei had insisted that the DoD respect limits the company had placed on how its AI could be used in certain military contexts.</p> <p>Matters came to a head in early January when the US military used Anthropic’s Claude LLM in conjunction with technology from Palantir to help plan and execute the operation to capture former Venezuelan president, Nicolás Maduro.</p> <p>Anthropic staff are believed to have raised questions internally about whether an operation in which dozens of people were killed was consistent with the guardrails set for Claude as part of its recently overhauled <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4120901/anthropics-claude-ai-gets-a-new-constitution-embedding-safety-and-ethics.html" target="_blank">safety and ethics Constitution</a>.</p> <p>Despite this, the fine details of Anthropic’s limits aren’t always clear. Some restrictions are referred to in its September 2025 <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/legal/aup" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Acceptable Use Policy</a> (AUP), for example, that it not be used for mass domestic surveillance, to compromise critical infrastructure, or to design or develop weapons.</p> <p>Beyond that, Amodei himself has alluded to limits in statements <a href="https://www.darioamodei.com/essay/the-adolescence-of-technology" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">and essays</a> or through reported conversations with officials modelling hypothetical situations. This includes his recent call for more regulation of AI: “I think I’m deeply uncomfortable with these decisions [on AI] being made by a few companies, by a few people,” Amodei told the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aAPpQC-3EyE" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">CBS News TV newsmagazine 60 Minutes</a> in November. “And this is one reason why I’ve always advocated for responsible and thoughtful regulation of the technology.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="supply-chain-implications">Supply chain implications</h2> <p>If Hegseth were to make good on the threat to ban Anthropic, this would have major implications for the DoD and its long supply chain. In principle, companies that are part of the broader Defense Industrial Base (DIB) would have to stop using Anthropic’s AI platform in all its forms, including, presumably, the <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/4136294/anthropics-claude-code-security-rollout-is-an-industry-wakeup-call.html" target="_blank">Claude Code Security cyber system</a> launched only this week.</p> <p>This seems highly unlikely. Banning a US company would be unprecedented; such an action was previously reserved for a small number of foreign companies. Anthropic is also currently one of only two frontier AI models that has achieved <a href="https://investors.palantir.com/news-details/2024/Anthropic-and-Palantir-Partner-to-Bring-Claude-AI-Models-to-AWS-for-U.S.-Government-Intelligence-and-Defense-Operations/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Impact Level 6 (IL6) certification</a> for use on classified networks, having been joined only this week by xAI’s Grok.</p> <p>Ripping Anthropic out altogether is unthinkable, not in the least because it is already tightly integrated with Palantir’s systems, which are also critical to the DoD. More likely, the DoD will simply compel Anthropic to concede ground by invoking the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/crs-product/R43767" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Defense Production Act</a>, the downside of which being that this might sour cooperation in the longer run.</p> <p>Alternatively, Anthropic will continue to insist on some limits, such as, for example, around using Claude to enable autonomous weapons, while the DoD will simply act as though they will be relaxed at some future point, allowing for an uneasy short-term truce.</p> <p>The DoD versus Anthropic conflict echoes the <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/559773/fbi-v-apple-one-year-later-it-hasn-t-settled-much.html" target="_blank">confrontation between the FBI and Apple</a> more than a decade ago over access to iPhones after the 2015 San Bernardino mass shooting. In that event, Apple refused to give ground, resulting in a long-running legal struggle. The current US administration seems less willing to be patient.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Las plataformas de agentes de IA podrían reducir los costes de las licencias SaaS]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137316/las-plataformas-de-agentes-de-ia-podrian-reducir-los-costes-de-las-licencias-saas-segun-un-informe.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137316/las-plataformas-de-agentes-de-ia-podrian-reducir-los-costes-de-las-licencias-saas-segun-un-informe.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>La sugerencia de Anthropic de que su herramienta Claude Code podría utilizarse para automatizar la modernización de un lenguaje de programación veterano como COBOL —que seis décadas después de su primera implementación sigue siendo una actividad relevante para IBM— provocó el lunes una fuerte reacción en los mercados.</p> <p>La compañía registró una caída del 13,2% en el precio de sus acciones, la mayor desde el estallido de la burbuja puntocom hace un cuarto de siglo.</p> <p>Pero IBM no es la única empresa afectada por el actual ciclo de expectativas en torno a la IA. En el ecosistema SaaS se extiende una sensación cercana al nerviosismo a medida que toma forma el potencial de la IA para automatizar la creación y gestión de software. Salesforce, Atlassian, ServiceNow y Snowflake han sufrido fuertes ventas en un episodio que una firma de trading calificó, de forma melodramática, como “SaaSpocalypse”.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="un-escenario-hipotetico-a-2028">Un escenario hipotético a 2028</h2> <p>El informe <em>The 2028 Global Intelligence Crisis</em> (La crisis de inteligencia global de 2028), elaborado por Citrini Research junto con Alap Shah, de Lotus Technology Management, va más allá. En este ejercicio prospectivo, se describe cómo podría verse el auge de la IA desde la perspectiva de 2028, apenas dos años después de un pico imaginario del S&amp;P 500 en los 8.000 puntos, en octubre de este año.</p> <p>“La productividad estaba en auge. La producción real por hora aumentó a un ritmo no visto desde la década de 1950, impulsada por agentes de IA que no duermen, no se ponen de baja por enfermedad ni necesitan seguro médico”, señala la firma en lo que define como un ejercicio de reflexión. Pero, en paralelo, “los propietarios de los ordenadores vieron cómo su riqueza se disparaba al desaparecer los costes laborales, mientras que el crecimiento de los salarios reales se desplomó”.</p> <p>En este escenario, las empresas, en su búsqueda de mayor productividad gracias a la IA, reducen plantilla. Sin embargo, al caer el empleo también se contrae la demanda de productos y servicios, lo que lleva a una nueva ronda de automatización. “En todos los sentidos, la IA superaba las expectativas, y el mercado era la IA. El único problema… era que la economía no lo era”, imagina Citrini.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="el-modelo-de-suscripcion-en-riesgo">El modelo de suscripción, en riesgo</h2> <p>Las primeras en notar este impacto serían las plataformas SaaS. Según esta hipótesis, los agentes de IA podrían asumir tareas actualmente cubiertas por aplicaciones empresariales, tanto en el ámbito corporativo como en el de consumo. El resultado sería una erosión del valor percibido y la necesidad de aplicar descuentos significativos para retener clientes.</p> <p>La atención sobre este escenario coincide con el anuncio, a principios de febrero, de la nueva plataforma empresarial Frontier por parte de OpenAI, presentada —según diversas informaciones— ante inversores como un posible competidor directo del SaaS tradicional.</p> <p>La consultora Xpert Digital lo resumía así: “Si los agentes de IA asumen el trabajo de departamentos completos o si las empresas generan su propio código, la base del lucrativo modelo de suscripción podría tambalearse”.</p> <p>En este contexto, surgen preguntas relevantes para los CIO: ¿podrán negociar mejores condiciones en las renovaciones de licencias a partir de 2026? ¿Existe un riesgo real de que algunas organizaciones abandonen soluciones SaaS tradicionales en favor de plataformas nativas de IA?</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="escribir-software-es-mas-facil-que-operarlo">Escribir software es más fácil que operarlo</h2> <p>Los expertos consultados por CIO.com se muestran, no obstante, escépticos ante la posibilidad de que la transición sea tan sencilla como plantea Citrini Research.</p> <p>En primer lugar, la capacidad de la IA para replicar con garantías las funciones críticas que hoy desempeñan las plataformas SaaS aún no está demostrada. En segundo lugar, incluso si se aproximan funcionalmente, persisten interrogantes clave en materia de auditoría, seguridad, cumplimiento normativo y rentabilidad.</p> <p>Maya Mikhailov, directora ejecutiva de SAVVI AI, señala que “la IA facilita enormemente la escritura de software. No facilita la operación de software empresarial. Son dos problemas muy distintos, y la mayor parte del coste reside en el segundo”.</p> <p>Y añade: “En el momento en que internalizas la creación de software, también asumes la seguridad, el cumplimiento normativo, la disponibilidad, las integraciones y el soporte 24/7. Sobre el papel puede resultar atractivo, pero los costes y la complejidad impactarán directamente en la cuenta de resultados”.</p> <p>Collin Hogue-Spears, experto técnico de Black Duck Software, subraya además los riesgos asociados a la gobernanza. “OpenClaw pasó de cero a 135.000 instancias expuestas en cuestión de semanas porque ejecuta flujos de trabajo con gran rapidez. Pero no genera pruebas de auditoría, no garantiza el cumplimiento de obligaciones de licencia ni produce la documentación regulatoria necesaria antes de desplegar código”.</p> <p>“Los agentes de IA ejecutan tareas” —explica—. no generan el rastro de evidencias que separa a una empresa de una posible sanción regulatoria. Este patrón se repite en distintos sectores: la IA tiende a convertir funcionalidades en <em>commodities</em>, mientras amplía las obligaciones de gobernanza”.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ventana-de-negociacion-para-los-cio">Ventana de negociación para los CIO</h2> <p>Con todo, el contexto actual podría jugar a favor de los clientes. La debilidad bursátil del sector SaaS abre una oportunidad poco habitual en la negociación de contratos.</p> <p>“Los proveedores SaaS afrontan la presión de precios más creíble desde que la nube desplazó a las licencias <em>on-premise</em>. Se ha abierto una ventana de negociación”, concluye Hogue-Spears.</p> <p>Para los CIO, el mensaje es claro: más allá del ruido, la irrupción de los agentes de IA puede convertirse en una palanca estratégica tanto para revisar el modelo operativo como para optimizar costes en el corto y medio plazo.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Vendor Specialization Is In The Spotlight In Forrester’s B2B And B2C Commerce Landscape]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/vendor-specialization-is-in-the-spotlight-in-forresters-b2b-and-b2c-commerce-landscape/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/vendor-specialization-is-in-the-spotlight-in-forresters-b2b-and-b2c-commerce-landscape/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Both of these things are true: The commerce solutions market continues to evolve, and more vendors that once specialized in B2B or B2C use cases now exclusively cover the other model, as well. Some vendors still provide deep specialization — sometimes exclusively — in one model or the other. As we continue to witness the [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[B2B Hyperpersonalization Is Not A Feature — It Is An Expectation!]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/b2b-hyperpersonalization-is-not-a-feature-it-is-an-expectation/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/b2b-hyperpersonalization-is-not-a-feature-it-is-an-expectation/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A procurement manager logging in at 10:47 p.m. isn’t there to browse — they need to reorder the right SKU, at the right price, under the right contract terms, and get back to keeping operations running. Hyperpersonalization makes that possible by removing friction the buyer never asked for, using AI to surface only what they’re allowed to buy, what fits their context, and what matters now — so digital self‑service feels effortless instead of obstructive.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Gartner Survey Shows 55% of Supply Chain Leaders Expect Agentic AI to Reduce Entry-Level Hiring Needs]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-25-gartner-survey-shows-55-percent-of-supply-chain-leaders-expect-agentic-ai-to-reduce-entry-level-hiring-needs?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-02-25-gartner-survey-shows-55-percent-of-supply-chain-leaders-expect-agentic-ai-to-reduce-entry-level-hiring-needs?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[More than half (55%) of supply chain leaders expect that advancements in agentic AI will reduce the need to hire for entry-level positions, while 51% believe the technology will drive a shift to overall workforce reductions, according to Gartner, Inc., a business and technology insights company.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[What We’re Looking Forward To At The RSAC 2026 Conference]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/what-were-looking-forward-to-at-the-rsac-2026-conference/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/what-were-looking-forward-to-at-the-rsac-2026-conference/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The annual RSAC Conference in San Francisco is the cybersecurity industry’s biggest event of the year. For the analysts attending, RSAC Conference week provides an opportunity to learn about cybersecurity trends and topics, meet with vendors and clients, and share our insights and observations. It’s also an excellent opportunity to meet our daily step goals [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Gartner HR Research Finds Only 31% of Recruiting Teams Use Labor Market Data to Inform Their Talent Strategy]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-2-25-gartner-hr-research-finds-only-31-percent-of-recruiting-teams-use-labor-market-data?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2026-2-25-gartner-hr-research-finds-only-31-percent-of-recruiting-teams-use-labor-market-data?utm_campaign=SM_GB_YOY_GTR_SOC_SF1_SM-PR&utm_source=threads,twitter&utm_medium=social]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[As the labor market undergoes unprecedented and rapid transformation, only 31% of recruiting functions are leveraging labor market data to shape their business and talent strategies, according to a survey by Gartner, Inc., a leading business and technology insights firm.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[It’s not your AI that’s failing. It’s your data]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136833/its-not-your-ai-thats-failing-its-your-data.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136833/its-not-your-ai-thats-failing-its-your-data.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>What do baseball’s Mario Mendoza and AI have in common? A 20% success rate. Mendoza’s batting average established the Mendoza Line: shorthand for barely acceptable performance. Across industries, <a href="https://www.hrreporter.com/focus-areas/automation-ai/why-do-4-in-5-ai-projects-fail/" rel="nofollow">four out of five AI initiatives</a> still fall short of expectations. In all likelihood, it’s typically not the AI that’s failing, but the lack of data readiness.</p> <p>Companies rush to embark on ambitious AI-driven transformation projects in search of increased efficiency, revenue or other benefits, but overlook data readiness as a fundamental prerequisite. <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/information-technology/topics/ai-readiness" rel="nofollow">Gartner predicts</a> that through 2026, organizations will abandon 60% of AI projects unsupported by AI-ready data.</p> <p>So, before investing in another model or tool, make sure your data is ready to ship.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">Establish a data foundation based on well-understood relationships and ground truth</h2> <p>Companies that succeed with AI use clean data pipelines, integrated data lakes and a shared understanding of what their data means. Even in 2024, <a href="https://www.secoda.co/learn/unleashing-the-power-of-data-study-shows-2-3-of-company-data-goes-unused">Secoda</a> reported that 68% of enterprise data remained untapped for the purposes of analysis and innovation. When most of your organization’s knowledge is locked away, your algorithms draw from a shallow, murky pool.</p> <p>When it comes to data readiness, Walmart offers a paradigm of patience. They spent years linking supply-chain, point-of-sale and vendor data. <a href="https://www.retailtouchpoints.com/topics/customer-experience/walmart-is-sharing-more-and-more-of-its-data-with-its-suppliers-heres-why" rel="nofollow">This robust foundation</a> made subsequent AI rollouts reliably smooth. It also helped shave costs, limit stock outages and streamline deliveries. Establishing and describing clear relationships across the various data sources within your organization ensures that AI will properly understand and interpret data across your business landscape.</p> <p>It is also critical to establish ground truth datasets when training AI models. Ground truth isn’t just labeled data—it’s your organization’s expertise turned into something machines can learn from to create scalable processes. Begin with clear ontologies and label taxonomies that map directly to the business problem you’re solving. Finally, ensure there is sufficient quantity, quality and diversity in your training data to ensure model performance is consistent across a variety of scenarios and mitigates bias, especially in the case of use cases that have compliance implications, like human resources or healthcare.</p> <p>“The takeaway is clear,” according to <a href="https://typewiser.com/why-80-of-ai-projects-fail-and-what-you-can-do-differently">Typewiser</a>. “Getting your data house in order is perhaps the unglamorous, yet most critical, step in AI adoption.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ensure data governance isn’t an afterthought</h2> <p><a></a>Although it can feel like governance slows you down, it actually speeds up approvals and cuts risk. Assign clear owners and stewards for your data, and codify the contracts, lineage and provenance from raw sources all the way to model outputs.</p> <p>When you train models or build RAG pipelines on data sources, ensure you enforce data access and retention policies across downstream AI applications. Pay attention to sensitive personal data and obtain consent where regulations require it.</p> <p><a></a>Governance also plays a key role in overall system reliability. Clear ownership, reproducible documentation and auditable processes can limit the chaos of emergency data fixes. The so-called red tape of governance works as a velocity engine: reliable quality drives faster workflows.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">Prevent temporal drift: The silent data decay undermining AI ROI</h2> <p>As a rule, wine ages well. Data typically doesn’t. Customers’ tastes shift, supply chains move and regulations tighten. The result is called drift: it’s the mismatch between what your AI thinks the world looks like and what it actually looks like.</p> <p>Such drift comes in two varieties. Data drift arises when model inputs change in distribution—say, a shift in patient demographics volumes. Concept drift occurs when the relationship between inputs and outcomes shifts—think clinical algorithms built ahead of a pandemic.</p> <p>When left unchecked, both forms of drift erode ROI. According to <a href="https://insightfinder.com/blog/model-drift-ai-observability/">InsightFinder</a>, the click-through rate at an e-commerce company dropped an unexpected 30% before anyone noticed.</p> <p>Drift can reduce or even erase the model’s value to the business. In some cases, it can even drive massive losses. At <a href="http://aijourn.com/the-dangers-of-ai-model-drift-lessons-to-be-learned-from-the-case-of-zillow-offers/" rel="nofollow">Zillow</a>, a “valuation algorithm led the company to overestimate the value of the houses it purchased in Q3 and Q4 2021 by more than $500M.”<br><br>To maintain resilience, organizations must add monitors to their pipelines, run statistical drift tests on key variables, compare prediction outputs to real-world feedback and retrain models on rolling intervals. Some even deploy <a href="https://neptune.ai/blog/how-to-monitor-your-models-in-production-guide" rel="nofollow">shadow models</a> that learn alongside production systems and sound the alarm when outputs diverge.</p> <p>The takeaway: your AI doesn’t fail in an instant. Its accuracy simply fades away. Establish metrics to catch data degradation before it costs you customers, your credibility or even a quarter’s worth of revenue.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">The payoff of sustainable data readiness</h2> <p>The stakes are clear: organizations that neglect to spend time on data readiness risk joining the large percentage of AI deployments that struggle to meet ROI expectations or fail outright. Those who master these data readiness fundamentals will join the echelon of AI projects that succeed and deliver real business value.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[From digital transformation to intelligent transformation]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136829/from-digital-transformation-to-intelligent-transformation.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136829/from-digital-transformation-to-intelligent-transformation.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Over the past decade, digital transformation has focused on converting manual processes to digital ones, migrating infrastructure to the cloud, updating applications and creating new channels for customer and employee engagement. These efforts have resulted in tangible benefits such as accelerated cycle times, increased transparency and reduced costs. However, these initiatives have also revealed limitations: Simply digitizing a flawed process does not resolve its underlying issues; it only makes the inefficiencies operate at a faster pace.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-shift-to-intelligent-transformation">The shift to intelligent transformation</h2> <p>A new shift is underway. The next phase moves beyond digital — it is intelligent. Intelligent transformation is about evolving enterprises into systems that can sense, reason, make decisions and take action with minimal friction. This evolution is driven by the emergence of AI agents: Autonomous software systems capable of achieving goals by orchestrating workflows and leveraging tools such as APIs, applications, databases and automation technologies.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-apps-and-dashboards-to-agents-and-actions">From apps and dashboards to agents and actions</h2> <p>In the digital era, organizational value was derived from systems of record like ERP and CRM, as well as systems of insight such as business intelligence and analytics. In the intelligent era, a new dimension is added: Systems of action, defined by agentic capabilities that execute tasks across diverse functions.</p> <p>AI agents don’t merely answer questions; they are capable of planning steps, invoking tools, retrieving relevant information and completing end-to-end workflows. Modern agent architectures employ tool calling or function calling, where a model determines the next action, the application executes it and the model continues based on the outcome. This approach effectively bridges language models and enterprise systems, transforming agents into practical operational levers rather than mere demonstrations.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cross-industry-value-where-agents-compound-outcomes">Cross-industry value: Where agents compound outcomes</h2> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="manufacturing-from-connected-factories-to-learning-factories">Manufacturing: From connected factories to learning factories</h3> <p>Industry 4.0 connected machines and visualised data through dashboards. Intelligent transformation advances this by converting signals into actions: Agents detect abnormal patterns, recommend parameter adjustments, initiate maintenance requests and coordinate the availability of parts. The cumulative benefits extend beyond uptime to faster root-cause analysis, reduced quality deviations and more predictable throughput. Even minor improvements in planning stability can lead to significant gains in service and inventory management across complex networks.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="healthcare-life-sciences-from-documentation-burden-to-decision-support">Healthcare &amp; life sciences: From documentation burden to decision support</h3> <p>Clinicians and scientists often navigate context overload due to guidelines, patient histories, research literature, protocols and regulatory requirements. Agents can collate relevant context, draft structured notes, suggest trial eligibility matches or summarise evidence, all while ensuring human oversight in decision-making. Responsible implementations integrate retrieval from trusted sources, audit trails and strict permissions, as accuracy, privacy and traceability remain essential.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="retail-consumer-from-personaliziation-to-orchestration">Retail &amp; consumer: From personaliziation to orchestration</h3> <p>Personalised recommendations marked the initial stage. Now, agents can orchestrate the entire customer journey — resolving issues, amending orders, offering suitable alternatives and updating inventory systems. Internally, agents produce assortment insights, conduct promotion analyses and automate supplier communication, reducing turnaround times from weeks to hours.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-new-enterprise-stack-agentic-workflows-built-on-trust">The new enterprise stack: Agentic workflows built on trust</h2> <p>As agents advance in capability, the critical question will shift from “Can the model write?” to “Can the enterprise operate safely with agentic systems?”</p> <p>A pragmatic stack is emerging:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Experience layer:</strong> Copilots within work tools (email, CRM, service desk) and role-based agent interfaces.</li> <li><strong>Reasoning &amp; orchestration:</strong> Policies, routing, human-in-the-loop approvals and monitoring.</li> <li><strong>Knowledge layer:</strong> Retrieval from curated internal content with permissions and provenance.</li> <li><strong>Tool layer:</strong> APIs, RPA, workflow engines and systems of record enabling agent actions.</li> <li><strong>Governance &amp; risk:</strong> Evaluation, security, compliance and auditability by design.</li>
</ul> <p>Consequently, AI risk management has become a board-level concern. Frameworks such as NIST’s AI Risk Management Framework stress the importance of embedding trustworthiness across the AI lifecycle and managing risks to individuals, organizations and society.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-uncomfortable-truth-agents-amplify-both-productivity-and-risk">The uncomfortable truth: Agents amplify both productivity and risk</h2> <p>Agents have the potential to deliver substantial productivity gains, but they also introduce new vulnerabilities: Prompt injection, data leakage, unsafe actions and excessive reliance on generated outputs. Leading platforms are continuously enhancing agent safety and implementing robust controls.</p> <p>Enterprises that succeed will treat agents like other critical systems — establishing guardrails, enforcing least-privilege access, mandating approvals for sensitive actions, continually evaluating performance and maintaining traceability of data and actions.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-operating-model-shift-product-thinking-not-project-thinking">The operating model shift: Product thinking, not project thinking</h2> <p>Intelligent transformation does not succeed as a one-time rollout. Agents are never static; they learn, adapt and evolve as business needs and risks change. This calls for a shift from project-based delivery to a product-oriented operating model:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Business-led outcomes:</strong> Each agent is linked to a measurable business KPI (cycle time, NPS, yield, cash conversion).</li> <li><strong>Fusion teams:</strong> Domain experts, engineers, data specialists and risk/compliance professionals collaborate as a unified team.</li> <li><strong>Evaluation as a discipline:</strong> Ongoing test suites for accuracy, safety, robustness and cost.</li> <li><strong>Change management at the edge:</strong> Successful adoption is achieved through daily workflow integration, not just on launch day.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="measuring-value-3-horizons-that-executives-can-govern">Measuring value: 3 horizons that executives can govern</h2> <p>To effectively scale enterprise value, leaders should consider three horizons:</p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Horizon 1: Assist.</strong> Copilots that draft, summarise, search and explain, delivering rapid adoption and immediate time savings.</li> <li><strong>Horizon 2: Augment.</strong> Agents that complete defined workflows with approvals, offering greater ROI and governance.</li> <li><strong>Horizon 3: Automate.</strong> New operating models that reinvent customer and enterprise value chains, presenting the largest opportunities but requiring significant change.</li>
</ol> <p>The common mistake is attempting to leap directly to Horizon 3. The most effective strategy is to build progressively: Use Horizon 1 to establish fluency and trust, Horizon 2 to standardise platforms and guardrails and Horizon 3 to transform the enterprise after developing confidence and capability.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="conclusion-intelligent-transformation-is-a-leadership-agenda">Conclusion: Intelligent transformation is a leadership agenda</h2> <p>Digital transformation modernised technology, while intelligent transformation modernises the enterprise itself — how work is discovered, decided and delivered. AI agents serve as force multipliers, converting knowledge into action and action into learning.</p> <p>Ultimately, success will not be determined by who can showcase the most impressive agent, but by who can develop the most trustworthy agentic ecosystem — one that is secure by design, outcome-oriented and embraced by employees who feel empowered rather than displaced.</p> <p>In the age of AI agents, scaling enterprise value transcends traditional transformation. It requires building an organization capable of continuous self-transformation, with intelligence embedded in every decision and action.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The agentic enterprise: Why value streams and capability maps are your new governance control plane]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136798/the-agentic-enterprise-why-value-streams-and-capability-maps-are-your-new-governance-control-plane.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136798/the-agentic-enterprise-why-value-streams-and-capability-maps-are-your-new-governance-control-plane.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-economic-pivot-from-creation-to-execution">The economic pivot: From creation to execution</h2> <p>The enterprise is currently undergoing a seismic pivot from generative AI, which focuses on content creation, to agentic AI, which focuses on goal execution. Unlike their predecessors, these agents possess “structured autonomy”: the ability to perceive contexts, plan actions and execute across systems without constant human intervention.</p> <p>For the CIO and the enterprise architect, this is not merely an upgrade in automation speed; it is a fundamental shift in the firm’s economic equation. We are moving from labor-centric workflows to digital labor capable of disassembling and reassembling entire value chains.</p> <p>In my experience, this autonomy introduces non-deterministic behaviors that traditional IT governance cannot contain. According to an <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.01732#:~:text=3%20Jan%202025%5D-,Combined%20Hyper%2DExtensible%20Extremely%2DSecured%20Zero%2DTrust%20CIAM%2D,specifically%20for%20large%2Dscale%20enterprises." rel="nofollow">article by Shivom Aggarwal, Shourya Mehra and Safeer Sathar,</a> the rise in persistent cyber threats and advancements in technology require organizations to move toward adaptive and zero-trust security frameworks, making it essential to rethink and repurpose core architectural models like value streams and business capability models, rather than relying solely on new tools.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-governance-gap-why-agents-break-traditional-it">The governance gap: Why agents break traditional IT</h2> <p>Agents operating without defined boundaries create significant operational capacity. Because they can make decisions dynamically, it becomes difficult to trace decision paths or audit outcomes. Furthermore, in multi-agent systems, a single error or hallucination can propagate downstream, creating “chained vulnerabilities” that compromise entire workflows — a risk distinct from the static failures of traditional software.</p> <p>To govern this complexity, enterprise architecture must elevate its artifacts from static documentation to active governance instruments.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="value-stream-engineering-the-new-control-plane">Value stream engineering: The new control plane</h2> <p>In an agentic enterprise, the value stream map is no longer just a diagram; it is the control plane. It must explicitly define the handoff protocols between human and digital agents. In my opinion, Value stream maps must move from static documents stored in a repository to context documents used to drive agentic automation.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="hardening-the-legacy-estate">Hardening the legacy estate</h2> <p>Most existing value streams were designed for human judgment. To introduce agents, we must harden these streams to tolerate non-deterministic actors.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Define autonomy zones:</strong> Architects must audit streams to identify contiguous blocks of high-volume, low-ambiguity tasks. These become autonomy zones where agents cycle freely.</li> <li><strong>Implement halt-on-exception: </strong>To prevent cascading errors, streams must include explicit logic that triggers an immediate routing change to a human actor when an agent’s confidence score drops (e.g., below 90%).</li> <li><strong>The flight recorder:</strong> Agents are inherently opaque. Value streams must be augmented with mandatory logging steps — observability checkpoints — where an agent must cryptographically sign a log entry before proceeding to the next stage.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading">Case study: The over-the-air (OTA) software update stream<br><br></h2> <p>Consider the value stream for vehicle software patch deployment. This process is high-risk; an error can incapacitate a fleet of vehicles.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Current state (fragile):</strong> Steps include code commit &gt; automated test &gt; regional deployment. The risk is that an agent tasked with optimizing deployment speed might bypass a slow testing gate to meet a goal, resulting in a flawed update.</li> <li><strong>Architected state (governed):</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Step 1: Ingest (autonomy zone):</strong> An agent acts as the release coordinator, autonomously packaging the build and triggering 5,000 simulation tests.</li> <li><strong>Step 2: The observability checkpoint:</strong> The value stream enforces a hard gate requiring the agent to sign a log entry detailing the simulation results cryptographically.</li> <li><strong>Step 3: The halt-on-exception logic:</strong> If &gt;0.5% of simulations show latency spikes, the agent is technically blocked from accessing the deployment API. The stream automatically creates a Jira ticket for a human safety engineer.</li> <li><strong>Step 4: Execution:</strong> Only if the threshold is met does the stream permit the agent to schedule the OTA rollout.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-greenfield-approach-agent-first-mapping">The greenfield approach: Agent-first mapping</h2> <p>If a value stream does not exist, you cannot automate it. For new agentic workflows, do not map the current human process. Instead, use an outcome-backwards approach. Work backward from the concrete deliverable (e.g., customer onboarded) to identify the minimum viable API calls required. Before granting write access, run the new agentic stream in shadow mode to validate agent decisions against human outcomes.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="capability-models-the-readiness-heatmap">Capability models: The readiness heatmap</h2> <p>According to Enterprise Strategy Group (ESG) research, <a href="https://kpmg.com/kpmg-us/content/dam/kpmg/pdf/2025/esg-showcase-red-hat-kpmg-aug-2025.pdf" rel="nofollow">38% of organizations cite unclear business goals as the primary blocker to AI value realization</a>. In the era of agentic AI, this lack of clarity is dangerous and I see this leading to agentic AI sprawl.</p> <p>As chief architect at Ford, I learned that the business capability model is the most effective tool for preventing the deployment of toy pilots that fail to scale. It serves as a readiness heatmap, identifying which business functions possess the structural maturity to host autonomous agents.</p> <p><strong>Assessing agent readiness</strong></p> <p>Do not deploy agents based on use case popularity. Deploy based on capability maturity.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Data integrity:</strong> Is the lineage within this capability clean enough for machine consumption?</li> <li><strong>Boundary isolation:</strong> Are the APIs defined? If a capability relies on spaghetti code, an agent will likely break it or cause unintended side effects.</li> <li><strong>Action:</strong> Block deployments in capabilities that do not meet these structural standards.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-digital-insider-strategy">The digital insider strategy</h2> <p>We must treat agents not as software, but as digital insiders mapped to specific capabilities.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Containment via capability:</strong> Assign agents role-based access control (RBAC) strictly tied to the resources of their parent capability. This prevents a compromised agent from moving laterally across the enterprise.</li> <li><strong>Budgeting as governance:</strong> Bind compute and token budgets to the capability. If an agent enters a loop of rapid-fire, low-value transactions, the capability’s budget cap acts as a circuit breaker, preventing runaway costs.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="case-study-rd-vs-aftermarket-sales">Case study: R&amp;D vs. aftermarket sales</h2> <p>An automotive OEM evaluates two potential pilots. The capability map determines viability based on boundary isolation and data integrity.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Capability A: Autonomous drive research (high maturity)</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><em>Assessment:</em> Data integrity is high (petabytes of structured driving data). Boundary isolation is strict (air-gapped simulation environment).</li> <li><em>Decision:</em> <strong>Go.</strong> The agent is deployed to generate synthetic training scenarios and is bound to the R&amp;D compute budget.</li>
</ul>
</li> <li><strong>Capability B: Aftermarket parts supply chain (low maturity)</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><em>Assessment:</em> Data integrity is low (reliance on legacy mainframes and manual spreadsheets). Boundary isolation is poor (tightly coupled systems).</li> <li><em>Decision:</em> <strong>No go.</strong> Deploying an agent here creates identity sprawl and high risk. The recommendation is to remediate the data architecture <em>before</em> piloting the agent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-cost-of-inaction">The cost of inaction</h2> <p>The trade-offs of ignoring these architectural primitives are severe.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Financial:</strong> Without capability-tied controls, organizations risk unmanaged operational spikes from inefficient agent loops.</li> <li><strong>Security:</strong> A lack of value stream definitions leads to unmanaged agent-to-agent interactions, allowing threats to exploit undefined trust boundaries.</li> <li><strong>Strategic:</strong> Fragmented pilots result in identity explosion — thousands of non-human identities that cannot be audited, rotated or governed.</li>
</ul> <p>In the age of agentic AI, architecture is no longer an ivory tower discipline. It is the prerequisite for safety, scalability and value.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-gatekeeper-to-market-maker">From gatekeeper to market maker</h2> <p>For the past decade, EA has often been mischaracterized as a department of no — a friction layer that slows agile delivery. In the agentic era, this dynamic inverts. Because agents are non-deterministic, governance is no longer a constraint on speed; it is the mathematical prerequisite for it.</p> <p>Without the structural guardrails of value streams and capability maps, the CIO cannot scale agentic fleets beyond the prototype stage. The risk of hallucinations cascading into production databases forces the organization to keep human-in-the-loop ubiquitously, negating the economic benefits of the labor substitution.</p> <p>By implementing these architectural primitives, the chief architect transforms from a gatekeeper into a market maker for digital labor.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-new-economic-equation-cost-of-verification-vs-cost-of-execution">The new economic equation: Cost of verification vs. cost of execution</h2> <p>The value of an agent is not defined by how fast it runs, but by how little it needs to be watched.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>The ungoverned state:</strong> The cost of execution is low, but the cost of verification is infinite. Every output requires human review because trust boundaries are undefined.</li> <li><strong>The architected state:</strong> By hardening the value stream with observability checkpoints and halting logic, the cost of verification drops to near zero for all transactions within the defined autonomy zone.</li>
</ul> <p><strong>The recommendation:</strong> Shift the ROI metric. Do not measure AI adoption (a vanity metric). Measure autonomous throughput — the volume of transactions an agent executes <em>without</em> human intervention, enabled strictly by architectural confidence.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-technical-implementation-the-dynamic-control-plane">The technical implementation: The dynamic control plane</h2> <p>To operationalize this, EA must partner with platform engineering to embed these concepts into the runtime environment. The capability map must evolve from a static PowerPoint into a policy engine residing within your API gateway or service mesh.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Policy-as-code:</strong> When an agent attempts an API call, the gateway checks the readiness heatmap.</li> <li><strong>Runtime logic:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><em>Does the calling agent possess the cryptographic signature required for this value stream stage?</em></li> <li><em>Is the target capability rated “mature” for write-access?</em></li> <li><em>Is the request within the capability’s token budget?</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul> <p>If the answer is no, the transaction is rejected at the network layer. This allows the chief architect to govern 10,000 agents without reviewing a single line of code.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-architects-moment">The architect’s moment</h2> <p>We are witnessing the industrialization of cognition. Just as the assembly line required industrial engineers to organize labor into efficient physical streams, the agentic enterprise requires enterprise architects to organize digital labor into efficient logical streams.</p> <p>The organizations that treat this transition as a software upgrade will drown in operational opacity. The organizations that treat it as an architectural restructuring — using value streams to direct flow and capabilities to secure boundaries — will capture the market.</p> <p>Architecture is no longer an ivory tower discipline. I believe it is the only way to build a firm that is both safe and fast.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Anthropic’s claim that AI can quickly refactor COBOL rattles IBM investors]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137185/anthropics-claim-that-ai-can-quickly-refactor-cobol-rattles-ibm-investors.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137185/anthropics-claim-that-ai-can-quickly-refactor-cobol-rattles-ibm-investors.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Anthropic’s assertion that its agentic coding tool Claude Code can rapidly refactor legacy COBOL code has unsettled IBM investors, triggering a sell-off in shares, which resulted in the stock registering a 13% drop on Monday — its biggest single-day drop since October 2000.</p> <p>The assertion came in the form of a blog post from Anthropic that suggested that AI could take away the cost and complexity associated with modernizing a mainframe.</p> <p>“AI excels at streamlining the tasks that once made COBOL modernization cost-prohibitive. With it, your team can focus on strategy, risk assessment, and business logic while AI automates the code analysis and implementation,” the company wrote.</p> <p>Investors were concerned that Claude Code would erode the value of IBM’s strong and growing infrastructure services and consulting business, which depends on high-margin COBOL modernization on mainframes.</p> <p>However, modernizing COBOL applications to counter the dwindling numbers of developers proficient in the programming language is not a novel idea.</p> <p>IBM itself, in 2023, expanded the abilities of its generative AI-based Watson Code Assistant to include COBOL code translation into Java.</p> <p>Hyperscalers, such as <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/mainframe-modernization/" rel="nofollow">AWS</a>, <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-in/solutions/migration/mainframe#Products" rel="nofollow">Microsoft</a>, and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/solutions/mainframe-modernization?hl=en" rel="nofollow">Google</a>, too, have been offering mainframe modernization tools, including AI services. IBM-spin off <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/1250044/mainframe-modernization-gets-a-boost-from-kyndryl-aws-collaboration.html">Kyndryl has also been partnering with hyperscalers</a> to offer similar services.</p> <p>Yet competition from hyperscalers and partners has so far failed to meaningfully slow IBM’s mainframe business.</p> <p>During its fourth-quarter earnings calls last month, IBM CEO Arvind Krishna, in his prepared remarks, said that its Z family of mainframes had seen a 48% increase in yearly revenue — its highest in 20 years.</p> <p>Krishna further pointed out that the increase in revenue from its Z line could be attributed to the efficiency of the Watson Code Assistant in modernizing COBOL applications, in turn making it easy for enterprise development teams to run the mainframes.</p> <p>Moreover, IBM, in response to Anthropic’s assertions and to allay investors’ fears, put out a blog post of its own arguing that translating COBOL code is not equivalent to modernizing the underlying systems in a mainframe.</p> <p>“Translation captures almost none of the actual complexity. The modernization challenge is not a COBOL language problem. It is everything the application runs on and integrates with,” Rob Thomas, SVP of IBM software, wrote in the post.</p> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Rethinking ERP Transformation: A Governance Centric Framework for Sustainable Value Realization]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/uncategorized/rethinking-erp-transformation-a-governance-centric-framework-for-sustainable-value-realization/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/uncategorized/rethinking-erp-transformation-a-governance-centric-framework-for-sustainable-value-realization/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Rajesh Arangamany Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) transformation remains one of the most significant investments organizations undertake. Yet, despite advancements in platforms, delivery methodologies, and implementation tooling, many ERP programs continue to struggle with cost overruns, <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/uncategorized/rethinking-erp-transformation-a-governance-centric-framework-for-sustainable-value-realization/" title="Rethinking ERP Transformation: A Governance Centric Framework for Sustainable Value Realization">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Rethinking ERP Transformation: A Governance Centric Framework for Sustainable Value Realization]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/25/rethinking-erp-transformation-a-governance-centric-framework-for-sustainable-value-realization/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/25/rethinking-erp-transformation-a-governance-centric-framework-for-sustainable-value-realization/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Rajesh Arangamany Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) transformation remains one of the most significant investments organizations undertake. Yet, despite advancements in platforms, delivery methodologies, and implementation tooling, many ERP program...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Using AI to unlock human potential at Liberty Mutual]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135220/using-ai-to-unlock-human-potential-at-liberty-mutual.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135220/using-ai-to-unlock-human-potential-at-liberty-mutual.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Liberty Mutual’s approach to gen AI reflects a deeper understanding of enterprise transformation in that the hardest challenges aren’t technical but human. So global CIO Monica Caldas focuses on the central priorities of enterprise leaders: establishing effective AI governance, moving promising pilots into scalable solutions, and empowering employees to confidently adopt new ways of working.</p> <p>Such a strategy requires balancing seemingly contradictory goals: maintaining rigorous integrity while encouraging experimentation, building platforms without proliferating tools, and driving adoption without overwhelming the organization — and all of this without a proven playbook as <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4064313/what-world-class-it-looks-like-in-the-gen-ai-era.html?utm=hybrid_search">gen AI reaches an inflection point</a>. The result so far is a transformation that treats AI as a fundamental opportunity to rewire how 40,000 employees work and better serve customers.</p> <p><strong>How is Liberty Mutual using AI to improve your employee experience?</strong></p> <p>We’ve been using AI to understand and predict for years, so when gen AI emerged in late 2022, we were already thinking about how it could change the way we work. Our early AI focus was on predictive tools that improved underwriting and claims forecasting, strengthening our core operations. Those investments built the discipline and foundation we needed to adopt gen AI thoughtfully when it emerged. Our first lens of it was protecting integrity of the data and decisions, and how to govern in an environment when the technology’s promise is so expansive yet unproven. Then we adopted the philosophy of “You can’t learn to swim by reading about water,” and provided employees with training and safe spaces to test, learn, and develop intuition.</p> <p>Our plan was to first understand this new capability. We launched LibertyGPT, our secure, internal gen AI platform to ensure we were protecting data with the right controls. In parallel, we developed an <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4125163/why-digital-transformation-fails-without-an-upskilled-workforce.html?utm=hybrid_search">employee training program</a>, which functioned like a driver’s license. Once you have it, you can test and learn.</p> <p>In parallel, we established an experimentation framework we call our Digital Progression Framework that enables employees to learn, experiment, and innovate responsibly while understanding how AI can support their everyday work and decision-making in a meaningful way.</p> <p>We also focused on leadership training. When I joined Liberty Mutual, we started Executech, an executive training program focused on improving digital and data literacy. The program covered technology fundamentals, emerging trends, and how technology can drive business value. So shifting our focus from digital to AI was a natural progression, and these efforts are supported by a growing learning ecosystem, including a gen AI hub for hands-on guidance, an AI@Liberty community for peer collaboration, a responsible AI steering committee, and a change champion network that helps teams adopt and integrate new tools.</p> <p>Lastly, our broader ambition is to embed AI into the way we work every day. We’re not just improving speed and quality, we’re giving people the confidence and capacity to focus on what matters most: solving more audacious challenges and delivering meaningful outcomes for customers. Ultimately, we’re empowering employees to see AI as a core enabler, to imagine what’s possible, and to apply it in thoughtful, innovative ways.</p> <p><strong>How are you approaching the technical aspect of the transformation?</strong></p> <p>We began by defining a destination that’s aligned to our business aspiration of rewiring the enterprise for AI. From a technology perspective, that means <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4117094/data-management-trends-whats-in-whats-out.html?utm=hybrid_search">enabling data to move securely</a> and seamlessly across the entire stack in near real time while creating a platform that allows our teams to innovate and deploy new capabilities at speed.</p> <p>Achieving this requires modernization on three interconnected fronts. First, we’re transforming our core systems so they’re modular, interoperable, and built for continuous evolution. Second, we’re redesigning our data pipelines and ingestion layers to ensure that high-quality, well-governed data flows reliably across the enterprise. Third, we’re strengthening identity, access, and governance frameworks to enable broader use of advanced AI capabilities, while maintaining rigorous controls, security, and regulatory compliance.</p> <p>Rewiring for AI isn’t simply a technology upgrade. It’s a multidimensional transformation that aligns architecture, data, security, and governance to responsibly realize the full power of AI across the organization. Ultimately, this isn’t just a technical shift, rather it’s technology acting as a force multiplier for our business. So it’s a technological transformation, but it’s also an operational and cultural transformation — one interconnected body of work.</p> <p><strong>How do you avoid pilot purgatory?</strong></p> <p>My peers and I are aligned around a simple rule: we must be outcome oriented and aligned to our business aspirations as the first guiding principle. We also agree that greater value comes from disciplined platform-orientation, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4111139/cios-keep-buying-tools-workers-keep-burning-out-heres-the-disconnect.html?utm=hybrid_search">not tool-proliferation</a>. So we won’t run multiple pilots with different AI companies just to get a headline or check a box. Rather, we take a thoughtful, value-driven approach that’s yielded 50 use cases in production and scaling. The discipline of use case selection, input and output criteria, sponsorship, and governance is how we avoid too many pilots.</p> <p>Also on tool proliferation, we’ve listed over 30 AI capabilities that we’ll build or buy. If we buy, we’re deliberate that the tool solves a real need. Because there’s no AI playbook yet, we exchange ideas with a network of multi-industry CIOs and their technical teams. We also benchmark with consulting companies to make sure we don’t miss anything. As new tools and capabilities come to market, we know how to respond and capture value.</p> <p><strong>How do you tell the story of AI to your stakeholders?</strong></p> <p>I talk about AI unlocking human potential, which is a very personal transformation. When we all initially learned our jobs, we developed a set of skills, applied them, and developed behaviors and expectations. And here gen AI is introducing a completely different dynamic.</p> <p>This is a vulnerable moment for all of us, where we reflect, learn, and evolve. So I don’t talk about the technology inflection point as one dimension. Rather, the conversation is about all the dimensions of the shift. For example, operationally, we need to change the way we work and think about tasks we do today that can be offloaded into a well architected and governed gen AI solution. For example, we had a manual help desk process that was time consuming and slow to respond to internal employee questions. So our helpdesk team reimagined the workflow to leverage gen AI to take on 80% of the process. This eliminated manual steps and improved our ability to respond to employee questions faster and with greater accuracy. We were then able to redeploy the technology team that was doing the manual work toward the backlog of higher complexity problems.</p> <p>When you’re a CIO talking about AI, you need to show possibilities relevant to your different audiences. For me, the best strategy is to talk about realizing human potential with a few examples. It removes the abstract nature of the possibilities and helps provide real examples. We can also talk about what works and what’s still evolving. Despite the progress, there’s much that’s still left to be fully figured out.</p> <p><strong>With such change upon us, how do you advise up and coming tech leaders on how to manage their careers?</strong></p> <p>The technology leader of tomorrow will have domain expertise in their industry and will always have to be imagining the art of the possible.</p> <p>Ten years from now, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4107216/7-changes-to-the-cio-role-in-2026.html?utm=hybrid_search">CIOs </a>will operate in an environment defined by agentic and collaborative intelligence at scale. The pace of execution will be extraordinary, and the operational backbone of technology will be deeply instrumented, observable, and increasingly autonomous. Many of today’s tactical and repetitive responsibilities will be orchestrated by intelligent agents, enabling faster and more precise decision-making across the enterprise.</p> <p>But this doesn’t diminish the CIO role, it elevates it. As automation absorbs operational friction, the CIO gains capacity to focus on higher-order impact: deepening industry expertise, shaping business strategy, and partnering with domain leaders to reimagine products, services, and experiences. The technology executive becomes not just a steward of systems, but a co-architect of competitive advantage.</p> <p>The technical mandate remains critical in terms of modernizing platforms, enabling trusted data flows, and safeguarding security and governance at scale. Yet the differentiator will increasingly be leadership. The CIO of the future must maximize human potential, guide organizational change, and cultivate a culture that blends human judgment with machine intelligence.</p> <p>In an AI-powered enterprise, the CIO’s influence broadens from running technology to shaping the future of the business itself.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[What AX can do to deliver cohesion and uniformity to AI agents]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135922/what-ax-can-do-to-deliver-cohesion-and-uniformity-to-ai-agents.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135922/what-ax-can-do-to-deliver-cohesion-and-uniformity-to-ai-agents.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The point of agentic AI is for it to act by writing code, running scripts, executing commands, or calling APIs. All of that is more effective if those actions are discoverable, documented, consistent, and designed to be easy for agents to use in the first place.</p> <p>Agents need slightly different information from people. Both benefit from complete, accurate and up to date documentation or error messages that include the correct commands to use, but, for example, DevOps agents need the full context of the entire CI/CD pipeline, and developers usually don’t.</p> <p>Generally, though, better management of business logic, code, data, documentation, API design, policies, and best practices will help your human users as well. And if you don’t do the work, you risk a new level of shadow IT as members of staff turn to services their agents can work well with.</p> <p>“<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4132031/why-most-agentic-ai-projects-stall-before-they-scale.html?utm=hybrid_search">People are starting to believe and buy into agentic AI</a>, but there’s so much work to be done to actually achieve this,” says Forrester VP and principal analyst of enterprise architecture, Charles Betz. Agents need precise, structured, and accessible information, and AI will amplify strengths and weaknesses. “If you have weak system understanding, you’re going to have some awfully confused AI agents,” he adds.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="optimizing-the-agent-experience">Optimizing the agent experience</h2> <p>Getting your existing enterprise systems ready for agents is part of what Netlify CEO Mathias Biilmann calls <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4130913/cx-ai-and-the-data-trap-why-your-best-customers-are-slipping-away.html?utm=hybrid_search">agent experience</a> (AX) or what an agent encounters as the user of a product of platform.</p> <p>Every product and tool already has an agent experience, though, because AI agents already try to use them. “It’s just a question of does it have a good agent experience or a bad one,” he says.</p> <p>If you expect an agent to work with a product or service you rely on, it’s important to know if it has the structured, predictable interface, the comprehensive error handling, session persistence for workflows with multiple steps, and real-time feedback that it needs.</p> <p>“How does an agent discover your product,” says Biilmann. “Is it the user that tells them, or does it figure out on its own this might be a good solution? How do you help it understand what it can do with your product, and how do you make it easy for it to get access to the product, ideally, with as little asking the user for permission as possible? Then in that agent loop, how do you give context to the agent to make sure it can get the best possible experience of that product and solve the tasks for its user in the most efficient way?”</p> <p>The term has already caught on with both AI coding agents and developer tool providers, and Biilmann expects it to become more widely relevant. “As lessons from coding agents, and especially Claude Code, start making their way to agents more oriented at businesses and consumers,” he says, “we’ll start seeing the next layer of tools and services understand that if we don’t work well with those agents, we’re going to start getting routed around.” <a href="https://www.akamai.com/blog/security/ai-pulse-how-ai-bots-agents-will-shape-2026" rel="nofollow">Akamai’s latest research</a> shows that shift has begun.</p> <p>In the enterprise, AX is about doing the foundational work to effectively integrate agentic AI with existing systems. So do you bolt them on as an afterthought, like RPA that scrapes data out of legacy applications, or do you make sure workflows and tools are set up for <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3997968/mcp-is-enabling-agentic-ai-but-how-secure-is-it.html?utm=hybrid_search">MCP</a> to work against so agents are more effective?</p> <p>Investors are starting to talk about these principles as part of how they do valuations and predict agent-led growth. Anthropic has guidelines for how to write tools so they work well with agents, and Microsoft is building new accounts with access limitations into Windows just for agents so they run securely. One AI code tool provider even ripped out the CMS it had just paid to set up because its Cursor coding agent couldn’t access it easily, and the marketing team found asking a chatbot to add their content to the website as Markdown easier than a traditional CMS interface.</p> <p>Of course, as a company building AI coding tools, even Cursor’s non-technical employees are fairly technical, and soon after that provider gave up on the CMS, the vendor released an MCP server designed to give agents access to create, update, and manage a website without such a drastic change. But it’s an example of the impact AI agents can have on traditional software usage.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="beyond-mcp">Beyond MCP</h2> <p>Biilmann suggests four principles for good AX based on if agents can reach a system with the right permissions; the LLM can get the right context to use it effectively; tools like APIs, SDKs or the command line interface are built so agents can act as an interface to use them; systems make it easy to trigger and coordinate a favourite agent.</p> <p>“There’s a whole field of context engineering emerging that involves MCP, skills, context files, and tweaking tool responses to make sure agents have the right context when they’re using your product,” he says, adding that a single line of output added to the error message for a Netlify CLI command fundamentally transformed the AX from not being able to use the tool, to deploying it in one go.</p> <p>But it’s not enough to just make an MCP that wraps an API. “Think about the MCP as a UI for an agent that gives it the right context to not just do API calls but accomplish tasks efficiently with your API,” he says. “Give it context, structure and how API endpoints are typically used together.”</p> <p>Sean Blanchfield, CEO of AI infrastructure company Jentic, agrees that AI needs context, not more integration glue. “If you give an LLM clean documentation for a well-designed API, it can already interface with it directly,” he says. “That makes high-quality API management the real foundation of enterprise AI capabilities. Existing investments in OpenAPI, gateways, authentication, and governance will pay serious AI dividends.”</p> <p>Agents also need APIs that match their specifications, which many don’t. Jentic’s free AI Readiness Scorecard tool is one way to check that.</p> <p>Common mistakes are broken references, malformed schemas in OpenAPI specs, or APIs that don’t specify the server that hosts them and only have authentication information written for human developers not available through the API. Human developers might be able to laboriously work around those but agents will struggle.</p> <p>API specifications alone have no concept of operational sequence, says David O’Neill, COO of SaaS platform APIContext, so you need to use OpenAPI’s Arazzo workflow standard to encode those. “Suddenly OpenAPI specifications and Arazzo workflows are important because those are the things MCPs and agentic systems use to validate if something’s going to work,” he says.</p> <p>Forrester’s Betz refers to this kind of work as generative engine optimization to help agents get details about services.</p> <p>“Documenting APIs, getting robust business definitions of your data and information, understanding unambiguously where that data and information live, and what system is authoritative are absolutely critical,” he adds. “All the things your data and enterprise architects have been trying to build for the last 20 years, AI needs all that stuff to do what it does.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="testing-ax-ground-rules">Testing AX ground rules</h2> <p>Most organizations will use older code and architectures they aren’t ready to get rid of but don’t want to replicate, says Michael Coté, staff technologist at Broadcom. “Make sure to go through and mark up what you think is a well behaved database and data architecture versus a functional one you don’t like,” he says.</p> <p>Some of this is basic IT hygiene but it’s still critical, adds Martin Heyder, director of IT at data analytics platform KNIME, especially if you’re <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3848260/how-automation-forges-a-sense-of-community-and-purpose-at-6sense.html?utm=hybrid_search">automating workloads</a> that have relied on staff manually collating data from multiple sources that haven’t had to be kept up to date or available before. “If inventories, logs, or documentation are unreliable, any AI system will simply automate bad information,” he says.</p> <p>Also, agents will often initially expose where tacit knowledge exists, so establishing standards across code, enforcing code reviews, and keeping a single reference for system definitions and documentation gives agents an easy framework to work within.</p> <p>Microsoft CVP for apps and agents Amanda Silver refers to that as an agentic constitution, a natural language way to specify requirements or common expectations across the organization or code base. “You make sure the agent always has that in its context,” she says.</p> <p>This can apply much more broadly and be used as a meta prompt, that can include specific ways an agent should do things when it needs to manage identity, create a human in the loop interface, or build something that allows you to observe the agent’s operations.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="context-and-connection">Context and connection</h2> <p>Identity, access management, and permissions for existing infrastructure are fundamental. Most organizations likely need to start with an inventory, to make sure they know about everything they want agents to interact with, and that they can update it if necessary.</p> <p>That may mean adding new APIs or even replacing legacy apps where core logic and user interface are so tightly coupled, they’re hard for agents to use with SaaS that has APIs built in, or composable, headless architectures. <a href="https://events.zoom.us/ev/At8qPt_kj8QuwIYG-sraITvjG7V3-bY95Qu9tNxjQDv68RKdJI_-~AmE-M2frw15GgasODwnOQgGp45dscNHHca10KDub2su3TOyGyWyR1Gq9OA" rel="nofollow">Almost 30% of organizations IDC talks to</a>, for instance, are working through how to modernize their entire software portfolio to take better advantage of AI and agents.</p> <p>“The highest value ROI task agents are capable of is backend workflow processing,” Silver says. “You might use a protocol like MCP to expose data to agents, but that doesn’t mean they can take actions. Think about what the actions are you want to automate, that you can expose as tools to agents, that they can invoke to go not just from intent to planning, but to actual execution and action.”</p> <p>If you want agents to be useful to resolve an outage, they need access to an API that lets them add information to the dashboard where you collate incident details. Workflows will also need to include agents so they can subscribe to events like whether an order has shipped or an invoice has been disputed, and they need to be able to trigger the right actions in response.</p> <p>Plus, policies may be arranged in code rather than written down, and extracted into natural language policy documents agents can access. As organizations start to use more agents, Silver believes they’ll need not just sequential orchestration to cover an entire workflow, but adversarial evaluation, where workflow needs to follow multiple policies, all trying to deliver specific outcomes. “For that, you might implement multi agent orchestration with policies, then fan out where you consult multiple expert agents, and then those expert agents come back and make a judgment call, solving for multiple policies codified in natural language.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="finops-for-agents">FinOps for agents</h2> <p>Early adopters are already finding that agents can be relentless and prone to issuing multiple queries. “They keep trying, they’ll do anything,” Biilmann says. “They won’t stop and they can overwhelm a service.” If you can’t redesign an API to return hints because you don’t own it, you may need to implement quotas or prioritize queries.</p> <p>“I think there’s going to be a lot of manually created guardrails for scenarios because agentic stuff is really bad at policing itself,” O’Neil says. “It’s designed to deliver solutions, not turn itself off when it’s failed to deliver a solution.”</p> <p>Enforce idempotence, retries, quotas, and limits to prevent runaway or repeated API consumption, Betz adds. “Agents aren’t an unlimited resource, and if they’re not getting the right answer, they need to know when to abandon the attempt,” he says.</p> <p>Part of governance, Silver says, is understanding which MCPs are exposed to agents. “You could revoke access to them, govern token consumption, and enforce governance polices that make sense for you and your organization,” she says.</p> <p>So AX is a similar discipline to UX in that it’s iterative, and it’s about understanding what users or agents are trying to accomplish, says Biilmann. “You have to staff a team that does the research and figures out the problems and opportunities,” he says. That means looking at session replays, identifying failing agent behaviors, and building responses and interfaces to make them successful.</p> <p>As agent models have improved, Netlify doesn’t have to rely as much on adding context files that guide agents to the most recent API, but that just means they’re moving targets. “There’s a new audience of agents you constantly have to work with and iterate on,” he says.</p> <p>APIContext users already using MCPs find that the numbers of transactions, the APIs, and even the specific services used can change unexpectedly, O’Neill says. “The services returned by the MCP have changed, and it’s trying a different way to create a record, and that doesn’t work anymore,” he says. “It’s not like a gateway where you’re defining everything. It’s more of a black box providing you with a list of tools you can use.”</p> <p>A new MCP server performance monitoring tool lets you check and set alerts, and create governance rules based on performance thresholds, specifications, network functionality, or data transfer rules for data sovereignty. Agents require paying more attention than ever to API management. “It’ll force people to take this API governance seriously,” O’Neill adds.</p> <p>Also, lean on your API gateways in addition to governance tools, monitoring, and <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4110550/5-stages-to-observability-maturity.html?utm=hybrid_search">observability</a>, says Betz. “An agent is a service that happens to have an LLM involved, and maybe some chain of thought, intention management, and goal seeking behaviors,” he says. “But it’s all still just software.”</p> <p>That means your logging infrastructure will be placed under load. “If you fully embrace agentic, and you’re tracking all the agents, this traffic is going to bounce around in somewhat nondeterministic ways,” he says. In the end, measuring whether agents are successful is about outcomes as well as observability, Silver says. “Over time, you’re going to need to evaluate whether the agent is actually executing the thing you want it to execute, including not going off the rails,” she says.</p> <p>Microsoft is already using agents for Site Reliability Engineering to reduce the cost of responding to live site incidents, and improve remediation time. “To be able to do that, you need labeled, timestamped, traceable data you can look over,” she adds. “You also need to have rich, structured signals, and a clear sense of what’s good and bad from an outcomes perspective.”</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How weak talent strategy leaves IT with too much — and not enough — talent]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136794/how-weak-talent-strategy-leaves-it-with-too-much-and-not-enough-talent.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4136794/how-weak-talent-strategy-leaves-it-with-too-much-and-not-enough-talent.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>In my work architecting AI transitions for global enterprises, I have identified a recurring systemic failure, a collision between hyper-accelerated output and stagnant governance. IT &amp; Software Services (IT companies) are currently trapped in a talent paradox where they have an oversupply of AI-augmented ‘coding speed,’ yet a critical shortage of ‘architectural safety.’ They have effectively commoditized the ‘build,’ but in doing so, they have made accountability the most expensive resource in the room (developers/engineers → AI-augmented coding speed, project managers → AI-augmented delivery efficiency, solution architects → AI-augmented design quality, technical architects → AI-augmented system reliability, business analysts → AI-augmented requirements clarity, testers → AI-augmented defect detection rate, etc.).</p> <p>Currently, the workforce in IT companies is imbalanced, with both a surplus and a <a href="https://www.innoloft.com/blog/software-developer-shortage" rel="nofollow">shortage of engineers at all levels</a>. Because most primary tasks are being automated, yet these engineers are starving for ‘Performance Architects’ who can govern those very automations. Therefore, managers must treat our oversupplied resources as a talent reservoir, aggressively re-skilling them to manage the ‘hidden costs’ of AI, turning our legacy developers into the AI-governance experts the market is desperately lacking.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="an-oversupply-of-labor-exists-as-engineers-lack-specialized-skills">An oversupply of labor exists as engineers lack specialized skills</h2> <p>The labor market is oversupplied because engineers mainly possess general skills in the field of IT in general and software outsourcing in particular represents one of the most pressing challenges in workforce planning. In the past five years, since the emergence of generative AI, universities and training institutions have produced a large number of graduates with broad IT competencies, such as generic software development, basic database management, cloud computing concepts, cybersecurity fundamentals or basic networking. While these skills are foundational, they often lack the specialization required to address the complex, evolving needs of modern IT corporations. As a result, many professionals enter the workforce with overlapping capabilities, leading to inefficiencies in hiring and deployment for mass projects or outsourcing for complex business domains.</p> <p>In IT companies (India, Philippines, Vietnam, Poland and Ukraine), this oversupply creates a paradox: Organizations have access to a large talent pool, yet still struggle to fill critical roles or workforce assurance (WA) division is unable to provide sufficient manpower when dealing with large-scale and technologically complex projects from clients. For example, a business unit (BU) has a big project of client in banking and finance services, the BU may need hundreds of applicants for a software developer position, but very few candidates with expertise in smart-based secure payment systems or international regulatory compliance frameworks. The mismatch leads to underemployment for the current BU’s workforce, and even some individuals are assigned to roles that fail to utilize their full abilities, or worse, remain unemployed despite possessing professional qualifications.</p> <p>The consequences of <a href="https://www.mordorintelligence.com/industry-reports/japan-ict-market" rel="nofollow">short-term mismatch skills</a> in the IT field extend beyond career path development for individuals. The WA division in IT companies is facing a large idle labor pool, bloated recruitment pipelines, higher turnover rates and wasted resources on retraining as well. Moreover, the oversupply of generalists dilutes the competitive edge of the industry in the IT outsourcing market, as innovation increasingly depends on niche expertise. Without long-term corrective approaches, such as rebalancing educational curricula for internships, enriching skilling for oversupply resources, filling gaps in programs for potential engineers, or incentivizing specialization, the growth rate of the sector risks stagnation.</p> <p>To address this issue systematically, comprehensively and without overlap, coordinated actions are needed among human resources, workforce assurance, learning &amp; development (L&amp;D) and policymakers to ensure that the company has professionals with both breadth and depth of skills.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="short-term-shortage-of-nickel-skills-and-their-root-causes">Short-term shortage of nickel skills and their root causes</h2> <p>The shortage of specialized IT skills has far-reaching implications for the growth and scale extension. It also slows productivity initiatives, increases reliance on external resource vendors and exposes organizations to regulatory and operational risks. Moreover, competition for scarce internal talents between BUs and the labor market drives up salaries, creating inequities and making it difficult for workforce allocation and the cost of enriching skills programs.</p> <p>In most IT companies, one of the most persistent challenges in talent development is the mismatch between education and industry demand, not only for AI-augmented IT services but also for relevant skills in the AI-driven business domain. Academic curricula often lag behind technological advancements, especially in the AI ecosystem, leaving graduates ill-prepared for the realities of modern banking. For instance, while universities may still emphasize legacy programming languages or outdated IT business models, the industry increasingly requires expertise in AI-augmented engineering, agentic AI, cloud computing, digital transformation and advanced analytics.</p> <p>Upon being hired by the company, this lag creates a widening skills gap. Interns enter the workforce with knowledge that is already obsolete, forcing companies to invest in retraining. Meanwhile, emerging technologies such as quantum computing, semiconductors, self-driving cars, flying cars, or decentralized finance remain absent from most curricula. The serious mismatch also discourages innovation, as junior engineers are not exposed to cutting-edge tools or real-world applications during their studies. The consequences are significant. BUs are facing delays in implementing new technologies for clients, as they must wait for employees to acquire relevant skills.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="resource-allocation-inefficiency-and-issues-of-turnover-rates">Resource allocation inefficiency and issues of turnover rates</h2> <p>In the competitive labor market today, recruitment is particularly costly. Instead of accelerating employee professional development through various methods available on the market, IT companies often compete for the same pool of specialized talent, which inadvertently drives up salaries and recruitment fees compared to the industry average. However, many hires leave within a few months or years, forcing organizations to repeat the cycle.</p> <p>Enriching (refreshing or retraining) is equally model and same expensive, as employees must be upskilled or reskilled to meet evolving demands, while clients have requests for upgrading new technologies to their business. However, without a clear alignment between professional training programs and prioritized resource needs for each job level, retraining or enriching skilling efforts are often wasteful and fail to deliver measurable returns.</p> <p>Resource allocation inefficiency slows innovation, drains financial reserves and undermines clients’ satisfaction, leading to BUs failing to meet revenue targets, as they lack the budgets to sustain repeated review benefits and consider increasing job rank as well as retraining cycles.</p> <p>Any issues related to workforce size lead to issues related to operating costs, growth rates and the micro and macro management policies of the business. Therefore, resource allocation inefficiency is a hidden but critical challenge in talent development. IT companies spend heavily on recruitment, retraining and retention, yet much of this investment fails to produce sustainable results. The root cause lies in misaligned talent pipelines, where resources are directed toward filling immediate gaps rather than building long-term capabilities.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="enrich-skilling-strategy-and-the-professional-training-ecosystem">Enrich skilling strategy and the professional training ecosystem</h2> <p>To solve this challenge, BUs must invest in targeted training programs, AI tools, short-term specialization courses, professional courses on online platforms such as Coursera, edX, edXOps, Datacamp, etc., partnerships with technical universities, and global LABs. Additionally, the head office and overseas branches also play a role by funding specialized training programs and creating certification standards. Without such interventions and reforms, the mismatch between education and industry demand and the shortage of specialized skills will remain a critical barrier to achieving the 2030 roadmap.</p> <p>As results, the bottleneck of talent development and workforce assurance in IT companies isn’t technical; it’s strategic and organizational. We see the same story in most IT service providers, including the outsourcing sector. The AI team creates a breakthrough, but the project stalls because the people responsible for performance and the people responsible for risk operate in silos. To bridge this gap, the WA division must adopt agile approaches that evolve in enriching skilling tandem with industry needs by treating continuous training, AI performance and governance risk as a single measurable system, ensuring that every component of AI‑generated deliverables is as fiscally sound and legally compliant as it is productive.</p> <p>The training ecosystem for IT talent is highly fragmented, with universities, bootcamps, online platforms and corporate learning programs operating in silos. Each institution designs curricula independently, often without alignment to specific objective priorities (scientific research team or provider of high-quality human resources) or industry-wide needs (AI, Data, Cloud, Robotic and Automotive engineering, etc.). This lack of coordination creates inefficiencies and weakens the overall readiness of the workforce in the era of an AI-driven economy.</p> <p>For example, universities tend to emphasize theoretical knowledge, producing graduates with strong academic foundations but limited practical exposure to emerging technologies. Bootcamps, on the other hand, focus on rapid skill acquisition, often prioritizing coding or data analysis without integrating broader industry context. Corporate training programs are tailored to immediate organizational needs, but they rarely scale beyond the company’s boundaries. The result is a patchwork of training initiatives and the lack of synchronization that fail to produce a cohesive talent pipeline that adapt complexity technology stack in mass projects of BUs or high-level requests from clients.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="need-consistency-principles-and-futuristic-approaches">Need consistency principles and futuristic approaches</h2> <p>As a technology expert and IT workforce structure consultant for various technology companies worldwide over the years, I have witnessed these fragmentation and overlap in the workforce development system has led to unexpected results.</p> <p>First, this is because the person in charge has not categorized the courses according to professional level, specialized skills, business model, project specifics, system structure and client culture. Instead of organizing training courses or providing skill-enhancing courses at the general and basic skills levels (offline, online, hybrid learning), the focus is on specialized and project-based courses, which fall under the training phase for transitioning into the production unit and are the responsibility of their senior engineers. They lead to wasted effort due to excessive, misdirected and mistargeted training. As a result, the training program produces interns whose skills do not meet BU’s requirements.</p> <p>Second, most IT companies have career path diagrams for each job. By identifying core skills and advanced skills in these diagrams, we can build the most suitable learning path for each job group. The problem is that not all employees in a job group have the same needs for knowledge, skills or experience enhancement. Some may already possess these skills, while others may need to develop themselves to meet unit requirements or serve specific projects. Therefore, allowing employees to choose their own skills is essential. Forcing employees to develop mandatory skills according to a specific learning path will confuse them, forcing them to struggle to navigate between many different paths without clear guidance on which skills are most valuable at any given stage. Therefore, personalizing the learning path is a standard that must be considered for employees in production units. Conversely, it would waste a lot of time for learners, incur costs for instructors (mentors, trainers), cover operating costs (training officers), infrastructure usage costs and investments in online platforms. As a result, the training program produces engineers who have skills that do not meet client expectations or BU’s requirements.</p> <p>Third, for IT service companies, organizing professional training courses on technology, application functionality, industry standards, etc., at various levels for staffs whose engaged in projects is almost mandatory when BUs receive projects from clients. The development of training curriculum, conducting the training and evaluation of results in this format is usually done by senior engineers within the BU (those with expertise matching the project’s requirements), external trainers (those with expertise matching the project) or experts from the client. Furthermore, the absence of standardized curricula makes it difficult to benchmark skills across the industry. Solving this issue requires collaboration between academia, industry and managers to create integrated frameworks that align training programs with priorities for workforce development strategy. Only then can your company build a workforce capable of meeting the challenges of 2030. Otherwise, the consequence is wasted costs and trainees acquiring insufficient knowledge and skills to complete the assigned project tasks.</p> <p>Fourth, the human resource development process is a continuous cycle encompassing contextual research, needs assessment, model design, strategic planning, resource recruitment, training implementation and results evaluation to align employee skills with business unit needs and organizational goals. This process fosters synergistic development of individuals and businesses through activities such as skill building, career orientation and creating appropriate learning pathways to avoid waste, increase productivity, retain employees and prepare for future needs. To accomplish this mission, the relevant departments need a consistent strategy, reliable information sharing, avoiding overlapping approaches to BUs, refraining from abuse of power and taking full responsibility not only for providing basic vocational training programs for beginners, advanced training for mid-level engineers and professional-level training, but also for focusing on developing programs to address skill gaps to meet ever-changing demands. If these principles are not applied flexibly, the results of human resource development will not meet the organization’s expected goals.</p> <p>Ultimately, if managers don’t address these issues at their root, the company’s competitiveness in the IT services market is likely to be weakened, as other technology companies may have better coordinated training ecosystems, putting them in a better position to meet industry needs and customer expectations.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="workforce-development-strategy-for-it-excellence">Workforce development strategy for IT excellence</h2> <p>In conclusion, IT companies need to build a future-ready workforce that is specialized and aligned with both corporate goals and industry trends. This strategy bridges the gap between education and practice, ensuring that skills evolve in tandem with emerging technologies such as AI, cloud computing, cybersecurity and data governance.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Anthropic targets core business systems with new Claude plug-ins]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137146/anthropic-targets-core-business-systems-with-new-claude-plug-ins.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137146/anthropic-targets-core-business-systems-with-new-claude-plug-ins.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Anthropic is expanding its push into the enterprise market with a new set of “coworker” plug-ins designed to embed its Claude AI directly into tools used by investment bankers, HR teams, and engineers, signaling a shift from standalone assistants toward AI agents that operate inside core business workflows.</p> <p>In a blog post, the company said new connectors are available for widely used enterprise platforms, including Google Workspace tools such as Calendar, Drive, and Gmail, as well as DocuSign, FactSet, MSCI, and LegalZoom, while partners such as Slack, LSEG, and S&amp;P Global have built plug-ins for joint customers.</p> <p>The integrations allow Claude to assist with tasks such as reviewing deals, analyzing portfolios, drafting HR materials, and supporting engineering and design work, Anthropic added.</p> <p>“Admins can now set up plugins from starter templates or build them from scratch, with Claude guiding you through setup by asking questions to tailor skills, commands, and connectors (MCPs) to your company,” Anthropic said in a blog post.</p> <p>The rollout comes weeks after the company introduced a legal-focused integration that drew intense attention across the technology sector.</p> <p>While Anthropic has previously said its goal is to improve outcomes for customers rather than replace software providers, the speed of its enterprise expansion highlights growing competition among AI vendors to become the underlying engine powering corporate workflows.</p> <p>Earlier this week, OpenAI said it had formed <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4136024/openai-partners-with-consulting-giants-to-deploy-enterprise-ai-agents.html">multi-year partnerships</a> with consulting firms including Accenture, Boston Consulting Group, Capgemini, and McKinsey to help enterprises integrate systems and scale AI deployment globally.</p> <p>The move unfolds against a politically sensitive backdrop, as US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth has <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2026/02/24/hegseth-sets-friday-deadline-for-anthropic-to-drop-its-ai-red-lines-00795641" rel="nofollow">reportedly given Anthropic</a> a deadline to revisit AI use restrictions linked to government contracts.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="implications-for-enterprises">Implications for enterprises</h2> <p>For CIOs and IT leaders, the development raises practical questions about <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/4134728/is-ai-killing-technology.html">integration complexity</a> and data governance.</p> <p>From a functional perspective, the new plug-ins may not introduce entirely new capabilities but could enhance productivity and accelerate delivery timelines, according to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/fainalysis/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Faisal Kawoosa</a>, founder and lead analyst at Techarc. That is the yardstick many CIOs are likely to use when assessing their value.</p> <p>“CIOs should take an outcome-driven approach to evaluate these offerings directly against capabilities already embedded in core SaaS platforms,” said <a href="https://www.forrester.com/analyst-bio/charlie-dai/BIO5344" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Charlie Dai</a>, VP and principal analyst at Forrester. “They should measure whether the plug-ins reduce cycle time, manual effort, or error rates in specific, high-friction workflow steps rather than simply generating similar outputs in a different interface.”</p> <p>Dai said plug-ins built with stronger business controls and governance, and designed to work across multiple enterprise systems, are more likely to deliver lasting value than tools that simply repeat basic summarizing or drafting features already found in existing software.</p> <p>However, “Most enterprises are still cautious and primarily deploy AI agents in advisory or assistive roles rather than granting autonomous authority over mission-critical processes,” Dai added.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="governance-and-risk-concerns">Governance and risk concerns</h2> <p>Connecting AI agents across core enterprise systems introduces concentrated risk around identity management, access control, and potential data leakage, particularly when those systems span finance, HR, and collaboration platforms.</p> <p>“Broad permissions, opaque agent actions, and unintended data blending across finance, HR, and collaboration systems can create compliance exposure and audit gaps,” Dai said. “Enterprises must embrace zero-trust principles to enforce least-privilege access, maintain detailed action logs, and apply policy-based constraints on what agents can read, infer, and execute, especially in regulated or irreversible workflows.”</p> <p>Kawoosa said many enterprises are likely to begin by deploying such plug-ins in non-core functions, treating them as experimental tools before expanding their role. Building trust in these systems could take nine to ten months or longer, he said, depending on internal governance maturity and risk tolerance.</p> <p>“But at the same time, there is immense pressure on CIOs to do something with AI within their enterprises,” Kawoosa said. “Many CEOs have started believing that they could be wiped out if they don’t act now. This pressure could force some enterprises to move toward quick implementations, even in critical tasks, to avoid any kind of FOMO.”</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI agents popular for programming — but not much else]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137033/ai-agents-popular-for-programming-but-not-for-much-else.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137033/ai-agents-popular-for-programming-but-not-for-much-else.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>AI agents are becoming more common in practice, but their use is still heavily focused on programming, according to <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/research/measuring-agent-autonomy" rel="nofollow">new analysis by Anthropic</a> of millions of interactions between humans and AI agents, where researchers studied how tools like Claude Code and public API solutions are used in real-world environments.</p> <p>According to the report, software development accounts for nearly half of all agent-based activity. AI agents are primarily used to write, run, and test code, and users are increasingly letting them work autonomously for longer periods of time. Among the longest sessions, the amount of time the agent worked autonomously almost doubled in three months, from under 25 minutes to over 45 minutes.</p> <p>At the same time, its use outside of programming is still limited. While researchers see early examples in areas such as healthcare, finance, and cybersecurity, these are still small-scale and mostly involve low-risk tasks that can be undone or corrected.</p> <p>The researchers believe that developments point towards a future where AI agents become increasingly autonomous, but that broader use outside of programming likely requires new ways of monitoring and controlling the interaction between humans and AI.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Accenture links senior-level promotions to AI usage]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137041/accenture-links-promotions-to-ai-usage.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4137041/accenture-links-promotions-to-ai-usage.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Accenture is now starting to link the use of internal AI tools to senior-level promotions, reports <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ac672f97-a603-4c56-afa3-4a5273d45674" rel="nofollow">the Financial Times</a>. The global consulting firm tracks how often certain managers log in and use AI systems, and regular use becomes a factor in leadership promotions.</p> <p>The aim is to get more employees to embrace AI. This applies particularly to senior employees, as younger employees have often been quicker to adopt the technology.</p> <p>Several consulting firms find that older and more experienced managers are more hesitant about AI, which has led to strategies that combine both “carrots and sticks.”</p> <p>At the same time, some employees have criticized the tools and questioned their quality. The policy does not apply to everyone. For example, staff in twelve European countries are exempt.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Salesforce Consulting Landscape Shows No Sign Of Slowdown]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-salesforce-consulting-landscape-shows-no-sign-of-slowdown/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/the-salesforce-consulting-landscape-shows-no-sign-of-slowdown/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Salesforce has been the dominant CRM vendor globally for the last 12 consecutive years. Its FY 2025 revenue of $35.7 billion speaks to the sheer volume of its market presence. More than 150,000 customers use Salesforce’s solutions, from SMBs to enterprises, including 90% of the Fortune 500. With the high stakes involved, enterprises often turn [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-25]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
