<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Merged RSS (n8n)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></link>
    <description><![CDATA[Merged feed generated by n8n]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:48:46 GMT]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language><![CDATA[it-IT]]></language>
    <dc:identifier><![CDATA[https://example.local/webhook/merged-rss]]></dc:identifier>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[3 hidden risks of moving VDI to the cloud and how organisations avoid them]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134620/3-hidden-risks-of-moving-vdi-to-the-cloud-and-how-organisations-avoid-them.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134620/3-hidden-risks-of-moving-vdi-to-the-cloud-and-how-organisations-avoid-them.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For many UK organisations, the move from on-premises VDI to the cloud feels inevitable. The drivers are well understood: cost pressure, ageing infrastructure, hybrid work, and the need for greater agility. Yet for all its promise, cloud migration still triggers hesitation, especially among risk-averse IT leaders responsible for security, performance, and continuity.</p> <p>That caution is justified. While cloud desktops remove many legacy constraints, they also introduce new risks if the transition isn’t planned and managed carefully.</p> <p>Here are three of the most common (and often underestimated) risks of moving VDI to the cloud and how leading organisations are addressing them.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risk-1-cost-sprawl-replaces-cost-control">Risk 1: Cost sprawl replaces cost control</h2> <p>One of the most persistent fears around cloud DaaS is runaway spend. On-premises VDI may be expensive, but at least the costs feel fixed. Cloud introduces consumption-based pricing, which can quickly spiral if environments are oversized, left running unnecessarily, or poorly governed.</p> <p>This risk is rarely about the cloud itself, but about visibility and control. Without clear insight into usage patterns, organisations default to conservative sizing, which drives up costs. Over time, what was meant to be a more efficient model becomes harder to explain to finance.</p> <p><strong>How organisations avoid it</strong><br>Successful teams use data-driven sizing from the start, continuously optimise resources, and apply guardrails around scaling and scheduling. Centralised visibility across environments makes it possible to understand what’s being used, by whom, and why, turning cloud economics into something that can be actively managed rather than feared.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risk-2-performance-and-user-experience-become-inconsistent">Risk 2: Performance and user experience become inconsistent</h2> <p>Another concern is that moving desktops to the cloud could degrade performance or create an uneven user experience, especially for graphics-intensive roles or latency-sensitive applications. In on-premises environments, proximity to users and known workloads can feel safer.</p> <p>In reality, inconsistent performance in the cloud usually stems from poor alignment between user personas and desktop models. Treating all users the same (or lifting and shifting existing designs without re-evaluation) often leads to frustration on both sides of the service desk.</p> <p><strong>How organisations avoid it</strong><br>High-performing cloud DaaS deployments start with understanding users, not infrastructure. By mapping roles to the right desktop type—persistent vs non-persistent, pooled vs personal, always-on vs on-demand—organisations can deliver a consistent experience while avoiding unnecessary spend. Ongoing monitoring ensures performance issues are identified early and resolved before they affect productivity.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risk-3-operational-complexity-just-moves-it-doesnt-disappear">Risk 3: Operational complexity just moves; it doesn’t disappear</h2> <p>Cloud migrations are sometimes sold as a way to “simplify everything.” In practice, many organisations discover that complexity hasn’t vanished but has just changed shape. Multiple management portals, disconnected tooling, manual processes, and inconsistent policies can quickly undermine the benefits of cloud DaaS.</p> <p>This is particularly risky for lean IT teams, especially since many don’t have deep Azure expertise or extensive training on the specific processes required for manual management. Without automation and standardisation, the operational burden of overseeing cloud desktops can rival (or even exceed) that of legacy VDI.</p> <p><strong>How organisations avoid it</strong><br>The key is reducing operational friction from day one. Leading organisations standardise images, automate lifecycle tasks, and manage cloud desktops through a single control plane. This not only lowers day-to-day effort but also improves security, consistency, and resilience. The result is an environment that’s easier to run, easier to scale, and easier to explain to stakeholders.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="turning-perceived-risk-into-operational-confidence">Turning perceived risk into operational confidence</h2> <p>The most successful cloud desktop initiatives acknowledge risk and plan for it. By focusing on cost visibility, user-centric design, and operational simplicity, organisations can avoid the common pitfalls that stall or derail cloud VDI projects.</p> <p>It’s also worth recognising that the status quo can feel like the safer option. Change comes with upfront cost, effort, and perceived risk—and for many organisations, that “known” environment feels easier to defend than a major shift. But over time, staying put often becomes the greater risk. Legacy platforms grow increasingly expensive to maintain, harder to adapt, and less capable of supporting the speed and flexibility modern businesses need to compete.</p> <p>This is where the right management platform becomes critical. Tools that provide automation, insight, and centralised control help IT teams move faster with confidence, rather than trading one set of risks for another.</p> <p>If you’re exploring or expanding cloud DaaS and want to reduce risk while improving control, Nerdio Manager for Enterprise is designed to help organisations plan, deploy, and operate cloud desktops securely, efficiently, and at scale… without adding unnecessary complexity.</p> <p><a href="https://getnerdio.com/nerdio-manager/enterprise/" rel="sponsored">Explore Nerdio Manager for Enterprise today</a> and take the first step towards desktop modernization.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[IT automation as a strategic advantage]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134632/it-automation-as-a-strategic-advantage.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134632/it-automation-as-a-strategic-advantage.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Across UK organisations, the pressure on IT teams is no longer abstract. Skilled resources are limited, recruitment is slow, and experienced engineers are increasingly stretched across security, operations, and transformation initiatives at the same time. Yet expectations on IT have continued to increase.</p> <p>In this environment, time has become one of the most valuable assets IT leaders manage. Every hour spent on repetitive, manual tasks is an hour not spent on risk reduction, service improvement, or strategic change. That reality is pushing many organisations to rethink how they operate their desktop environments.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-quiet-cost-of-manual-desktop-operations">The quiet cost of manual desktop operations</h2> <p>Even in modern environments, desktop management is full of hidden labour. Provisioning users, maintaining images, scaling capacity, applying updates, optimising costs, and responding to change all demand skilled attention. Individually, these tasks don’t look dramatic. Collectively, they consume an enormous amount of time.</p> <p>What makes this particularly challenging is that much of this work requires senior expertise. Junior staff can’t easily take it on, and automation is often inconsistent or homegrown. As a result, highly skilled engineers spend significant portions of their time keeping environments running rather than improving them.</p> <p>This is where cloud desktops alone aren’t enough. Without automation layered on top, organisations risk recreating the same operational burden they had with on-premises VDI… just in a different platform.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-automation-changes-the-equation">Why automation changes the equation</h2> <p>Automation shifts effort away from individuals and into systems. It turns one-off tasks into repeatable processes, reduces the impact of human error, and creates consistency at scale.</p> <p>In practice, this shows up in small but meaningful ways: desktops that scale automatically instead of requiring manual intervention, images that are updated once and applied everywhere, users who can be provisioned in minutes rather than days, and environments that optimise themselves instead of relying on periodic reviews.</p> <p>Over time, these gains compound. Teams recover hours every week. Projects move faster. Operational risk drops because fewer tasks depend on individual knowledge.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="an-example-of-time-reclaimed">An example of time reclaimed</h2> <p>Brentwood Borough Council offers a useful illustration of this shift. Serving a growing population with a small IT team, the council needed to modernise its desktop environment without increasing operational load or dependency on specialist skills.</p> <p>By adopting Azure Virtual Desktop with Nerdio Manager for Enterprise, the team focused on automation as a way to protect time. Provisioning that once involved multiple manual steps was reduced to a repeatable, automated process. Image management was centralised, removing the need for constant hands-on maintenance. Scheduling and scaling controls reduced the need for out-of-hours intervention.</p> <p>The impact wasn’t framed internally as a technology win, but as a capacity win. Automation reduced day-to-day toil and allowed the team to operate more like a larger organisation—a benefit one IT leader described as being “like hiring another member of staff,” without adding headcount.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-reactive-work-to-resilient-operations">From reactive work to resilient operations</h2> <p>The lesson from Brentwood is that notice-and-respond work can be replaced by design-and-optimise work. IT teams spend less time reacting to routine demands and more time shaping how services are delivered.</p> <p>For UK organisations facing ongoing skills shortages, this shift is becoming essential. Automation makes environments more resilient, knowledge less siloed, and teams less vulnerable to absence or turnover. It also creates space for the kind of forward planning that’s increasingly expected of IT leaders.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="turning-time-into-long-term-value">Turning time into long-term value</h2> <p>In a market where skilled resources are scarce and expensive, protecting IT time is one of the smartest investments an organisation can make. Automation changes what teams are able to focus on.</p> <p>To learn more about how Brentwood Borough Council and other UK organizations are using automation in Azure Virtual Desktop and Nerdio Manager for Enterprise to focus more on strategic work, <a href="https://getnerdio.com/customer-story/brentwood-borough-council-nerdio-manager-for-enterprise-case-study/" rel="sponsored">read the full customer story</a>.</p> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When cloud-only isn’t realistic: why hybrid desktop strategies are back]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134635/when-cloud-only-isnt-realistic-why-hybrid-desktop-strategies-are-back.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134635/when-cloud-only-isnt-realistic-why-hybrid-desktop-strategies-are-back.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For many UK IT leaders, “cloud-only” desktop strategies sounded like the inevitable destination just a few years ago. Azure Virtual Desktop (AVD), Windows 365, and other DaaS platforms promised simplified management, lower CAPEX, and agile access for users everywhere.</p> <p>But in the real world, a pure cloud-only model isn’t always achievable… at least not overnight. Instead, hybrid desktop strategies are emerging as the practical, strategic way to modernise end-user computing without forcing organisations to rip and replace what still works today.</p> <p>The reason is simple: organisations are diverse, and their constraints are real.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="legacy-systems-compliance-performance-and-on-prem-dependencies-still-matter">Legacy systems, compliance, performance, and on-prem dependencies still matter</h2> <p>Many enterprises still run mission-critical applications and data in their own datacentres or on specialised infrastructure. These workloads may be latency-sensitive, bound by regulatory or data-sovereignty requirements, or tightly coupled to on-premises systems that can’t be migrated quickly. Legacy VDI platforms like Citrix, Omnissa, or other traditional stacks often sit at the heart of these ecosystems—not because teams are resistant to change, but because those environments simply support business needs in ways cloud-only options cannot yet replicate.</p> <p>For these organisations, abandoning all on-premises infrastructure for a cloud-only VDI doesn’t make sense, even if cloud desktops are directionally where they want to be. Migration projects can be long, costly, and disruptive, especially when applications and estates are tightly integrated.</p> <p>Microsoft’s response has been to evolve AVD itself.</p> <p><strong>Cloud-centric management, on-premises execution: what AVD hybrid delivers</strong></p> <p>At Microsoft Ignite 2025, Microsoft announced Azure Virtual Desktop for hybrid environments, a significant expansion of AVD that lets organisations run AVD session hosts on-premises infrastructure via Azure Arc in addition to running in Azure or Azure Local.</p> <p>In practice, AVD hybrid gives IT teams the ability to:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Use existing on-premises infrastructure,</strong> including Hyper-V, VMware vSphere, Nutanix AHV, or other Arc-connected environments as AVD session hosts.</li> <li><strong>Keep sensitive data local</strong> for compliance or sovereignty requirements while still using Azure’s unified control plane.</li> <li><strong>Run latency-sensitive workloads on-premises</strong> where performance matters while still centrally managing the environment through the cloud.</li> <li><strong>Phase legacy VDI migrations on your terms</strong> instead of forcing a big-bang cutover.</li>
</ul> <p>Rather than asking IT teams to choose between “all cloud” and “all on-premises,” AVD hybrid creates a third option: cloud-managed desktops with execution wherever it makes sense. This flexibility helps organisations balance risk, continuity, and long-term transformation in a way that aligns with their unique timelines and constraints.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="hybrid-isnt-a-compromise-its-a-bridge-to-the-cloud">Hybrid isn’t a compromise. It’s a bridge to the cloud</h2> <p>This hybrid model goes beyond solving today’s blockers and future-proofs the organisation and acts as a long-term bridge to the cloud. By centralising management in Azure while preserving on-premises investments where needed, hybrid AVD enables phased migration, improved governance, and a consistent user experience.</p> <p>For example:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Organisations with strict compliance requirements can retain sensitive workloads on local infrastructure while still benefiting from cloud-centric identity, security, and management controls.</li> <li>Teams supporting performance-critical applications can keep session hosts close to the backend systems users depend on, avoiding latency concerns.</li> <li>IT leaders no longer need to maintain legacy VDI control planes (and their associated costs) while they plan longer-term modernisation.</li>
</ul> <p>And importantly, this strategy gives IT teams breathing room to grow cloud skills at their own pace, a practical benefit when resource scarcity is already top of mind.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-management-matters-in-hybrid-environments">Why management matters in hybrid environments</h2> <p>Hybrid desktops introduce flexibility. But without unified tooling, they can also introduce complexity. Organisations need consistent automation, lifecycle management, policy enforcement, cost optimisation, and monitoring, whether desktops are running in Azure, on Azure Local, or on-premises via AVD hybrid.</p> <p>This is where an automated management layer plays a major role in turning hybrid flexibility into operational simplicity.</p> <p>If your organisation is navigating the reality that cloud-only isn’t realistic right now (but cloud-enabled, hybrid desktops are), <a href="https://getnerdio.com/avd-hybrid/" rel="sponsored">learn more about Azure Virtual Desktop for hybrid environments</a> and how modern EUC strategies bridge on-premises and cloud without disruption.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Future-proofing virtual desktops: what IT leaders need to plan for now]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134641/future-proofing-virtual-desktops-what-it-leaders-need-to-plan-for-now.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134641/future-proofing-virtual-desktops-what-it-leaders-need-to-plan-for-now.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>If the past few years have taught IT leaders anything, it’s that stability is no longer the default state. Work patterns shift quickly. Security threats evolve constantly. Business priorities change mid-year, not mid-decade. Against that backdrop, many organisations are re-examining a question that once felt settled: <em>how future-ready is our desktop strategy, really?</em></p> <p>Future-proofing means building a desktop environment that can absorb change without requiring a complete rethink every time conditions shift. Several forces are already reshaping what “good” looks like for end-user computing… and they’re only accelerating.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="demand-will-keep-getting-less-predictable">Demand will keep getting less predictable</h2> <p>User demand is no longer linear. IT teams now support a mix of full-time staff, contractors, third parties, seasonal workers, and project-based teams. Mergers, restructures, and new initiatives can introduce hundreds of users overnight—and remove them just as quickly.</p> <p>Over the next five years or so, this variability will increase, not decrease. Desktop strategies built around fixed capacity and long planning cycles will struggle to keep up. The organisations that succeed will be those that can scale desktops up or down quickly, align resources to actual usage, and adjust without introducing operational risk.</p> <p>This requires more than cloud infrastructure. It requires operational flexibility: the ability to manage, optimise, and govern desktops continuously, not periodically.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="security-and-compliance-pressure-will-intensify">Security and compliance pressure will intensify</h2> <p>Security has already moved to the centre of desktop strategy, and the bar continues to rise. Zero Trust, conditional access, identity-driven controls, and tighter compliance expectations are becoming standard rather than exceptional.</p> <p>At the same time, regulation is evolving. Data residency, auditability, and policy enforcement requirements will continue to change, often faster than organisations can redesign their environments.</p> <p>Future-proof desktop strategies assume that controls will need to adapt. They prioritise centralised management, consistent policy application, and visibility across environments so security teams can respond without disrupting users or slowing the business.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-will-change-how-desktops-are-used-and-what-they-need">AI will change how desktops are used and what they need</h2> <p>3-5-year refresh cycles are likely a thing of the past, and AI is no longer a distant consideration. Tools like Microsoft Copilot, automation platforms, and data-driven workflows are already changing how users interact with their desktops. Over the next few years, AI will influence everything from compute demand and performance expectations to how support and troubleshooting are delivered.</p> <p>This introduces new challenges for IT teams. Some users will need more compute for short periods. Others will need always-on access to AI-enabled tools. Capacity planning becomes more complex, and static desktop models start to show their limits.</p> <p>Future-ready desktop strategies are designed to adapt to these shifts. They make it easier to align desktop types to user needs, adjust resources dynamically, and evolve as workloads change without rebuilding the environment from scratch.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="operational-efficiency-will-matter-more-than-ever">Operational efficiency will matter more than ever</h2> <p>Perhaps the most underestimated factor in future-proofing is operations.</p> <p>Skilled IT resources are already scarce, and there’s little indication that pressure will ease. Over the next several years, IT teams will be asked to deliver more with the same (or smaller) teams. Manual processes, fragmented tooling, and bespoke environments won’t scale in that reality.</p> <p>Future-proof organisations are investing now in automation, standardisation, and centralised management. Not because it’s fashionable, but because it’s the only sustainable way to protect time, reduce risk, and maintain service quality as complexity grows.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-resilience-to-readiness">From resilience to readiness</h2> <p>Taken together, these trends point to a simple conclusion: Future-proofing the desktop isn’t about choosing the “right” platform once. It’s about building an operating model that can evolve.</p> <p>That means choosing technologies and tools that don’t lock organisations into rigid designs, support hybrid and cloud environments, surface insight rather than hide it, and automate routine work so teams can focus on what comes next.</p> <p>IT leaders who plan for this now put their organisations in a stronger position to absorb change with confidence. Nerdio Manager for Enterprise helps teams simplify operations, optimise continuously, and stay ready for whatever comes next.</p> <p><a href="https://getnerdio.com/nerdio-manager/enterprise/">Learn more about how Nerdio Manager can help your organization stay future-ready today</a>.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Cloud DaaS vs on-premises VDI: why the TCO conversation has finally changed]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134610/cloud-daas-vs-on-premises-vdi-why-the-tco-conversation-has-finally-changed.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134610/cloud-daas-vs-on-premises-vdi-why-the-tco-conversation-has-finally-changed.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For a long time, the total cost of ownership (TCO) debate between cloud desktops and on-premises VDI felt unresolved. On paper, on-premises environments looked cheaper once the infrastructure was “paid for.” Cloud DaaS promised flexibility, but sceptics questioned whether that flexibility justified ongoing consumption costs.<strong></strong></p> <p>That conversation has shifted decisively. Rising infrastructure costs, licensing complexity, operational overhead, and changing workforce demands have altered the economics of end-user computing. According to the <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/6828434" rel="sponsored">Gartner Magic Quadrant for DaaS</a>, by 2027, virtual desktops will be cost-effective for 95% of workers compared to 40% in 2019, and virtual desktops will be used as the primary workspace for 20% of workers (up from 10% in 2019).</p> <p>Today, the question UK IT leaders are asking isn’t whether cloud DaaS can compete on cost, but why on-premises VDI still makes financial sense at all.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-hidden-cost-of-already-owned-infrastructure">The hidden cost of “already owned” infrastructure</h2> <p>On-premises VDI is often defended because the data centre already exists. Hardware is depreciated. Licences are in place. Teams know how to run it. But sunk costs don’t equal low costs.</p> <p>Most on-premises VDI environments still rely on regular hardware refresh cycles, typically every three to five years. Servers, storage, networking, backup infrastructure, and redundancy all require capital investment whether demand grows or not. Those refresh cycles are becoming more expensive as hardware costs rise, and supply chains remain unpredictable.</p> <p>Then there’s the data centre itself. Power, cooling, floor space, and resiliency commitments continue regardless of how heavily desktops are used. Even organisations planning to exit the data centre often carry these costs longer than expected due to overlapping migrations and risk management.</p> <p>Licensing complexity adds another layer. Traditional VDI stacks often include multiple vendor agreements, true-ups, and renewal cycles that are difficult to optimise and even harder to forecast.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="operational-overhead-rarely-shows-up-in-spreadsheets">Operational overhead rarely shows up in spreadsheets</h2> <p>One of the biggest blind spots in TCO comparisons is operational cost. On-premises VDI demands a broad skill set: storage, networking, virtualisation, image management, security, patching, capacity planning, and troubleshooting. In many organisations, this requires multiple specialists or highly experienced generalists, both of which are increasingly difficult and expensive to retain.</p> <p>Manual processes also take their toll. Image updates, user onboarding, scaling capacity for peak periods, and responding to incidents all consume time that doesn’t directly move the business forward. The result is an environment that appears cost-controlled but is operationally heavy.</p> <p>As IT teams face growing skills shortages and pressure to focus on strategic outcomes, the true cost of maintaining complex, bespoke desktop environments is harder to justify.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-cloud-daas-changes-the-economic-model">Why cloud DaaS changes the economic model</h2> <p>Cloud DaaS fundamentally reshapes the cost structure of EUC.</p> <p>Hardware refresh cycles are replaced with consumption-based infrastructure that scales with demand. Instead of overprovisioning for peak usage, organisations can right-size desktops based on actual user needs and adjust as those needs change.</p> <p>For many organisations, traditional desktop environments carry a built-in overhead because they must be prepared for the worst-case scenario at all times. Cloud desktops remove that constraint, allowing IT teams to scale resources up when demand increases and scale them back when it doesn’t, paying only for what’s actually required.</p> <p>At the same time, data centre costs begin to fall away. Power, cooling, and physical resilience are shifted to the cloud provider, freeing organisations from long-term facilities commitments tied to desktop delivery.</p> <p>Licensing becomes more transparent. Microsoft Cloud desktops (Azure Virtual Desktop and Windows 365) integrate tightly with existing Microsoft investments, and costs can be aligned more closely to users rather than infrastructure blocks.</p> <p>Perhaps most importantly, operational effort is reduced. Standardised images, automation, and centralised management help IT teams spend less time maintaining the platform and more time optimising it. Fewer manual tasks mean fewer hidden costs.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-the-tco-conversation-is-happening-now">Why the TCO conversation is happening now</h2> <p>Several factors are accelerating this shift in the UK market.</p> <p>Economic pressure has sharpened scrutiny on operational spend, not just capital expenditure. Sustainability goals are forcing organisations to reassess energy-intensive data centre workloads. Workforce models continue to fluctuate, making fixed-capacity environments inefficient. And AI-driven workloads are introducing new patterns of demand that legacy VDI was never designed to handle.</p> <p>At the same time, cloud desktop platforms have matured. Performance, security, and user experience are no longer the limiting factors they once were. The remaining challenge is understanding what the move actually costs and what it replaces.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-assumptions-to-data-driven-decisions">From assumptions to data-driven decisions</h2> <p>The organisations seeing the biggest financial gains from cloud DaaS aren’t guessing, but modelling.</p> <p>By analysing real user profiles, workloads, and usage patterns, IT leaders can compare on-premises VDI costs with cloud-based alternatives using consistent assumptions. This shifts the TCO discussion from opinion to evidence and often reveals savings that aren’t obvious at first glance.</p> <p>If you want to understand what cloud DaaS could look like for your organisation and how the economics stack up against your current environment, <a href="https://nmeadvisor.getnerdio.com/?_gl=1*118ed0m*_gcl_au*MTY0NTE4MDkzOC4xNzY3MDIyNzUx" rel="sponsored">explore the Nerdio Modeler</a>. It’s designed to help enterprises model, compare, and plan desktop strategies based on real-world data, not estimates.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The modern desktop reset: why UK IT leaders are rethinking end-user computing]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134507/the-modern-desktop-reset-why-uk-it-leaders-are-rethinking-end-user-computing.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134507/the-modern-desktop-reset-why-uk-it-leaders-are-rethinking-end-user-computing.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>For years, end-user computing (EUC) strategy felt like a balancing act between two imperfect options: continue extending on-premises desktops and legacy VDI, or commit to a cloud initiative that promised long-term value but short-term complexity. In 2026, that middle ground is disappearing. The desktop is being reset—not because IT leaders are chasing the next trend, but because the business environment around them has fundamentally changed.</p> <p>Desktop as a service (DaaS) has emerged as a practical response to that change. It offers a way to meet fluctuating demand, reduce legacy overhead, and introduce the agility required to support modern work, including the rapid emergence of AI-driven tools and workflows.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="whats-driving-the-reset-for-uk-organisations">What’s driving the reset for UK organisations</h2> <p>Across the UK, several forces are converging at the endpoint.</p> <p>Security and resilience are now baseline expectations, not differentiators. With cyber risk firmly on the board agenda, IT teams are under pressure to reduce exposure while maintaining productivity. Cloud desktops help by keeping data off local devices, enforcing consistent policies, and enabling faster response when incidents occur… without locking organisations into rigid infrastructure models.</p> <p>Cost scrutiny is intensifying. Economic uncertainty and tighter budgets have shifted the focus from capital expenditure to operational efficiency. DaaS allows organisations to move away from large refresh cycles and instead align spend to actual usage. Desktops can be scaled up or down as demand changes, giving finance and IT a shared, more predictable model.</p> <p>Workforce models remain fluid. Hybrid work is now standard, but variability is the real challenge. Different roles, locations, and work styles—from office-based employees to fully remote contractors—place new demands on how desktops are delivered.</p> <p>Contractors, seasonal workers, mergers, new locations, and project-based teams can quickly strain traditional approaches, especially when access depends on shipping, securing, and supporting physical hardware across multiple regions. DaaS removes that friction by enabling secure, consistent desktops to be provisioned wherever work happens, for the right users and the right duration without over-engineering the environment or shipping devices around the world.</p> <p>Legacy environments are becoming an agility tax. Many organisations are discovering that the true cost of legacy EUC is operational drag rather than upfront costs. Complex image management, manual patching, slow onboarding, and exception handling all consume time that could be better spent on strategic initiatives. Cloud agility shifts the focus from maintenance to optimisation.</p> <p>AI is raising expectations for the desktop experience. Whether organisations are exploring Copilot, automating workflows, or enabling data-driven decision-making, users expect consistent performance and secure access from anywhere. At the same time, AI introduces new compute patterns—some predictable, others burst-y—making flexibility and visibility more important than ever.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="daas-as-an-operating-model-not-just-a-deployment-choice">DaaS as an operating model, not just a deployment choice</h2> <p>When DaaS is approached strategically, it stops feeling like a “virtual desktop project” and starts functioning as an operating model. Onboarding is faster. Environments are standardised. Costs are easier to understand and optimise. Governance improves without slowing teams down.</p> <p>This is why many UK IT leaders are positioning Microsoft Cloud desktops (Azure Virtual Desktop and Windows 365) as long-term platforms rather than tactical fixes. The goal is to simplify how desktops are delivered, managed, and evolved over time.</p> <p>Where organisations often struggle is after initial deployment. Day-two operations—scaling, optimisation, cost control, and consistency—can quickly erode the promised benefits if they rely on manual processes or disconnected tools. Manual work means senior staff are bogged down in routine tasks rather than freed for strategic work.<br><br>This is where automation, visibility, and built-in guidance make the difference.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-smarter-way-to-modernise-euc">A smarter way to modernise EUC</h2> <p>A modern approach to DaaS focuses on reducing complexity while increasing control. That means centralised management across environments, data-driven sizing and optimisation, and migration planning based on real usage rather than assumptions. It also means giving IT teams the tools to adapt as requirements change without re-architecting the desktop every time the business shifts.</p> <p>For UK organisations navigating security pressure, cost constraints, and rapid change, the modern desktop reset is less about technology choice and more about operational readiness.</p> <p><a href="https://getnerdio.com/nerdio-manager/enterprise/" rel="sponsored">Explore how enterprises are simplifying cloud desktop management</a> and turning DaaS into a scalable, cost-efficient operating model with Nerdio Manager for Enterprise.</p> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why CIOs need analytics capability to scale AI]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134765/why-cios-need-analytics-capability-to-scale-ai.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134765/why-cios-need-analytics-capability-to-scale-ai.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>AI is accelerating analytics at unprecedented speed. But organizations that mistake AI adoption for analytics capability development are discovering that technology alone does not scale into value.</p> <p>For CIOs, the real differentiator is not AI sophistication, but the strength of the <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4105140/analytics-capability-the-new-differentiator-for-modern-cios.html">analytics capability</a> that governs how AI is embedded into purposeful decision-making.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-as-the-dominant-emerging-technology">AI as the dominant emerging technology</h2> <p><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4077276/ai-is-the-new-ui.html">AI is the most prominent emerging technology</a> in the world today. No other technology matches its breadth of impact, speed of adoption or level of executive attention. Across healthcare, finance, government, manufacturing, defense, education and the creative industries, AI is reshaping how organizations operate, compete and create value.</p> <p>What sets AI apart is how deeply it is now embedded in everyday business activity. Advances in generative AI have moved AI beyond routine internal processes into frontline decision-making, customer engagement and operational execution. Global investment and widespread adoption have firmly positioned AI at the center of the CIO agenda.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-evolution-of-ai-within-analytics">The evolution of AI within analytics</h2> <p>Over the past decade, analytics has evolved significantly. What began as descriptive reporting through dashboards and historical metrics progressed into predictive and optimization-driven analytics as data volumes increased and analytical techniques matured.</p> <p>Machine learning became embedded in standard analytics practice, enabling forecasting, pattern discovery and optimization across increasingly complex datasets. At the same time, advances in data engineering, modeling techniques and cloud platforms pushed analytics closer to operational decision support. Insights could be generated faster, applied more broadly and integrated directly into business workflows.</p> <p>The emergence of genAI in the early 2020s marks the most significant inflection point in this evolution. Analytics systems are no longer limited to structured data or static outputs requiring expert interpretation. They now engage with unstructured information, automate analytical tasks, generate narratives and visualizations and support scenario exploration and simulated outcomes.</p> <p>AI did not arrive as an external disruption to analytics. It emerged as the next phase in its evolution, extending analytics from insight generation into adaptive, decision-oriented intelligence.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-coevolution-of-ai-and-analytics-capability">The coevolution of AI and analytics capability</h2> <p>AI and analytics are often discussed as separate — and sometimes competing — technologies. In practice, their relationship is better understood as one of coevolution. Each advances in response to the other and each amplifies the value of the other over time.</p> <p>AI enhances analytics by accelerating pattern discovery, automating insight generation and extending analysis into problems that were previously too complex or data intensive. Generative and agentic approaches allow analytics to scale faster, moving from isolated use cases to broader organizational impact.</p> <p>At the same time, the value organizations realize from AI is constrained by their analytics capability. Disciplined problem framing, well-governed data, model validation and integration into decision processes provide the foundations AI depends on to operate effectively in organizational contexts. Without these capabilities, AI systems tend to remain experimental and difficult to embed into core business operations.</p> <p>This reciprocal dynamic means AI does not replace analytics, nor does analytics merely feed AI. They evolve together. As AI becomes more sophisticated, it raises expectations for how analytics is governed, embedded and trusted. As analytics capability improves, it enables AI to be applied reliably and at scale.</p> <p>In this sense, AI increasingly acts as a stress test for analytics capability. Because AI operates at speed and scale, weaknesses in data ownership, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4050744/fixing-the-broken-ai-governance-playbook.html">decision rights</a>, skills and trust surface far more quickly than they did in earlier generations of analytics.</p> <p>For CIOs, the implication is clear. AI accelerates outcomes, but analytics capability determines whether that acceleration produces value or risk.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-is-a-resource-not-a-capability">AI is a resource, not a capability</h2> <p>Many organizations struggle to scale AI because they treat it as a capability in its own right. In doing so, they misidentify where value is actually created.</p> <p>Within an analytics capability framework, the distinction is straightforward. Resources enable processes. Processes shape capability. Capability determines value. AI sits within the resources domain, alongside data, platforms, tools and technical skills. It enables analytics processes, but it does not constitute a capability on its own.</p> <div class="extendedBlock-wrapper block-coreImage undefined"><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?w=1024" alt="Analytics capability framework diagram" class="wp-image-4134768" srcset="https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?quality=50&amp;strip=all 1719w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=300%2C82&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 300w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=768%2C209&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 768w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=1024%2C278&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1024w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=1536%2C417&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1536w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=1240%2C337&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 1240w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=150%2C41&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 150w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=854%2C232&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 854w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=640%2C174&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 640w, https://b2b-contenthub.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/analytics-capability-framework.png?resize=444%2C121&amp;quality=50&amp;strip=all 444w" width="1024" height="278" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p class="imageCredit">Ranko Cosic</p></div> <p>Capabilities emerge only when resources are applied consistently through well-designed processes. In analytics, this includes disciplined problem framing, data governance, model validation, integration into decision workflows and feedback mechanisms that connect insight to action. Without these processes, AI initiatives remain isolated and fail to deliver consistent enterprise-wide impact.</p> <p>This distinction explains why comparable investments in AI produce vastly different outcomes across organizations. Where analytics capability is strong, AI accelerates insight generation and improves <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4051633/evidence-based-decision-making-a-framework-for-it.html">decision quality</a>. Where capability is weak, AI amplifies fragmentation and risk, creating the appearance of progress without delivering enterprise-wide value.</p> <p>From a CIO perspective, the implication is practical rather than theoretical. AI should be managed as a high-impact resource. Analytics capability is the organizational mechanism that converts that resource into value.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-cios-should-invest-first-in-analytics-capability">Why CIOs should invest first in analytics capability</h2> <p>For CIOs, the central question is not whether to invest in AI, but where investment will most reliably translate into business value. Analytics capability determines whether AI becomes embedded in decision-making or remains a collection of disconnected tools, pilots and proofs of concept.</p> <p>Analytics capability is the ability to consistently convert data into insights that inform decisions and action. It encompasses disciplined problem framing, trusted and well-governed data, appropriate analytical techniques and the integration of insights into everyday business processes. Together, these elements determine whether AI outputs are understood, trusted and acted upon.</p> <p>When analytics capability is weak, AI amplifies existing problems. Insights fail to influence decisions, outputs are misunderstood or mistrusted and value remains localized rather than enterprise-wide. When analytics capability is strong, AI accelerates what already works, improving decision quality, reducing decision cycle time and scaling impact across the enterprise.</p> <p>CIOs should invest first in analytics capability. AI provides acceleration, while analytics capability provides direction and control.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="10-lessons-cios-should-know-about-analytics-capability-and-ai">10 lessons CIOs should know about analytics capability and AI</h2> <p>Analytics capability determines whether AI scales into sustained value or stalls at experimentation. The following lessons translate that reality into practical guidance for CIOs.</p> <ol start="1" class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI amplifies analytics capability. It does not create it. AI delivers sustained value when governance, data quality, business engagement and decision ownership are already in place.</li> <li>AI assets are not analytics capability. Tools, platforms, skills and models are resources. Treating them as capability obscures where value is created.</li> <li>Analytics capability matters more than AI sophistication. Clear roles, decision rights and repeatable practices consistently outweigh model complexity.</li> <li>AI shifts the bottleneck from insight generation to decision-making. As insight production accelerates, accountability and decision processes become the constraint.</li> <li>Weak analytics governance turns AI into a risk multiplier. Poor governance scales flawed assumptions, bias and compliance risk.</li> <li>AI expands analytics access when analytics capability is built by design. Analytics literacy, standards and decision clarity determine whether AI creates value or noise.</li> <li>Strong analytics capability allows AI to scale beyond pilots. Established workflows and governance enable enterprise-wide adoption.</li> <li>Decision quality, not more AI tools, determines analytics capability. As AI becomes commoditized, organizational performance depends on consistently better decisions.</li> <li>AI exposes analytics capability gaps faster than previous technologies. Speed and scale reveal weaknesses that slower analytics once concealed.</li> <li>AI success requires CIO leadership beyond technology deployment. CIOs need to treat analytics as an organizational system, not merely a technical function.</li>
</ol> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="final-takeaway-for-cios">Final takeaway for CIOs</h2> <p>As AI becomes faster, cheaper and more accessible, differences in performance are increasingly driven by analytics capability rather than technology adoption. AI does not level the playing field. It widens the gap between organizations that can consistently convert insight into decisions and those that cannot.</p> <p>For CIOs, the question is not how quickly AI can be deployed, but how well the organization’s analytics capability equips it to use AI effectively. AI will accelerate whatever capability already exists. Where that capability is strong, AI compounds value. Where it is weak, AI compounds risk.</p> <p>In the age of AI, competitive advantage belongs to organizations that invest deliberately in analytics capability and allow AI to amplify it, rather than those that pursue the technology in isolation.</p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Salesforce Acquires Momentum: What it means]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/whats-salesforces-acquisition-of-momentum-means/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.forrester.com/blogs/whats-salesforces-acquisition-of-momentum-means/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Salesforce’s planned acquisition of Momentum (a revenue orchestration startup) is less about “another sales AI feature” and more about owning the highest-value input for autonomous agents: the customer conversation, and turning it into structured, actionable system data inside Salesforce + Slack. What Salesforce is really buying Momentum will extend Agentforce 360 and Slackbot by ingesting/analyzing [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Plan vs. planning: Why continuous planning must traverse time]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134757/plan-vs-planning-why-continuous-planning-must-traverse-time.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134757/plan-vs-planning-why-continuous-planning-must-traverse-time.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Most enterprises are not short on plans. They have strategic roadmaps, multi-year investment portfolios, annual operating plans and governance frameworks to create alignment and control. These plans are often thoughtful, analytically sound and approved with confidence.</p> <p>Yet when conditions change, those same organizations struggle. Projects stall. Priorities collide. Capacity tightens. Leadership teams revisit decisions not because rigor was lacking, but because the assumptions underlying them no longer hold.</p> <p>The problem is not the plan’s quality. The problem is that a plan freezes a moment in time while the organization continues to move through time.</p> <p>Planning, by contrast, must be a continuous discipline, remaining active as assumptions decay, signals emerge and constraints shift. CIOs have increasingly acknowledged this shift as <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3618308/whatever-happened-to-the-three-year-it-roadmap.html">traditional long-range planning models give way to more adaptive approaches to enterprise planning and decision-making</a>.</p> <p>Dwight D. Eisenhower captured this distinction succinctly: “Plans are nothing; planning is everything.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-planning-matters-now">Why planning matters now</h2> <p>In stable environments, the distinction matters less. In today’s environment, resilience is defined. A plan assumes stability. Planning assumes change. A plan encodes assumptions about demand, funding, capacity, dependencies and risk that are valid or at least plausible at the moment of approval.</p> <p>Planning exists to test those assumptions continuously, a distinction long recognized in leadership and management literature that <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/252345/business-alignment-misconception-it-strategies-should-be-driven-by-business-strategies.html">separates planning as an ongoing discipline from planning as a static artifact</a>.</p> <p>Plans are optimized for agreement and commitment. Planning is optimized for learning, decision-making and managing consequences in the face of uncertainty. In practice, this means consequences must be visible at the moment of decision, not discovered months later through execution.</p> <p>Peter Drucker warned of the danger in static logic long before today’s volatility: “The greatest danger in times of turbulence is not the turbulence; it is to act with yesterday’s logic.”</p> <p>When planning is treated as episodic quarterly reviews, annual cycles or stage-gated approvals, yesterday’s logic quietly governs today’s execution. That temporal mismatch is where even disciplined organizations begin to fail.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-planning-is-episodic-consequences-arrive-late">When planning is episodic, consequences arrive late</h2> <p>Most organizations discover the implications of decisions only after execution has begun. This delay is structural, not accidental.</p> <p>When planning occurs only at fixed moments, assumptions are not revisited continuously. Dependencies remain hidden. Capacity constraints surface only once teams are already overcommitted.</p> <p>A familiar scenario illustrates this clearly. A major cyber incident triggers emergency remediation, regulatory scrutiny and unplanned investment. Run-the-business capacity is consumed almost overnight. Yet the change portfolio continues to execute against a plan approved months earlier, built on assumptions that no longer apply.</p> <p>Leaders know trade-offs are required. What they lack is visibility into which decisions lead to which consequences over time.</p> <p>This is not an execution failure. It is a planning system failure.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-well-documented-example-nokia">A well-documented example: Nokia</h3> <p>Nokia’s decline is often framed as a missed technology shift. Subsequent academic research and industry postmortems paint a more precise picture. Nokia recognized smartphone trends and ecosystem risks early. Still, it lacked a planning discipline capable of continuously revisiting assumptions as market dynamics evolved; <a href="https://www.academia.edu/129931899/How_Nokia_Missed_the_Smartphone_Revolution_A_Case_Study_of_Strategic_Failure" rel="nofollow">a pattern explored extensively in analyses of the company’s strategic collapse</a>.</p> <p>Decisions continued to be judged against plans optimized for a moment in time, while competitive conditions changed continuously. Signals arrived faster than planning cycles could absorb. Learning occurred after execution, not before.</p> <p>Plans froze time. Planning did not traverse it.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="continuous-planning-pulls-learning-forward-in-time">Continuous planning pulls learning forward in time</h2> <p>One of the least visible casualties of modern bureaucracy is organizational learning.</p> <p>Many enterprises optimize for compliance, predictability and approval at the expense of feedback and adaptation. Learning is pushed downstream, arriving only after outcomes are locked in and costs incurred.</p> <p>Systems theorist Russell Ackoff described this dynamic clearly: “Most organizations are not short of information. They are short of the ability to learn from it.”</p> <p>Continuous planning restores learning by design, not as postmortem analysis, but as pre-decision feedback. Feedback that arrives before commitment changes behavior. Feedback that arrives after execution becomes an explanation. In volatile environments, that timing difference is decisive, which is why <a href="https://www.ftms.edu.my/images/Document/MOD001074%20-%20Strategic%20Management%20Analysis/WK4_SR_MOD001074_Schoemaker_1995.pdf" rel="nofollow">scenario planning and structured foresight have re-emerged as critical executive tools</a>.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="decision-advantage-is-temporal-not-analytical">Decision advantage is temporal, not analytical</h2> <p>Speed alone does not confer advantage. Decision advantage comes from faster, higher-quality learning cycles.</p> <p>Military strategist John Boyd articulated this through the OODA Loop: Observe, Orient, Decide, Act, demonstrating that success depends on <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/193677/what-military-strategy-can-tell-us-about-decision-making-in-a-post-covid-world.html">cycling through decisions faster with better orientation, not merely acting quickly</a>.</p> <p>The enterprise parallel is direct. The opponent is not only competitors or market forces, but time itself, as assumptions decay faster than governance and planning cycles can respond. Organizations that can observe signals early, orient around constraints and dependencies, decide with consequences in view and act deliberately will outperform those locked into slower planning cycles, regardless of analytical sophistication.</p> <p>Planning systems must therefore support decision cycles, not just plans.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-systems-must-be-enabled-to-support-planning-not-just-plans">What systems must be enabled to support planning, not just plans</h2> <p>Research across systems thinking, military decision theory and enterprise governance consistently shows that decision advantage comes from faster feedback and continuous assumption revision, not from producing more detailed initial plans.</p> <p>If planning must traverse time rather than freeze it, the systems that support planning must behave differently. These are not tool preferences. They are functional requirements.</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Explicit assumption management</li> <li>Integrated, decision-grade data</li> <li>Scenario and consequence modeling before commitment</li> <li>Cadence aligned to decision velocity</li> <li>Fast feedback for the next decision</li>
</ul> <p>Together, these capabilities define an enterprise planning discipline, not a methodology or PMO artifact.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="when-systems-cannot-support-continuous-planning-plans-collapse">When systems cannot support continuous planning, plans collapse</h2> <p>Target’s Canadian expansion illustrates this clearly. Despite detailed plans and disciplined execution, early signals around data quality, inventory accuracy and supply-chain readiness conflicted with approved assumptions. Planning did not adapt quickly enough.</p> <p>Run-the-business issues quietly consumed change capacity while execution continued against frozen plans. When plans were revisited, systemic damage had already occurred. Target exited Canada in less than two years, with losses exceeding $5 billion, <a href="https://corporate.target.com/press/release/2015/01/target-corporation-announces-plans-to-discontinue-canadian-operations" rel="nofollow">a failure widely documented in postmortem analyses of the retailer’s Canadian strategy</a>.</p> <p>Execution followed the plan.</p> <p>Planning did not move with time.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="continuous-planning-at-scale">Continuous planning at scale</h2> <p>Continuous planning is not theoretical.</p> <p>Amazon does not succeed because it predicts the future better than others. It succeeds by institutionalizing planning as a continuous discipline. Assumptions are regularly challenged. Trade-offs are explicit. Decisions are revisited when signals change, not when planning calendars allow. Planning remains active between plans.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="planning-is-what-endures">Planning is what endures</h2> <p>In environments where assumptions decay faster than execution cycles, the quality of decisions matters more than the precision of plans.</p> <p>Plans provide alignment at a moment.</p> <p>Planning provides coherence across time.</p> <p>The organizations that outperform their peers will not be those with the most detailed plans, but those whose planning disciplines can traverse uncertainty without losing alignment.</p> <p>The plan still matters.</p> <p>But planning is what endures.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Los sueldos subirán un 6% en el sector de las TI en 2026 en España]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135172/los-sueldos-subiran-un-6-en-el-sector-de-las-ti-en-2026-en-espana.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135172/los-sueldos-subiran-un-6-en-el-sector-de-las-ti-en-2026-en-espana.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>Un año más la compañía de selección de personal <strong>Hays </strong>ha dado a conocer cuáles, según sus datos, son las tendencias laborales y, en concreto, de salarios para el año en curso en España. Los datos, referentes a 15 sectores productivos, aparecen en la <em>Guía del Mercado Laboral 2026</em> que elabora la firma recopilando los datos de más de 7.400 salarios (la empresa especifica que para ello calcula la media de los salarios ofrecidos por sus clientes durante el último año, lo que le permite proyectar las tendencias para el siguiente período). Según la Guía, <strong>el sector de las Tecnologías de la Información (TI) experimentará un aumento del 6% en los salarios</strong> <strong>en 2026</strong>, siendo el tercer sector que más subirá los sueldos, solo superado por el sector de atención al cliente y administración y el de finanzas (los dos con un 7% de aumento) y seguido por el de la banca (5%). El porcentaje de incremento es destacable, pues tanto en 2024 como en 2025 este apenas alcanzaba el 2%.</p> <p>En concreto, los datos de Hays prevén un <strong>aumento de la demanda de posiciones de mandos intermedios y directivos</strong>, con salarios superiores a 50.000 euros brutos anuales. “Las empresas, inmersas en procesos de contratación permanente, buscan profesionales de alto nivel, mientras que para roles menos críticos optan por la externalización o soluciones en otros países”, reza el informe.</p> <p>Los perfiles más solicitados serán los de desarrollador de .NET, desarrollador de Java/J2EE, product owner (software/SaaS/mobile), desarrollados de IA, consultor de ciberseguridad y auditor de TI, ingeniero cloud e ingeniero DevOps, mientras que los menos solicitados serán los desarrolladores de PHP y de Ruby On Rails.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="cuanto-cobraran-los-directivos-de-ti-en-2026">¿Cuánto cobrarán los directivos de TI en 2026?</h2> <p>Según la tabla salarial que incluye la edición de 2026 de la Guía de Hays, y que analiza las cinco mayores provincias españolas, estos serán los sueldos de los principales directivos de TI:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Un <strong>CIO </strong>(director de sistemas de información) de una empresa multinacional, con perfil internacional, capacidad de gestión de presupuesto y a nivel estratégico y con una experiencia de más de cinco años cobrará de media en 2026 unos 175.000 euros en Madrid y Barcelona; un sueldo que se reduce a los 140.000 euros en Valencia y a 135.000 euros en el caso de ciudades como Bilbao o Sevilla.</li> <li>Por su parte, un <strong>director de TI (<em>IT director</em>) </strong>de una empresa cliente final, con capacidad de gestión presupuestaria y estratégica y de administración de proyectos y con una experiencia de más de cinco años percibirá unos 100.000 euros en Madrid y Barcelona, 80.000 euros en Valencia y 75.000 euros en Bilbao o Sevilla.</li> <li>Un <strong>gerente de TI o <em>IT manager</em></strong>, es decir, aquel que trabaja para una pyme, gestionando infraestructura, proveedores y proyectos, y con más de cinco años de experiencia, contará con un sueldo de 80.000 euros en Madrid, Barcelona, Bilbao y Sevilla, y de 65.000 euros en Valencia.</li> <li>Un <strong>CTO (director de tecnología)</strong> experimentado (más de cinco años) que trabaje para una <em>startup </em>o empresa tecnológica, realizando gestión técnica y presupuestaria percibirá un sueldo medio de 180.000 euros en Madrid y Barcelona, y 135.000 euros en Valencia, Bilbao y Sevilla.</li> <li>Un <strong>CISO (director de seguridad de la información)</strong> con más de cinco años de experiencia cobrará unos 135.000 euros en Madrid y Barcelona, y 95.000 euros en Valencia, Bilbao y Sevilla.</li> <li>Un <strong>CDO (Chief Data Officer o director de datos)</strong> experimentado percibirá un salario medio de 135.000 euros en Madrid y Barcelona, y 125.000 euros en Valencia, Bilbao y Sevilla.</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="adios-a-la-burbuja-laboral-del-sector-tecnologico">Adiós a la burbuja laboral del sector tecnológico</h2> <p>El informe también analiza el comportamiento del empleo el pasado 2025. Respecto al vertical de TI, resalta que el pasado fue un año sin un incremento significativo en la creación de empleo, pero en el que la digitalización ha avanzado con mayor intensidad en empresas de los sectores logístico, financiero y farmacéutico, frente a otros donde el negocio <em>online </em>tiene menor peso. Respecto al ecosistema de <em>startups</em>, según el informe, el crecimiento también ha sido discreto, “manteniendo estrategias orientadas a recuperar la inversión realizada”.</p> <p>La Guía también apunta que <strong>en el sector tecnológico se ha desinflado con fuerza la burbuja que había caracterizado a este vertical en los últimos años</strong>. Es más, indica que el número de ofertas rechazadas ha caído de forma rotunda, de modo que es habitual encontrar profesionales del ámbito digital en situación de desempleo temporal, un escenario, según los expertos de Hays, “difícil de imaginar no hace tanto tiempo”.</p> <p>Pese a este contexto, la Guía subraya que los perfiles especializados en TI continúan ocupando un lugar clave en las estrategias corporativas. “Los perfiles IT siguen siendo esenciales para las organizaciones y mantienen un alto reconocimiento, con una especialización creciente impulsada por la consolidación de la inteligencia artificial en todos los niveles”, apunta.</p> <p>Las grandes tendencias del sector TI en 2025 en materia laboral han sido, dice la guía, el <strong>aumento salarial en perfiles con experiencia</strong> (senior) y la <strong>actualización masiva de descripciones de puestos</strong>, un elemento impulsado por el impacto transversal de la inteligencia artificial en todas las funciones tecnológicas.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="la-ia-generativa-impacta-con-fuerza-en-el-mercado-de-trabajo-espanol">La IA generativa impacta con fuerza en el mercado de trabajo español</h2> <p>El informe de Hays también analiza el impacto de la IA, y en concreto de su sabor generativo, en el mercado laboral general, donde, afirma, esta tecnología se está consolidando como una herramienta cotidiana en el trabajo.</p> <p>Según el documento, en España, <strong>el 62% de los profesionales ya utiliza IA en su día a día</strong>, frente al 34% en 2024, lo que supone un fuerte aumento de uso. El 52% de las empresas reconoce fomentar el uso de esta tecnología de forma activa. Una tendencia que, según el director para el Sur y Oeste de Europa de Hays, Christopher Dottie, “está transformando la forma de trabajar, las habilidades que son clave y los perfiles más demandados, generando una brecha que va creciendo con el tiempo entre aquellos que dominan estas herramientas y quienes aún no se han adaptado”.</p> <p>A pesar de este auge de la IA, <strong>la mayoría de las empresas (81%) prevé contratar a más profesionales en 2026</strong>. No obstante, la dificultad para encontrar talento cualificado sigue siendo, para el 93% de las empresas, un desafío. Precisamente para hacer frente a este, muchas organizaciones se están planteando opciones que motiven a los empleados como pagar más por habilidades específicas (lo que se llama ‘skills-based pay’).</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="la-vuelta-a-la-presencialidad-y-el-quiet-thriving-como-tendencia">La vuelta a la presencialidad y el ‘quiet thriving’ como tendencia </h2> <p>El informe también destaca otras tendencias que vive el mercado laboral español. Una es la vuelta a la presencialidad, con muchas compañías obligando a sus empleados a volver a la oficina. El informe indica, de hecho, que el 50% de las empresas ya opera de forma totalmente presencial, frente al 38% registrado en 2025. No obstante, indican desde Hays, que “las empresas siguen buscando equilibrio entre flexibilidad, productividad y cohesión de los equipos”.</p> <p>Por otro lado, tras el fenómeno de la renuncia silenciosa, el famoso término de ‘quiet quitting’ en inglés, que caracterizó a 2023, en 2026, dice la guía, gana fuerza todo lo contrario: el ‘quiet thriving’ o prosperar de forma silenciosa, con el que se describe una situación en la que el empleado realiza pequeños cambios personales o laborales para mejorar el bienestar, la motivación y la satisfacción que tiene en el trabajo; una tendencia que puede hacer que los empleados reduzcan incluso su intención de cambiar de empresa incluso en un mercado lleno de oportunidades. En este sentido, el informe asegura que en la actualidad casi siete de cada diez trabajadores se declara satisfecho con su empleo.</p> <p></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Future-proof tech skills for the evolving AI job market]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134749/future-proof-tech-skills-for-the-evolving-ai-job-market.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134749/future-proof-tech-skills-for-the-evolving-ai-job-market.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>I started in technology at a time when writing clean code, managing infrastructure and mastering a specific programming language could sustain a decades-long career. Each major shift — from client-server computing to the internet and from virtualization to the cloud — brought both disruption and opportunity. The professionals who stayed curious, adaptable and grounded in business outcomes didn’t disappear. They evolved.</p> <p>Today, artificial intelligence feels different to many people. I hear and speak it every day in conversations with CIOs, CHROs and technologists at every level of their careers. There’s a real fear that <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/ai-jobs-layoffs-us-2025/" rel="nofollow">AI will hollow out tech jobs</a> — especially at the entry level — and concentrate value in a <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/godfather-of-ai-geoffrey-hinton-2026-job-losses-2025-12" rel="nofollow">smaller number of elite roles</a>. I understand that concern: AI is already automating routine coding, testing and data-processing work at a pace we haven’t seen before.</p> <p>But after decades of watching technology reshape work and after countless conversations with clients navigating this shift, I don’t believe we’re heading toward a jobless future. We are heading toward a skills transformation. Some roles will decline. Others will grow. Entirely new roles will emerge. The organizations that succeed will be the ones that act now to align talent strategies with how AI is actually changing work, not how headlines suggest it is.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="how-ai-is-reshaping-tech-roles-in-practice">How AI is reshaping tech roles in practice</h2> <p>When I talk with CIOs across industries, a few consistent patterns emerge.</p> <p>First, roles centered on routine execution are shrinking. Tasks like basic application maintenance, repetitive coding, manual data preparation and simple QA are increasingly handled by AI-enabled tools. This shift disproportionately affects early-career technologists, who historically learned through repetition and exposure to foundational tasks. That’s a real challenge we must acknowledge and address through better onboarding, mentoring and structured upskilling.</p> <p>At the same time, demand is rising sharply for roles that sit closer to decision-making and system design. Machine learning and AI engineers, data and analytics professionals, cloud and DevOps specialists, cybersecurity leaders and UX/UI designers are all seeing sustained growth. These roles require people who can frame problems, work across domains and evaluate outcomes, not just execute instructions.</p> <p>We’re also seeing the creation of entirely new positions. Titles like “AI ethics officer,” “responsible AI lead,” and “human-AI strategist” didn’t exist in most organizations five years ago. Today, they’re becoming essential as enterprises grapple with governance, trust, bias and the human impact of automation.</p> <p>The throughline here is simple: AI isn’t eliminating the need for technologists. It’s raising the bar on what technologists need to know and how they add value.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="the-future-proof-technical-skills-cios-should-prioritize">The future-proof technical skills CIOs should prioritize</h2> <p>From my perspective, CIOs should focus less on chasing individual tools and more on building capability clusters — combinations of skills that remain valuable even as platforms change. Here are the technical skill sets I believe will matter most over the next several years.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="machine-learning-and-applied-ai">Machine learning and applied AI</h3> <p>While AI fluency is no longer optional, I want to be clear: Not everyone needs to be training large language models from scratch. What organizations need are professionals who can frame the right problems for AI, manage data pipelines, evaluate model outputs and explain results to non-technical stakeholders.</p> <p>Skills like prompt engineering, vector search and responsible AI practices are becoming foundational. On the tooling side, familiarity with Python, TensorFlow, PyTorch and cloud-based AI services across major platforms is critical. Certifications can help, but hands-on experience applying AI to real business problems matters far more.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="data-and-analytics">Data and analytics</h3> <p>AI is only as good as the data behind it. That’s why data and analytics skills continue to grow in importance. The most valuable professionals are those who can take large, messy datasets, apply advanced analytics or machine learning and translate insights into action.</p> <p>Visualization tools such as Power BI, Tableau and Looker Studio remain important, as do core languages like SQL, Python and R. But the differentiator is the ability to connect insights to business decisions. Data literacy across the organization — not just in analytics teams — will increasingly separate leaders from laggards.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cloud-computing-and-devops">Cloud computing and DevOps</h3> <p>AI accelerates everything, including the need for scalable, resilient infrastructure. Managing hybrid and multicloud environments, automating deployments and ensuring security at scale are no longer niche skills.</p> <p>Proficiency in platforms like AWS, Azure and Google Cloud, combined with tools such as Kubernetes and Terraform, is table stakes. What’s emerging as even more valuable is the ability to design architectures that balance speed, cost, compliance and sustainability. DevOps is no longer just about faster releases; it’s about operational intelligence.</p> <h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="cybersecurity">Cybersecurity</h3> <p>As AI expands the attack surface, cybersecurity skills are evolving rapidly. We’re seeing growing demand for professionals who understand AI-enabled threats, automated defense mechanisms and identity-centric security models.</p> <p>CIOs should invest in continuous training here, not just point-in-time certifications. The threat landscape is changing too fast for static skill sets.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="upskilling-turning-displacement-into-opportunity">Upskilling: Turning displacement into opportunity</h2> <p>One of the biggest mistakes organizations make is believing they can hire their way out of a skills gap. Today’s talent market doesn’t work that way. Competition is fierce, roles are evolving quickly and specialized expertise is harder to find than ever. Across industries, leaders are increasingly aligned on this reality: Solving hiring challenges requires investing in the people they already have, not just competing for the same limited talent pool.</p> <p>I’ve seen the most success when companies create clear pathways from declining roles into growing ones. That means pairing technical training with real project experience, mentorship and time to learn. It also means rethinking how early-career talent gains exposure when entry-level tasks are automated. Rotational programs, apprenticeships and supervised AI-augmented work can fill those gaps.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="why-human-skills-matter-more-than-ever">Why human skills matter more than ever</h2> <p>As AI takes on more technical execution, human-centered skills become a competitive advantage. This is something we emphasize heavily at Dexian and it’s echoed by what we hear from employers and employees alike. For example, <a href="https://dexian.com/news/dexians-2025-humankindex/" rel="nofollow">85% of business leaders and 87% of workers</a> agree that their organizations are putting more emphasis on human skills alongside technical expertise.</p> <p>UX and UI designers are great examples. Designing inclusive, intuitive experiences requires empathy, creativity and cultural awareness — capabilities AI can assist with but not replicate. The same is true for roles like product managers, change leaders and human-AI strategists who sit at the intersection of technology, ethics and business execution.</p> <p>These professionals ensure AI enhances human interaction rather than eroding it. They ask questions like: How does this system affect trust? How do we keep humans in the loop? How do we measure success beyond efficiency?</p> <p>Creativity, communication, emotional intelligence, resilience and lifelong learning are no longer soft skills. They are core skills in an AI-centric organization.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="what-the-future-holds-and-what-cios-should-do-now">What the future holds — and what CIOs should do now</h2> <p>If there’s one lesson my career has reinforced, it’s that technology never stands still and neither can we. AI will continue to reshape the tech workforce in ways we can’t fully predict. But the direction is clear. Fewer highly specialized roles, more multifaceted ones. Less emphasis on rote execution, more on judgment, integration and impact.</p> <p>My advice to CIOs is straightforward. Start with an honest assessment of how AI is already changing work inside your organization. Identify which roles are at risk of becoming obsolete and which capabilities will matter most in three to five years. Invest aggressively in upskilling, especially early-career talent. And don’t underestimate the power of human skills to differentiate your organization in a world where technology is increasingly commoditized.</p> <p>AI isn’t the end of tech careers; it’s the next chapter. The leaders who embrace that reality and prepare their people accordingly will shape not just the future of IT, but the future of work itself.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Enterprise Architects Have Stepped Out Of The Ivory Tower]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Stéphane Vanrechem, Senior Analyst, Forrester For years, many enterprise architecture (EA) teams operated in isolation, building elaborate frameworks that few understood and even fewer used. Then something shifted: Architects started solving actual business problems <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower/" title="Enterprise Architects Have Stepped Out Of The Ivory Tower">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Enterprise Architects Have Stepped Out Of The Ivory Tower]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/20/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower-2/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/20/enterprise-architects-have-stepped-out-of-the-ivory-tower-2/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Stéphane Vanrechem, Senior Analyst, Forrester For years, many enterprise architecture (EA) teams operated in isolation, building elaborate frameworks that few understood and even fewer used. Then something shifted: Architects started solving actual ...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[State of IT jobs: AI sparks rapidly changing market for skills]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134254/state-of-it-jobs-ai-sparks-rapidly-changing-market-for-skills.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134254/state-of-it-jobs-ai-sparks-rapidly-changing-market-for-skills.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>In the past year, IT professionals have weathered significant transformation in the workplace at the hands of AI. The technology has shifted demand for skills, altered several IT career paths, and disrupted day-to-day operations in nearly every business as leaders and employees adapt workflows and processes to incorporate AI.</p> <p>With layoffs once again making headlines, companies have shifted to hiring for specific skillsets they need to implement, adopt, secure, and make the most of AI, while upskilling employees internally to meet those same needs.</p> <p>Heading into 2026, top priorities in the hiring market include skills such as IT security, AI and ML integration, data analytics, governance and compliance, software engineering and development, and AI governance and ethics. However, a significant skills gap remains between what organizations seek and the skills candidates have on their resumes.</p> <p>Here is a look at the state of IT jobs today and how IT hiring and training strategies are evolving to address a quickly changing market for talent.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-push-for-skills-first-hiring">A push for skills-first hiring</h2> <p>The past year has seen a significant shift towards <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2509754/generative-ai-and-preparing-for-a-shift-to-skills-based-hiring.html">organizations hiring for skills</a> over experience, education, and background. While those traditional criteria remain relevant, IT leaders are looking to hire specifically for skillsets the organization needs or is lacking. This new focus is also seen as a way to open talent pipelines to candidates who may have been filtered out in the past.</p> <p>According to data from <a href="https://www.roberthalf.com/us/en/insights/salary-hiring-trends/demand-for-skilled-talent/tech-it" rel="nofollow">Robert Half</a>, 65% of IT leaders had more difficulty finding skilled IT professionals for open roles in 2025 than 2024. This year, 61% say they plan to increase permanent headcount in the first half of 2026, while 55% will increase contract and temporary hiring in the same time frame.</p> <p>Roles that have seen “above-average sequential growth and consistent demand” over the past year include AI/ML engineer, cybersecurity engineer, data analyst, data scientist, DevOps engineer, ERP business analyst, IT project manager, network/cloud engineer, software engineer, and systems administrator, according to Robert Half.</p> <p>The recruiting agency’s survey of IT leaders identified the following as the most apparent skills gaps:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI and machine learning (cited by 45% of respondents)</li> <li>IT operations and infrastructure (36%)</li> <li>IT governance and compliance (25%)</li> <li>Cloud architecture and operations (24%)</li> <li>Data engineering and analytics (22%)</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="demand-for-ai-skills-continues-to-grow">Demand for AI skills continues to grow</h2> <p>Job postings that require AI literacy skills are growing at a rate of more than 70% year over year, according LinkedIn’s <a href="https://economicgraph.linkedin.com/content/dam/me/economicgraph/en-us/PDF/ai-labor-market-update-header-sept-2025.pdf" rel="nofollow">AI Labor Market Update report</a>, which identified AI agents as the fastest-growing AI skill of 2025. Moreover, demand for AI skills such as prompt engineering are extending beyond IT to include roles in marketing, sales, and design.</p> <p>Other AI skills that grew the most in 2025 include Azure AI Studio, AI productivity, Spring AI, custom GPTs, prompt flow, large language model operations (LLMOps), AI strategy, OpenAI API, and automated feature engineering, according to LinkedIn.</p> <p>This marks somewhat of a shift from 2023, when the fastest growing AI skills included model training, hyperparameter optimization, and other skills considered vital to building AI tools. In just a few years, organizations are shifting to hiring and training workers skilled at getting the most from AI tools, as well as those who can help develop them.</p> <p>As AI increasingly takes on technical tasks, demand for soft skills is growing, according to Robert Half. To help oversee and guide AI-driven solutions, IT leaders are looking for workers with the skills to ensure AI is effective in supporting business goals, including:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Critical thinking and problem solving (72%)</li> <li>Adaptability and continuous learning (69%)</li> <li>Creativity and innovation (65%)</li> <li>Communication (36%)</li> <li>Emotional intelligence (22%)</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="tech-salaries-remain-strong-in-2026">Tech salaries remain strong in 2026</h2> <p>In the coming year, Robert Half projects a 1.6% average salary increase across IT roles, with a 4.1% increase for AI/ML engineer and data scientist salaries, a 2.3% increase for software and applications development roles, and a 1.7% increase for consulting and enterprise systems roles, along with data engineering, analytics, and reporting positions.</p> <p>Additionally, 87% of IT leaders say they will typically offer higher salaries to candidates who possess specialized skills over those without them it, with 52% “willing to negotiate a higher starting salary with a candidate if the role supports a critical business need.”</p> <p>However, 69% of IT leaders express concerns about keeping pace with candidates’ pay expectations. To get ahead of this, leaders are prepared to not only increase starting salaries but also to add benefits and perks and to include salary ranges in job descriptions.</p> <p>The skills leaders say they’re most willing to boost salary for include:</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>AI, machine learning, and data science</li> <li>Cybersecurity</li> <li>Cloud computing, cloud security, and cloud architecture</li> <li>Software and applications development</li> <li>Data analytics, business intelligence, and reporting</li>
</ul> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="rto-mandates-sparking-employee-dissatisfaction">RTO mandates sparking employee dissatisfaction</h2> <p>A <a href="https://www.ivanti.com/resources/research-reports/tech-at-work" rel="nofollow">report from Ivanti</a> found that 64% of IT professionals say they have “experienced pressure to return to the office during the last 12 months” whether that’s a strict RTO requirement or “encouraged” by management, despite the fact that <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4119562/work-from-office-mandate-expect-top-talent-turnover-culture-rot.html">RTO mandates can spark talent turnover and decreased morale</a>, as employees continue to value flexibility.</p> <p>Among the top cited reasons given for RTO mandates are improved productivity (41%) and stronger company culture (37%). Cybersecurity is also often cited as a reason, though more than half of IT professionals (56%) say security isn’t enough to justify strict RTO mandates. Moreover, while leadership seeks improve productivity via RTO mandates, 82% of workers say they are “at least as productive as, if not more” when working at home compared to the office.</p> <p>Still, employees expressed increased willingness to return to the office if offered a higher salary (75%); of those, 69% said a salary increase of 10% or more would be needed to consider it, according to Robert Half.</p> <p>Retention once workers return to the office is another concern, with 48% of respondents to the Ivanti survey reported feeling “resenteeism,” which is when workers dislike their jobs but stay despite the negative feelings. And 37% say they engage in “presenteeism” — coming into the office to be seen working, rather than to be productive.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-continues-to-reshape-the-it-job-landscape">AI continues to reshape the IT job landscape</h2> <p>In the <a href="https://www.weforum.org/publications/the-future-of-jobs-report-2025/" rel="nofollow">Future of Jobs Report 2025</a> from World Economic Forum, 60% of employers say they expect AI to transform their business by 2030. The report noted that 63% of employers report that skills gaps are “categorically considered the biggest barrier to business transformation,” and 85% have plans to prioritize upskilling their workforce. Additionally, 70% of employers say they expect to source skills by hiring new staff, 40% plan to reduce staff as skills become redundant, and 50% plan to “transition staff from declining to growing roles.”</p> <p>Employees are largely adopting AI in the workforce, with 80% of respondents in the <a href="https://www.hiringlab.org/2026/01/19/2025-indeed-workforce-insights-survey/" rel="nofollow">2025 Indeed Workforce Insights Report</a>, reporting they save at least one hour per day using generative AI. Additionally, 37% of tech professionals say their role has been “redefined or restructured due to gen AI in the past two years.” As AI takes over more menial, repetitive tasks, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4073419/ai-pushes-cios-to-redefine-it-roles-for-the-future.html">organizations are redefining IT roles</a> to make way for the future of AI in the workplace.</p> <p>Organizations are increasingly offering courses on prompt engineering, AI fundamentals, and other skills that will help employees get up to speed on effectively using AI to boost productivity and efficiency. Training and upskilling can also help organizations <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4077448/ai-workslop-the-new-productivity-killer-only-training-can-stop.html">avoid falling into pitfalls of “AI workslop,”</a> which occurs when employees use AI in ill-advised ways, ultimately creating more work for coworkers who have to revise or edit AI-generated content. To make the most of AI investments, organizations will need to continue focusing on providing training and upskilling opportunities to employees within the organization.</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[What IT leaders need to know about the world’s first national AI law]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134658/the-era-of-the-ai-framework-act-begins-what-response-paths-are-proposed-by-legal-industry-and-academic-leaders.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134658/the-era-of-the-ai-framework-act-begins-what-response-paths-are-proposed-by-legal-industry-and-academic-leaders.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>The enforcement of the <a href="https://aibasicact.kr/" rel="nofollow">AI Basic Act</a> is significant as it represents the world’s first full-scale implementation of a national AI framework law. <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4032894/analysis-of-the-european-ai-regulation-one-year-after-its-entry-into-force.html?utm=hybrid_search">The EU has enacted its own AI Act</a> and in the US, AI regulation remains fragmented, limited largely to state-level initiatives. So against this backdrop, South Korea’s move to enforce a comprehensive AI law is seen as a proactive step on the global stage.</p> <p>The AI Basic Act, spearheaded by the Ministry of Science and ICT, was shaped through an extensive preparatory process. Starting in January last year, more than 80 private-sector experts formed a dedicated task force to refine the law’s subordinate regulations. The enforcement decree alone went through over 70 rounds of stakeholder consultations, but to ease the transition following the law’s rollout, the government has published five sets of guidance documents and established an AI Basic Act support desk to underscore its commitment to hands-on assistance.</p> <p>Still, industry reaction has been mixed. AI remains an unfamiliar technology for many, and the introduction of a new regulatory framework has prompted sharply divergent views. Critics argue the Act is too lenient, while supporters see it as a pragmatic starting point that strikes a realistic balance with industrial needs.</p> <p>To find out what IT leaders and corporate executives should prepare for, experts let their voices be heard.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="whats-needed-right-now">What’s needed right now</h2> <p>Eunseong Kang, a professor of intelligent information security at Seoul Women’s University, says the structure of the AI Basic Act deserves close attention. “It’s built around sound development of AI, and establishment of a foundation for trustworthiness,” he says. “It follows a familiar Korean legislative approach that seeks to promote technological advancement and mitigate potential side effects.”</p> <p>At the same time, Kang describes the Act as a law that inevitably has limitations common to technology regulation. “Most laws are, by nature, reactive,” he adds. “In the case of AI, regulation can only be introduced after the technology has raced ahead.”</p> <p>Still, he’s careful to distinguish between acknowledging those limitations and questioning the need for the Act itself. Given that AI extends far beyond a mere technology, affecting life, physical safety, fundamental rights, and society at large, leaving it entirely unregulated would pose serious risks.</p> <p>“In that sense, the Act occupies a middle ground between a fully proactive law and a purely reactive one,” Kang says. “It carries the inherent constraints that legislation faces in keeping pace with technological change, but it was nonetheless a law we needed. However, it’s easy to misread the Act as either too lax or overly restrictive. Rather than imposing heavy sanctions from the outset, it should be seen as a law that first establishes a minimum framework for managing AI as a society.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="open-to-interpretation">Open to interpretation</h2> <p>Kang also highlights a clear gap in how businesses and advocacy groups perceive the Act, especially in regard to uncertainty. “Companies are expected to determine for themselves whether they fall under its scope and what obligations apply,” he says. “This is especially confusing for organizations that don’t develop AI themselves but deploy it, so they may not even know if they’re subject to regulation at all.”</p> <p>From a corporate standpoint, ambiguity revolves around criteria for high-risk AI, boundaries of gen AI, and the level of responsibility placed on AI service users. “For companies, regulatory risk ultimately boils down to ambiguity,” Kang adds. “When it’s unclear what constitutes non-compliance, firms tend to act conservatively or overreact.”</p> <p>Advocacy groups, on the other hand, argue the Act is too lenient and lacks meaningful enforcement. “They tend to view AI through the lens of potential violations of fundamental rights,” he says, “which leads them to feel the current framework doesn’t provide adequate safeguards.”</p> <p>As it stands, administrative fines are largely confined to violations of transparency obligations — specifically, failures to provide required disclosures. Penalties are set at about USD$3,500 and rise sharply with each additional violation.</p> <p>By comparison, the EU AI Act allows for fines of up to 7% of a company’s global annual turnover or roughly USD$38 million, whichever is higher, for violations of prohibited practices. “Compared to the EU AI Act, South Korea’s AI Basic Act has a relatively narrow scope and a lower level of sanctions,” Kang says. “From that perspective, it’s understandable that advocacy groups question whether the regulation goes far enough.”</p> <p>Kang also flags potential blind spots in how regulated AI systems are classified. Obligations to implement safety measures apply only when two conditions are met simultaneously: cumulative computational usage exceeding 10²⁶ FLOPs, and a significant impact on life, physical safety, public safety, or fundamental rights. The problem is this computational threshold is so high that realistically only a handful of companies or state-level projects can reach it. And because these criteria are applied conjunctively, there’s a strong concern that AI systems with tangible impacts on fundamental rights, but lower computational footprints, could slip through the regulatory net.</p> <p>Despite these concerns, Kang expresses a positive view of the government’s commitment to supporting the Act’s rollout. “Publishing five detailed sets of guidelines immediately upon the law’s entry into force is something we’ve rarely seen before,” he says. “When you consider the release of high-risk AI assessment guidelines, the launch of a support desk, and the establishment of an expert advisory system, it’s clear the government is serious about making this work.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-sound-risk-based-approach-but-vague-standards">A sound risk-based approach, but vague standards</h2> <p>Attorney Ted Koo highlights how the AI Basic Act adopts a risk-based approach and offers a positive assessment of its framework. “You can’t apply medical device–level regulation just because someone built a chatbot,” he says. “The idea of focusing on high-risk areas is inherently reasonable.” In a landscape where AI has become routine, blanket regulation would inevitably stifle industry growth, he says.</p> <p>He also underscores the significance of principles such as AI impact assessments, explainability, and <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4127712/what-cios-must-get-right-for-the-ai-era.html?utm=hybrid_search">transparency obligations</a> being written into law. Provisions that previously existed only as voluntary guidelines now carry legal force. And while endorsing the overall direction, Koo stresses the current framework reveals several limitations, like overly abstract criteria to determine what qualifies as high-risk AI.</p> <p>Although the Enforcement Decree lists factors such as severity and frequency of risks posed, it remains unclear which AI systems actually fall into this category. In practice, businesses must make their own determinations, or request case-by-case confirmation from the Ministry of Science and ICT.</p> <p>“Services like AI-based loan screening may end up setting standards through complaints or civil petitions,” Koo says, adding that how consistently the government maintains its criteria during the early stages of implementation will be crucial. Sectors with outsized social impact, such as finance, recruitment, healthcare, and education, will also inevitably draw heightened scrutiny, and he urges relevant stakeholders to watch early corporate cases closely.</p> <p>Koo likened this dynamic to a university admissions cutoff score, where it’s difficult to know in advance whether you’ve crossed the line, and early decisions may become the benchmark for all future judgments.</p> <p>Another limitation he sees is a blurred line between self-regulation and legal obligation. While operators of high-risk AI systems are required to conduct impact assessments, either internally or through third parties, there’s no direct government evaluation or prior approval process. As a result, provisions that are formally mandatory may function in practice more like self-assessments, with compliance potentially reduced to filing reports that assert appropriate management is in place.</p> <p>Plus, there are concerns about alignment with the global regulatory landscape. As major jurisdictions such as the EU, the US, and China establish distinct AI regulatory frameworks, Korean companies are increasingly forced to navigate different national rules on their own. While global enterprises may simply align with the strictest standards, SMEs and startups face a far heavier burden in interpreting and complying with multiple legal regimes.</p> <p>Koo then says preparation for next-gen tech remains insufficient. The current AI Basic Act is designed around technologies already in commercial use, but next-stage developments like physical AI and <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3802779/with-agi-looming-cios-stay-the-course-on-ai-partnerships.html?utm=hybrid_search">AGI</a> already loom. “Given the pace of change, it’s hard to rule out the possibility that the law itself could become outdated sooner than expected,” Koo says.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="a-readiness-checklist-not-just-regulation">A readiness checklist, not just regulation</h2> <p>So how does the AI Basic Act look from an industry perspective? Gartner senior executive partner Youn Choi says it’s a law that emphasizes guidance and preparedness over punishment. “While the EU AI Act is closer to an enforcement-driven regime centered on sanctions and penalties, Korea’s AI Basic Act places greater weight on guidance and readiness,” he says. “It’s a law positioned at the starting line rather than a finished product.”</p> <p>In practice, the Korean law adopts a relatively moderate structure built around administrative fines, and the government plans to operate a one-year grace period during the early phase of implementation.</p> <p>That said, this doesn’t mean companies can afford to be complacent. Choi identifies four key areas that enterprises should begin assessing now: <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4117094/data-management-trends-whats-in-whats-out.html?utm=hybrid_search">data quality</a>, data governance, security, and data pipelines.</p> <p>“Over the long term, companies that internalize the standards early will gain a competitive edge over those that merely try to avoid regulation,” he says. “The AI Basic Act is closer to a questionnaire asking companies how prepared they really are.”</p> <p>More specifically, he advises companies to focus on ensuring transparency and explainability. “If proper logging and traceability are in place so companies can explain how models were trained and how outputs were generated, issues can be verified through audits when problems arise,” Choi says. “It’s equally fundamental to apply masking or de-identification to prevent personal data from being exposed during training, and to manage fairness and bias so AI systems don’t disadvantage particular groups.”</p> <p>He adds that companies using gen AI in particular shouldn’t take labeling and disclosure obligations lightly. Clearly indicating content generated by AI through watermarks or metadata isn’t just a legal requirement, but a factor directly tied to corporate trust and brand reputation.</p> <p>“When GDPR was first introduced, many companies dismissed it as excessive regulation, but it ultimately became a catalyst to raise data management maturity,” Choi says. “There’s a strong possibility the AI Basic Act will follow a similar trajectory.” Companies that already have robust data governance and security frameworks, he adds, will face lower compliance costs and be better positioned to adapt.</p> <p>“In the end, it’s not the companies trying to dodge AI regulation but those that internalize the standards early that will gain a lasting competitive edge,” he says. “The AI Basic Act is essentially a prompt asking companies how ready they are.”</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="from-ownership-to-action">From ownership to action</h2> <p>Analysts and legal professionals say the starting point for responding to the AI Basic Act is to designate an internal lead responsible for overall compliance, ideally at the executive level.</p> <p>“Just as companies have executives responsible for information security, AI also requires an executive who oversees overall quality and governance,” says Choi. “But it’s not realistic for a single individual to shoulder all these responsibilities.”</p> <p>In practice, many functions implicated by the AI Basic Act, like data quality management, access controls, personal data protection, and log management, are already things companies do to some degree. Choi says that because AI ultimately runs on data, the key question is whether existing <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3999449/the-3-key-pillars-of-data-governance-for-ai-driven-enterprises.html?utm=hybrid_search">data governance</a> is functioning properly. “The transparency and explainability required by the AI Basic Act will be ultimately determined by the maturity of a company’s data management,” he adds.</p> <p>So Choi recommends building a structure that brings together multiple stakeholders. The key isn’t creating a new organization but connecting existing ones and aligning decision-making processes. If the CIO, security, legal, and data teams remain siloed, responding effectively to the AI Basic Act will be difficult.</p> <p>“The Act isn’t a signal to start AI over from scratch,” Choi says. “It’s closer to a message asking companies to review what they’ve already been doing in data, security, and governance, but this time through an AI lens.” Framing it this way, he adds, can help companies avoid perceiving compliance as an excessive burden in terms of headcount or organizational restructuring.</p> <p>More concretely, Choi proposes forming a steering committee involving senior leaders such as the CEO, CFO, CIO, and heads of legal. Such a structure is necessary, he says, to assess business risks and opportunities, impacts on customers and partners, and potential effects on brand reputation.</p> <p>Kang shares a similar view, saying the team leading AI Basic Act compliance may differ depending on a company’s size and structure. For companies that develop AI directly, the development or AI-dedicated teams may take the lead, while firms with strong regulatory experience may rely on legal or compliance departments. In practice, however, Kang says the requirements of the Act — safety, reliability, and regulatory compliance — significantly overlap with the responsibilities traditionally handled by security and information protection teams, making it likely that security organizations will serve as the primary operational point of contact in many companies.</p> <p>“The important issue isn’t which department takes the lead,” Kang says, “but whether development, security, and legal teams are organically connected and able to explain how AI systems operate and where responsibility lies.” He adds that responding to the Act should be viewed not as a task for a single department, but as an exercise in coordinating roles across existing teams.</p> <p>“The AI Basic Act may look like a set of principles today,” Kang says. “But if disputes or incidents arise down the road, explainability could become a key benchmark for determining corporate liability.”</p> <p>He puts particular emphasis on internal preparedness. “The duty to explain can’t be satisfied by posting boilerplate language on a website,” he says. “From the development stage onward, teams must be able to articulate in their own words what criteria and logic their AI uses to reach decisions.” Even if those explanations aren’t technically perfect, companies need a framework that can reasonably describe how decisions are made.</p> <p>Koo also emphasizes that response strategies should vary by company size. “Large enterprises are more likely to already have a baseline level of preparedness,” he says. “But startups need to begin building these systems now.” While obligations such as labeling and disclosure can often be addressed through relatively simple technical measures, Koo says impact assessments and safety assurance are difficult to implement without proper internal governance.</p> <p>So Koo recommends taking a proactive stance. “Rather than leaving matters ambiguous, companies, especially those operating AI systems in biometrics, recruitment, credit evaluation, <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4068984/how-the-ai-governance-committee-in-healthcare-is-a-force-multiplier.html?utm=hybrid_search">healthcare</a>, or education, should consider requesting confirmation from the Ministry of Science and ICT in advance,” he says. “The government is required to respond within 30 days, and if companies simply assume it doesn’t apply to them and move on, they may find themselves without enough time to respond when issues actually arise.”</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How agentic AI will reshape engineering workflows in 2026]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134741/how-agentic-ai-will-reshape-engineering-workflows-in-2026.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134741/how-agentic-ai-will-reshape-engineering-workflows-in-2026.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>In the two years since generative AI exploded into the mainstream, we’ve moved from awe at its capabilities to a more pragmatic question: What comes next? The answer is evident in the rise of agentic AI, systems that don’t just respond to prompts but can reason, plan and pursue complex, multi-step goals autonomously.</p> <p>In 2026, this evolution will fundamentally reshape how engineering teams build, operate and innovate. However, any organization undergoing this transformation will require a strategic overhaul of people, processes and platforms.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="agentic-ai-is-structurally-different">Agentic AI is structurally different</h2> <p>What makes agentic AI structurally different from earlier generations of developer tooling is not better prompting, but sustained execution. Frontier models can now reason across long-running, multi-step workflows, invoking tools, interpreting results and iterating over time. As this capability accelerates, entire segments of the software development lifecycle will move from human-executed to autonomously executed. By the end of this year, the defining challenge will not be whether AI can participate across engineering workflows, but how deliberately organizations design for it.</p> <p>The most immediate and tangible impact will be on development velocity. We are moving beyond AI as a sophisticated coding assistant to AI as an autonomous, multi-skilled team member. Agentic AI will increasingly act as a first-pass executor across the SDLC, analyzing feasibility during planning, implementing features during build, expanding test coverage during validation and surfacing risks during review; compressing weeks of coordination into continuous workflows.</p> <p>A recent McKinsey report highlights that <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/technology-media-and-telecommunications/our-insights/the-ai-centric-imperative-navigating-the-next-software-frontier" rel="nofollow">AI-centric organizations are achieving 20% to 40% reductions in operating costs and 12–14 point increases in EBITDA margins</a>, driven by automation, faster cycle times and more efficient allocation of talent and infrastructure. This isn’t just about speed; it’s about freeing human engineers from repetitive tasks to focus on the higher-order problems that require creativity and strategic thinking. The deeper gain is cognitive leverage: fewer handoffs, less context switching and reduced rediscovery of system knowledge, allowing engineers to operate at a higher level of abstraction for longer periods of time.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="engineers-as-orchestrators-not-just-builders">Engineers as orchestrators, not just builders</h2> <p>This shift necessitates a fundamental redefinition of engineering roles from creators to curators. It represents the core of the composable AI approach that many organizations are beginning to adopt. The engineer of 2026 will spend less time writing foundational code and more time orchestrating a dynamic portfolio of AI agents, reusable components and external services.</p> <p>Their value will lie in designing the overarching system architecture, defining the precise objectives and guardrails for their AI counterparts and rigorously validating the final output to ensure it is robust, secure and perfectly aligned with business goals. It’s a move from hands-on keyboard creation to high-level system design, quality assurance and strategic oversight. The core skill becomes systems thinking, not just syntax.</p> <p>As this shift takes hold, leading teams are converging on a simple operating model: delegate, review and own. AI agents handle first-pass execution, scaffolding, implementation, testing and documentation. Engineers review outputs for correctness, risk and alignment. Ownership of architecture, trade-offs and outcomes remains human. This clarity allows autonomy to scale without diluting accountability.</p> <p>Consequently, the focus of AI efforts will experience a decisive shift from prompt engineering to orchestration. Crafting the perfect prompt for a single task will become a basic, secondary skill.</p> <p>The primary technical challenge will be designing the sophisticated workflows and interaction protocols between multiple specialized agents. How does an agent that designs a database schema hand off its work seamlessly to an agent that writes the API and then to another that performs penetration testing? How do they collaborate, resolve conflicts and report status? This orchestration layer, which is the conductor of the AI orchestra, will become the central pillar of engineering workflows and a critical skill set for technology leaders.</p> <p>However, for this autonomous future to work, seamless integration with existing enterprise ecosystems is a must. An agentic AI platform that operates in a sterile, isolated lab environment is useless. It must be able to navigate, understand and operate within the complex, often messy, reality of an enterprise IT environment. This means deep integration with legacy monoliths, cloud-native CI/CD pipelines, project management tools and data lakes.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="risk-governance-and-trust-by-design">Risk, governance and trust by design</h2> <p>This integrated technology also necessitates robust risk management and ethical considerations. How do we mitigate the risk of an autonomous agent making a flawed architectural decision that scales and impacts a production system? This will require robust guardrails, circuit breakers and comprehensive audit trails from the ground up.</p> <p>To counter inherent biases in training data that could lead to discriminatory outcomes, as well as the risk of agents being manipulated or jailbroken, a proactive and rigorous governance framework is essential. The 2024 Stanford AI Index Report highlights <a href="https://hai.stanford.edu/ai-index/2024-ai-index-report" rel="nofollow">growing corporate attention to AI ethics, safety and governance as organizations struggle with rising risks</a>. We must build trust not through black boxes, but through transparency, explainability and human-in-the-loop control points for critical decisions.</p> <p>Agentic AI will evolve through distinct phases. We begin with assistance, where AI supports discrete, atomic tasks; largely the stage we are in today. This progresses to augmentation, where AI manages multi-step processes and workflows within defined domains, such as autonomously overseeing a CI/CD pipeline.</p> <p>Ultimately, the trajectory leads to autonomy, in which AI operates across domains and makes smarter decisions guided by high-level business objectives. Each phase will demand different engineering structures, skills and governance models. Companies must be intentional and measured in their progression, avoiding the temptation to run before they can walk.</p> <p>This journey leads to a critical build versus buy decision that every firm will need to make. Do you invest massive resources to develop a proprietary agentic AI platform, tailored to your unique workflows and offering a potential competitive moat? Or do you leverage and customize third-party platforms from vendors, gaining speed to market but potentially sacrificing deep integration and differentiation?</p> <p>There is no one-size-fits-all answer, but the decision must be guided by a cold-eyed assessment of your core competencies and long-term goals, not just by the allure of the technology.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="designing-the-hybrid-human-digital-workforce">Designing the hybrid human–digital workforce</h2> <p>All these threads culminate in the need for deliberate hybrid human-digital workforce planning. The future of engineering is not a fully automated, lights-out department; it’s a collaborative, synergistic ecosystem where human intuition and strategic oversight partner with AI speed and scale. Our focus must shift to defining the new organizational structures, communication protocols and leadership skills required to manage this blended workforce effectively.</p> <p>How do we evaluate the performance of an AI agent? How do we foster team cohesion between humans and digital workers? How do we retrain and upskill our existing talent? These are the profound management and cultural challenges of the near future and they require as much attention as the technology itself.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="managing-the-transformation-not-just-the-technology">Managing the transformation, not just the technology</h2> <p>The promise of agentic AI is a true step-function improvement in engineering productivity, quality and innovation. But the path is fraught with technical, ethical and organizational complexity.</p> <p>Success will belong to those who view it not just as a new tool to implement, but as a transformative force to manage, with a clear-eyed focus on seamless integration, rigorous ethics, proactive risk management and, most importantly, the deliberate evolution of their human talent.</p> <p></p> <p><strong>This article is published as part of the Foundry Expert Contributor Network.</strong><br><strong><a href="https://www.cio.com/expert-contributor-network/">Want to join?</a></strong></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[빗썸, 양자내성암호 도입해 보안 강화…“국내 거래소 가운데 최초”]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135044/%eb%b9%97%ec%8d%b8-%ec%96%91%ec%9e%90%eb%82%b4%ec%84%b1%ec%95%94%ed%98%b8-%eb%8f%84%ec%9e%85%ed%95%b4-%eb%b3%b4%ec%95%88-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94%ea%b5%ad%eb%82%b4-%ea%b1%b0%eb%9e%98.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135044/%eb%b9%97%ec%8d%b8-%ec%96%91%ec%9e%90%eb%82%b4%ec%84%b1%ec%95%94%ed%98%b8-%eb%8f%84%ec%9e%85%ed%95%b4-%eb%b3%b4%ec%95%88-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94%ea%b5%ad%eb%82%b4-%ea%b1%b0%eb%9e%98.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>빗썸은 지난 11일 서울 강남구에 소재한 빗썸금융타워에서 핀테크 보안 기업 아톤과 ‘양자내성암호(PQC) 보안 솔루션 도입을 위한 기술협약’을 체결하고, 플랫폼 전반에 PQC 보안 솔루션을 적용하기로 했다. 빗썸 측은 이번 도입이 국내 가상자산 거래소 가운데 최초라고 밝혔다.</p> <p>이번 협약은 가상자산 산업이 빠르게 성장하면서 거래소에 요구되는 보안 수준이 높아지는 환경 변화에 선제 대응하기 위한 조치다. 향후 양자컴퓨터가 상용화될 경우 기존 보안체계에 위협이 될 수 있다는 우려에 대비해 빗썸은 양자내성암호(PQC)를 선제적으로 도입하고, 중장기 보안 대응 체계를 단계적으로 강화해 나간다는 계획이다.</p> <p>이에 빗썸은 국내 주요 시중은행과 증권사에 인증보안 솔루션을 공급해 온 아톤의 PQC 보안 솔루션을 단계적으로 도입한다. 해당 솔루션은 미국 국립표준기술연구소(NIST)가 선정한 표준 양자내성암호 알고리즘인 ML-DSA와 ML-KEM을 적용했으며, 자체 개발한 화이트박스 암호화 기술을 결합해 양자컴퓨터 기반 해독 위협은 물론 기존의 해킹 공격까지 이중으로 대응할 수 있도록 설계됐다.</p> <p>빗썸은 아톤의 솔루션을 통해 거래소 서비스의 입력, 인증, 전송, 저장 등 보안 라이프사이클 전 구간에 양자내성암호 기반 보호 체계를 적용할 계획이다.</p> <p>아울러 빗썸과 아톤은 공동 기술협의체를 구성해 거래소 환경에 최적화된 PQC 보안 체계를 단계적으로 구축하고 지속적인 고도화를 추진한다. 이를 통해 빗썸은 양자컴퓨터 시대의 ‘선수집 후해독(Harvest Now, Decrypt Later)’ 위협에 대비하고, 정부의 암호체계 전환 정책에도 발맞춰 이용자 보호 체계를 강화해 나갈 예정이다.</p> <p>이기택 빗썸 보안부문 총괄은 “장기적인 보안 환경 변화에 대비해 양자내성암호 기반 보안 체계 도입을 추진하게 됐다”라며 “단계적인 적용과 고도화를 통해 이용자 자산 보호 체계를 지속적으로 강화해 나가겠다”라고 말했다.<br>jihyun.lee@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[백오피스 IT에서 벗어나자…CIO가 끊어야 할 7가지 익숙함]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135040/%eb%b0%b1%ec%98%a4%ed%94%bc%ec%8a%a4-it%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%eb%b2%97%ec%96%b4%eb%82%98%ec%9e%90cio%ea%b0%80-%eb%81%8a%ec%96%b4%ec%95%bc-%ed%95%a0-7%ea%b0%80%ec%a7%80-%ec%9d%b5%ec%88%99.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135040/%eb%b0%b1%ec%98%a4%ed%94%bc%ec%8a%a4-it%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%eb%b2%97%ec%96%b4%eb%82%98%ec%9e%90cio%ea%b0%80-%eb%81%8a%ec%96%b4%ec%95%bc-%ed%95%a0-7%ea%b0%80%ec%a7%80-%ec%9d%b5%ec%88%99.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>CIO의 역할은 끊임없이 진화하고 있다. 오늘날 IT 리더가 다양한 고객, 파트너, 벤더 등 비즈니스 중심 이해관계자와 일상적으로 교류하는 모습이 이를 보여준다. 그럼에도 일부 C레벨 경영진이 CIO를 여전히 전형적인 백오피스 운영 책임자로 인식하면서, 이런 낡은 시각은 쉽게 사라지지 않고 있다.</p> <p>그렇다면 CIO는 진정한 전면 리더로 자리매김하기 위해 어떤 노력을 해야 할까? 다음은 백오피스 이미지를 완전히 벗어나는 데 도움이 될 7가지 전략이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="1-%ec%a0%84%ec%82%ac-%ec%b0%a8%ec%9b%90%ec%9d%98-%ed%98%91%ec%97%85-%ec%97%ad%eb%9f%89-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94">1. 전사 차원의 협업 역량 강화</h2> <p>오디오 제품 기업 슈어(Shure)의 CTO 샘 사벳은 백오피스 사고방식은 CIO를 전략적 생산성과 혁신을 이끄는 주체가 아닌, 단순히 시스템을 안정적으로 운영하는 역할에 머물게 만든다고 설명했다. 사벳은 슈어의 후원을 받아 시장조사업체 IDC가 진행한 최근 연구를 인용하며, 백오피스 중심 IT 마인드를 가진 CIO는 협업과 업무 환경 경험에 대한 투자를 과소평가하는 경향이 있다고 전했다.</p> <p>사벳은 “이 경우 협업은 단순히 있으면 좋은 요소로 간주되고, 그 결과 조직은 IT 투자를 실제 ROI로 연결하는 데 어려움을 겪게 된다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>성공적인 CIO는 사업부 리더와 긴밀히 협력해 기술이 구체적인 성과와 연결되도록 한다고 사벳은 설명했다. 또한 HR과 업무 환경 팀과 적극적으로 협업해 직원 경험을 깊이 이해하고, 협업을 하나의 생태계로 이해하는 기술 파트너와 함께 일한다고 밝혔다.</p> <p>사벳은 “부서 경계를 넘는 협업을 적극적으로 수용하는 조직일수록 경쟁사 대비 더 뛰어난 성과를 낼 가능성이 높다”라고 분석했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="2-%eb%b9%84%ec%a6%88%eb%8b%88%ec%8a%a4-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc-%ec%a4%91%ec%8b%ac%ec%9d%98-%eb%a6%ac%eb%8d%94%ec%8b%ad-%eb%b0%9c%ed%9c%98">2. 비즈니스 성과 중심의 리더십 발휘</h2> <p>기술 리서치 및 자문 기업 ISG의 파트너 <a href="https://isg-one.com/about-us/people/ola-chowning" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">올라 차우닝</a>은 IT가 구체적인 비즈니스 가치를 창출하는 경험에 집중하지 않고, 일반적인 사용자 경험 관점에서 단순 지원 기능이자 비용센터로만 운영될 때 백오피스화가 발생한다고 설명했다.</p> <p>차우닝은 백오피스 사고방식을 가진 CIO는 혁신이나 비즈니스 성과 개선, 전략적 파트너로서의 역할보다 시스템 안정성, 장애 대응, 가동 시간 유지에 더 큰 관심을 두는 경향이 있다고 진단했다. 또한 이러한 조직은 인프라와 애플리케이션이 분리된 구조를 갖고 있으며, 엔드투엔드 책임 체계나 성과 중심 관점이 부족한 기능적 분절이 특징이라고 분석했다.</p> <p>차우닝은 “이 같은 환경에서는 CIO가 전략 논의에 지속적으로 참여하기보다, 단순히 요청을 처리하는 ‘오더 테이커’ 역할에 머물게 된다”라며 “기술이 기업의 방향성과 전략을 어떻게 지원할 수 있을지 논의하는 자리에 안정적으로 참여하지 못하게 된다”라고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="3-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85-%ec%a0%84%eb%b0%98%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%ec%98%81%ed%96%a5%eb%a0%a5-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94">3. 기업 전반에서 영향력 강화</h2> <p>PR 기업 엠부스(M Booth)의 CTO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alfredobernal/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">알프레도 베르날</a>은 백오피스 IT 사고방식이 기술을 성장과 경쟁 우위의 동력이 아닌, 가동 시간과 티켓 처리, 비용 통제에 초점을 둔 지원 기능으로 인식하게 만든다고 설명했다. 베르날은 “이 모델에서는 성공의 기준이 비즈니스 성과가 아니라 안정성과 리스크 회피에 맞춰져 있다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>이 같은 사고방식이 초래하는 위험은 적지 않다. 베르날은 “섀도우 IT와 단편화된 도구가 확산되고, 경쟁사는 자동화와 AI를 적극 도입해 더 빠르게 움직이게 된다”라며 “그 사이 CIO는 경영진 회의에서 점차 영향력을 잃게 된다”라고 전했다. 시간이 지날수록 IT는 전략적 파트너가 아닌 비용센터로 인식되고, 그 결과 예산 심의나 조직 개편 과정에서 더욱 취약한 위치에 놓이게 된다.</p> <p>따라서 CIO는 비즈니스 중심 IT로의 전환을 추진하는 데 그치지 않고, 기업 전반에서 자신의 영향력을 높일 수 있는 방안을 적극적으로 모색해야 한다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="4-%ea%b2%bd%ec%9f%81%eb%a0%a5-%ed%99%95%eb%b3%b4">4. 경쟁력 확보</h2> <p>소프트웨어 개발 기업 유리스틱(Euristiq)의 CTO <a href="https://euristiq.com/author/pavlotkhir/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">파블로 트키르</a>는 백오피스 IT 사고에서 벗어나기 위해서는 기술을 경쟁 우위의 원천으로 인식해야 한다고 설명했다. 그렇지 않으면 IT는 여전히 비즈니스 혁신보다 ‘운영 유지’ 중심의 목표와 지표에만 집중하게 된다는 지적이다.</p> <p>트키르는 “고객 영향이나 성장 가능성보다 리스크 최소화와 비용 절감만을 기준으로 IT 의사결정을 내리는 기업을 여러 차례 봤다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>백오피스 마인드의 징후는 CIO 조직에서 비교적 뚜렷하게 나타난다. 비즈니스 성과 대신 가동 시간과 SLA에 집중하고, 제품 논의에 참여하지 않으며, 실험을 두려워하고, ‘아직 준비되지 않았다’는 태도가 만연해 있다는 설명이다. 트키르는 이러한 상황이 지속되면 결국 사업 부문이 IT를 우회하게 되고, 외부 벤더와 서로 다른 솔루션이 난립하는 결과로 이어진다고 분석했다. 그 결과 보안 리스크와 비용, 기술 부채가 증가하고 IT의 신뢰도도 떨어지게 된다.</p> <p>트키르는 CEO와 제품 리더, 엔지니어링 팀도 CIO가 올바른 방향으로 전환하는 데 중요한 역할을 할 수 있다고 밝혔다. 특히 IT가 기능 출시 속도, 매출 기여도, 고객 유지율 등 비즈니스 언어로 소통하기 시작할 때 변화의 계기가 마련된다고 설명했다. 그는 “백오피스 사고로 되돌아가지 않으려면 IT를 기업 전략에 통합하고, 서버나 티켓이 아닌 비즈니스 성과 기준으로 기여도를 지속적으로 측정해야 한다”라고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="5-%ec%99%b8%eb%b6%80%eb%a1%9c-%ec%8b%9c%ec%95%bc-%ed%99%95%ec%9e%a5">5. 외부로 시야 확장</h2> <p>카네기멜론대 하인즈 칼리지(Heinz College)의 임원 교육 강사 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sumeet-chabria-a683617/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">수밋 차브리아</a>는 많은 CIO가 의미 있는 비즈니스 성과 달성보다 체크리스트 완료 여부와 프로세스 이행에 따라 성공을 판단하는 내부 지향적 사고에 머무는 경우가 많다고 설명했다.</p> <p>차브리아는 “IT가 비즈니스 우선순위와 연결되지 않은 채 ‘기술을 위한 기술’에 집중하며 사일로처럼 운영될 때 이런 현상이 나타난다”라며 “CIO가 비즈니스 임원과 시간을 보내지 않으면, 비즈니스 조직도 IT를 파트너가 아닌 벤더처럼 대하게 된다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>AI와 디지털 경제 환경에서 백오피스 사고방식은 조직의 존속 자체를 위협할 수 있는 요소라고 차브리아는 경고했다. 그는 “백오피스 마인드는 성과가 아닌 규정 준수 여부에 따라 승진이 결정되는 문화를 만든다”라며 “이는 브랜드 가치를 훼손하고, 자신의 업무가 회사의 성공과 어떻게 연결되는지 보지 못한 핵심 인재가 조직을 떠나게 만드는 요인이 된다”라고 분석했다.</p> <p>진정한 전면 리더로 자리매김하려면 높은 수준의 비즈니스 이해력이 필요하다고 차브리아는 밝혔다. 차브리아는 “CIO는 CEO만큼 핵심 가치 동인과 손익계산서(P&amp;L)를 이해해야 한다”라고 말했다. 또한 CIO는 기업 전체를 바라보는 관점을 갖춰야 하며, 보상을 비즈니스 성과와 연계하면 조직이 올바른 방향으로 움직이도록 유도할 수 있다고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="6-%ec%a1%b0%ec%a7%81-%ec%9a%b4%ec%98%81-%eb%b0%a9%ec%8b%9d%ea%b3%bc%ec%9d%98-%ec%a0%95%eb%a0%ac">6. 조직 운영 방식과의 정렬</h2> <p>루시드 소프트웨어(Lucid Software)의 기술 및 보안 부사장 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-torgerson-lucid/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">데이비드 토거슨</a>은 IT가 매출과 생산성을 이끄는 전략적 동력이 아니라 유지보수와 리스크 회피, 내부 지원에 집중하는 비용센터로 인식될 때 백오피스 사고방식이 자리 잡는다고 설명했다.</p> <p>토거슨은 “이러한 환경에서는 IT 의사결정이 사후 대응적이고 규정 준수 중심으로 이뤄지며, 비즈니스 성과와 단절되는 경우가 많다”라며 “보안, AI, 인프라 투자가 성장의 핵심 도구가 아니라 단순히 체크리스트를 채우는 항목처럼 취급된다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>이 같은 흐름을 바로잡기 위해서는 IT 내부 노력만으로는 부족하다고 토거슨은 지적했다. 토거슨은 “CIO는 조직 전반의 팀과 긴밀히 협력해 실제 업무 흐름에 기반해 의사결정을 내리고, 리스크를 식별하고 대응하는 데 실제로 얼마나 시간이 소요되는지 측정해야 한다”라고 조언했다.</p> <p>또한 리스크와 기대 효과를 함께 따져 묻는 질문을 던질 필요가 있다고 제안했다. 토거슨은 “이는 ‘아무것도 신뢰하지 않는다’는 접근에서 벗어나, 현대적 협업 환경을 반영한 명확한 검증 프로세스로 전환하는 것을 의미한다”라고 설명했다. 아울러 산업 인증도 수요와 성숙도, 실질적 가치에 따라 재평가해야 하며, 단일 활용 사례만으로는 투자를 정당화할 수 없다는 점을 인식해야 한다고 밝혔다. 토거슨은 “조직이 실제로 운영되는 방식과 IT 전략을 정렬하는 것이 무엇보다 중요하다”라고 말했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="7-%eb%b9%84%ec%a6%88%eb%8b%88%ec%8a%a4-%ea%b0%90%ea%b0%81-%ea%b0%95%ed%99%94">7. 비즈니스 감각 강화</h2> <p>벤더 중립 교육 및 자격 인증을 제공하는 비영리 무역 단체 컴퓨팅기술산업협회(CompTIA)의 최고 기술 에반젤리스트 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesstanger/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">제임스 스탱어</a>는 동료가 CIO를 ‘기술 담당자’로만 인식해 비즈니스 활동에 포함하지 않는다면 이는 분명한 경고 신호라고 말했다.</p> <p>스탱어는 최근 호주의 한 대형 은행이 데이터 수집 프로젝트를 추진하면서 기술적 구현에만 초점을 맞춘 사례를 직접 목격했다고 전했다. 스탱어는 “해당 CIO는 프로젝트의 비즈니스 요구를 충분히 이해하기 위한 조치를 취하지 못했다고 인정했다”라며 “그 결과 프로젝트는 고객 기대를 충분히 충족하지 못했다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>CIO는 스스로를 고객 중심의 가드레일, 즉 안전장치 같은 존재로 인식해야 한다고 스탱어는 제안했다. 스탱어는 “동료가 고객 관점에서 사고하지 못하는 모습을 발견하면, 그들이 올바른 사고방식으로 전환하도록 유도할 수 있는 제도적 장치를 마련해야 한다”라고 말했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[“기존 방식은 한계에 다다랐다”···AI 수요 및 비용 급등에 기업은 가상화 전략 전면 재검토 중]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135036/%ea%b8%b0%ec%a1%b4-%eb%b0%a9%ec%8b%9d%ec%9d%80-%ed%95%9c%ea%b3%84%ec%97%90-%eb%8b%a4%eb%8b%a4%eb%9e%90%eb%8b%a4%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7ai-%ec%88%98%ec%9a%94-%eb%b0%8f-%eb%b9%84%ec%9a%a9.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135036/%ea%b8%b0%ec%a1%b4-%eb%b0%a9%ec%8b%9d%ec%9d%80-%ed%95%9c%ea%b3%84%ec%97%90-%eb%8b%a4%eb%8b%a4%eb%9e%90%eb%8b%a4%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7ai-%ec%88%98%ec%9a%94-%eb%b0%8f-%eb%b9%84%ec%9a%a9.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>비용 예측의 불확실성과 AI 준비도에 대한 우려로 많은 IT 리더가 가상화 전략을 대대적으로 변경할 계획인 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>HPE의 최근 <a href="https://www.hpe.com/us/en/solutions/cloud.html?slug=a00155927enw&amp;x=MHm9Z2&amp;pf_route=uccldfav" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">설문조사</a>에 따르면, IT 의사결정권자 3분의 2가 향후 2년 내 가상화 배포 환경을 재정비할 계획이라고 밝혔다. 그러나 실제로 조직 차원에서 변화에 대비가 돼 있다고 답한 비율은 5%에 그쳤다.</p> <p>HPE가 ‘대규모 가상화 재편’이라고 칭한 이번 흐름의 배경에는 비용 문제가 있다. 2023년 말 브로드컴(Broadcom)이 <a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3604503/vmware-makes-workstation-and-fusion-free-for-everyone.html" target="_blank">VM웨어(VMware)</a>를 인수한 이후 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2093486/vmware-customers-take-wait-and-see-approach-amid-broadcom-changes.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank">라이선스 비용이 인상</a>되면서 일부 조직은 ‘<a href="https://www.cio.com/article/2513749/will-vmwares-licensing-changes-push-devirtualization-of-data-centers.html?utm=hybrid_search" target="_blank">탈가상화</a>’를 검토하기 시작했다. 다만 설문에 참여한 조직의 절반 이상은 여전히 VM웨어를 주력 가상화 플랫폼으로 운영하고 있는 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>설문에 따르면 VM웨어의 가격 인상에 더해, 올해 클라우드 비용이 예상보다 높게 집행되고 있다는 점도 IT 리더의 부담으로 작용하고 있다.</p> <p>HPE 하이브리드 클라우드 부문 COO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hangtan/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">행 탄</a>은 “가상화 비용이 사실상 5배로 뛰었고, 동시에 AI 투자와 급여 체계 현대화까지 추진해야 하는 상황이라 기업은 감당하기 어려운 비용 부담을 떠안게 됐다. 이제 모두가 대안을 찾고 있다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>다만 HPE는 이런 움직임의 이면에, 기업이 AI 시대에 걸맞은 인프라를 갖추고 있는지에 대한 근본적인 고민과, 클라우드에서 운영 중인 가상머신 구조가 AI 워크로드를 제대로 감당할 수 있는지에 대한 의문이 있다고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ea%b0%80%ec%83%81%eb%a8%b8%ec%8b%a0%ea%b3%bc-%ed%81%b4%eb%9d%bc%ec%9a%b0%eb%93%9c%eb%a5%bc-%eb%8f%99%ec%8b%9c%ec%97%90-%ec%9e%ac%ec%84%a4%ea%b3%84">가상머신과 클라우드를 동시에 재설계</h2> <p>많은 IT 리더가 AI에 최적화된 가상화 역량을 원하고 있다. 동시에 AI와 가상화가 어떤 방식으로 결합해야 하는지를 고민하며 기존 <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4015769/%EC%8B%A4%ED%97%98-%EB%81%9D%EB%82%9C-ai%EB%8A%94-%EB%8B%A4%EC%8B%9C-%EC%98%A8%ED%94%84%EB%A0%88%EB%AF%B8%EC%8A%A4%EB%A1%9C-%ED%8D%BC%EB%B8%94%EB%A6%AD-%ED%81%B4%EB%9D%BC%EC%9A%B0.html" target="_blank">클라우드 컴퓨팅 환경</a> 전반을 다시 들여다보고 있다.</p> <p>AI 비용을 통제하고 워크로드를 면밀히 모니터링하며 벤더 종속을 피하려는 요구가 커지면서, 하이브리드 클라우드 환경에 대한 수요도 빠르게 증가했다고 탄은 설명했다. 조사에 따르면 IT 리더는 가상화와 클라우드 환경을 현대화하는 과정에서 통합 백업, 크로스 플랫폼 거버넌스, 통합 옵저버빌리티와 같은 기능도 함께 요구 중인 것으로 나타났다.</p> <p>탄은 비용 부담과 AI 현대화 과제가 맞물리는 지금이 IT 리더가 기존 가상화 스택을 원점에서 다시 점검할 기회일 수 있다고 분석했다. 그는 “위기 속에도 기회는 있다”라며 “CIO 입장에서는 ‘이제 전략을 다시 설계할 수 있는 시점이 왔다’고 판단할 수 있다”라고 말했다. 이어 “대부분의 IT 리더는 그동안 하나의 스택과 운영 모델로 표준화해 왔지만, 해결해야 할 과제가 있다는 사실도 알고 있었다”라고 설명했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai%ea%b0%80-%eb%b0%94%ea%be%b8%eb%8a%94-%ea%b0%80%ec%83%81%eb%a8%b8%ec%8b%a0%ec%9d%98-%ec%97%ad%ed%95%a0">AI가 바꾸는 가상머신의 역할</h2> <p>IT 서비스 및 애플리케이션 개발 기업 탭포스(Tapforce)의 설립자 겸 CTO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/balabanskyy/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">아르투르 발라반스키</a>는 AI가 기존 가상화 활용 방식을 근본적으로 뒤흔들고 있다고 진단했다.</p> <p>발라반스키는 “AI 워크로드는 GPU 의존도가 높고 수요 예측이 어렵다. 한 번 용량을 산정해 가상머신을 구성한 뒤 그대로 운영하던 기존 모델은 더 이상 통하지 않는다. 기업은 전면적인 가상화가 과연 필요한지, 아니면 더 가벼운 계층이 AI 기반 프로젝트에 더 적합한지 고민하기 시작했다”라고 설명했다.</p> <p>그는 기존 가상화 플랫폼이 CPU 중심 구조이며 비교적 안정적인 수요를 전제로 설계된 반면, AI 워크로드는 메모리 사용량이 크고 GPU에 크게 의존하며 지연 시간에도 민감하다고 분석했다. 발라반스키는 “추상화 계층은 비용과 성능 저하를 유발하고, 모델이 실제 대규모로 확장되는 순간 문제가 본격적으로 드러난다. 미래 수요를 예측하고 설계하는 역할을 맡은 이들에게는 전혀 새로운 환경”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>냉난방 및 데이터센터 부품 제조 기업 댄포스(Danfoss)의 CIO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sune-tornbo-baastrup-3950402/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">수네 바스트럽</a>은 비용 문제를 넘어, 가상화와 AI가 ‘양질의 데이터 확보’라는 지점에서 맞닿아 있다고 설명했다. 그에 따르면 댄포스는 최근 데이터 이동성과 유연성에 초점을 맞춰 가상화 기술 전반을 재평가했다.</p> <p>바스트럽은 “가상화는 단순히 하나의 물리 서버에서 자원을 더 효율적으로 활용하는 수준을 넘어선다. 앞으로 등장할 훨씬 더 역동적인 사용례에 대비하는 과정이다. 많은 워크로드가 중앙에서 분산된 위치로, 나아가 엣지로 이동하게 될 것”이라고 말했다.</p> <p>그는 댄포스에서 AI를 도입함에 따라 가상화와 데이터 전략 역시 진화해야 할 것이라고 내다봤다. 그는 “AI에서 실질적인 가치를 끌어내기 위해 핵심적으로 요구되는 것은 결국 양질의 데이터에 대한 접근성”이라고 강조했다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%a0%9c%ec%95%bd-%ec%9a%94%ec%9d%b8">제약 요인</h2> <p>설문에 따르면 가상화 전략을 바꾸는 과정에는 여러 걸림돌이 존재한다. 응답자의 4분의 1 이상은 예산 제약이 핵심 걸림돌이라고 답했다. 또한 약 4분의 1은 기술 복잡성, 마이그레이션 리스크, 역량 격차를 주요 장벽으로 지목했다.</p> <p>바스트럽은 IT 조직 차원의 준비 부족도 또 다른 장벽이라면서, CIO의 역할 중 하나가 벤더나 기술을 변경해야 하는 이유를 내부에 설득하는 것이라고 설명했다.</p> <p>그는 “CIO가 결국 고민해야 할 질문은 ‘이미 시장에 나와 있는 기술을 어떻게 받아들일 준비를 할 것인가, 그리고 AI 혁신 사례가 현실화되는 시점에 함께할 파트너를 어떻게 찾을 것인가’다”라고 말했다.</p> <p>발라반스키는 예산과 역량 부족, 변화에 대한 두려움 역시 가상화 전환의 제약 요인이라고 분석했다. 발라반스키는 “대규모 전환은 이론적으로 타당해 보여도 비용이 크고 조직에 혼란을 초래한다. 팀은 현재 운영 중인 환경에 익숙하고, 이를 재교육하거나 대체하는 데에는 실제 위험이 따른다. 결국 내부 의사결정에서는 가격과 안정성이 우선순위를 차지하는 경우가 많다”라고 밝혔다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ec%8b%a0%ec%a4%91%ed%95%9c-%ec%a0%91%ea%b7%bc-%ed%95%84%ec%9a%94">신중한 접근 필요</h2> <p>가상화 전환에 여러 제약 요인이 존재하는 만큼, HPE는 IT 리더의 속도 조절이 필요하다고 조언했다. 탄은 모든 워크로드를 한번에 새로운 업체로 옮길 필요는 없다고 설명했다.</p> <p>탄은 “비용이 오르니 가능한 한 빨리 이전해야 한다는 반응이 나올 수 있다. 그러나 지금은 전략을 다시 설계할 기회인 만큼 충분히 고민하고 접근해야 한다. HPE 고객에게도 서두르지 말 것을 권하고 있다”라고 전했다.</p> <p>IT 서비스 기업 스라이브(Thrive)의 COO 스콧 스틸은 새로운 가상화 솔루션이 전체 IT 환경에 어떻게 들어맞는지 종합적으로 검토해야 한다고 강조했다. 가상화가 더 큰 IT 전환 논의의 한 축인 만큼 AI와 향후 수요를 중심에 두고 접근해야 한다는 설명이다.</p> <p>스틸은 “AI 역량을 갖춘 새로운 기술과 인프라를 앞세운 신규 벤더가 잇따라 등장하고 있다. 지금은 과거의 환경에 맞추는 것이 아니라, 앞으로 전개될 방향에 대비해 전체 인프라를 점검해야 할 시기”라고 조언했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[아웃시스템즈 기고 | 한국 기업의 AI 전환을 좌우할 에이전틱 AI 도입 전략 3가지]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135019/%ec%95%84%ec%9b%83%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%85%9c%ec%a6%88-%ea%b8%b0%ea%b3%a0-%ed%95%9c%ea%b5%ad-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85%ec%9d%98-ai-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9d%84-%ec%a2%8c%ec%9a%b0%ed%95%a0-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135019/%ec%95%84%ec%9b%83%ec%8b%9c%ec%8a%a4%ed%85%9c%ec%a6%88-%ea%b8%b0%ea%b3%a0-%ed%95%9c%ea%b5%ad-%ea%b8%b0%ec%97%85%ec%9d%98-ai-%ec%a0%84%ed%99%98%ec%9d%84-%ec%a2%8c%ec%9a%b0%ed%95%a0-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>국내에서도 이러한 변화는 이미 체감되고 있다. 작년 8월 공개된<a href="https://www.bok.or.kr/portal/bbs/P0002353/view.do?nttId=10093071&amp;searchCnd=1&amp;searchKwd=&amp;depth=201150&amp;pageUnit=10&amp;pageIndex=1&amp;programType=newsData&amp;menuNo=200433&amp;oldMenuNo=201150" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"> 한국은행 보고서에 따르면</a> 국내 근로자의 63.5%가 생성형 AI를 사용한 경험이 있으며, 절반 이상은 실제 업무에 활용하고 있다고 답했다. 반면 이러한 확산 속도와 달리, AI를 핵심 비즈니스 프로세스에까지 성공적으로 내재화한 기업은 여전히 소수에 불과하다. ‘도입’과 ‘운영’ 사이의 간극이 본격적으로 드러나는 지점이다.</p> <p>이 간극을 메우는 새로운 패러다임으로 주목받는 개념이 바로 에이전틱 AI(Agentic AI)다. 단순히 프롬프트에 반응하는 도구가 아니라, 사용자의 의도 파악·계획·결과 검증·반복 수행까지 가능한 목적 기반의 자율성을 제공한다. 아웃시스템즈가 선보인 ‘에이전트 워크벤치(Agent Workbench)’ 역시 이러한 원칙을 바탕으로 여러 특화된 AI 에이전트들이 복잡한 개발·운영 전반에 걸쳐 협력하도록 지원한다.</p> <p>이미 산업별 초기 도입 사례들은 가시적 효과를 보여주고 있다. 반복 업무 자동화는 물론, 미션 크리티컬한 애플리케이션 개발 가속, 검증 과정의 자동화까지 결과가 다양하게 나타나고 있다. 그리고 하나의 공통점이 도출된다. 에이전틱 AI는 독립형 기능이 아니라 기존 프로세스에 자연스럽게 녹아들 때 가장 큰 가치를 만든다는 것이다.</p> <p>그렇다면 한국 기업이 에이전틱 AI를 효과적으로 구현하기 위해 무엇을 우선적으로 고려해야 할까?</p> <p>핵심은 세 가지 원칙으로 정리된다.</p> <p>첫 번째는, 기술 선정보다 ‘문제 정의’를 우선하는 것이다. 많은 AI 프로젝트가 기대에 미치지 못하는 이유는 모델의 성능 한계 때문이 아니라, 해결해야 할 실제 비효율·병목·리스크가 명확히 규정되지 않았기 때문이다. AI를 가장 효과적으로 활용하기 위해서는, 어떤 영역에서 에이전트가 실질적으로 가장 높은 임팩트를 낼 수 있는지 선명하게 규명하는 것이 성공의 출발점이 된다.</p> <p>두 번째는, 기존 워크플로와의 ‘마찰 없는 통합’이다. 에이전틱 AI는 직원들이 이미 익숙하게 사용하는 도구와 시스템 안에서 작동할 때 가장 높은 효율을 낸다. 인터페이스나 프로세스를 대폭 변경하면 오히려 도입 속도가 느려지고 조직 내 저항이 생길 수 있다. 반대로, 에이전트 오케스트레이션을 기존 생태계에 자연스럽게 얹는 방식은 강력한 자동화와 인사이트를 제공하면서도 불필요한 변화를 최소화한다. 에이전트 워크벤치(Agent Workbench)가 기존 워크플로 안에서 여러 에이전트의 협업을 가능하게 설계된 이유도 여기에 있다.</p> <p>세 번째는, 신뢰와 거버넌스를 ‘선행 조건’으로 두는 것이다. 기업 환경에서 데이터의 민감도와 규모가 커질수록 AI 에이전트의 자율성에는 투명성이 반드시 수반돼야 한다. 데이터 경계 설정, 접근 권한 관리, 버저닝, 감사 추적 기능은 선택이 아니라 필수다. 즉, 거버넌스는 도입 후에 붙이는 안전장치가 아니라, 전사적 확장을 위한 전제 조건이어야 한다.</p> <p>에이전틱 AI 개념에 익숙하지 않은 사용자에게는 기술적 구조를 설명하기보다, 에이전트가 수행하는 역할과 해결하는 문제, 기대되는 성과를 명확히 보여주는 방식이 실제 이해에 더 도움이 된다. 사용자는 AI를 ‘블랙박스’가 아닌, 자신의 업무를 보완하고 확장시키는 목적 기반의 협업자로 받아들이게 된다.</p> <p>에이전틱 AI는 기업의 개발, 운영, 서비스 전반을 재정의할 잠재력을 지니고 있다. 그러나 그 성공 여부는 기술 자체보다 전략, 통합, 신뢰에 달려 있다. 지금 한국 기업이 던져야 할 질문은 “AI를 도입할 것인가?”가 아니라, “에이전틱 AI를 어떻게 제대로 구현할 것인가?”다.</p> <p>이 질문에 명확한 해답을 가지고 실행하는 기업이 다음 단계의 디지털 전환을 선도하게 될 것이다.</p> <p><em>*필자 안세준 아웃시스템즈 코리아 지사장은 한국 내 사업을 총괄하며, 국내 비즈니스 개발과 고객 및 파트너 생태계 강화를 통해 다양한 산업 분야에서 AI 기반 로우코드 디지털 전환을 이끌고 있다. IT 업계에서 20년 이상의 경력을 쌓은 안세준 지사장은 아웃시스템즈 합류 이전 카토 네트웍스(Cato Networks), 지니어(Zinier), 스플렁크(Splunk), 팁코(TIBCO), GXS, 마이크로스트래티지(MicroStrategy), 오라클(Oracle), PGi 등 글로벌 소프트웨어 및 클라우드 기업에서 근무하며 관련 경험을 쌓았다.</em><br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p> <p><br><br></p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[“AI 안 쓰면 승진 없다” 액센추어, 고위직 인사 평가에 AI 활용 연동]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135028/ai-%ec%95%88-%ec%93%b0%eb%a9%b4-%ec%8a%b9%ec%a7%84-%ec%97%86%eb%8b%a4-%ec%95%a1%ec%84%bc%ec%b6%94%ec%96%b4-%ea%b3%a0%ec%9c%84%ec%a7%81-%ec%9d%b8%ec%82%ac-%ed%8f%89%ea%b0%80%ec%97%90.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135028/ai-%ec%95%88-%ec%93%b0%eb%a9%b4-%ec%8a%b9%ec%a7%84-%ec%97%86%eb%8b%a4-%ec%95%a1%ec%84%bc%ec%b6%94%ec%96%b4-%ea%b3%a0%ec%9c%84%ec%a7%81-%ec%9d%b8%ec%82%ac-%ed%8f%89%ea%b0%80%ec%97%90.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ac672f97-a603-4c56-afa3-4a5273d45674" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">파이낸셜타임스(FT)</a> 보도에 따르면 액센추어는 최근 내부 이메일을 통해 고위 관리자 직책에 있는 직원들에게 “임원으로 승진하기 위해서는 AI 도구의 ‘정기적 사용’이 필요하다”라고 통보했다.</p> <p>액센추어는 이를 공식 확인하며 “고객을 가장 효과적으로 지원하기 위해서는 최신 도구와 기술의 채택이 필수적”이라고 밝혔다. 실제로 액센추어는 일부 고위 직원들을 대상으로 AI 도구의 주간 로그인 데이터를 수집하며 사용 여부를 추적하고 있는 것으로 알려졌다. </p> <p>모니터링 대상에는 자사 플랫폼인 ‘AI 리파이너리(AI Refinery)’가 포함된다. 이 플랫폼은 기업이 업무 프로세스를 재설계하고 AI 솔루션을 전사적으로 확장할 수 있도록 지원하는 통합 도구다.</p> <p>다만 유럽 12개국과 미국 정부 계약을 담당하는 부서 직원은 이번 정책의 영향을 받지 않을 전망이다.</p> <p>액센추어 CEO 줄리 스위트는 지난해 9월 실적 발표에서 “모든 직원에게 대규모 재교육과 재정비가 필요하다. 필요 역량을 갖추지 못한 인력은 조직을 떠나게 될 것”이라고 밝히며 구조조정 가능성을 시사한 바 있다.</p> <p>액센추어는 이미 대규모 AI 재교육에 착수했으며, 현재까지 전체 직원 78만 명 중 55만 명이 생성형 AI 기본 교육을 이수했다. 직원 교육을 위해 오픈AI, 앤트로픽, 팔란티어 등 기업과 협력 중인 것으로 알려졌다.</p> <p>특히 액센추어는 AI 컨설팅 서비스 업체로 구조를 재편하기 위해 지난해 전략, 컨설팅, 기술, 크리에이티브, 운영 부문을 ‘리인벤션 서비스(Reinvention Services)’라는 단일 조직으로 통합하고, 직원들을 ‘리인벤터(Reinventor)’로 칭하고 있다.<br>yuseong.kim@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[칼럼 | 오픈소스가 AI 시대의 ‘치트키’가 될 이유]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135023/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%ec%98%a4%ed%94%88%ec%86%8c%ec%8a%a4%ea%b0%80-ai-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80%ec%9d%98-%ec%b9%98%ed%8a%b8%ed%82%a4%ea%b0%80-%eb%90%a0-%ec%9d%b4%ec%9c%a0.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4135023/%ec%b9%bc%eb%9f%bc-%ec%98%a4%ed%94%88%ec%86%8c%ec%8a%a4%ea%b0%80-ai-%ec%8b%9c%eb%8c%80%ec%9d%98-%ec%b9%98%ed%8a%b8%ed%82%a4%ea%b0%80-%eb%90%a0-%ec%9d%b4%ec%9c%a0.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>대규모 언어 모델(LLM)의 경쟁 구도는 하루가 다르게 바뀌고 있다. GPT-5.1, 클로드 4.4, 제미나이 3 프로는 불과 몇 달 전까지만 해도 최첨단으로 평가받던 모델의 성능을 이미 넘어섰다. 상용 AI가 빠르게 고도화되면서 기업 리더 사이에서는 같은 질문이 반복되고 있다. 이를 실제 업무에 어떻게 활용할 것인가다. 빠르게 움직이려는 기업에 그 해답은 오픈소스일 수 있다.</p> <p>현장에서는 전 세계 수천만 명의 데이터 엔지니어, 데이터 과학자, 분석가가 오픈텔레메트리(OpenTelemetry), 프로메테우스(Prometheus), 리눅스(Linux), 쿠버네티스(Kubernetes), 아파치 스파크(Apache Spark) 같은 오픈소스 기술을 중심으로 긴밀히 협업하고 있다. 이들은 블로그, 영상, 깃 리포지토리, 각종 공개 문서를 통해 토론을 이어가고, 모범 사례를 공유하며 API와 대시보드를 교환한다. 이 활동은 폐쇄형 플랫폼이 아닌 개방된 웹 환경에서 이뤄진다.</p> <p>결론적으로 최신 LLM은 개방형 생태계와 상호작용하는 방법을 이미 학습한 상태로 제공된다. 수천 건에 이르는 공개 사고 대응 보고서를 학습 데이터로 활용해, 오픈소스 프로젝트를 기반으로 전문가가 장애에 어떻게 대응하는지에 대한 맥락을 이해한다. 예를 들어 쿠버네티스 환경에서 ‘서비스를 스케일 업한다’는 표현이 어떤 조치를 의미하는지 정확히 파악하고, 해당 기술에 익숙하지 않은 직원이라면 혼란을 겪을 수 있는 작업도 곧바로 수행할 수 있다.</p> <p>이 같은 특성은 벤더와 고객 모두가 새로운 에이전틱 AI 기능을 보다 신속하게 활용하도록 돕는다. 가령 오픈소스 기반의 데이터 시각화 및 모니터링 플랫폼 그래파나(Grafana)의 경우 새로운 AI 에이전트 인터페이스를 며칠 만에 구축하고 확장할 수 있었다. 자사 오픈소스 시스템을 이해하고 상호작용하도록 LLM을 별도로 학습시킬 필요가 없었기 때문이다.</p> <p>물론 기업 기술 환경에서 만능 해법은 존재하지 않는다. 방대한 공개 문서 데이터를 학습한 모델이 그 안에 포함된 부정확하거나 부적절한 정보를 그대로 노출할 가능성도 배제할 수 없다. 비교적 최근 등장한 오픈소스 기술의 경우, 참고할 만한 콘텐츠의 양과 깊이가 충분하지 않은 점도 한계로 지적된다. 오픈소스 생태계의 힘이 커뮤니티에서 나오는 만큼, 현대 IT 스택의 핵심을 이루는 프로젝트를 떠받치는 커뮤니티를 지속적으로 지원해야 한다는 부담이 생길 수도 있다. 하지만 커뮤니티는 다양한 사례와 문서를 생산하며, 모델 학습에 활용되는 가치 있는 데이터를 만들어내는 ‘증폭 장치’ 역할을 하고 있다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="ai-%ec%95%95%eb%b0%95-%ec%86%8d%ec%97%90%ec%84%9c-%eb%b9%a0%eb%a5%b4%ea%b2%8c-%ec%84%b1%ea%b3%bc%eb%a5%bc-%eb%82%b4%eb%8a%94-%ec%84%a0%ed%83%9d%ec%a7%80%eb%a1%9c-%eb%96%a0%ec%98%a4%eb%a5%b8-%ec%98%a4">AI 압박 속에서 빠르게 성과를 내는 선택지로 떠오른 오픈소스</h2> <p>기업의 AI 청사진은 실제 도입 현실과 부딪히고 있다. 투자자의 기대에 직면한 기업은 속도를 중시할 수밖에 없다. 엔지니어, 계정 관리자, 마케팅 팀 등 다양한 구성원이 활용할 수 있는 챗봇형 인터페이스를 도입해 생산성과 효율성을 높이고, 이를 바탕으로 새로운 성장 기회를 만들어내려는 요구가 커지고 있다.</p> <p>기업의 <a href="https://www.pwc.com/us/en/tech-effect/ai-analytics/ai-agent-survey.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">거의 절반</a>이 경쟁사에 뒤처질 수 있다는 우려를 안고 있다는 조사 결과가 있다. 이 때문에 기업은 폭넓은 사용례를 지원하면서도 빠르게 도입할 수 있는 독립형 시스템을 찾고 있다. 필요할 경우 자사 고유의 도메인 특화 데이터를 활용해 성능을 높일 수 있는 유연성 역시 중요한 조건으로 떠오르고 있다.</p> <p>한편 오픈AI와 앤트로픽 등은 수백억 달러에 이르는 투자 자금과 세계 최고 수준의 AI 인재를 확보하고 있다. 상당수 기업은 이런 경쟁 구도를 따라잡기 어렵다. 데이터 중심 기업으로 평가받는 스노우플레이크조차도 더 이상 <a href="https://www.thestack.technology/snowflake-llms-training/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">모델 구축 경쟁</a>에 집중하지 않는 이유가 여기에 있다.</p> <p>그렇다고 해서 모든 벤더가 챗GPT-5, 그록 4 등 최신 LLM이 출시되자마자 곧바로 자사 시스템을 연결할 수 있는 것은 아니다. 현장에서는 별도의 통합 과정을 거치는 경우가 많다. 이때 기술 기업은 자사 독점 시스템의 구조와 작동 방식을 모델이 이해하도록 학습시키는 데 시간과 인력, 자원을 투입해야 한다.</p> <p>오픈소스나 SQL, JSON처럼 널리 사용되는 개방형 표준은 상황이 다르다. 사용 방법을 설명하는 가이드 문서와 포럼 게시글, 각종 튜토리얼 등 방대한 공개 콘텐츠가 이미 주요 기반 모델에 학습 데이터로 반영돼 있다. 물론 독점 소프트웨어 역시 공개 문서를 제공하지만, 그 규모는 상대적으로 제한적인 경우가 많다. 대부분의 모델 개발사가 활용하는 강화 학습을 충분히 뒷받침할 만큼 방대한 데이터가 축적되지 않은 것이다.</p> <p>오픈소스 커뮤니티의 영향력이 커진 지금, 벤더가 사용자 간 대화와 정보 공유를 적극적으로 지원하는 것이 어느 때보다 중요해졌다. 일상적인 업무 상호작용이 점차 에이전틱 AI 인터페이스 안에서 이뤄지고 있는 만큼, 관련 문서는 탄탄한 구조와 정확성, 신뢰성을 갖춰야 한다. 또한 상호운용성을 중시하는 오픈소스의 특성은 AI 에이전트가 여러 시스템을 아우르는 통합된 경험을 제공하는 데 유리하게 작용한다. 업계 일부 업체가 폐쇄형 생태계를 강화하더라도, 협업과 개방의 문화를 유지하고 확산하는 책임은 벤더에 있다.</p> <p>즉각적인 성과를 요구하는 시장 환경에서 오픈소스는 드문 경쟁력을 제공한다. 모델은 이미 이러한 도구를 이해하고 있으며, 커뮤니티는 그 활용 방식을 지속적으로 축적해 왔다. 더 적은 자원으로 더 빠른 혁신을 가능하게 한다는 의미다. CIO와 개발자에게 ‘치트키’는 단순히 AI 자체가 아니다. 개방형 시스템 위에 구축된 AI가 핵심이라는 점이 점차 분명해지고 있다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[AI 에이전트, 깃허브서 대량 PR로 신뢰 축적 중···공급망 공격 위험 커지나]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134993/ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ea%b9%83%ed%97%88%eb%b8%8c%ec%84%9c-%eb%8c%80%eb%9f%89-pr%eb%a1%9c-%ec%8b%a0%eb%a2%b0-%ec%b6%95%ec%a0%81-%ec%a4%91%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ea%b3%b5%ea%b8%89.html]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.cio.com/article/4134993/ai-%ec%97%90%ec%9d%b4%ec%a0%84%ed%8a%b8-%ea%b9%83%ed%97%88%eb%b8%8c%ec%84%9c-%eb%8c%80%eb%9f%89-pr%eb%a1%9c-%ec%8b%a0%eb%a2%b0-%ec%b6%95%ec%a0%81-%ec%a4%91%c2%b7%c2%b7%c2%b7%ea%b3%b5%ea%b8%89.html]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<div id="remove_no_follow"> <div class="grid grid--cols-10@md grid--cols-8@lg article-column"> <div class="col-12 col-10@md col-6@lg col-start-3@lg"> <div class="article-column__content">
<section class="wp-block-bigbite-multi-title"><div class="container"></div></section> <p>대규모 풀 리퀘스트(PR)를 오픈소스 프로젝트 유지관리자에게 제출할 수 있는 AI 에이전트가 향후 주요 소프트웨어 프로젝트를 겨냥한 공급망 공격의 토대를 만들 수 있다고 보안 기업 소켓(Socket)이 주장했다.</p> <p><a href="https://socket.dev/blog/ai-agent-lands-prs-in-major-oss-projects-targets-maintainers-via-cold-outreach" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">이번 주장</a>은 소켓 소속 개발자 놀란 로슨이 2월 초 자신이 유지관리하는 자바스크립트 데이터베이스 파우치DB(PouchDB)와 관련해 ‘카이 그리튼(Kai Gritun)’이라고 자칭한 AI 에이전트로부터 이메일을 받은 뒤 제기됐다.</p> <p>해당 이메일에는 “나는 자율형 AI 에이전트로, 단순히 대화만 하는 것이 아니라 실제로 코드를 작성하고 배포할 수 있다. 오픈클로(OpenClaw)에서 6건 이상의 PR이 병합됐으며, 영향력이 큰 프로젝트에 기여하고 싶다”라고 적혀 있었다. 이어 “파우치DB나 당신이 유지관리하는 다른 프로젝트의 미해결 이슈를 맡아볼 의향이 있느냐. 품질을 입증하기 위해 작은 작업부터 시작해도 좋다”라고 제안했다.</p> <p>조사를 진행한 결과, 카이 그리튼의 깃허브 프로필은 2월 1일 생성됐으며 며칠 사이 95개 저장소에 걸쳐 103건의 PR을 생성한 것으로 나타났다. 그 결과 22개 프로젝트에서 23건의 커밋이 이뤄졌다.</p> <p>PR을 받은 103개 프로젝트 중 상당수는 자바스크립트와 클라우드 생태계에서 핵심적인 역할을 하는, 산업 ‘핵심 인프라’에 해당하는 프로젝트였다. 실제로 개발 도구 Nx, ESLint용 유니콘 정적 코드 분석 플러그인, 자바스크립트 명령줄 인터페이스 Clack, 클라우드플레어 워커스 SDK 등에서 커밋이 반영됐거나 현재 검토가 진행 중이다.</p> <p>주목할 점은 카이 그리튼의 깃허브 프로필에 AI 에이전트라는 사실이 명시돼 있지 않았다는 점이다. 로슨이 이메일을 직접 받았기 때문에 해당 정체가 드러난 것이다.</p> <h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="%ed%8f%89%ed%8c%90-%ed%8c%8c%eb%b0%8d">평판 ‘파밍’</h2> <p>추가 분석 결과, 카이 그리튼은 오픈클로(OpenClaw) 개인용 AI 에이전트 플랫폼(구 몰트봇·클로디봇)의 설정과 운영, 유지관리를 지원하는 유료 서비스를 <a href="https://www.kaigritun.com/services" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">홍보하고 있는 것</a>으로 나타났다. 오픈클로는 최근 몇 주 사이 여러 이슈로 주목을 받아왔으며, 그중에는 부정적인 내용도 포함돼 있다.</p> <p>소켓에 따르면 이는 신뢰할 수 있는 기여자로 인식되기 위해 의도적으로 활동 이력을 만들어내는 전략으로 해석된다. 이른바 ‘평판 파밍(reputation farming)’다. 겉으로는 활발히 활동하는 것처럼 보이면서, 잘 알려진 프로젝트와의 연관성과 기여 이력을 동시에 쌓아 신뢰 기반을 구축하는 방식이다. 소켓은 카이 그리튼의 활동이 악의적이지 않았고 인간 검토를 통과했다는 사실이 이러한 전술의 구조적 의미를 가려서는 안 된다고 지적했다.</p> <p>소켓은 “순수하게 기술적인 관점에서 보면 오픈소스는 개선을 얻은 셈”이라며 “그러나 그 효율성을 얻는 대가로 무엇을 내주고 있는지 따져봐야 한다”고 분석했다. 이어 “해당 에이전트에 악의적 지시가 있었는지는 본질적인 문제가 아닐 수 있다”며 “신뢰는 빠르게 축적될 수 있고, 이는 영향력이나 수익으로 전환될 수 있다는 점이 분명하다”고 설명했다.</p> <p>일반적으로 신뢰를 쌓는 과정은 오랜 시간이 걸린다. 이는 악의적 행위자를 일정 부분 걸러내는 완충 장치로 작용해왔다. 2024년 발생한 XZ-유틸스 공급망 공격은 이를 역설적으로 보여주는 사례다. 국가 차원의 개입이 의심된 해당 사건에서 문제의 개발자 지아 탄은 유틸리티에 백도어를 삽입하기까지 수년간 평판을 축적해야 했다.</p> <p>그러나 소켓은 카이 그리튼 사례의 성공이 동일한 수준의 평판을 훨씬 짧은 시간 안에 구축할 수 있음을 시사한다고 평가했다. 이는 같은 AI 에이전트 기술을 활용해 공급망 공격을 더욱 빠르게 전개할 수 있는 가능성을 의미한다. 더구나 유지관리자가 인간이 쌓은 신뢰와 에이전트형 AI가 인위적으로 만들어낸 이력을 명확히 구분할 방법이 없다는 점도 문제로 지적됐다. AI 에이전트가 생성하는 대량의 PR을 처리하는 것 자체가 부담으로 작용할 수 있다는 분석이다.</p> <p>소켓은 “XZ-유틸스 백도어는 우연히 발견됐다”며 “다음 공급망 공격은 그렇게 분명한 흔적을 남기지 않을 수도 있다”고 경고했다.</p> <p>API 보안 기업 월람(Wallarm)의 AI 보안 총괄이자 업계 ‘에이전틱 AI 런타임 보안 및 자기방어(<a href="https://a2as.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">A2AS</a>)’ 프로젝트를 이끄는 <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mlsecops/?originalSubdomain=ae" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">유진 닐루</a>는 “소프트웨어 기여 행위 자체가 프로그래밍 가능한 영역으로 바뀌고 있다는 점이 중요한 변화”라고 평가했다.</p> <p>닐루는 “기여와 평판 구축이 자동화되면 공격 표면은 코드에서 이를 둘러싼 거버넌스 프로세스로 이동한다”며 “비공식적 신뢰나 유지관리자의 직관에 의존하는 프로젝트는 어려움을 겪을 수 있지만, 강력하고 집행 가능한 AI 거버넌스와 통제 체계를 갖춘 프로젝트는 회복력을 유지할 수 있다”고 짚었다.</p> <p>이어 “장기적인 해법은 AI 기여자를 금지하는 것이 아니라, 출처 검증과 정책 집행, 감사 가능한 기여 기록을 포함한 기계 검증 기반의 소프트웨어 변경 거버넌스를 도입하는 것”이라며 “AI에 대한 신뢰는 기여자의 의도를 추정하는 데서가 아니라, 검증 가능한 통제 장치에 기반해야 한다”고 설명했다.<br>dl-ciokorea@foundryco.com</p> <ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://www.cio.com/article/4131963/%EC%98%A4%ED%94%88%ED%81%B4%EB%A1%9C%EB%B0%9C-%EB%B3%B4%EC%95%88-%EB%A6%AC%EC%8A%A4%ED%81%AC-%ED%99%95%EC%82%B0%C2%B7%C2%B7%C2%B7ciso%EB%A5%BC-%EC%9C%84%ED%95%9C-%ED%95%B5%EC%8B%AC-%EC%A0%90%EA%B2%80.html">관련 기사 : 오픈클로發 보안 리스크 확산····CISO가 지금 점검해야 할 핵심 사항</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div></div></div>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[JDK 26 and JDK 27: What We Know So Far]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-26-so-far/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-26-so-far/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/java-26-so-far/en/headerimage/java-istock-image-01-1771538935227.jpg"/><p>JDK 26, the first non-LTS release since JDK 25, has reached its second release candidate with a final set of 10 new features, in the form of JEPs, that can be separated into five categories: Core Java Library, HotSpot, Java Language Specification, Security Library and Client Library. We examine JDK 26 and predict what features have, or could be, targeted for JDK 27.</p> <i>By Michael Redlich</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-20]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Meet Our Director of AI: Jarand Narbuvold]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/meet-our-director-of-ai-jarand-narbuvold/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/meet-our-director-of-ai-jarand-narbuvold/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[At Ardoq, we’ve always believed that meaningful innovation comes from combining strong technical foundations with clear strategic intent. As AI rapidly reshapes how software platforms are built and used, it’s increasingly important for us to b...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Reducing Onboarding from 48 Hours to 4: inside Amazon Key’s Event-Driven Platform]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=Architecture+%26+Design-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/amazon-key-event-driven-platform/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771041547572.jpg"/><p>Amazon Key modernized its event platform by adopting a centralized, event-driven architecture built on Amazon EventBridge. The redesign processes millions of daily events with millisecond latency, improves schema governance, automates cross-account routing, and reduces service onboarding time from 48 hours to four, while maintaining 99.99 percent reliability.</p> <i>By Leela Kumili</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When Excellent Technology Architecture Fails to Deliver Business Results]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Nadzeya Stalbouskaya Strong technology architecture is no longer rare. Clean layers, cloud-first strategies, modern platforms, and well-defined principles have become standard practice across large organizations. On paper, architecture often looks solid, coherent, and defensible. And <a class="mh-excerpt-more" href="https://www.architectureandgovernance.com/applications-technology/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/" title="When Excellent Technology Architecture Fails to Deliver Business Results">[...]</a>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[When Excellent Technology Architecture Fails to Deliver Business Results]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://eavoices.com/2026/02/19/when-excellent-technology-architecture-fails-to-deliver-business-results/]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By Nadzeya Stalbouskaya Strong technology architecture is no longer rare. Clean layers, cloud-first strategies, modern platforms, and well-defined principles have become standard practice across large organizations. On paper, architecture often looks s...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hugging Face Introduces Community Evals for Transparent Model Benchmarking]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/hugging-face-evals/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.infoq.com/news/2026/02/hugging-face-evals/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&utm_source=infoq&utm_medium=feed&utm_term=AI%2C+ML+%26+Data+Engineering-news]]></guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://res.infoq.com/news/2026/02/hugging-face-evals/en/headerimage/generatedHeaderImage-1771448477065.jpg"/><p>Hugging Face has launched Community Evals, a feature that enables benchmark datasets on the Hub to host their own leaderboards and automatically collect evaluation results from model repositories.</p> <i>By Daniel Dominguez</i>]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
      <dc:date><![CDATA[2026-02-19]]></dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
